<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>music on dill &amp; fennel</title>
    <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in music on dill &amp; fennel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Copyright Brook Shelley 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Favorite Albums of 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-12-09-favorite-albums-of-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-12-09-favorite-albums-of-2020/</guid>
      <description>Listen on Apple Music
Viewing — Stay Inside
Despite a band name that’s a bit on the nose for this year, I really enjoyed this album especially during the anger stage of quarantine.</description>
      <content:encoded><p><a href="https://music.apple.com/us/playlist/favorites-of-2020/pl.u-ZPWLjTB1qLJ">Listen on Apple Music</a></p>
<p><strong>Viewing</strong> — Stay Inside</p>
<p>Despite a band name that’s a bit on the nose for this year, I really enjoyed this album especially during the anger stage of quarantine. There&rsquo;s something about this style of pop-punk/midwest emo that takes me back to my youth in the best way.</p>
<p><strong>The Caretaker</strong> — Half Waif</p>
<p>Lavender, Half Waif’s previous album was on my list in 2018 and again this year she delivered a haunting, beautiful record. There&rsquo;s a lot more dancy-bits this year than in 2018, but her voice stays just as emotive, holding its own against the tracks.</p>
<p><strong>Likewise</strong> — Frances Quinlan</p>
<p>Quinlan’s voice is wildly passionate, and incredibly unique. I love the organ and keys on various tracks, and hearing her voice complemented by a board swath of harp, and strings. The tone shift is significant from her Hop Along project, and I think it shows a ton of depth and creativity. Your Reply and Now That I&rsquo;m Back are favorites.</p>
<p><strong>Every Bad</strong> — Porridge Radio</p>
<p>This is a new band for me this year. Margolin&rsquo;s voice is a delight as she hoarsely sings loud parts, and croons right into my heart. Excellent music for feeling a bit romantic and just chilling out.</p>
<p><strong>Myopia</strong> — Agnes Obel</p>
<p>Every Agnes Obel album is an opportunity to remember how much I love her music. Between her beautiful voice, and the haunting melodies and instrumentation, this album is perfect for a crisp morning, or a chill night&rsquo;s walk.</p>
<p><strong>Walking Like We Do</strong> — The Big Moon</p>
<p>This album contains an anthem for ADHD. Extra points for being a band of four women as well. Every track on this album is catchy as hell, with some driving rhythms on Your Light and anthems to lost loves like on Barcelona.</p>
<p><strong>Shadow Offering</strong> — Braids</p>
<p>I first saw Braids years ago at a SXSW as they were working on their first album, Lemonade. Since then, every release was great, but this album is really them in their stride.</p>
<p><strong>Jump Rope Gazers</strong> — The Beths</p>
<p>The Beths put on one of the best shows I saw last year, with superb pop punk.</p>
<p><strong>Holding</strong> — Hailaker</p>
<p>Beautiful. I love the simple breathy quality of Jemima Coulter&rsquo;s voice. The UK really represents on my list this year with some awesome female vocals.</p>
<p><strong>Microphones in 2020</strong> — Microphones</p>
<p>If you want to sob for a while, throw on a recent Microphones record. After a few years of truly devastating work about the death of his wife, and a breakup with his second wife, Elverum is back to exploring.</p>
<p><strong>Punisher</strong> — Phoebe Bridgers</p>
<p>Duh.</p>
<p><strong>Hannah</strong> — Lomelda</p>
<p>This might be my favorite album of all this year. Lomelda was a soundtrack for a few trips to Osaka, as I sat in small kissaten and sipped coffee while reading. Her voice is soft, and sad in the best ways. This album builds on her earlier work and goes from apologetic to proud as it plays on.</p>
<p><strong>The Quiet City</strong> — Library Tapes</p>
<p>This is an absolute banger of a chill out album. There are a lot of fantastic collaborations in this collection with Akira Kosemura standing out particularly.</p>
<p><strong>Hold Space For Me</strong> — Orion Sun</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m a sucker for these weird backing tracks and her lush vocals. This is a fucking dope album with a blend of so many styles and moods. A real spring surprise for me, though she played a big festival in 2018. Definitely an artist to watch. Coffee for Dinner is a standout. It&rsquo;s impossible not to dance a little when you listen.</p>
<p><strong>Oar</strong> — Manami Kakudo</p>
<p>For some reason this album is considered J-Pop by Apple Music, but it feels a bit more like the songs I loved from Lily Chou-Chou or some folks artists. I love the delicate instrumentation, heavy on strings and keys. There&rsquo;s a real intimacy in the performance here that makes me wish I could see her play at some small venue&hellip; or like I already have.</p>
<p><strong>Forever</strong> — Midwife</p>
<p>This album is largely instrumental, but when her voice comes through it&rsquo;s ethereal and fantastic. This album is about losing a friend in 2018, and it&rsquo;s best saved for those down times.</p>
<p><strong>Honeymoon</strong> — Beach Bunny</p>
<p>A truly excellent indie bop. Beach Bunny slots in nicely with the recent revival of amazing female-fronted pop-punk. Rearview and Cuffing Season are especially dope.</p>
<p><strong>In Waiting</strong> — Pillow Queens</p>
<p>Bless queer lady music. This album makes me want to fall in love again.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Favorite Albums of 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-26-favorite-albums-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-26-favorite-albums-2019/</guid>
      <description>The Playlist Here&amp;rsquo;s all the albums I really loved this year easily accessible as an Apple Playlist.
The Albums  Cheap Queen — King Princess  Bless lesbian musicians.</description>
      <content:encoded><h2 id="the-playlist">The Playlist</h2>
<p><a href="https://music.apple.com/us/playlist/favorites-of-2019/pl.u-vp3jjIrk0xN">Here&rsquo;s all the albums I really loved this year</a> easily accessible as an Apple Playlist.</p>
<h2 id="the-albums">The Albums</h2>
<ol>
<li><strong>Cheap Queen</strong> — King Princess</li>
</ol>
<p>Bless lesbian musicians. King Princess first caught my attention with the song Pussy is God, which damn. This album is a bop.</p>
<ol start="2">
<li><strong>Emily Alone</strong> — Florist</li>
</ol>
<p>A deeply sparse, sad album that I enjoy quite a bit. Florist has always made beautiful songs, but this is a so quiet and so delightful.</p>
<ol start="3">
<li><strong>Interloper</strong> — Momma</li>
</ol>
<p>Just the right amount of harmonies and hooks to draw you into a strange and fun indie rock band.</p>
<ol start="4">
<li><strong>Family Tree</strong> — Oh Land</li>
</ol>
<p>A gorgeous album from a Danish former dancer. I just love her voice—from the start the album has a haunting beauty.</p>
<ol start="5">
<li><strong>Scholars</strong> — Buke &amp; Gase</li>
</ol>
<p>I&rsquo;ve had every album Buke &amp; Gase put out on repeat for some time after their release, and dearly love their jangly, angular rock. This album doesn&rsquo;t disappoint.</p>
<ol start="6">
<li><strong>Beast on Beast</strong> — Gabby&rsquo;s World</li>
</ol>
<p>This is the first band I&rsquo;ve listened to that has gone through three name changes, from Eskimeaux, to Ó, then finally Gabby&rsquo;s World. I&rsquo;ve loved them the whole time, and find this to be especially good sad subway music for when you&rsquo;re a little bummed and riding home at night.</p>
<ol start="7">
<li><strong>Placeholder</strong> — Hand Habits</li>
</ol>
<p>A complex jam album with fantastic guitars and vocals weaving in and out of downtempo songs.</p>
<ol start="8">
<li><strong>Memory Streams</strong> — Portico Quartet</li>
</ol>
<p>I first heard this band at a vinyl bar in Oakland, and their latest album rules.</p>
<ol start="9">
<li><strong>Trust In The Lifeforce Of The Deep Mystery</strong> — The Comet Is Coming</li>
</ol>
<p>Fantastic end of the world music. This is really strange, funky jazz, and I dig it. Many mornings start off with this album and some coffee.</p>
<ol start="10">
<li><strong>Nowhere Now Here</strong> — MONO</li>
</ol>
<p>I&rsquo;ve been stoked on MONO since high school, and was lucky enough to see them perform many times at Emo&rsquo;s (RIP) in Austin. They just keep on making fantastic music that vacillates softer beautiful sounds and driving melodies. Whether you&rsquo;re walking around the city or taking a train to another city, this album creates a gorgeous soundtrack for your life.</p>
<ol start="11">
<li><strong>Patience</strong> — Manequin Pussy</li>
</ol>
<p>A chill mix of punk and indie rock jams. I think I first saw this band at a show/benefit for Bernie Sanders that I didn’t know was a benefit. It was a super washed crowd, but Manequin Pussy owned bones. This record rules.</p>
<ol start="12">
<li><strong>Crush on Me</strong> — Sir Babygirl</li>
</ol>
<p>I’m really enjoying the new influx of queer and lesbian pop music these days. This album is infectiously catchy and often hilarious. Put it on and enjoy the short bouts of sun this winter.</p>
<ol start="13">
<li><strong>Miss Universe</strong> — Nilüfer Yanya</li>
</ol>
<p>I&rsquo;m not sure how to describe this album, but it&rsquo;s a jam. A bit of r&amp;b, a bit of indie rock, and a lot of really solid tunes. I&rsquo;ve put this album on a repeat a few times this year.</p>
<ol start="14">
<li><strong>Hifalutin</strong> — Lowly</li>
</ol>
<p>Super dance-y-yet-downtempo album. I can throw this on for a variety of moods, and it seems to always suit them. There’s something about Denmark that must inspire people to make brilliant music—this album was recorded in a small warehouse near Aarhus.</p>
<ol start="15">
<li><strong>Weird</strong> — Juliana Hatfield</li>
</ol>
<p>Oh hey, an album that feels like I do sometimes: “I&rsquo;m staying in/My hair’s not right/And if I go out/Somebody might
Take me for a functioning/Human being”. I’m sure I heard Hatfield before this album, but this is the one where she came together for me as an artist.</p>
<ol start="16">
<li><strong>Fibs</strong> — Anna Meredith</li>
</ol>
<p>This album is a solid jam. Anna Meredith&rsquo;s compositions feel important, weird, and powerful. I often listen to this album in the morning to wake up and feel better about the day.</p>
<ol start="17">
<li><strong>Four of Arrows</strong> — Great Grandpa</li>
</ol>
<p>For a sophmore effort this is a really fun, mature album. I like that they&rsquo;ve moved from more straightforward poppy indie music to a little more melodic rock.</p>
<ol start="18">
<li><strong>Two Hands</strong> — Big Thief</li>
</ol>
<p>Honestly, the fact that Big Thief put out <em>two</em> incredible albums this year is wild to me. I love both of their 2019 records, but Two Hands especially keeps going back on the stereo. It&rsquo;s gorgeous. Jia Tolentino wrote about them recently, and I recommend <a href="https://www.newyorker.com/culture/cultural-comment/the-ordinary-brilliance-of-big-thief">reading her piece</a>.</p>
<ol start="19">
<li><strong>Any Human Friend</strong> — Marika Hackman</li>
</ol>
<p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;ve got BDE/I think it&rsquo;s a venereal disease&rdquo;. Ugh. This album is an instant lesbian classic. I&rsquo;ve loved every album Hackman has put out, with That Iron Taste immediately pulling me in, and constantly being on rotation. I got to see her perform in Portland a few years back, and the show was outstanding. Between her soft vocal delivery, which whispers with poetry and sensuality, and the brutally raw lyrical content&hellip; just wow.</p>
<ol start="20">
<li><strong>Lost Wisdom Pt.</strong> — Mount Eerie</li>
</ol>
<p>After the utter devastation of his past two albums, this truly sad album about an impending divorce with beautiful guest vocals from Julie Doiron almost comes as a relief. This is a tragedy I can almost understand, feelings I have felt. Microphones and Mount Eerie have held me through many hard times, and this album is an excellent entry into their discography.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My favorite albums of the year</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-12-20-my-favorite-albums-of-the-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-12-20-my-favorite-albums-of-the-year/</guid>
      <description>in no particular order On Apple Music
The list Dilly Dally Heaven: I listened to this amazing band’s first album so much in the three years since it came out, and the vocal delivery is raw and beautiful.</description>
      <content:encoded><p><em>in no particular order</em> <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/playlist/favorites-of-2018/pl.u-PJExpCqGgBj">On Apple Music</a></p>
<h2 id="the-list">The list</h2>
<p><strong>Dilly Dally</strong> <em>Heaven</em>: I listened to this amazing band’s first album so much in the three years since it came out, and the vocal delivery is raw and beautiful. A true jam.</p>
<p><strong>Ex:Re</strong> <em>Ex:Re</em>: A delightfully sad and smart album about lost love, and healing. This was a late-arrival this year, and has already been a constant repeat.</p>
<p><strong>Anna McClellan</strong> <em>Yes and No</em>: A similarly raw singing style to Dilly Dally, this is a bummer jam. The juxtaposition between her low, gritty voice, and when she moves into a higher register is fantastic.</p>
<p><strong>Gia Margaret</strong> <em>There’s Always a Glimmer</em>: Continuing down the bummer album trail, Gia Margaret created a gorgeous album that combines piano, light percussion, and a hint of electronics to create an album that perfectly compliments how I feel when I’m lost in thought.</p>
<p><strong>The Beths</strong> <em>Future Hates Me</em>: This album <em>rips</em>! Like, wow. What a fantastic, tightly instrumented, and infectious pop-punk album. This is a band to watch. It’s almost impossible not to sing along to this.</p>
<p><strong>The Internet</strong> <em>Hive Mind</em>: This is a blessed year—right after getting a new Syd album, 2018 brings a new album from The Internet. Every track is a bop, and is a good way to come back up from some of the bummer tunes listed above.</p>
<p><strong>Tirzah</strong> <em>Devotion</em>: This album feels stripped down to the core of Tirzah’s voice. There’s light instrumentation, and just hypnotic melodies and just enough percussion to get you going.</p>
<p><strong>Svalbard</strong> <em>It’s Hard to Have Hope</em>: This album encapsulates so much of the pain and anger of being a woman in the 2010s. Tracks cover abortion, feminism, and a lot more. Crank this up when you’re lifting weights, or just need to feel seen for a bit.</p>
<p><strong>Remember Sports</strong> <em>Slow Buzz</em>: More amazing pop punk from a band I’ve been repeatedly listening to from before they had to change their name to “Remember Sports”. Their lyrics crack me up sometimes, and I feel real joy listening to these tracks.</p>
<p><strong>Camp Cope</strong> <em>How to Socialise and Make Friends</em>: This is just solid indie rock. I love the lead woman’s voice, and the songs have a punk ethos and feeling, even as they’re a bit slower paced.</p>
<p><strong>Sara Renberg</strong> <em>Night Sands</em>: “I googled elderly lesbians to cheer myself, but the results were all porn”. The grim humor and fantastic delivery of the vocals on this album made me repeat it often. Another great “yea that’s how I’m feeling exactly!” jam.</p>
<p><strong>Hop Along</strong> <em>Bark Your Head Off, Dog</em>: This was definitely a year for listening to gritty female vocals. I have no clue how she sings this way on tour without just shredding her throat, but also it’s so, so fucking good. Every Hop Along album has ruled, and this might be my favorite.</p>
<p><strong>Half Waif</strong> <em>Lavender</em>: I cried to this album on planes a lot this year. Half Waif rules, and if my other picks were kinda rough, her voice might be a salve. This is <em>only her second album</em> and there’s already so much depth.</p>
<p><strong>Soccer Mommy</strong> <em>Clean</em>: Another really, really pretty and sad album. The vibe of this album is so perfect for Fall.</p>
<p><strong>Let’s Eat Grandma</strong> <em>I’m All Ears</em>: This music makes me dance. I got to see them perform earlier this year, and even in Portland, people were getting down. It’s also super clear the women in this band are just stoked to be making these jams.</p>
<p><strong>Tancred</strong> <em>Nightstand</em>: One of the gayer albums I loved this year. At times she reminds me of PJ Harvey, or Fiona Apple. The phrasing and style of her delivery is pitch-perfect.</p>
<hr>
<h2 id="a-note-on-listening-this-year">A note on listening this year</h2>
<p>This isn’t a comprehensive list of what I listened to by any means, and by switching to Apple Music partway through the year, my listening is fractured in a way that’s hard to glue together. Music at home often happens on my Sonos, and still gets sent to Last.fm, I think, but anything on mobile (most of my time) is mostly locally stored as history.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>August shows</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-13-august-shows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-13-august-shows/</guid>
      <description>A few years ago, after moving to Portland, I discovered a secret: you can do almost anything alone. I&amp;rsquo;d lived in Austin for most of my life, and as I quickly learned once moving, making friends in Portland is a long process.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>A few years ago, after moving to Portland, I discovered a secret: you can do
almost anything alone. I&rsquo;d lived in Austin for most of my life, and as I
quickly learned once moving, making friends in Portland is a long process. So,
on a whim, I started seeing movies by myself. I went to dinner alone with a
book. I even saw concerts&hellip; solo, and it was fun. I don&rsquo;t know why we all
think you have to do these activities with other people, but when you go alone
you don&rsquo;t have to wait for anyone to be ready to go, or to leave. There&rsquo;s no
coordination necessary, and if you want to talk to someone, you can always text
or use Slack. At dinner, I usually bring a book, and just relax with whatever
author I&rsquo;m reading at the time. It&rsquo;s magical.</p>
<p>This last weekend, I went to two shows: one alone, and one with a new friend I
met in SF at Karaoke who lives in Portland—Hi Mehan.</p>
<h2 id="hop-along--thin-lips">Hop Along &amp; Thin Lips</h2>
<p><img src="/photos/photo-2.jpeg" alt="Hop along"></p>
<p>Friday was <a href="https://hopalong.bandcamp.com">Hop Along</a>, with <a href="https://xxthinlipsxx.bandcamp.com">Thin Lips</a> opening. I&rsquo;ve never seen either of these
Philly bands before, but they were both excellent. Thin lips is a punk-y band
with a rad queer lady lead singer, who covers chosen family, dating, and
anxiety. I&rsquo;d never heard of them before this show, but now they&rsquo;re on a regular
rotation in my headphones. Hop Along is a favorite of mine since their first
album, and Frances' voice was incredible in person. They have a sound that&rsquo;s
difficult to discuss, so I hope you listen. Her voice is singular, and hella
powerful. I usually have at least one of their songs humming in my head any
given week while I grocery shop, or go on walks. I stood and danced a bit for
both of these bands, and in between, I read on my Kindle iOS app, when I
might&rsquo;ve made small talk. There were a LOT of couples at this show, many of
them queer, which ruled. Seeing bands is kinda cool as a date, in my
experience, because how often do you get to quietly enjoy something with a
loved one?</p>
<h2 id="deafheaven">Deafheaven</h2>
<p><img src="/photos/photo.jpeg" alt="Deafheaven"></p>
<p>Sunday night, I saw <a href="https://deafheavens.bandcamp.com">Deafheaven</a>, who&rsquo;re kind
of &ldquo;metal for folks who don&rsquo;t like metal&rdquo;. They&rsquo;re sick, and both times I&rsquo;ve
seen them they play and sing their hearts out. Bonus points for Geroge, the
lead singer, growing out his hipster haircut into some serious 90s metal locks.
Headbanging just works better with long hair. Hung with my friend in between
sets, and made dumb jokes. The openers weren&rsquo;t really my jam, but Deafheaven
put on such a wild long set, I immediately forgot about the first hour or so of
so-so music.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve got a few more shows coming up this year, and I&rsquo;m stoked AF to see Mitski,
especially.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
