<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tv on dill &amp; fennel</title>
    <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/tv/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tv on dill &amp; fennel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Copyright Brook Shelley 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/tv/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stoked on Survivor</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-06-12-stoked-on-survivor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-06-12-stoked-on-survivor/</guid>
      <description>After twenty years of this CBS reality show being on TV, I finally jumped on board as a fan. A few years ago, a podcast I enjoy discussed a John Siricusa’s longstanding love of Survivor, and even offered a list of his favorite seasons.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>After twenty years of this CBS reality show being on TV, I finally jumped on board as a fan. A few years ago, <a href="https://www.relay.fm/rd">a podcast</a> I enjoy discussed a John Siricusa’s longstanding love of Survivor, and even offered a <a href="https://www.relay.fm/rd/94">list of his favorite seasons</a>. I dipped a toe in with one season, then promptly decided that was enough, until March brought a shelter at home.</p>
<h2 id="my-survivor-history">My survivor history</h2>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="und" dir="ltr"> <a href="https://t.co/idklXV8QtN">pic.twitter.com/idklXV8QtN</a></p>&mdash; Drew Schuster (@nuncamind) <a href="https://twitter.com/nuncamind/status/1271576075185737728?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 12, 2020</a></blockquote>
<script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>

<p>Until the being stuck inside this year, I had only seen season 37, David vs Goliath. Growing up I thought Survivor and most reality tv show was garbage, and instead watched a lot of auteur film and highbrow dramas. I can’t say that Survivor is high-brow, but I’ve been pleasantly surprised at the strange subtleties of its comedy, and the joy of a weird cast of characters. My friend Drew, who bought me the Cameo above, was the person that finally tipped me over the edge into being a fan. He’s got great silly taste, and our near-daily chats about this show are a balm in this time.</p>
<p>When you watch Survivor, it turns out there’s a lot to get sucked into: constant politicking and a mix of grim and utterly bizarre challenges every episode. Too often folks end up very badly injured, and need to be sent home for their safety, which I could do without. I think they do a good job of having medical staff, but I still worry someone will eventually die on this show. However as an effort to convince the viewer that this competition is grueling, folks suffering in the rain and sun and other scenes of misery are effective to say the least.</p>
<h2 id="the-format">The format</h2>
<p>Survivor is an often Machiavellian social game, albeit with occasional gaffes. There are <a href="https://survivor.fandom.com/wiki/Survivor_Rulebook">official rules</a>, and throughout the years you can watch the show staff figure out strange edge cases during an episode.</p>
<p>Every season begins simply with 20 people from various backgrounds, chosen by the producers (save for one season) for their potentially compelling stories. They usually start from a boat, or a helicopter as they’re abandoned on a tropical island or deserted location. Most seasons then break the contestants down to two or three groups, occasionally with a silly theme like “brains vs. beauty vs. brawn” that can feel a little contrived. Every episode these “tribes” compete for a reward, and immunity from voting a member of their group out. As the seasons progress, Survivor adds in strange twists, like immunity idols, fire tokens, and an exile island. Some seasons are truly entertaining, with a great cast, and shocking twists. Others, I’m told, are very boring.</p>
<p>As the season continues, there is usually a shuffling of tribal membership, and eventually a “merge” of the tribes for the final ten players. There are meals from various fast-casual restaurants, prizes from weird big box stores, and people nearly crying from the chance to have a soda. It’s hugely entertaining tv.</p>
<h2 id="winning-it-all">Winning it all</h2>
<p>Different styles of players win each season, which means I’ve often found myself guessing until late in the season who might take home the cash prize. Sometimes, it’s someone physically strong, but often it’s the clever social butterfly, or conniving “villain” that doesn’t mind betraying everyone. The especially fun twist at the end of every season is that the last 8-10 people voted out of the show by their tribes vote for the winner from the last 2 or three contestants. Play too dirty, or too vindictively, and survivors run the risk of alienating their judges.</p>
<h2 id="is-it-all-white-guys">Is it all white guys?</h2>
<p>Recently, the show has grappled with its own sexism and prejudices a bit more than usual, and hopefully in future seasons women can seen in a more positive light for doing the things men are rewarded for every episode. With a very odd mistake of making a “race war” season, the casting tends to be somewhat diverse, and includes queer and trans characters occasionally as well. For CBS especially, this feels impressive—though I think that’s perhaps a low bar. Folks do tend to dislike cops on the show, which honestly checks out.</p>
<h2 id="how-i-watch">How I watch</h2>
<p>I recommend not googling any season you’re curious about too hard, as there tend to be spoilers. In my quest to watch “the good seasons” after watching the 20th anniversary season Winners at War, with only previous winners playing, I found <a href="http://www.purplerockpodcast.com/survivor-season-rankings-spoiler-free-summaries/">this spoiler-free list</a> of all forty seasons, ranked by quality. At this point, I’ve watched most of 9 seasons, and am working through Fans vs. Favorites as I write this. A few seasons offered spoilers through their “redemption” theme, but in general that list has worked well for me thus far.</p>
<p>If you can handle the SD quality of the first season, it might be nice to start right at the beginning and meet the character that made fun of my CSS earlier in this post. Richard Hatch is a whole wild story, but don’t look him up until you’ve seen at least the first season. If something more modern and HD is up your alley, David vs. Goliath was a nice starter for me, and offered a lot of entertainment, and Cagayan (Season 28) also left me laughing more often than not.</p>
<h2 id="give-it-a-try">Give it a try</h2>
<p>Ultimately if you’ve thought, like me, that Survivor isn’t worth watching, I recommend challenging that notion. Sure, it’s not the smartest thing on TV, but as we sit inside indefinitely, with limited options to visit islands of ourselves (unless you live on one), this is prime action and escapism for this time.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rewatching Halt &amp; Catch Fire</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-01-09-rewatching-halt-catch-fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-01-09-rewatching-halt-catch-fire/</guid>
      <description>The first time When Halt &amp;amp; Catch Fire first aired, I was lucky enough to clue in and watch it weekly on AMC.</description>
      <content:encoded><h2 id="the-first-time">The first time</h2>
<p>When Halt &amp; Catch Fire first aired, I was lucky enough to clue in and watch it weekly on AMC. As a Texan with a dad who occasionally worked in or at least around tech, and then joined the industry myself, it captured the world I grew up in incredibly well. Starting out a little rough, it became a show all about family and how ambition can destroy everything. H&amp;CF remains one of my favorite shows of all time, and despite it being entirely too emotionally intense to watch again before now, I happily tuned back in this past fall.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/Halt.jpg" alt="halt and catch fire logo"></p>
<h2 id="a-rewatch-begins">A rewatch begins</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;d almost forgotten how hopeful the show began. Joe, Cameron, Donna, Boz, and Gordon all dove in and ended up going to an early CES—when AVN still happened next door. As I write this, CES is happening again in Vegas, but the dreams are smaller and <a href="https://daringfireball.net/2020/01/concept_electronics_show">the concepts more far-fetched</a>. In the 80s of this show, the world was about to change completely. We follow a company at the time of IBM&rsquo;s dominance, with a parallel but less successful track than Apple. Word processors barely existed, and computers weighed 30lbs.</p>
<p>What so quickly began as a dream to make the future of computing turned into just making another IBM clone. What stuck with me in this first season was the crushing sadness of mediocre money. When I watched season one, I was a younger woman with a lot of dreams. Five years later, I&rsquo;ve had a fair amount of failure, and some great success. I work for <a href="https://slackhq.com">an amazing company</a> after <a href="https://www.turbinelabs.io">our Mutiny</a> petered-out. Unlike the Cardiff Electronics or McMillain Utility of H&amp;CF, my next adventure is delightful.</p>
<p>I still haven&rsquo;t seen another show that so fully captures how difficult it is to build something with the folks you love or how much it hurts to lose them. With a second watch, I brought my feelings and memories of all of the ups and downs, which compounded each wave. Everyone was so young. It felt like this show was about adults when I first saw it, but now they seem like me or even younger. This realization helped me have more compassion for the idiocy and backstabbing as I watched. Before I saw a thoughtless jerk, and now I saw the pain of making tough decisions. When I first watched this show, I had just moved to Portland, Oregon, and now that I&rsquo;m watching it for a second time, I&rsquo;m in the bay—the setting for most of the show. I see many of the backdrops that Joe and Donna see on a daily basis, and it really makes the show come alive.</p>
<h2 id="a-queer-angle">A queer angle</h2>
<p>From the first time I saw him on <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pushing_Daisies">Pushing Daisies</a>, I had a feeling <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lee_Pace">Lee Pace</a> was on my team. Last year <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/04/style/gay-actors-on-broadway-lee-pace.html">in the NY Times</a>, he confirmed it. H&amp;CF showed a brief glimpse of the AIDs crisis, and one fleeting queer party at Joe&rsquo;s house. I wish they&rsquo;d let written the show with more queer characters, or done more too how the struggle of gay men in the 80s and 90s, but even these little bits were more than I ever expected from a show about tech. I hope one day a story like this can have queer and trans women too.</p>
<h2 id="donna-and-cameron">Donna and Cameron</h2>
<p>By the second season, it seems like the show runners had the same revelation many of my friends watching the show for the first time have: this show is better when it&rsquo;s about Donna and Cameron. The tensions between them, and the challenges of their friendship are the lifeblood of the show. Cameron needs Donna&rsquo;s stability, and Donna wants the respect that everyone has for Cameron&rsquo;s abilities. As Mutiny struggles, and Swap Meet kicks off the tensions almost destroy them, but by the end of the show, they&rsquo;re ready to trust again. Their love and sisterhood are often sad, but ultimately an inspiring look at how two women can go beyond a competition to something lasting.</p>
<p>I haven&rsquo;t seen Kerry Bishé in much since H&amp;CF, but it seems like she&rsquo;s been busy with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Happily_(film)">big film projects</a>. Meanwhile, Mackenzie Davis was in an <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/San_Junipero">incredible episode of Black Mirror</a>, the upcoming adaptation of Station Eleven, and the ridiculous new <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Terminator:_Dark_Fate">Terminator film</a>. I don&rsquo;t know if they&rsquo;ll ever work together again, but they were incredible together in this show.</p>
<h2 id="the-tech">The tech</h2>
<p>Most of the first few seasons were populated with technology I never got to use as a kid, save for the Apple IIe, but by the third season I saw myself in Donna and Gordon&rsquo;s daughter&rsquo;s eagerly waiting for a chance to play the NES. My parents used to bogart Super Mario Brothers just like Cameron and Gordon did as they played it on their new projection screen. My dad was never a HAM radio guy, but the single-minded love of hobbies mirrored Gordon&rsquo;s. I remember Lotus software, and the rise of laser tag, the thrill of dialing-up to the burgeoning world-wide web. I wish anyone on this show had learned how to touch-type.</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t fondly remember the rise of security software, but hey, neither did the show. Watching this show, I saw myself as a kid around with a big set of headphones over my head, and a walkman on my belt. Those were the days. The community of Mutiny was what I found eventually on forums and in queer chat rooms and that too fly true in this show. I even love some of the cars—RIP Joe&rsquo;s 944.</p>
<h2 id="halt-and-catch-fire-is-incredible">Halt and Catch Fire is incredible</h2>
<p>This rewatch was inspired by <a href="https://500ish.com/halted-caught-fire-8128de2d111a">a newsletter I read</a>, wherein the writer is afraid to finish the show completely. I understand this feeling completely, as I find myself slowing down while I watch in order to savor every episode. I&rsquo;ll probably rewatch this show a few more times this decade, and I can only hope someone else one day makes a show I&rsquo;ll love as much as this one.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formula 1</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-04-13-formula-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-04-13-formula-1/</guid>
      <description>When I mention my love of Formula 1 racing, most of the time I hear, &amp;ldquo;is that like NASCAR?&amp;rdquo; This speaks to the sad lack of F1 information and excitement in the states, and it&amp;rsquo;s a bummer.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>When I mention my love of Formula 1 racing, most of the time I hear, &ldquo;is that like NASCAR?&rdquo; This speaks to the sad lack of F1 information and excitement in the states, and it&rsquo;s a bummer. NASCAR is a sport in its own right, but comparing it to F1 is a bit like comparing rotary phones to an iPhone. F1 is fast, the roads twist this way and that, and most importantly the drivers are from across the globe. Drama between these drivers, these princes of speed, is often even more entertaining than the drama on the track. With the launch of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Formula_1:_Drive_to_Survive">Netflix&rsquo;s F1 documentary</a> that covers the events of the 2018 season, my hope is more folks in the states will get excited about the best racing series in the world.</p>
<h2 id="my-history-with-racing">My history with racing</h2>
<p>When I was a kid, my uncle was involved in car racing as a pit crew member, and occasional pit chief. He&rsquo;d gotten his start racing motorcycles in the 70s and early 80s, and by the time he&rsquo;d moved away, I&rsquo;d been to a number of CART and Grand Prix races around Dallas. My whole family loved cars. I grew up around Mustangs being worked-on, oil changes, and DIY repairs. I rode a small motorcycle as a kid I inherited from that same uncle who raced and wrenched on cars, and fell deeply in love with speed.</p>
<p>We watched a few racing series when I was younger, but my attention span meant nothing really stuck. Years later, that changed.</p>
<h2 id="watching-weekly">Watching weekly</h2>
<p>After college, I settled into a tech career and had relatively low-key weekends full of TV and reading. The exact impetus escapes me (it was probably Top Gear related), but at one point, I found a way to stream F1 races every week. My new routine was watching the qualification rounds on Saturday, and then watching an F1 race the next day. I was quickly sucked into the dramatic rise of Sebastian Vettel, who seemed to be incapable of failure as he racked-up victories in the Red Bull F1 car. I loved watching Jenson Button, who seemed like a charming enough fellow, and Kimi Raikonnenn, who&rsquo;s dry wit, and sour temperament was weirdly hilarious.</p>
<p>The modern era of F1 is largely ruled by three teams:</p>
<pre><code>- [Mercedes](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mercedes-Benz_in_Formula_One): Hamilton &amp; Bottas (Formerly Rosberg)
- [Red Bull](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red_Bull_Racing): Verstapen &amp; Gasly (Formerly both Ricciardo &amp; Vettel)
- [Ferrari](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scuderia_Ferrari#Domination_in_the_early_2000s): Vettel &amp; LeClerc (Formerly Schumacher &amp; Raikonnen)
</code></pre>
<p>These teams have huge budgets, some of the best drivers, and a cutthroat ability to rule the front positions of almost every race. It&rsquo;s a little frustrating that for the most part, other teams don&rsquo;t win unless there&rsquo;s a big wreck or engine failure, but at least at times the competition between these three is heated.</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;ve watched the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Formula_1:_Drive_to_Survive">Netflix documentary</a>, you won&rsquo;t have seen too much about these top teams, as Mercedes and Ferrari declined to participate. But, what you did see was the exciting race to be best-of-the-rest, and a very optimistic goal for Renault or HAAS to become the 3rd or 4th place team one day. Rules changes may eventually help even the field, but until then, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HurubWM67MM">even back markers can cause a ruckus</a>.</p>
<h2 id="hope-for-the-future">Hope for the future</h2>
<p>With a launch of a <a href="https://wseries.com">women&rsquo;s race series</a> that has the stated goal of &ldquo;[giving] remarkable female drivers an opportunity in motorsport that simply hasn’t been available to them before now&rdquo;, I seriously hope one day we&rsquo;ll have a female F1 driver. It&rsquo;s fun enough to watch 20 guys race, but watching a few women shake things up would be incredible. I want young girls to dream of racing at 300km/h and have it be a real possibility. The <a href="https://wseries.com/races/hockenheim/">first race</a> of this rad new series is May 4th, and I can&rsquo;t wait to watch.</p>
<p>In a different direction, there&rsquo;s an all electric racing series called <a href="https://www.fiaformulae.com/en/championship/teams-and-drivers">Formula E</a>. Due to battery constraints, and I think to make for an exciting race, teams change cars mid-race, and there&rsquo;s odd bonuses to speed that fans can vote on. I&rsquo;ve watched a few of these races, and while I&rsquo;m glad to see a more eco-friendly race start to gain steam, it definitely feels like the neglected little brother of F1 at this point. Perhaps in the future, this race will have its own cache.</p>
<h2 id="getting-started">Getting started</h2>
<p>There are a <a href="https://www.techradar.com/news/2019-f1-live-stream-how-to-watch-every-grand-prix-online-from-anywhere">lot</a> of <a href="https://www.strikeout.nu/formula-1">ways</a> to <a href="https://formula1-live.stream">watch</a> <a href="http://stream.nbcsports.com/f1/">F1</a> <a href="https://f1tv.formula1.com/en/">racing</a>. Some of them are questionable legal, but Formula 1 has it&rsquo;s own <a href="https://www.formula1.com/en/subscribe-to-f1-tv.html#en">streaming plan</a>, which is probably the easiest way to watch if you don&rsquo;t mind spending a little money. Racing series might not be for you, but I hope if you do love it, you share it with folks. It&rsquo;s a cool, weird sport.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Favorite TV shows of 2018</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-01-01-favorite-tv-shows-of-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-01-01-favorite-tv-shows-of-2018/</guid>
      <description>This year I travelled quite a bit—almost 90 hours in the air. When I fly I always have my Kindle, but I usually find myself binge-watching a tv show, and keep my Plex loaded on my iPad with things to see.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>This year I travelled quite a bit—almost 90 hours in the air. When I fly I always have my Kindle, but I usually find myself binge-watching a tv show, and keep my Plex loaded on my iPad with things to see. I watch shows on Netflix and Amazon Prime as well, but the local storage and caching isn’t always dependable for planes, and nothing is more disappointing than getting on a plane and finding out that your shows won’t play. These shows are a mix of joyful, and melancholy, and I loved each one.</p>
<p><strong>Patriot</strong></p>
<p>Sad spies. This isn’t a very well-named show, as many folks have covered. Reviewing this show feels <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/review/patriot-review-1159350">a little redundant</a> because so many folks have talked about it in my sphere of tech news, but it’s <em>amazing</em>. If you like whimsy, and dark comedy, this is a splendid blend of both.</p>
<p><strong>Terrace House: Boys and Girls Next Door</strong></p>
<p>This show is the one that started it all. I loved Boys and Girls in the City, and the <em>bonkers</em> Aloha State, and this year meant the end of the fan-subbing of the original show. There was a movie at the end of this series called Closing Doors that made me cry quite a bit as well. From the introduction of Seina, to the tireless Tecchan, and some of the weirdest folks ever on Terrace House, this season is spectacular. It’s a gentle show, that shows what randomly living with 5 strangers is like when the drama is low.</p>
<p><strong>Counterpart</strong></p>
<p>Another spy show, this time set in Berlin. I don’t want to spoil much, but it’s a show about parallel universes, memory, and growth. I love the vibe of this show, and the way they play with modern and old technology. In some ways this reminds me of Fringe, but with a more serious tone. Well-worth a watch, if you can find it—it plays on Starz.</p>
<p><strong>Veep</strong></p>
<p>This year I watched all of Veep, and in a time of political turmoil, when everything feels farcical, this show was perfect. Dreyfus leads a cast of masterful comedians, and the stories felt timely and fresh. I can’t wait for the next season. Everyone is so accidentally clever, idiotic, or hilarious.</p>
<p><strong>Killing Eve</strong></p>
<p>Lesbian tension + spies &amp; international assassin ladies. It’s perfect.</p>
<p><strong>Baskets</strong></p>
<p>Another dark comedy that I initially dismissed. Zach Galafanikis plays two brothers and Louie Anderson plays a perfect suburban mom with so much heart. I never quite knew what to expect from this show, and it took me from uproarious laughter to tears in a single episode.</p>
<p><strong>Billions</strong></p>
<p>Another show I initially thought was not my thing, but got sucked deep into. This show, similar to Veep, felt like a great way to satirize and use current events to tell a wild story of a determined state prosecutor and his battle against a hedge fund manager. I’ve loved Damian Lewis since his turn as a marine-to-terrorist in Homeland, and he is outstanding in this.</p>
<p><strong>Documental</strong></p>
<p>10 comedians. One room. A ticking clock. The last one standing wins their own $1000 and everyone else’s too. The level of goofy, absurd, and scatological comedy is off the charts, and I learned of a ton of weird comedians through this. This is a Japanese show, and I hope that it continues to be translated by Amazon, because there are 4 more season in Japan than the two we have so far.</p>
<h2 id="anime">Anime</h2>
<p><strong>Girl’s Last Tour</strong></p>
<p>Post-apocalyptic queer anime girls. A friend told me the writer of this show wanted to illustrate how it felt to be queer in Japan. I’m not sure how true that is, but it’s a great show about friendship, and exploration.</p>
<p><strong>A Place Further Than the Universe</strong></p>
<p>Beautiful and sad. This is a show about a woman’s journey to the South Pole to visit the site of her mom’s death, and the friends she makes along the way. It’s gorgeous.</p>
<p><strong>Kokkoku</strong></p>
<p>A show about family and time-stopping dimensional shifting. Out of the shows this season, this was one that I was excited to go back to each week. My friend Ren got me into watching anime again this year while in Portland, and it was lovely to get together with her every week with fried chicken wings and anime time.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
