<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>travel on dill &amp; fennel</title>
    <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in travel on dill &amp; fennel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Copyright Brook Shelley 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 03:00:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hiking</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-09-03-hiking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 03:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-09-03-hiking/</guid>
      <description>Hiking Thanks to my friend Lena, I got to test out my new hiking shoes today at Redwood Regional Park.</description>
      <content:encoded><h1 id="hiking">Hiking</h1>
<p>Thanks to my friend Lena, I got to test out my new hiking shoes today at Redwood Regional Park.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/onshoes.jpg" alt="On shoes"></p>
<p>We did a very chill 5 mile hike with 1500’ climb and a total descent of 1000’.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/redwoodhiking.jpg" alt="redwood hiking path"></p>
<p>I think my workout program is really helping because while it wasn’t always easy to hike this trail, it was super doable and really fun. I ended-up with only a couple small blisters I chalk up to brand new shoes.</p>
<p>The thought of crowded trails during COVID was stressful, but the reality of hiking during the day (since I’m on vacation this week) was incredibly relaxing. I think we saw a total of 10 people over the course of 2 hours, and everyone was masked. We also saw a bunch of lizards, and cute dogs.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/forest.jpg" alt="forest"></p>
<p>The forest paths were naturally very cool, and relaxing, and even the sunny bits were around 20C/68F which meant we didn’t need to constantly stop to hydrate.  I haven’t hiked a lot since I lived in Texas, so I’m looking forward to trying to do more hiking even without flying anywhere. Lena and I talked about how much walking we both enjoy doing when traveling, but how we’re less likely to do so in our hometown. Hopefully I can do a bit more and actually embrace traveling close to home.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/me_hiking.jpg" alt="me"></p>
<p>Thanks again Lena for encouraging me to get out and walk!</p>
<p><img src="/photos/lena.jpg" alt="lena"></p>
<p>(I didn’t really edit these photos—all straight out of the JPEG processor of my <a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-08-07-a-few-weeks-with-a/">new Ricoh GRIII</a>.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 Backpacking gear</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-08-30-2020-backpacking-gear/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 20:45:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-08-30-2020-backpacking-gear/</guid>
      <description>Backpacking gear With flying out of the question, especially to other countries, I decided to do a bit of local adventuring.</description>
      <content:encoded><h1 id="backpacking-gear">Backpacking gear</h1>
<p>With flying out of the question, especially to other countries, I decided to do a bit of local adventuring. With the encouragement and planning of some Slack pals, I began to plan for a few days of backpacking, and more importantly, a few days of gear. Anyone who’s read my blog for a bit knows I’m a nerd about backpacks, technical clothing, and having the absolute minimum amount of stuff with me on trips. At home, I live pretty comfortably, but when I’m out of the house, I love the deep thrill of having exactly what I need.</p>
<p>The last camping trip I went on was during the eclipse 3 years ago in Dallas, Oregon. We drove there, and barely had to hike to put down our gear, so I brought a blow-up couch, a Nintendo switch, and medium-weight backpacking gear. I had an old REI sleeping bag that I’ve used for years, a <a href="https://www.rei.com/product/864138/mountain-hardwear-optic-25-tent">Mountain Hardware Optic 2.5 tent</a>, and a few jugs of water. All my gear, with 2 gallons of water hanging outside my pack as I was used to desert camping in Texas, weighed a bit over 25lbs, without food. This is pretty great for a car camping or one night camping situation, butI love going further and not having nearly as much on my back, plus I needed to bring food in my bag because I wouldn’t have a cooler with me on this upcoming trip.</p>
<p>Thus began my list:</p>
<h3 id="total-weight-337kg-or-744lbs">Total weight: 3.37kg or 7.44lbs</h3>
<h2 id="shelter">Shelter</h2>
<p><img src="/photos/nemo.jpg" alt="nemo"></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>1275.72g <a href="https://www.outdoorgearlab.com/reviews/camping-and-hiking/backpacking-tent/nemo-dragonfly-2">Nemo Dragonfly</a></p>
<p>This is a new addition to my list, but so far it seems neat, albeit very small. If I needed to spend extended time in a tent, I’d probably want something larger, but for a spot to sleep I think this will do just fine. I replaced the stakes with 60g of <a href="https://www.msrgear.com/tents/tent-accessories/groundhog-tent-stakes/05807.html">MSR groundhog stakes</a>.
<img src="/photos/nemopacked.jpg" alt="nemopacked"></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>60g <a href="https://www.msrgear.com/tents/tent-accessories/groundhog-tent-stakes/05807.html">MSR Groundhog tent stakes</a></p>
<p>Dependable light stakes. I’ve bent one of these only once when applying my full body weight through my foot into hard ground. In most cases this is very chill. I’ll probably dig a hole in the future, or possibly not even use stakes depending on the setup.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="/photos/sleepsystem.jpg" alt="sleep system"></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>455.01 <a href="https://enlightenedequipment.com/revelation-stock/">Enlightened Equipment Revelation</a></p>
<p>My most recent trip was with my old sleeping bag, and I spent the entire night with it open due to the heat. I learned that my air mattress is super comfy even sleeping directly on it, and that I made the right decision to switch to a quilt.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>340g <a href="https://www.hyperlitemountaingear.com/collections/new-arrivals/products/therm-a-rest-neoair-xlite-air-mattress">Thermarest Neoair XLite air mattress</a></p>
<p>This is a big comfort upgrade over my Z-Packs folding mat, even though it’s definitely more annoying to blow up and deflate. I sleep on my side often, so I like knowing I can adjust this a bit to facilitate that instead of basically sleeping on a thin foam cover over bits of rock. I might try bringing the inflation sack to save my lungs, and maybe I’ll store clothes in it or something in the meantime.
<img src="/photos/nemoinside.jpg" alt="inside Nemo"></p>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="weight-213073">Weight: 2130.73</h3>
<h2 id="bag">Bag</h2>
<p><img src="/photos/hyperlitebag.jpg" alt="hyperlite"></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>904g <a href="https://www.hyperlitemountaingear.com/products/2400-junction">Hyperlite Mountain Gear Junction 2400</a></p>
<p>This bag is outstanding. It’s so, so light, while still being incredibly tough, and roomy. It’s rated at 40L, but seems absolutely to be an endless bag of holding. I love that it has waist pockets for snacks, and a few webbing loops on the shoulder straps for a water bottle or a phone or camera.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="weight-904g">Weight: 904g</h3>
<h2 id="food">Food</h2>
<p><img src="/photos/cookingsystem.jpg" alt="cooking system"></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>72g <a href="https://www.toaksoutdoor.com/collections/frontpage/products/pot-550-l">Toaks titanium pot</a></p>
<p>Another new addition. Up until now I used the terra system that came with my crux lite, but never used both pots. I can’t fit my fuel and my stove inside with the lid, but that’s totally fine. I love that I can easily use this as a mug too.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>72g <a href="https://www.rei.com/product/146426/optimus-crux-lite-stove">Crux lite stove</a></p>
<p>Absolutely my favorite stove. It’s effective, quick and super light. I’ve used this for years, and it’s always worked save for the time I was trying to boil water with a 50mph wind blowing at me. Eventually, I hid behind a car and was able to make coffee.
<img src="/photos/foodbag.jpg" alt="food bag">
food bag</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>16g <a href="https://snowpeak.com/products/titanium-spork">Snow Peak Spork</a></p>
<p>I’ve had this spork for a long time—even before Snow Peak was cool again. Like, seriously I think I’ve eaten meals with this spork for 15 years. Love it. Durable and delightful. Mine is purple.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Ursa bear bag</p>
<p>This bag is only approved at certain campsites, but should be nice for those as an alternative to a rigid bear canister.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="weight-270g-terra-stoves-471g">Weight: 270g (Terra stoves 471g)</h3>
<h2 id="electronics">Electronics</h2>
<p><img src="/photos/assortedcamp.jpg" alt="tech gear and other accessories"></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>188g <a href="https://bookriot.com/amazon-kindle-oasis-review/">Kindle Oasis</a></p>
<p>My entire library can camp with me without adding bulk or weight. Plus, it’s waterproof!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>188g iPhone 11 Pro</p>
<p>Basically whatever the latest phone from Apple is, I’ll have it. This one is great.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>192g 10000mAh external USB battery</p>
<p>Keeps my iPhone, watch, and AirPods charged. This one is very small, and only has one USB-C and one USB-A port, so I do a little juggling of plugs.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>20g Assorted cables</p>
<p>A small Satechi watch charger and a C to Lighting and C to C cable.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>(Optional) 416.74 Anker Solar charger</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="weight-588g-98474g-with-a-solar-charger">Weight: 588g (984.74g with a solar charger)</h3>
<h2 id="assorted-gear">Assorted gear</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p>14.7g <a href="https://kulacloth.com">Kula cloth</a></p>
<p>A recent trip was my first time using this cloth, and largely it ruled! My one big mistake was getting a little too much camp soap on it, and having to wash it for a while to remove the soap. I think I can probably safely avoid soap for a couple days, and just wash it off with water.
<img src="/photos/befree.jpg" alt="befree bag"></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>70g <a href="https://www.katadyn.com/us/us/14946-8019639-katadyn-beefree-0.6L_usa">Katadyn BeFree bottle with filter</a></p>
<p>This water filter sack is outstanding. The flow rate is super fast and the entire setup is light AF. I also picked-up a 3L version of the same setup for group camping or if I think I’ll be away from water sources for longer.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>70g Matador water bottle</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>There’s a straw with the ability to bite to get water, which makes this easy for drinking on the trail.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>113.40g <a href="https://www.miir.com/collections/pourigami-travel-coffee-system/products/pourigami-portable-travel-coffee-dripper">Miir Pouragami</a></p>
<p>This is a little heavy to bring along if I’m hiking a lot, but it’s hard to beat the ability to do a pour over for friends. Usually I’ll bring <a href="https://canyoncoffee.co/collections/coffee/products/instant-coffee">fancy instant coffee</a> instead.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>46g <a href="https://www.opinel-usa.com/products/opinel-knives-no-7-carbon-steel-folding-knife">Opinel knife</a></p>
<p>A fantastic classic knife. This is good for cooking or various cutting tasks. It’s not the lightest but I dig it.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="weight-1547-2681g-with-pourigami">Weight: 154.7 (268.1g with pourigami)</h3>
<h2 id="clothes">Clothes</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Icebreaker merino shirt</p>
<p>This is my standard shirt that I wear almost every day. It’s great, comfortable, and light. It also keeps me warm and dry most of the time, and stands up to hand-washing well.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Coalatree trailhead pants</p>
<p>I used these pants on a recent trip, and was a excited about the pillow feature of the pockets, but ultimately it was a little uncomfortable so I might try something different next trip.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Sports bra</p>
<p>Sometimes this is wool, but it’s always wicking. No cotton here.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Icebreaker merino underwear</p>
<p>Dries quick, doesn’t get too stinky, and is comfy.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Darn tough merino socks</p>
<p>I’ve had a bunch of merino and other material socks, and I keep coming back to these. They’re comfy, wash and dry quickly, and keep my feet comfy for hikes.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Merino buff</p>
<p>Works as a hat, a scarf, a temp face cover, and even as a wrap for my improvised pillow that is a bit softer. Love it. I’d resisted getting a buff for years, but frankly, I was a fool.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="/photos/onshoes.jpg" alt="on shoes"></p>
<ul>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.on-running.com/en-us/products/cloudventure-peak">On Cloudventure Peak</a> shoes</p>
<p>I’ve never worn hiking shoes or boots on backpacking trips or even to hike—I’ve never even owned any! I picked these up to help mitigate my slippiness on loose terrain, as the last time I went hiking I kept falling down. Hopefully these are comfy and grippy.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>311g <a href="https://www.teva.com/women-sandals/original-universal/1003987.html?dwvar_1003987_color=CYR#start=3&amp;cgid=women-sandals">Teva sandals camp shoes</a></p>
<p>I don’t know if I’ll bring trail sandals on every trip, but they’re super comfy and I enjoy being able to take off my shoes at the end of the day but still wander around camp a bit.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Jacket</p>
<p>This depends on the conditions, but either a <a href="https://huckberry.com/store/proof/category/p/60691-shift-packable-shell">Proof shell</a> or a <a href="https://missionworkshop.com/products/the-torre-womens-high-performance-windpro-hoodie-jacket">Mission Workshop Torre jacket</a>. If it’s particularly cold or rainy, I also have a <a href="https://hiconsumption.com/snow-peak-fire-resistant-outerwear/">Snow Peak FR trench</a>. I tend to get warm pretty easily, but hate getting super soaked, so I optimize for staying dry and layer a bit. The FR trench plus my Torre worked well for me down to -5C.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Hat</p>
<p>Merino wool watch cap from <a href="https://www.tannergoods.com/collections/hats">Tanner Goods</a>. This hat is excellent and has kept my head and ears warm in four or five countries. It also doesn’t get too stinky when it’s been hiked in a lot.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="camping-report">Camping report</h2>
<p>I’ve only camped once with a lot of this gear, and eagerly wait for the end of fire season so I can do a bit more camping. Ultimately, it performed well but I’m excited to see how nice it is to hike with so little weight and set up shop in my little Nemo tent. If you want to chat about gear or ask questions about mine, feel free to <a href="mailto:brookshelley@gmail.com">hit me up</a>.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPad Magic Keyboard Review</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-04-24-ipad-magic-keyboard-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-04-24-ipad-magic-keyboard-review/</guid>
      <description>Watching friends and reviewers get their new Magic Keyboards in the mail all week was brutal, because every word I read about them, and video I watched just made me want to touch one more.</description>
      <content:encoded><p><img src="/photos/magickeyboard.jpg" alt="iPad and Magic Keyboard"></p>
<p>Watching friends and reviewers get their new Magic Keyboards in the mail all week was brutal, because every word I read about them, and video I watched just made me want to touch one more. In the time of quarantine, there’s no store to visit to try new products out, so instead we’re left waiting for delivery, and hoping everything lives up to our dreams.</p>
<p>In a sentence: this is my new favorite keyboard.</p>
<h2 id="heavy">Heavy</h2>
<p>My first thought when I took the Magic Keyboard package out of the mailbox was, “yow, this <em>is</em> heavy.” After taking the keyboard out of its packaging, the heft remained, but once I attached my iPad to it and started typing, I forgot all about the weight. Sure, this will be a bit heavier for travel, but the modularity is worth it for me. I can’t wait to type on this while traveling, then pull the iPad off the keyboard to carry around for reading in a park, or watching a tv show. It makes me wish it were possible to pull the screen off of my work computer and walk around with it too!</p>
<h2 id="modular">Modular</h2>
<p>Ever since getting the Smart Keyboard, my iPad basically never left it. I carried my iPad around daily, fingers pressed into the keys awkwardly on the back of the screen. The previous keyboard for the iPad was also super strange in its own way, but looking back, having a primary iPad case expose you to the keyboard buttons constantly when all you want to do is read is so silly. This new Magic Keyboard makes no concessions to using it while <em>not</em> typing. The ease of removing the iPad from the keyboard (I’m almost tempted to call it a dock) is such that I don’t even think about taking my iPad with me to another room, sans keyboard. This mode-changing makes the iPad feel even more futuristic than it did before, especially because my hands are only now becoming accustomed to the thin, metallic body of the iPad, instead of the strange rubber skin of the keyboard case its lived in up until now.</p>
<h2 id="thunk">Thunk</h2>
<p>So, what’s the keyboard actually like to type on?</p>
<p>Fantastic.</p>
<p>Unlike most folks, I really enjoyed both the butterfly keyboard in my MacBook, and the cloth-covered one on the Smart Keyboard. I enjoyed the short-travel, and the weird texture, but the feel and thunk of this new keyboard is even better. I don’t really care about the backlighting, and I’m a little bit more concerned about the gaps that invite in stray drops of water, but as I mentioned above, I don’t plan to carry this with me all the time, so it’s more likely I’ll have a glass of wine sans non-waterproof keyboard, and keep drinks away when I plan to <em>type</em>.</p>
<p>I typed this review on the new keyboard, and the experience was absolutely fantastic. The new trackpad <em>is</em> small, but the ability to quickly laser-target my edits is a delight. No longer do I have to tap, stab, tap tap, arrow, arrow, arrow. I can just point, and click, and voila. When I’m not at work, I more or less <em>only</em> use my iPad, and this new keyboard means the typing I do will be faster, feel better, and even sound more pleasingly thunky.</p>
<h2 id="should-you-buy-it">Should you buy it?</h2>
<p>Do you type on your iPad? Do you want to? Have you been tempted to plug your iPad into a monitor and use a Bluetooth trackpad? Do you love writing on the go?</p>
<p>If so, then this is probably the right keyboard for you. If you only occasionally reach for your iPad to watch YouTube videos, or are the kind of person who thinks traveling with an iPad <strong>and</strong> a MacBook is totally acceptable, then save your $300. In the same way that I’ve never purchased an Apple Pencil, many iPad users will never purchase this keyboard, and I think that’s totally fine. But the folks that do buy one, and get to experience the entirely wonderful experience of typing and editing will be incredibly satisfied, I think.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pandemic travel: 5</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-24-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-five/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-24-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-five/</guid>
      <description>Before it was clear we were headed for a pandemic, I booked a “treat yourself” trip to Japan. After a great first year at Slack, I wanted a nice non-work trip to really relax and refresh before going back into 2020 with a renewed sense of vigor.</description>
      <content:encoded><p><em>Before it was clear we were headed for a pandemic, I booked a “treat yourself” trip to Japan. After a great first year at Slack, I wanted a nice non-work trip to really relax and refresh before going back into 2020 with a renewed sense of vigor. Previously, I wrote about my time in Asakusa.</em></p>
<h2 id="last-day-in-asakusa">Last day in Asakusa</h2>
<p>What was supposed to be my last day in Asakusa started late. The combination of tiredness and a very comfortable bed meant I slept in until 1pm. I played Animal Crossing for a while, then went to get ramen.</p>
<p>Later, I headed to Kamakura to meet up with <a href="https://www.craigmod.com">Craig Mod</a> who showed me around his neighborhood, and chatted with me about the world, design, and reading. It really changes the nature of trips abroad when you have friends in various cities, I’ve found. I’m lucky to have a few friends scattered around Japan, so I’ve got a few mini-trips I can take each time I visit. Hopefully I’ll get to see Craig again in November for his writing retreat in Yoshino. I’m pretty excited to do a lot of hiking with him and the other participants.</p>
<p>That night, I said bye to Craig, then got ramen at a Michelin-starred spot in Kamakura, then headed back to Tokyo for some fried chicken and conbini chuhai. I caught up on tv, then got to bed on the early side.</p>
<h2 id="real-last-day-in-asakusa">Real last day in Asakusa</h2>
<p>I woke up, packed, and got coffee downstairs. I took my time because I had to kill 6 or so hours until my flight home. A coworker (hi Ricky) met up with me at Fuglen in Asakusa to get coffee and chat about the state of the world for a while, and then I introduced him to the joy of Lemon Chuhais before we parted at the subway.</p>
<p>After a brief misadventure at the wrong airline terminal, and some confusion about whether or not my flight was cancelled, I made it into the airline terminal, and found a window seat at the airline lounge. Shockingly, they had Georgian orange wine on tap, so I definitely enjoyed my last few hours before my flight.</p>
<p>The flight was bumpy as hell, but I managed to sleep for a bit.</p>
<p>And now, I&rsquo;m home&hellip; quarantined like the rest of California.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pandemic travel: 4</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-22-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-four/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-22-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-four/</guid>
      <description>Before it was clear we were headed for a pandemic, I booked a “treat yourself” trip to Japan. After a great first year at Slack, I wanted a nice non-work trip to really relax and refresh before going back into 2020 with a renewed sense of vigor.</description>
      <content:encoded><p><em>Before it was clear we were headed for a pandemic, I booked a “treat yourself” trip to Japan. After a great first year at Slack, I wanted a nice non-work trip to really relax and refresh before going back into 2020 with a renewed sense of vigor. Previously, I wrote about my time in Onomichi.</em></p>
<h2 id="yakitori-party焼き鳥のパーテイ">Yakitori party/焼き鳥のパーテイ</h2>
<p>After a drink at my hotel’s bar, I got a hot tip to check out a yakitori place a ten-minute walk away. I threw on my coat, and walked over, enjoying the peace and darkness of a city that actually sleeps.</p>
<p>The place was called 鳥徳 or Toritoku, and immediately on entering I was befriended by a Brazilian guy and his partner and their older math teacher friend. We talked for a while about tattoos, and drinking, and I mostly kept up in Japanese, which felt like a huge accomplishment. I stayed after they left, and then met a cadre of carpenters, including a very grateful American man named Jason (hi Jason!). The drinking continued as we cleared the place of all of its chicken bits, and all gotta a little cheerier and a little louder.</p>
<p>Finally, around midnight, I left to walk home. Somehow I’d spent quite a bit of money, and was a bit more tipsy than I figured. When I got back to my hotel, I had the presence of mind to take a bath, and wash all my clothes, then throw a few things on the charger for the next day.</p>
<p>I had an inkling I’d have a hangover&hellip;</p>
<h2 id="二日酔い">二日酔い</h2>
<p>Ouch. I woke up with a wanging headache, and managed to get dressed and fill myself with the multi-course breakfast, including a very tall dairy-free pancake. I finished packing, then checked out of my hotel, quickly hopping on the phone with Chase to address my ticket issue and try to head back to the states earlier, in light of the US state department’s recommendation.</p>
<p><em>Cut to four hours later</em></p>
<p>Good news: I started playing animal crossing
Bad news: Chase never picked up (shakes fist at Chase Bank), and at the four hour mark, the call suddenly disconnected. What. The. Fuck.</p>
<p>I gave up.</p>
<p>I walked around for a while to find ramen and at least fill the hole in my stomach.</p>
<h2 id="back-to-tokyo">Back to Tokyo</h2>
<p>Freshly full of karaage and ramen from a cute local shop, I hopped on the X train, followed by a trip on the Nozomi high-speed Shinkansen to Tokyo. Unsurprisingly, I spent the whole train trip playing Animal Crossing and trying to appease that bastard Tom Nook.</p>
<h3 id="animal-crossing-interlude">Animal Crossing interlude</h3>
<p>Animal Crossing was a favorite of mine in college on the GameCube, and each iteration is a simple joy. The Switch update is the best version yet, and looks gorgeous. If you’re the type of person who enjoys games like Harvest Moon, or just has a lot of time over the next few months while we’re all social distancing, I highly recommend picking this game up. Email or text me for my friend code so we can trade fruit, or whatever. My island is called Lesbos. So far we only have peaches on Lesbos, which is kind of a cliche, but oh well.</p>
<h2 id="asakusa">Asakusa</h2>
<p>Found my hotel, and checked-in. There was art all over the place, including some from <a href="https://www.frankie-cihi.com">Frankie Cihi</a> from Terrace House. Dinner was a chill diner meal of yakitori and some cucumber stuff while watching a weird 罰ゲーム (punishment game) tv show. I rounded out the night with Devs episode 4 and some Animal Crossing.</p>
<h2 id="day-two-in-asakusa">Day two in Asakusa</h2>
<p>It was David’s birthday (hi David), so I woke up at 8:30am to play Animal Crossing with him and his pals. This continued through breakfast, where Haley (hi Haley) even visited my new island.</p>
<p>Later, I went to Fuglen for coffee and was recognized from tv by a Kanae and her boyfriend. I read for a while over a tasty cup of Columbian coffee, then headed back to my hotel for some shochu. After a shiokoji shochu-induced nap, I headed to get onigiri from the oldest onigiri shop in Tokyo, Yadoroku. Wow. It was so, so good. Afterwards I wandered around and ran into my first 外国人を入れない on this trip. Dang.</p>
<p>I ended up at a shop called 初代チョベリバ for a few drinks and chicken parts, then went home to read and watch tv.</p>
<p>Overall, a pretty chill day.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pandemic Travel: 3</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-19-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-19-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-three/</guid>
      <description>Before it was clear we were headed for a pandemic, I booked a “treat yourself” trip to Japan. After a great first year at Slack, I wanted a nice non-work trip to really relax and refresh before going back into 2020 with a renewed sense of vigor.</description>
      <content:encoded><p><em>Before it was clear we were headed for a pandemic, I booked a “treat yourself” trip to Japan. After a great first year at Slack, I wanted a nice non-work trip to really relax and refresh before going back into 2020 with a renewed sense of vigor. Previously, I wrote about my time in Osaka.</em></p>
<h2 id="heading-south">Heading south</h2>
<p>Hopping on a call in the morning with Haley, Drl, and Zech was a nice way to start my last morning in Osaka. Background images were quickly swapped, and everyone was both upbeat, and a little stir-crazy. It felt nice to speak English a little, and hear about the bay and NYC.</p>
<p>After packing up my stuff, I headed to Lawson for onigiri, then walked towards my go-to coffee shop. Sadly, it was closed for the morning, so I sat and read until I could grab some ramen. I briefly got a little lost near Osaka station, but eventually made my way to the Shinkansen to head to Fukuyama, then Onomichi.</p>
<p>Transit is the scariest part of this trip.</p>
<p>Every year, the train journeys are one of my favorite part of coming to Japan, but this time, they feel a little more like steel-encased petri-dishes. The train to Fukuyama was busier than I thought it would be, and I sat next to a very quiet older woman for the 2 hour trip. I’d picked up some water and a lemon chuhai to keep me hydrated and chill during the trip, but since I was still reading Chuck Wendig’s <em>Wanderers</em>, I wasn’t exactly relaxed.</p>
<p><strong>Top Tip</strong> be careful not to read about plagues while you’re in the middle of one.</p>
<p>A brief stop in Fukuyama meant a small cup sake, then a local train to Onomichi.</p>
<h2 id="onomichi">Onomichi</h2>
<p><img src="https://www.brookshelley.com/photos/ono_view.jpg" alt="onomichi view"></p>
<p>Wow. This town is gorgeous. I fully plan to come back here and spend more serious time when I’m able to in the future. I love the river that runs through the middle of town, and the winding hilly roads and stairs. I learned on my first night that this town is <em>well known</em> for <a href="https://www.boredpanda.com/cats-sneaking-security-ken-chan-gosaku-hiroshima-onomichi-city-museum-of-art/?utm_source=google&amp;utm_medium=organic&amp;utm_campaign=organic">cats</a>. I’m sure somewhere in the back of my head, I’d seen this and taken note, but mostly I came here to stay at <a href="https://monocle.com/magazine/issues/122/destination-japan/">LOG</a> and relax a little.</p>
<p>My first day was certainly relaxing after a hike up a hill to get to the hotel. I walked into the lobby sweating profusely and was offered oolong tea. After a brief tour I rested in my room and read. Later I took a long bath (I still can’t get over how wonderful Japanese bathtubs are—they actually <em>fit</em> my whole body), and then got a welcome drink at the bar.</p>
<p>Wow! They had <em>natural wine from Alsace</em>. Honestly LOG felt like a heaven—a retreat and a recharge from my worries. I hope more of you reading this are able to visit in the future, despite the nightly rate being a little steep (~$350 a night).</p>
<p><img src="https://www.brookshelley.com/photos/ono_dinner.jpg" alt="dinner"></p>
<p>Dinner was a multi-course vegetable-focused feast with more white and whiskey to go with it. The small restaurant could seat 20, but only myself and two other women (a couple?) were there. It was utterly bizarre to be the only guests in a hotel.</p>
<p>I chatted with the waiter and the other guests a little about food, drift-racing, and Slack.</p>
<p>Later I read by my window, and listened to jazz.</p>
<h2 id="day-two">Day two</h2>
<p><img src="https://www.brookshelley.com/photos/ono_pancake.jpg" alt="pancake"></p>
<p>I woke a little before my alarm and got ready for the day. My breakfast was served in the same small cafe as dinner, and included the best pancake I’ve had in years. The maple syrup was delightful and not to sweet, and there was coarse sea salt sprinkled over the top to balance the flavor.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.brookshelley.com/photos/ono_library.jpg" alt="library"></p>
<p>While my room was cleaned, I hung out in the library of the hotel with the windows open, despite the construction on the street outside. The sawing and jackhammering was somehow oddly soothing. I liked the idea that despite everything, this crew was still repairing a mountain path hundreds of years older than my own country.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.brookshelley.com/photos/ono_library_view.jpg" alt="view from library"></p>
<p>From what I’ve read, Onomichi was spared from bombing during the war, so many of the houses I see around are a very old style, with tiled roofs and small engawas. If it wasn’t for the electrical lines running overhead, my view from the library window would’ve seemed like time-travel.</p>
<p>It was gorgeous.</p>
<h2 id="cat-hunting">Cat hunting</h2>
<p>Later, I walked on the literature path all the way up to an observation point, and also visited the famous Tadao Ando-designed museum. I saw more than a few cats, but fellow was my favorite. We sat together for five minutes or so and appreciated the view.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.brookshelley.com/photos/mr_cat.jpg" alt="mr cat"></p>
<p>All told I climbed 50 flights of steps during my hike. I only saw one other foreigner, but made sure to greet the older folks I walked past in the neighborhood with a cheerful 「こんにちは！」.</p>
<p><img src="https://www.brookshelley.com/photos/elephant.jpg" alt="I later learned photographs were prohibited"></p>
<p>The museum had so much great cat art. I’m not a huge fine art lady, but even I enjoyed the 18th and 19th century Japanese paintings. It was pretty funny to see how white people were depicted in these paintings—all the bearded cello-playing weirdos from Holland and Portugal.</p>
<p>I also saw a mini-museum to the maneki neko while on the short cat alley walk, and later visited a few temples.</p>
<p>Overall, I loved the hike, and all the spectacular views of the city and the hills to the north and west of Onomichi.</p>
<h2 id="lunch-and-relaxing">Lunch and relaxing</h2>
<p>After a climb down the hill, I dropped by a 7/11 to pick up cash, then got ramen at a shop that I <em>think</em> used beef lard in the stock. I’m unclear. It was called 牛ちゃん, but the ramen had tonkatsu, and I also got karaage, so who knows. It was tasty though, with a Hakata-style straight noodle.</p>
<p>I made a fresh cup of Haiku-roasted Ethiopian coffee beans, and read for a while before exploring the city more for dinner.</p>
<p>I knew I would be sad to leave this place on Friday.</p>
<p><em>read <a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-16-traveling-during-a-pandemic/">part 1</a> or <a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-17-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-two/">part 2</a></em></p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pandemic travel: 2</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-17-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-17-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-two/</guid>
      <description>Wow, things sure are quiet&amp;hellip;
Before it was clear we were headed for a pandemic, I booked a “treat yourself” trip to Japan.</description>
      <content:encoded><p><strong>Wow, things sure are quiet&hellip;</strong></p>
<p><em>Before it was clear we were headed for a pandemic, I booked a “treat yourself” trip to Japan. After a great first year at Slack, I wanted a nice non-work trip to really relax and refresh before going back into 2020 with a renewed sense of vigor. Previously, I wrote about packing and my initial few days in Koenji in western Tokyo.</em></p>
<h2 id="off-to-kyoto">Off to Kyoto</h2>
<p>Tokyo station and the Tokaido Shinkansen were both relatively empty, which was very odd to experience. If you’ve ever been to Japan, there’s a near-constant mass of people traveling via train stations, so I was both sad and glad to see folks taking none traveling seriously. I picked up an ekiben of box sushi and a chuhai, then headed to the old capital city for one night at BNA Alter Hotel, the Kyoto cousin of Koenji’s BNA.</p>
<p>In general, Kyoto was also much quieter, but had a slightly upbeat vibe and a bit more foot traffic than I saw in Tokyo. I think the smaller number of COVID cases meant Kyoto kept moving.</p>
<p>I found some amazing yakitori for dinner and drank a few glasses of fancy whiskey later on back at my hotel. I watched Contagion before drifting off to sleep, and it unfortunately felt prescient. I hope we have more Matt Damons and less Gwyneth Paltrows in our current pandemic.</p>
<p>Day two meant a solo breakfast at the hotel. There were only two of us there in the entire 31 room place. Wild.</p>
<p>I went on a walk later, to get some air, and come coffee at Dongree, where I also sat alone. On the way to the train station I got ramen at an empty shop run by two older people who were very happy to have me. One downside of this spot—they didn’t have hand soap in the restroom. Fortunately, I was carrying alcohol wipes, but I made a note to find alcohol spray at the next conbini I visited.</p>
<h2 id="osaka">Osaka</h2>
<p>The train ride to Osaka was a little nerve-wracking. The small train got much more crowded than any other train I’d been on, and the asshole youth who sat next to me picked his nose under his mask and coughed into his mask for a few stops. The older woman sitting near us kept giving him the stink eye. Seriously, fuck that guy.</p>
<p>I made it to my hotel a little early, and sat in the lobby before check-in. In a stark contrast to my huge room in Kyoto, the Nest hotel is a very tiny business hotel. I wasn’t really clear on the amenities when I booked it, but it’s basically a room large enough for a bed and a small chair. I spent most of the first night in my room, with a short excursion to get udon nearby. Later I watched Casino Royale, and had a canned highball. Truly high class, eh?</p>
<p>Every morning so far has meant catching up on the news around the world, practicing kanji, and trying to keep a little calm. I definitely felt more anxious in Osaka than in Koenji or Kyoto. Everyone outside seems much more blasé than other parts of Japan I’ve been to on this trip, despite the higher infection rate here.</p>
<p><em>knocks on wood</em> I hope this apparent nonchalance is fully warranted, and folks here will stay healthy.</p>
<p>I got Vietnamese food in an empty restaurant with my friends Laurie and Stephan, and then got coffee at Haiku, a local spot I love. Later I took a leisurely walk, followed by a little chuhai purchasing at the Lawson. Having a beer in my hotel room isn’t as great as a nice whiskey out, but I figured it’s better safe than sorry.</p>
<p>Day two meant a long walk after buying some onigiri at the Lawson. Crowds were sparse, but a surprising number of people were still walking around and playing baseball in the park. I’d just read about the shutdown in San Francisco, and Osaka felt like the opposite. I got more coffee at Haiku, and made sure to buy extra pourover bags to-go so I would have backup coffee for my time in Onomichi.</p>
<p>I spent the afternoon back at my hotel, watching sim-racing championships and napping. Later I got karaage and more chuhai at Johnny’s, then walked back under the subway line, and listened to a podcast. I felt lucky in a way that I could still experience wandering around Osaka during this pandemic, but also scared for what lies ahead for my friends and our homes.</p>
<p>Lawsons came through with another chuhai for my tv-filled evening. First up was the finale of Avenue 5, and then Quantum of Solace. Uncomplicated action movies are a nice escape, I think.</p>
<p>I set my alarm for a video call with my friend Haley, then headed to bed.</p>
<p><em>read <a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-17-traveling-during-a-pandemic/">part 1</a> or <a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-19-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-three/">part 3</a></em></p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pandemic travel: 1</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-16-traveling-during-a-pandemic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-16-traveling-during-a-pandemic/</guid>
      <description>Wow, things sure are quiet&amp;hellip;
Before it was clear we were headed for a pandemic, I booked a “treat yourself” trip to Japan.</description>
      <content:encoded><p><strong>Wow, things sure are quiet&hellip;</strong></p>
<p>Before it was clear we were headed for a pandemic, I booked a “treat yourself” trip to Japan. After a great first year at Slack, I wanted a nice non-work trip to really relax and refresh before going back into 2020 with a renewed sense of vigor.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, in the following weeks COVID-19 grew at a wild rate, the cases in the United States were clearly skyrocketing despite a complete failure of the CDC and leadership to provide ample testing. My company cancelled business travel, but left it to us to determine our risk profile for personal travel, so I reached out to friends in the US and Japan to take stock. After a weekend of thinking and reading, I decided to travel to Japan unless flights were cancelled.</p>
<h2 id="the-trip-begins">The trip begins</h2>
<p>Many travelers had clearly cancelled their flights, as the plane was largely empty. Out of caution and care for passengers, the staff of the JAL plane were all wearing masks, and taking extra measures to clean and prepare our plane as well. As I boarded and settled-in, my first thought was “I wish folks too health this seriously all the time”.</p>
<p>Our flight was fairly bumpy, but I managed to sleep for a few hours, and even eat a bit before landing at HND. The usual self-service immigration booths were closed, but as one of the only visitors, I still made it through immigration and customs in minutes. As usual, the customs agent gave me an odd look for my small backpack and lack of luggage.</p>
<h2 id="the-bag">The bag</h2>
<p>This trip I brought a single bag: the <a href="https://bellroy.com/products/studio-backpack/venture/black">Bellroy Studio in Venture Weave Black</a>. After many trips with my RYU Quick Pack with a smaller day bag, I looked forward to a single light bag instead. So far on this trip, it’s been a comfortable bag, that easily hauls between locations. I haven’t used it very much outside of traveling to my hotels, as due to the virus I haven’t done a lot of writing from coffee shops or hiking. I used this bag daily for the past few months to go to work though, and am confident it would also be great to take a couple things with me to a coffee shop.</p>
<p>My packing list was pretty typical:</p>
<h3 id="clothes">Clothes</h3>
<ul>
<li>1 pairs of <a href="https://darntough.com/products/womens-ss18-vertex-no-show-tab-ultra-light">Darn Tough wool socks</a></li>
<li>1 <a href="https://www.icebreaker.com/en-us/womens-tops/cool-lite-solace-short-sleeve-scoop/104640.html">wool shirt from Icebreaker</a></li>
<li>1 pair of <a href="https://www.outdoorvoices.com/products/rectrek-pant">RekTrek pants from OV</a></li>
<li>1 <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Snow-Peak-Womens-Rain-Trench/dp/B07MWC4KZ8">Snow Peak FR trench</a></li>
<li>2 pairs of <a href="https://negativeunderwear.com/collections/underwear/products/black-whipped-high-rise">Negative underwear</a></li>
<li>1 sports bra</li>
<li>1 <a href="https://www.amazon.com/Arcteryx-Eagan-Tank-Top-Womens/dp/B078XHPXJH/ref=pd_sbs_468_4/136-2112403-2472869">tank from Arcteryx</a></li>
<li>1 pair of <a href="https://www.foxers.com/boxer-briefs/">shorts from Foxers</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="electronics">Electronics</h3>
<ul>
<li>iPad 11” Cellular</li>
<li>Kindle Oasis</li>
<li>Switch Lite</li>
<li>Anker 10kmah battery</li>
<li>Cables</li>
<li><a href="https://satechi.net/products/usb-c-magnetic-charging-dock">Satechi watch charger</a> (got this for free from a Satechi rep. Thanks!)—short review: this is a little more compact and chill than bringing a watch cable, and can stick into the side of my iPad to let me charge while I’m writing. It’s a little more awkward plugged into a battery, but not too bad. It’s <a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/product/MX2G2AM/A/apple-watch-magnetic-charging-cable-03m?fnode=83">only 10 bucks more than an Apple charger</a> so if you don’t have a travel charger this might be a good idea.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="other-stuff">Other stuff</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2020/all_about/weeks/">Hobonichi Weeks</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.kaweco-pen.com/en">Kaweco fountain pen</a></li>
<li>Toiletries in a <a href="https://matadorup.com/products/flatpak-toiletry-case">Matador bag</a> which so far, wow. I love this little bag.</li>
</ul>
<p>I’m additionally wearing a duplicate of most of what I brought, save for the jacket and sleep clothes. I’m also testing out some <a href="https://us.soakwash.com/collections/laundry-soap">new laundry soap</a> while I’m here to see if it can keep my clothes fresh without needing a full in-shower scrub.</p>
<h2 id="koenji-social-distancing">Koenji social distancing</h2>
<p>My trip started in Koenji, where I stayed at my <a href="https://www.bna-hotel.com">favorite BNA</a>. By and large, I kept to my room, or did some socially-distanced hiking around Suginami. Lawson was a block away, and provided coffee and onigiri, but I also had coffees at Coffee AMP and INC near the train station. Honestly, other than mounting panic online, I found it to be relaxing to stick close to home. I went out for food a couple of times, but honestly felt a little afraid to go out. If I were in Oakland right now, it’s likely I wouldn’t have left the house this week at all, save for a walk around the block.</p>
<h2 id="to-be-continued">To be continued&hellip;</h2>
<p><em>read <a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-17-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-two/">part 2</a> or <a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-19-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-three/">part 3</a></em></p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bellroy Studio Pack Review</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-12-13-bellroy-studio-pack-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-12-13-bellroy-studio-pack-review/</guid>
      <description>A new backpack for everyday carry, and travel.
First Sight After first getting my new Bellroy sling, I fell in love with the delightful material for these bags.</description>
      <content:encoded><p><img src="/photos/bellroybackpack.jpeg" alt="Bellroy Studio Backpack"></p>
<p>A new backpack for everyday carry, and travel.</p>
<h2 id="first-sight">First Sight</h2>
<p>After first getting my new Bellroy sling, I fell in love with the delightful material for these bags. A few months later in Iitoya in Japan, I got to see their new Shift backpack in person, and almost bought one on the spot. that bag was a little larger than I need, but then I saw <a href="https://bellroy.com/products/studio-backpack/venture/black">this</a>. With the launch of the Studio Backpack, Bellroy has made an excellent bag that holds a little or a lot without every looking absurd.</p>
<h2 id="sizing">Sizing</h2>
<p>For quite a while, I’ve <a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/blog/2019/11/06/devreltour-packing-list.html">brought my Topo Trip Pack</a> to work as it fits my coffee bottle, iPad, journal, and a few other things perfectly. Adding in a spare jacket could stuff it pretty tight, but I preferred that to hauling a bag that was typically too large. With the Studio Backpack, my everyday stuff fits well, with ample space, but the shallow depth of the bag means it looks nice even unloaded.</p>
<h3 id="measurements">Measurements</h3>
<p>This is a slim, but tall-ish bag that measures 500L x 370W x 100D mm or 19.69”x14.57”x3.94”.</p>
<p>It has an 18-liter capacity, which while entry isn’t nearly as big feeling as my similarly-sized RYU Quick Pack. It weighs 650g or 1.43lbs, nearly half the weight of the <a href="https://ryu.com/shop/us/quick-pack/quick-pack-lux">RYU</a>, and only a little heavier than the 567g <a href="https://topodesigns.com/products/trip-pack?variant=946319253">Topo Trip Pack</a>.</p>
<p>All-in-all, this bag feels like a great balance between a daily size and one that I could fly around the world with.</p>
<h2 id="features">Features</h2>
<p><img src="/photos/bellroysmall.jpg" alt="Bellroy Front Pocket"></p>
<p>This bag is a top-loader, with a generously-wide opening, and a fidlock magnetic closure I can open with one hand using the small fabric loop. This flap makes for an easy way to use the main compartment, while keeping the rain off of my stuff. On the outside, there’s a pocket a little bit lower than mid-way that zips shut, and has pockets for pens, AirPods, and a few other things along with a key loop on a long fabric loop. Usually, I keep a Hobonichi Weeks, a Kaweco fountain pen, house keys, AirPods Pro and my work badge in here.</p>
<p>Inside of the main bag area, there’s a laptop area that can hold up to a 16” MacBook Pro—the new one with the real escape key—or an iPad Pro of either size. The bottom of the bag is generously padded to keep your stuff safe, and the laptop sleeve ends before the bottom for more safety. On the front wall of the main bag opening there is another zipped compartment for glasses, cables, or other odds and ends that you don’t need as often.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/mainbellroy.jpg" alt="Bellroy Main Pocket"></p>
<h2 id="colors-and-materials">Colors and Materials</h2>
<p>I have the black version of this bag, which I find delightful, though if I could customize it, I might have chosen a light purple or blue interior instead of the tan it comes with from Bellroy. Bellroy won me over on the idea that a lighter or brighter interior helps in finding your gear, though as a top-loader, even bright fabric doesn’t help you dig at the bottom of the bag. The Venture Weave fabric feels very strange, but in a cool, high-end way, and does a good job shrugging off rain. There are leather accents in various places on the bag that give it a little extra luxury.</p>
<h2 id="rating">Rating</h2>
<p>This bag rules, and I’ve thoroughly enjoyed it for the past few weeks. I plan to take it on my next trip abroad, and likely won’t bring a separate daypack. I think this bag will be comfortable on a hike, or fully-loaded with my typical travel gear. If you need a bit more space, I highly recommend checking out Bellroy’s other larger version of this, the <a href="https://bellroy.com/products/shift-backpack/venture/moss">Shift pack</a>.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevRel Tour Packing List</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-06-devreltour-packing-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-06-devreltour-packing-list/</guid>
      <description>As usual, when I go on a DevRel tour, I like to write about what I&amp;rsquo;ve packed. This trip was a 3 week journey from Tokyo, through Kyoto, to Osaka, and back.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>As usual, when I go on a DevRel tour, I like to write about what I&rsquo;ve packed. This trip was a 3 week journey from Tokyo, through Kyoto, to Osaka, and back. As I write this, halfway through the trip, I feel very good about the amount of stuff I brought.</p>
<h2 id="bags">Bags</h2>
<ul>
<li>RYU Quick Pack 18L</li>
<li>Topo Designs Trip Pack</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="/photos/ryubag2019.jpeg" alt="bags"></p>
<p><img src="/photos/travelbag2019.jpeg" alt="bag2"></p>
<p>Last time I went to Japan, I brought the DSPTCH Waist Bag as my day bag, and my shoulders immediately regretted it. I think my days or a one-shoulder bag with a computer are pretty much over. This time I returned to my tried and true setup. I’ve reviewed or written about both of these bags previously.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/drybags2019.jpeg" alt="drybags"></p>
<ul>
<li>Two Sea-to-summit dry bags</li>
</ul>
<p>These are great for clothes and toiletries, and additionally ensure that even in a downpour I can keep a few things dry.</p>
<ul>
<li>One Topo Designs accessory bag</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="/photos/drybagsinside.jpeg" alt="drybagsinsidebigbag"></p>
<p>This time around, I loaded my toothbrush and some other non-leaky toiletries into this bag because I noticed the metal tip of my electric toothbrush kept <em>almost</em> poking through my dry bag.</p>
<h2 id="clothes">Clothes</h2>
<p><img src="/photos/clothes.jpeg" alt="clothes"></p>
<h3 id="jackets">Jackets</h3>
<ul>
<li>Mission Workshop Torre Windshell</li>
</ul>
<p>My daily jacket. I’ve got two of these and they’re awesome. Not quite waterproof, but warm enough, and water-resistant enough for a drizzle and temperatures between 7-20C (mid-40s to mid-60s F).</p>
<ul>
<li>Arcteryx Cordetta</li>
</ul>
<p>If it rains, I’m covered.</p>
<h3 id="shirts">Shirts</h3>
<ul>
<li>Wool t-shirts from Ryu and Icebreaker</li>
</ul>
<p>A great way to stay dry and warm or cool. These wash easily and are comfy for all-day-travel.</p>
<h3 id="pants">Pants</h3>
<ul>
<li>Two pairs of Outdoor Voices RecTrek pants</li>
</ul>
<p>I wear these to work daily, and they’re pretty ideal. Comfy, flexible, and a bit water-resistant. The pockets are also <em>huge</em> which means my phone fits easily in a front pocket.</p>
<h3 id="shoes-and-socks">Shoes and socks</h3>
<ul>
<li>Blundstones</li>
<li>Bombas no-show</li>
</ul>
<p>These shoes go on and off pretty easily, and look nice enough for business meetings while still feeling good for longer walks. Half of this trip was a vacation, where I wandered around all day, including hiking. I almost went with my new KOIO shoes, but at the last minute, opted for slip-one with a <em>lot</em> of grip.</p>
<h3 id="underwear">Underwear</h3>
<ul>
<li>Wool stuff from Icebreaker</li>
</ul>
<p>Wool is the way to go. I’ve tried other solutions and they were nice enough, but ultimately, wool holds up the best and wicks super well.</p>
<h2 id="tech-gear">Tech gear</h2>
<p><img src="/photos/electronics2019.jpeg" alt="electronics"></p>
<ul>
<li>Kindle Oasis</li>
<li>Battery</li>
<li>USB-C -&gt; C, and Lightning: iPad and iPhone</li>
<li>USB-A -&gt; Watch</li>
<li>USB-A -&gt; Micro: Kindle</li>
<li>iPad Pro 10.5 w/ Smart Keyboard</li>
</ul>
<p>At some point, maybe I can travel with only USB-C cables, but that world doesn’t exist yet. Fortunately my external battery has a USB-C port and a USB-A port, so I use those two to charge my phone and watch at night. On the plane my USB-C to USB-C cable means I can top-up my iPad if I play too many games or get low mid-season of a tv show. It completely boggles the mind why the Kindle isn’t a USB-C device yet. Seriously. It’s 2019.</p>
<h2 id="other-stuff">Other stuff</h2>
<p><img src="/photos/weeks2019.jpeg" alt="weeks"></p>
<ul>
<li>Toiletries</li>
<li>Hobonichi Weeks &amp; Kaweco Al EF fountain pen</li>
<li>お土産</li>
</ul>
<p>The usual assortment of unguents, potions, and a toothbrush, along with my trusty new pen and notebook. I <em>love</em> this Kaweco pen, which is both completely blacked-out, and compact. I also brought some small gifts for 東京と大阪の同僚。</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wardrobe refresh</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-08-20-wardrobe-refresh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-08-20-wardrobe-refresh/</guid>
      <description>As my clothes gradually wear out, I’m slowly trying to replace everything with my current favorites. This makes for a very simple wardrobe that works for all 4 seasons.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>As my clothes gradually wear out, I’m slowly trying to replace everything with my current favorites. This makes for a very simple wardrobe that works for all 4 seasons.</p>
<p>Lots of this stuff is wool, all of it is pretty durable, and when possible I tried to find vendors that were environmentally friendly and smaller.</p>
<h2 id="shirts">Shirts</h2>
<p><a href="https://ryu.com/shop/us/women/tops/standard-issue-racerback-tank">4 tank tops</a> — These are fantastic tank tops. They wick well, don’t get stinky, and look good enough to wear outside of the gym.</p>
<p><a href="https://jungmaven.com/collections/hemp-shirts-womens-tees-tanks/products/hemp-shirt-ojai-tee-short-sleeve-womens">4 t-Shirts</a> — Comfy, and cool looking. There’re a lot of colors if you don’t want to wear all black all the time.</p>
<p>2 tailored dress shirts (long sleeve)</p>
<h2 id="pants">Pants</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.outdoorvoices.com/products/rectrek-pant?variant=34894691781&amp;size=1">3 pants</a> — I just keep buying these. They’re comfortable, stretch well during activity, and hold up to a lot of punishment.</p>
<h2 id="shorts">Shorts</h2>
<p><a href="https://ryu.com/shop/us/women-all/shorts/power-short">2 pairs of shorts</a> — Great for lifting weights, yoga, or just when it’s hot. I wouldn’t wear them to work, but I wouldn’t wear shorts to work generally.</p>
<h2 id="leggings">Leggings</h2>
<p><a href="https://ryu.com/shop/us/women/bottoms/cardio-tights">2 pairs of leggings</a> — These stay up during yoga and powerlifting really well. They’re comfortable and keep you dry even if you go out for a drink after working out.</p>
<h2 id="underwear">Underwear</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.icebreaker.com/en-us/womens-underwear/siren-hipkini/104704.html">10 pairs of underwear</a> — Wool underwear rules.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.calvinklein.us/en/womens-clothing/womens-bras/custom-modern-cotton-bralette-52705992">5 sports bras</a> — I keep trying to find something that’s more comfortable, but I keep coming back to these. Simple, and easy.</p>
<h2 id="socks">Socks</h2>
<p><a href="https://bombas.com/products/womens-no-shows-one-color-eight-pack?variant=black">8 pairs of socks</a> — Great wool socks that pack light and dry quickly.</p>
<h2 id="pajamas">Pajamas</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.foxers.com/black-tomboy-boxer-brief/">3 Shorts with pockets</a> — I love that i can throw a phone or keys in here and check the mail if I’m too lazy to put on pants.</p>
<h2 id="sweater">Sweater</h2>
<p><a href="https://www.icebreaker.com/en-us/womens-sweaters/waypoint-crewe-sweater/104316.html?dwvar_104316_color=401">1 sweater</a> — You never know when you need a nice sweater.</p>
<h2 id="jacket">Jacket</h2>
<p><a href="https://missionworkshop.com/products/the-torre-womens-high-performance-windpro-hoodie-jacket">Hoodie</a> — Great hoodie. I own two because I think they’re discontinuing them sadly. My backup is probably a Chrome one, I guess.</p>
<h2 id="rain-coat">Rain coat</h2>
<p><a href="https://arcteryx.com/us/en/shop/womens/andra-coat">Coat</a> — Very low-key and stealth. This jacket looks just as good in the city as it does on a hike.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimal travel clothing</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-04-08-minimal-travel-clothing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-04-08-minimal-travel-clothing/</guid>
      <description>Ten or so years ago, I realized I hated bringing heavy bags with me everywhere I traveled, so I slimmed down my packing to fit in one small backpack.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>Ten or so years ago, I realized I hated bringing heavy bags with me everywhere I traveled, so I slimmed down my packing to fit in one <a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/blog/2018/05/17/review-invisible-one-mini.html">small backpack</a>. My wardrobe generally cycles between a few pieces, so it wasn’t much of a stretch to adapt it to a month in <a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/blog/2019/03/13/travel-kit-update.html">Japan</a> or Berlin. I usually write a post-trip gear update, but today is all about clothing.</p>
<h2 id="whatre-you-wearing">What’re you wearing?</h2>
<p>Whether it’s a one week or one month-long trip, I bring the same things each time Including what I’m wearing during the flight, here’s the breakdown:</p>
<ul>
<li>3 pairs of <a href="#underwear">underwear</a></li>
<li>2 <a href="#shirts">shirts</a></li>
<li>2 sports <a href="#underwear">bras</a></li>
<li>2 pairs of wool <a href="#shoes">socks</a></li>
<li>1 water-resistant <a href="#jacket">hoodie</a></li>
<li>(weather-optional) 1 <a href="#jacket">jacket</a></li>
<li>1 pair of <a href="#shoes">shoes</a></li>
<li>1 pair of <a href="#pants">pants</a></li>
<li>1 pair of shorts or <a href="#pants">leggings</a></li>
</ul>
<p>None of the stuff I wear is particularly cheap, or particularly expensive, but on the whole, it’s held up well to lots of abuse, and many washes. The key to bringing very little clothing is a willingness to wash your clothes in the sink or shower while you bathe. If you find a washing machine, by all means, take advantage of it, but these clothes dry pretty quickly, and I prefer not to hope for something automated. If something gets destroyed (only happened once with some jeans), I can usually find a replacement, but taking stock before a trip of any of your clothing that’s in danger of ripping is a great plan.</p>
<h2 id="tops-a-nameshirtsa">Tops <!-- raw HTML omitted --><!-- raw HTML omitted --></h2>
<p>Day or night, the tops I wear look pretty good, wick sweat ok, and tend to hold up to a day of hiking. I spent a while only wearing wool, but recently got stoked on a few other shirts. Sadly, Ryu doesn’t make the wool shirt I wear anymore, but there are a bunch of brands making wool shirts these days, so have a look around if that appeals to you.</p>
<p>Usually, if it’s hot or I plan to layer, I wear a <a href="https://ryu.com/shop/us/women/tops/standard-issue-racerback-tank">tank top</a>. No sleeves means no pit stains, and with a hoodie you’re pretty set regardless of the modesty required in a temple or other spot. I’ve had good luck with Ryu and Lucy (though they’ve been bought by North Face, and I don’t know how good they are anymore). Arcteryx used to make a cool wool tank, but they make <a href="https://arcteryx.com/us/en/shop/womens/a2b-scoop-neck-shirt-ss">this</a> now, and if it’s the same fabric, it’s great!</p>
<p>A friend convinced me to try out these <a href="https://jungmaven.com/collections/hemp-core-tees-tshirt-womens/products/hemp-shirt-ojai-tee-short-sleeve-womens?variant=22065464279088">hemp shirts</a>, and for the first time in years, I wear a few colors. They’re super light, super soft, and don’t get stinky after a few wears.</p>
<p>I wear one of these shirts while I’m sleeping, and one during the day, and kinda rotate them around. If I’m gone for longer I might bring 2 shirts and a tank top, so I don’t have to wash as much.</p>
<h2 id="bottoms-a-namepantsa">Bottoms <!-- raw HTML omitted --><!-- raw HTML omitted --></h2>
<p>Most of the time I wear <a href="https://www.outdoorvoices.com/products/rectrek-pant?variant=34894684485">Outdoor Voices RecTrek pants</a>, which are comfy, stretchy, and cute. They run out of sizes all the time or I’d have a couple pairs. They dress up for the office ok, but also handle a <em>lot</em> of walking. Since I can’t find another black XL pair, I am currently trying out <a href="https://coalatree.com/collections/apparel/products/slim-fit-trailhead-pants-black">another brand</a>. These Coalatree pants are also pretty great, though the tie at the bottom of each leg is kinda ridiculous. They’re unisex, which means the fit might be weird, but they’ve also got a <em>ergonomic crotch gusset</em> a la <a href="https://www.artofmanliness.com/articles/chuck-norris-action-jeans/">Chuck Norris action jeans</a>. I don’t know <em>why</em> you’d do tons of high kicks in pants, but either of these pairs would handle them with gusto.</p>
<p>You probably already have your preferred brand of legging, but for me, I’m usually wearing either <a href="https://ryu.com/shop/us/women/bottoms/cardio-tights">Ryu</a> or <a href="https://www.girlfriend.com/collections/leggings/products/black-compressive-high-rise-legging">Girlfriend</a>. I’ve heard great things about Outdoor Voices leggings, but I’m waiting until I destroy a few more old pairs before I try them. For night time, leggings or <a href="https://www.foxers.com/black-tomboy-boxer-brief/">Foxers</a> are great for wandering around my Airbnb or hotel room.</p>
<h2 id="underwear-a-nameunderweara">Underwear <!-- raw HTML omitted --><!-- raw HTML omitted --></h2>
<p>Breathable, light, comfortable, and durable is the name of the game for underwear. I’m always on the search for a pair that hits all four targets. Thus far, some have done ok, but most aren’t that durable. A better pair I tried were <a href="https://knix.com/collections/underwear/products/athletic-bikini">Knix</a>, which were super comfy, but eventually blew up. Sometimes I bring <a href="https://www.meundies.com/products/womens-bikini">MeUndies</a>, but they too tend to fall apart too soon. These wool <a href="https://www.patagonia.com/product/womens-active-briefs-underwear/32396.html?dwvar_32396_color=BLK&amp;cgid=socks-underwear#tile-7=&amp;start=1&amp;sz=24">Patagonia briefs</a> were alright. I feel like I’ll be on the hunt indefinitely, but maybe a few pairs of one of these will do if for you. All three are comfortable, and dry fast, but the Knix and Patagonia pairs are better for sweaty hikes as the MeUndies tend to get a little swamped.</p>
<p>Three pairs of underwear might seem like too few, and feel free to adjust as necessary, but by and large: one to wear, one to wash, one that’s dry. This motto means you’re almost always set for two days, and worst case, you can dry a pair on the outside of your bag while hiking. The Knix and Patagonia briefs dry in only a few hours, so you could wash before breakfast, and come back, coffee in hand to some clean drawers.</p>
<p>For bras, I stick to sports bras from Pact or Calvin Klein. I hate underwrites, and sports bras last a lot longer between washes.</p>
<h2 id="jacket-a-namejacketa">Jacket <!-- raw HTML omitted --><!-- raw HTML omitted --></h2>
<p>Your mileage may vary heavily on style and need for this category, but my go-tos always include the <a href="https://missionworkshop.com/products/the-torre-womens-high-performance-windpro-hoodie-jacket">Torre Wind Pro</a>. I recently bought a second one of these, and even though I think Mission Workshop is getting rid of their women’s line (boo hiss), this is an incredible hoodie. It is DWR coated so light rain just falls off, and also fleece-lined so by itself I can handle temperatures down to 8c/46f. Colder or wetter, and I bring an overcoat. The two coats in my rotation right now are the <a href="https://www.arcteryx.com/us/en/shop/womens/codetta-coat">Arcteryx Codetta</a> and the <a href="https://snowpeak.com/products/jk-18au004-fr-rain-trench?variant=13074792972386">Snow Peak FR Rain Trench</a> (which is also <em>fireproof</em>?!). Good layering means even at freezing temperatures, I do well. If it was super cold, I’d probably include a wool sweater to wear under or over my hoodie, and I’d throw my leggings on under my pants.</p>
<h2 id="shoes-and-socks-a-nameshoesa">Shoes and socks <!-- raw HTML omitted --><!-- raw HTML omitted --></h2>
<p><a href="https://bombas.com/products/women-s-solid-invisibles-tan-small?variant=black">Bombas</a> or Darn Tough are the way to go for socks. Most of the time it’s not cold enough to wear longer socks, so I wear no-shows or ankle socks. Wool means these also wick well, and wash easily—depending on your food funk, a couple days is usually fine between washes.</p>
<p>If it’s cold or wet, I’m wearing <a href="https://www.blundstone.com/shop/black-premium-leather-chelsea-boots-womens-style-558">Blundstones</a>, or <a href="https://www.adidas.com/us/stan-smith-shoes/M20327.html">Stan Smiths</a>. Summer means something light and knit like <a href="https://www.adidas.com/us/samba-sock-primeknit-shoes/CQ2218.html">these Sambas</a>. Lightweight, comfortable, and breathable means you only need one pair of shoes. If they’re black, even sneakers work in many slightly fancy situations. In my opinion, sandals should only show up in a public shower, or on the beach, so I never bring any.</p>
<h2 id="hat">Hat</h2>
<p>A wool beanie is great for warmth, so I wear <a href="https://www.tannergoods.com/products/merino-watch-cap">this one from Tanner Goods</a>. It’s expensive, but it holds up.</p>
<h2 id="plan-ahead">Plan ahead</h2>
<p>All of my clothing works well for me, but I typically go to Europe or Japan. If you go somewhere much hotter or much colder, you’ll definitely need to adjust, especially if you go from a freezing spot to a hot one. If you end up bringing a lot of stuff for one leg of a trip, you can always mail stuff home too. Layering is your friend. There’re a lot of <a href="https://www.carryology.com/travel/how-what-to-put-in-your-minimalist-travel-capsule-wardrobe/">lists for women</a> that have much more feminine clothing, but that’s not really my jam. For me, functional &gt; cute any day of the week. But, regardless of your style choice, stretchy, lightweight clothing is the way to go.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel kit update</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-03-13-travel-kit-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-03-13-travel-kit-update/</guid>
      <description>Since 2019, I updated my kit a little bit, but mostly it stayed the same.
One old bag, one new My Ryu Quickpack was a delight once-again, as I used it to transport all my gear to Japan, and then from city to city.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>Since 2019, I updated my kit a <a href="https://twitter.com/brookshelley/status/1100823338497105921">little bit</a>, but mostly it stayed the same.</p>
<h2 id="one-old-bag-one-new">One old bag, one new</h2>
<p>My Ryu Quickpack was a delight once-again, as I used it to transport all my gear to Japan, and then from city to city. Most days it sat in my room as I travelled around with my DSPTCH Waist Bag or just what I could fit in my pockets. Ergonimically, this bag is one of the most comfortable bags I&rsquo;ve owned, but due to its size, I don&rsquo;t like hauling it around all day. I hoped that the DSPTCH bag would work really well during day to day travel, and it probably would have if it hadn&rsquo;t rained every day. The waist bag isn&rsquo;t waterproof (boo), or particularly comfortable for long stretches (double boo), due to the one shoulder setup. I wear the Waist Bag to work almost every day, but for way less time, so I&rsquo;d forgotten how little continual stress my left shoulder can take. Also, I learned that with <a href="https://www.arcteryx.com/us/en/shop/womens/codetta-coat">my rain coat</a> on, the bag slides up uncomfortably against my neck, so next time I&rsquo;ll need a day backpack again. Most days, I chose not to bring a bag to avoid this discomfort. I hauled my LAMY Safari pen + a <a href="https://www.jetpens.com/Hobonichi-Techo-Weeks/ct/4399">Hobonichi Weeks</a>, my phone, and some tissue paper, so a bag was overkill mostly.</p>
<h2 id="two-jackets">Two jackets</h2>
<p>I took my Arcteryx coat to Japan, and it served me well, despite being a <em>little</em> tight. However, I wandered into a Snow Peak store early in the trip, and my friend Sarah and the shopkeeper convinced me to try on a steeply discounted <a href="https://snowpeak.com/collections/outerwear-1/products/jk-18au004-fr-rain-trench?variant=13074792972386">Japanese XL <em>fire resistant</em> jacket</a>. It fit like a charm, and was long enough to easily cover my knees so I could stay warm and dry in the constant rain. I alternated between the two coats through the rest of the wet trip, but with both in my RYU bag, there wasn&rsquo;t much room for other stuff. I never plan on buying much in Japan, and certainly not clothes, so this was a pleasant surprise. As a back-up, I had a packable Baggu tote, but I never had to resort to carrying stuff in the tote on the way home. If I were traveling to a rainy area again, I&rsquo;d only bring one coat, and which one would depend on how much layering I needed to do. It&rsquo;s kinda nice to have options.</p>
<h2 id="just-enough-space">Just enough space</h2>
<p>By the end of my trip the RYU bag was a <em>tight</em> zip. I bought two manga tankoban, and one Japanese novel, as well as a series of gachapon souvenirs, <a href="https://www.tokyoweekender.com/2015/05/japanese-lucky-charms-the-guide-to-omamori/">omamori</a>, and a load of Vick&rsquo;s lozenges because of my cold. Everything fit, along with my two jackets, but only <em>just</em> so. I wore my DSPTCH bag on the front, outside of the RYU to get on the plane or train, but I could stuff it in if I needed to.</p>
<h2 id="planned-changes">Planned changes</h2>
<p>Next trip, if the weather is similar, my plan is to bring one jacket, and not buy another. Additionally, two pairs of pants was really beneficial, but <a href="http://www.coalatree.com/collections/kachula/products/trailhead-adventure-pant">a new pair I bought</a> should pack better than <a href="https://shop.nordstrom.com/s/nike-nikelab-x-mmw-womens-pants/4796841">the Nike pants</a> I brought, so that will save some space. My <a href="http://www.goby.co/products/electric-toothbrush-all-black">new toothbrush</a> worked swimmingly, and I didn&rsquo;t bring a charger, since my trip was ~2 weeks. I brought just enough toiletries, and that felt nice. I wish I&rsquo;d brought a tank top to sleep in, as I only had two shirts, so I felt like one was always a little funky from sleep, but because they wick, it was alright. For a daypack, I might look for an ultralight packable daypack, like one from Matador or <a href="http://www.ynotmade.com/en/shop/splitshift/?sku=5808">YNOT</a>, but my Topo Designs bag is probably good enough.</p>
<h2 id="next-trip">Next trip</h2>
<p>Next time I fly, it’s a short trip to Portland for a conference I’m doing a talk at with some friends. Two days means I’ll bring my Oppose This bag, and have a chill, easy time. Hopefully I’ll get to go back to Japan later this year and test this whole load-out again.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving to the bay</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-11-21-moving-to-the-bay/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-11-21-moving-to-the-bay/</guid>
      <description>Queers and Steers As a Texan, and a lesbian, I knew eventually I’d end up in California. That’s what we do.</description>
      <content:encoded><h2 id="queers-and-steers">Queers and Steers</h2>
<p>As a Texan, and a lesbian, I knew eventually I’d end up in California. That’s what we do. We leave Texas, and go west. I’ve spent the past four years hundreds of miles north in Portland, OR working remotely for various companies. I loved the trees, and the few amazing friends I made there, but found it hard to get through the long, lonely winters. It didn’t help that most of my jobs were remote—Portland has a burgeoning tech scene, but in general jobs haven’t kept up with rising cost of living. Working remotely meant rent was easier to pay, but that most of my world existed elsewhere. This all changed when <a href="https://www.turbinelabs.io">my last company</a>, my favorite job ever, shut down and went to work for <a href="https://slack.com">Slack</a>. I joined in the fun. Working for Slack, for me, also meant moving to the bay.</p>
<h2 id="fast-as-you-can">Fast as you can</h2>
<p>From the time I knew I had a job at Slack, to moving was all of two weeks. I started as soon as I could to ensure I didn’t run out of cash, and with the help of a moving company, all my stuff was packed-up and shipped the Saturday before my second week of work. Sunday meant driving Snorri, my friend <a href="https://twitter.com/local___honey">Amanda</a>, and some clothes for 10 hours to my new home <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emeryville,_California">near an IKEA</a>. It was a pretty drive, despite all the wild rain, and switchbacks. Snorri yelled intermittently.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/driving.jpeg" alt="driving"></p>
<p>Eventually, we arrived, quickly looted an IKEA for a few chairs, and set up my weird apartment. My stuff wouldn’t arrive for 2 weeks, so I was living that cool spy life until then.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/spylife.jpeg" alt="spy life"></p>
<h2 id="a-month-flew-by">A month flew by</h2>
<p>This week is my 5th at Slack, and I’ve already learned so much. My coworkers are rad as hell, the office is unbelievable, and for the first time in years I get to work on a product I’ve used since its inception—one that I earnestly love to use. Slack is where my friends live, where I talk to my chosen family. Slack is how I interact, increasingly, with every app that I use. It’s still amazing to me that I get to work there, and influence how API features and partnerships are built out. Seriously. Wow.</p>
<p>Snorri is still settling in, it feels like, especially due to his insistence that daylight savings doesn’t exist, and we must still eat breakfast at dawn. I think he misses his friend, Prince, but hopefully he’ll get a new one sooner than later. For a little while, I worried he’d get sick because he wasn’t eating much, but now he seems to love a variety of wet food, and even his <a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0146QXOB0?tag=thewire06-20&amp;linkCode=xm2&amp;ascsubtag=AgEAAAAAAAAAAPcR">fancy cat fountain</a>. He’s still getting used to me working out of the house every day, and seems to relish my semi-shut-in status while the smoke from the horrific fires in California rage in the north and south of my new state.</p>
<h2 id="bay-life">Bay life</h2>
<p>I’m looking forward to exploring the city more, finding tons of plants to outfit my place, and enjoying regular sunlight soon. It’s great to know so many of my friends live here, and now I can see them more than the once a month I spent here before moving to the bay. In addition to just wandering, I hope to get a few museum memberships, and get involved in the arts and music scene in a way I didn’t feel able to in Portland. I’ll miss the evergreens, and my friends, but so far this feels like a very good move.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 iPad Pro Review</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-11-07-new-ipad-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-11-07-new-ipad-review/</guid>
      <description>Today my phone buzzed to tell me my new iPad had arrived at my office. I rushed down to the mailroom, and eagerly ripped open the packaging.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>Today my phone buzzed to tell me my new iPad had arrived at my office. I rushed down to the mailroom, and eagerly ripped open the packaging. For a few years I’ve used an iPad Pro 9.7” as my primary travel computer when I didn’t need to work on Kubernetes/DevOps stuff, and I’ve loved it. Whether I was watching shows on Netflix or Plex that I’d downloaded before a flight, editing my website in Working Copy, or just editing photos and browsing Twitter, this was the machine I wanted to use.</p>
<p>Now, I have 1.3” more screen, a more lap-capable keyboard, and 120hz refresh, and I couldn’t be happier.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/ipad.jpeg" alt="iPad"></p>
<h2 id="the-screen">The screen</h2>
<p>This iPad might not feel like as huge of a revelation to someone who used the 10.5”, but coming from the 9.7”, this screen feels luxurious. The smooth 120hz refresh rate means opening apps, and moving around looks amazing. The color and viewing angles are still the best in the tablet world, and make my even my MacBook feel like a relic of the past. It’s responsive, bright, and a joy to watch tv on.</p>
<h2 id="the-case">The case</h2>
<p>My iPad is the Space Grey color, and it looks excellent. The industrial lines of the sides are reminiscent of my favorite iPhone, the 4. Overall the iPad feels thin, and around the weight of my 9.7” even with the added screen size, and when I have it out of the keyboard folio, I don’t want to put it down. This tablet feels great in my hands. I seriously hope that Apple brings this design language to the next generation of iPhones, even though I wonder if they can while still keeping the glass back for wireless charging.</p>
<h2 id="the-keyboard-folio">The keyboard folio</h2>
<p>My main use of the iPad is with a keyboard attached, as I use it as a laptop mostly, which sometimes becomes a handheld tablet for reading. I’m still not convinced there needed to be two viewing angles, but the stiffness and lack of weird folding means it feels pretty great in my lap or on a desk. The tablet-mode keyboard against your fingers thing is slightly odd, but it also reminds me of playing the accordion, which I find funny enough to enjoy it. The keys feel nice and responsive, and largely the same as the 9.7” keyboard. If they changed the keys, I can’t tell. I do enjoy the slightly larger size that matches the bigger device, and my mistypes are few and far-between. Clicking the iPad into the folio feels fast and easy, even if it requires slightly more lining up than previously. With the folio closed, the iPad feel grippy, and like a thin notebook in the best way. The weight and feel, in my opinion, remind you that you’re holding a high quality device. The folio adds a little thickness, but I think it only brings the device to the previous size, so I haven’t felt like it was too thick.</p>
<h2 id="usb-c">USB-C</h2>
<p>It’s great. I love using the same charger for this iPad and my MacBook. I already invested in USB-C to lighting cables, so bringing this iPad and no USB spare battery for my iPhone sounds great. I haven’t tried plugging anything weird into the port, but folks at the Verge did their damndest to stump the port. <em>Spoiler</em> it doesn’t work with printers.</p>
<h2 id="battery-life">Battery life</h2>
<p>It’s about the same as my old iPad, which is excellent.</p>
<h2 id="speakers">Speakers</h2>
<p>There’s four of them. They’re loud, and clear. A+</p>
<h2 id="faceid">FaceID</h2>
<p>Just as quick and easy as my previous iPhone X, and possibly a little slower than the XS. I can’t quite tell, but I feel a little like I’m waiting now compared to using my phone. I haven’t timed it though, but generally it’s much better and easier than the TouchID.</p>
<h2 id="wrap-up">Wrap-up</h2>
<p>This is the iPad to get—whether you get the 12.9” or the 11”, especially if you haven’t upgraded in a few years. I seriously feel like this is the future of Apple computing, and iOS 13 is sure to bring more advanced features that mean I might not need a Mac outside of my office.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSPTCH Waist Bag Review</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-10-04-dsptch-waist-bag/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-10-04-dsptch-waist-bag/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I ordered a medium Sling Pack after deciding I wanted a very small bag to bring with me to meetings or coffee shops where I only needed my iPad and a few other sundries.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>Recently, I ordered a <a href="https://www.dsptch.com/collections/packs/products/sling-pouch-medium">medium Sling Pack</a> after deciding I wanted a very small bag to bring with me to meetings or coffee shops where I only needed my iPad and a few other sundries. 11pm is not a great time to make <em>decisions</em>, so I clicked the order button before I checked measurements, and was sad when I realized it didn&rsquo;t actually fit my 9.7&quot; iPad. Luckily, I was already flying to San Francisco a week later, and was able to exchange it for the <a href="https://www.dsptch.com/products/waist-bag-black">Waist Bag</a>, after trying it on in the store. (An aside: the guy at DSPTCH was super nice, and really helpful, which further won me over. I think they have lots of great stuff, so even if this bag is too small for you, check it out.)</p>
<p>TL;DR this bag is fantastic for exactly what I bought it for—carrying an iPad and a few other things to meetings, or very short trips. A+ would buy again.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/wb_front.jpeg" alt="Front"></p>
<h2 id="pockets-and-zips">Pockets and zips</h2>
<p>I <em>love</em> the way the pockets and zipper are laid out in this bag. The top of the bag is accessible via a single, incredibly tactile zipper pull. Seriously, this zipper pull is rad. Once unzipped, the main compartment is broken into two parts: one slightly padded iPad sleeve, and a slightly larger main area with a D-ring for keys. My 12&quot; MacBook <em>fits</em> in the main area, which WOW. Not much else fits in the main area if I put my laptop in here, but still, this is unbelievably cool. With an iPad, a Kindle Oasis, a rolled-up shirt, a pair of underwear, keys, and toiletries this compartment is pretty tightly packed, but the zipper is sufficiently robust (it&rsquo;s a big YKK), so I don&rsquo;t feel worried about it failing.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/wb_main.jpeg" alt="Main"></p>
<p>The front of the bag is a flap with two super cool magnetic <a href="http://www.fidlock.com/en/fasteners/snap.html">Fidlock®</a> snaps. Pulling down slightly on each side reveals two slightly baggy pockets with elastic at the top. These pockets both have a vertical separation between the front and back of the pocket. I can fit a <a href="https://www.anker.com/products/variant/powercore-13000-c/A1216011">USB-C battery pack</a> and cables, plus some headphones on one side, and a <a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/">Hobonichi Techo</a>, a <a href="https://www.jetpens.com/LAMY-Safari-Fountain-Pen-Charcoal-Black-Fine-Nib/pd/5075?gclid=EAIaIQobChMImKKypcvt3QIVhWB-Ch2pAQarEAQYAiABEgKbO_D_BwE">Lamy Safari</a>, and keycards, lip balm, and essential oil in the other. I&rsquo;ve also fit a Kindle Oasis in one of the pockets, but it was a tight fit, and I prefer keeping it in the main bag pocket. The ease of popping open the snaps after pulling the bag around to the front reminds me why I loved messenger bags back in the day. It&rsquo;s super cool. I love having all of my stuff easily-accessible, but I&rsquo;m also glad my load ends up light enough not to hurt my shoulder. More on that later.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/wb_pockets.jpeg" alt="Pockets"></p>
<h2 id="material">Material</h2>
<p>The DSPTCH site says this bag is 1680D Ballistic Nylon with DWR coating, lined with 410D Nylon Packcloth with DWR coating. I haven&rsquo;t tested this bag in the rain yet, but the zip isn&rsquo;t seam-sealed, so while I&rsquo;d trust it in a light rain, I wouldn&rsquo;t swim with it. I bring a dry bag with me everywhere for toiletries though, and it&rsquo;s sufficiently large I could put the bag in it in a pinch, so I&rsquo;m not too worried. The material feels very nice, and high-quality, and the stitching and construction inspires confidence. The zipper pull is lightly textured on both sides, as well as contoured for a thumb and forefinger such that every use of it makes me smile.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/wb_zip.jpeg" alt="Main"></p>
<p>This is a bag you will want to open and close. The Fidlock® snaps are similarly fun to use. The strap is pretty solid as well, and my only complaint is that I wish the clasp was metal/magnetic instead of plastic, even though the plastic feels solid. This bag generally feels like it will hold up for over 10 years, and Dpstch warranties it, which gives me even more confidence as I lug it around. I&rsquo;d be amiss if I didn&rsquo;t mention the &ldquo;high air flow back mesh for longer periods of wear,&rdquo; which means I don&rsquo;t end up with <em>as much</em> sweat on my back when I&rsquo;m walking around in over environments &gt;20˚.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/wb_back.jpeg" alt="Back"></p>
<h2 id="size">Size</h2>
<p>This is a <em>small</em> bag. You can wear it over the shoulder, as a cross body, either in front or on your back, or as a fanny-pack/waist bag as the name indicates. In inches, it measures at 8L, or 13&quot; x 9&quot; x 1.5&quot; at 1.1lbs, but the numbers belie how much it can carry. This is the kind of bag your friends say &ldquo;wow&rdquo; to as you slide out a 9.7&quot; iPad or 12&quot; MacBook. This bag fits really well on the floor under a seat on a plane without compromising foot space. It also feels great to walk in a crowd or get onto a crowded train knowing I won&rsquo;t bonk anyone with this bag, as it barely sticks out from my back. It&rsquo;s very easy to adjust the strap that goes around my chest as well, and it&rsquo;s easy to slide this bag around to the front when I need to pull something out. I&rsquo;ve occasionally worn this bag on my hip/butt as a fanny-pack, and while I think it looks a little silly, it&rsquo;s very comfortable—your mileage may vary on style/feel.</p>
<h2 id="wrap-up">Wrap-up</h2>
<p>Overall, I love this bag, and look for every opportunity to bring it with me. In my effort to downsize and travel lightly, I&rsquo;ve found this to be a perfect companion. Every interaction I have with this bag feels great, and makes me smile. If you need something small to bring a few things to your next meeting, concert, or short trip, I highly recommend the <a href="https://www.dsptch.com/products/waist-bag-black">DSPTCH Waist Bag</a>. It&rsquo;s <em>seriously good</em> and my suspicion is the rest of their gear is equally great.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invisible One review</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-05-17-review-invisible-one-mini/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-05-17-review-invisible-one-mini/</guid>
      <description>Bags are my thing. Well, bags and shoes. Traveling as much as I do, having a dependable, comfortable, and sleek bag is pretty important.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>Bags are my thing. Well, bags and shoes. Traveling as much as I do, having a dependable, comfortable, and sleek bag is pretty important. For the past two or so years, I&rsquo;ve depended on my Topo Designs Trip Pack for short trips, and then nested it inside of my Ryu QuickPack for longer trips abroad. This has worked out well, but walking around Copenhagen, and going through a variety of international airport security, I wondered if I could consolidate to one bag, with an easier way to access my laptop and other stuff. The <a href="https://www.opposethis.com/products/invisible-backpack-one-mini">Invisible One Mini</a> seemed like a great way to test this out. I was drawn to the design of the bag, and the ethos of the company: &ldquo;Each year we reiterate and improve our designs&hellip;&rdquo; which I&rsquo;ve witnessed as I&rsquo;ve watched them iterate over the years.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/oneminifront.jpeg" alt="One Mini photo"></p>
<h2 id="pockets-and-zips">Pockets and zips</h2>
<p>My Topo Designs Trip Pack has three compartments—a main area where I can slip my laptop, a zip pouch in that main area, and a front pocket for a Kindle, notebook, etc. I found myself digging around more than I wanted to for my charger, pen, or chapstick. The Invisible One Mini has just a little more organization, and so far, it&rsquo;s made a huge difference.</p>
<p>The 2018 One Mini has a zipper pocket in the front, that&rsquo;s charmingly asymmetrical. A flap unzips, revealing a pocket that can hold an iPad or Kindle, a zipper-sealable area for keys, chapstick, glasses cloth, etc, and two smaller pouches. These pouches are the perfect size for a portable battery, and a Hobonichi Techo. There&rsquo;s a bit of additional space in the big zipper area for my MacBook charger as well. The entire big pouch is almost the width and heigh of the bag, but because of the clever organization, it doesn&rsquo;t feel like I&rsquo;ll lose things in it.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/oneminipocket.jpeg" alt="One Mini pocket"></p>
<p>On the top of the bag, there&rsquo;s a big zipper that opens the main compartment, which I use to hold a hoodie, my water bottle, and also a small bag of underwear and clothes for travel. Because of the front organization, I don&rsquo;t need to dig in this compartment often, and only need to keep a few easy-to-find or pack-to-leave unpack-at-destination items in it. This is a big improvement over the Topo Bag.</p>
<p>Finally, the back of the bag has a top-loading laptop sleeve that&rsquo;s soft and felt-lined. The bottom ends a bit above the bottom of the bag, providing a little cushion area, but I still wouldn&rsquo;t want to throw this bag around with my MacBook in it. Unlike the Ryu or the Topo Designs bags, this separate laptop area means I can dig my MacBook out on the occasions I can&rsquo;t get pre-check and have my laptop scanned separately. I try my damndest to avoid these instances, but inter-Europe travel usually means pulling out all my electronics.</p>
<p>Previous years of this bag had weird side zips on the front and back for the laptop, a water bottle, and documents and other stuff in the front, but this version feels more usable, and less confusing at a glance. I doubt I&rsquo;ll have any trouble remembering where I put various items, or how to quickly retrieve them. Read more about the year-over-year change <a href="https://www.opposethis.com/blogs/insidethis/invisible-backpack-one-2018">here</a>.</p>
<h2 id="the-material">The material</h2>
<p>The entire bag is a light-weight 800x600D waterproof nylon-polyester blend that looks and feels pretty lux. The top handle is a rubber-ish leather-is material that&rsquo;s grippy and feels nice, and the inside of the pack straps is a soft and breathable cloth. The top of the bag is ringed with the same rubberized material, encircling the main compartment. The inside of the two front areas is a gray nylon that feels like smooth quality. All over the bag, the stitches are even and seem made for longevity. I&rsquo;ll update this review later to see how well the bag stood up to travel wear-and-tear, but so far it inspires confidence. I&rsquo;m also curious how well the rain resistance does, as only the laptop sleep area has a waterproof YKK zipper, with the other two using a more standard zip. The pulls have rubber grips, with no dangling pull cords, which means they&rsquo;re slightly more fiddly than the RYU or the Topo bags, but once I&rsquo;ve found the tab, the pull feels smooth.</p>
<h2 id="the-size">The size</h2>
<p>This is a small bag, but feels a good deal bigger than my tiny Topo Designs bag. Measuring 38cm x 34cm x 14cm (15&quot;x13.5&quot;x5.5&quot;), with a volume of 11L, and a weight of 650g (22oz), it&rsquo;s easy to throw on, but doesn&rsquo;t look dwarfed by my 5'10&quot; frame. It sits well on my back, and the clever straps let me cinch it up or down, while the excess strap stays tucked into itself. The main compartment is roomy enough without making the other areas of the bag feel cramped, that I feel pretty confident I could take only this bag for a few weeks abroad.</p>
<h2 id="wrap-up">Wrap-up</h2>
<p>I haven&rsquo;t had this bag for long, but my first impressions are that this will be a major part of my travel kit. I can&rsquo;t wait to bring this with me to Oakland, or Japan, to see how well it fits under a seat, or loads and unloads in a crowded subway train.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pack light and still enjoy the trip</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2016-04-14-pack-light-and-still-enjoy-the-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2016-04-14-pack-light-and-still-enjoy-the-trip/</guid>
      <description>Why I choose to travel with a 16L bag everywhere I go.
The Past Years ago, I stopped checking bags when I flew.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>Why I choose to travel with a 16L bag everywhere I go.</p>
<h2 id="the-past">The Past</h2>
<p>Years ago, I stopped checking bags when I flew. I’d seen too many things get lost over the years, my own and other’s, and couldn’t stomach the thought of landing somewhere again, only to lose all my possessions. So, I began using a canvas duffel bag, as well as a small backpack.</p>
<p>The bag is grey, and around 30L in volume, has little toggle closures, and a couple internal pockets. It was great for trips in the car to Dallas to see my partner at the time’s family, or anywhere that I didn’t need to carry it. But it was horrible for planes and walking.</p>
<p>For a while, I just dealt with the shoulder pain and annoyance of a single, cross-chest strap full of gear, in addition to my backpack. But it hurt, and I didn’t really like the way I looked, carrying two different bags. I still felt much better about my setup than I would with a large rectangle of soon-to-be-lost gear, but I wanted to simplify more.</p>
<p><em>A note on my able-bodied privilege</em> This choice to carry a smaller bag, regardless of weight, is one that I was able to make because of my body. For those with chronic pain, or difficulty carrying weight on their back for whatever reason, my setup will likely not work. I see a lot of folks get frustrated with rolling bags, and I have shared that sentiment in the past, but it is very shitty to the folks who need those bags for any reason.</p>
<h2 id="simplify-your-gear">Simplify your gear</h2>
<p><em>Pack lighter by packing less</em></p>
<h3 id="clothing">Clothing</h3>
<p>The first thing I did to simplify, was to see what I could live without. Many of the <em>extras</em> that I was sure of needing got tossed. No more extra shoes for a trip. No more than the number of underwear I would need for the trip (and often less — it’s easy to hand-wash). Two bras (<strong>Nude label</strong>). A couple shirts that could also be hand-washed easily (yoga tank-tops from <strong>Lucy</strong>). Wool socks, usually two pairs. With my wardrobe thus whittled, I turned to my love of books.</p>
<h3 id="books">Books</h3>
<p>In the past I always brought at least 3 books with me on trip of more than 3 or 4 days, as I’d likely go through all of them. Books are heavy. Like, really heavy, and not very easy to pack tightly, especially if they’re lengthy. A <strong>Kindle</strong> helped fix that problem immediately. I bought the cheapest one, with ads, and loaded it up with a few books I’d acquired over the years, and some free ones from Project Gutenberg. I don’t like giving my money to Amazon, but there are other ways to buy books that support independent bookstores. Now I could carry as many books as I wanted, and acquire new ones instantly, without needing to add to the weight of my pack. Don’t get me wrong, I still love the smell and feel of books, and have a library at home that I treasure, but just like my other stuff, I don’t need to travel with everything I care about.</p>
<h3 id="electronics">Electronics</h3>
<p>When it came to electronics, I was already pretty lightweight. I had the ability to afford a <strong>Macbook Air</strong>, and learned that each year I could sell the previous one and buy a new one for ~100 dollars or so if I kept it from getting banged up. This 13&quot;, slim laptop could go most anywhere with me with a minimal strain on my back. I had a slender <strong>Tom Bhin</strong> sleeve for it, and its charger. I also had my <strong>iPhone</strong>, my Kindle (as mentioned above), and a small USB cable for both. In recent years, I’ve switched to the <strong>Macbook</strong>, which is even smaller and lighter than the Air. My company bought me a Kindle Paperwhite, so now I can read on dark planes with minimal disturbance. I also purchased an <strong>Anker</strong> powercore 15600 that can charge my phone ~6 times before needing to be charged itself. It’s a little heavy, but has made a huge difference in how I travel, as I don’t need to worry as much about finding an outlet when I am sure to need directions and contact with folks via Twitter, email, or text. For headphones, I’ve always loved in-ear ones, but on long flights, they are painful at best. I got a pair of **ATH-M40Xs **that I adore, and usually wear them around my neck when I’m not listening to them on trips. When I get where I am traveling, I often leave them in the room and switch to my <strong>RHA 10Ti</strong> in-ear-monitors. There are better headphones for the price, but these work well for me, and most-importantly, fit into my phone while the case is on it, unlike my <strong>Shure 215k</strong> that I previously wore everywhere.</p>
<p>The final electronic device I bring is a vibrator. At home, I have quite the array, and particularly love my wireless <strong>Magic Wand</strong>. But, taking a note from a friend about not becoming dependent on what amounts to a power tool, I travel with the easily-packed <strong>JimmyJane Form 2</strong>. It does the trick, has a travel mode (so it doesn’t vibrate in my bag), and is waterproof to boot.</p>
<h3 id="other-clothes">Other clothes</h3>
<p>When I go anywhere with either changeable temperature, or the likelihood of rain, I bring my <a href="http://www.ilsejacobsen.com/womens-raincoat-RAIN50.html?c=76695">**Ilse Jacobsen Raincoat 50</a> **jacket. It’s black, minimally adorned, and waterproof. I love it. Before I had this jacket, I always brought my older <strong>Marmot Precip</strong>, which could be stowed in my bag easily, unlike this new jacket. With warmer weather, I will probably return to that jacket, for ease of carry.</p>
<p>Yoga pants are the best. For both comfort on the plane, and versatile city exploring, I always bring a pair of yoga leggings that are black, and durable. The ones I have now are from Lucy, but anything will do. With these, my socks, and the yoga tanks I wear, the key is wicking. I sweat easily, and don’t always have a great way to wash clothes, so having clothing that stays pretty stink-free, and dry, is a huge plus. It also packs down really easily due to the thinness of the fabric. You might want something a little thicker if you get cold more easily. Sometimes I bring wool tights too, to wear under these or my jeans.</p>
<p>For pants, I also bring a pair of high-waisted, stretchy black jeans. This is a style choice, but I love them. I pack these in my bag while flying, and then wear them around half the time I’m on my trip. I also bring a small pair of shorts (<strong>Foxers</strong>), for sleeping and wandering around my hotel, or hostel.</p>
<h3 id="toiletries">Toiletries</h3>
<p>I don’t wear much makeup, and that means my toiletry packing is pretty straightforward. I bring a stick of eyeliner, a stick of lipstain, some coconut-oil deodorant, essential oil, and a toothbrush. I pack these in the front pocket of my backpack, along with my medicine, and some hand-sanitizer for those times I have no idea where to wash my hands, but want to eat.</p>
<p>I also bring a water bottle, which is a <strong>Hydroflask</strong>, but have thought about getting a collapsable water bottle, the <strong>Vapur</strong>, soon. (Edit: I got a Vapor bottle, and it’s amazing. It can fold up and fit in the small front zipper of my Fjalraven bag along with the makeup and pill-bottle I keep in there. A+)</p>
<h3 id="the-bag">The bag</h3>
<p>I switch between two bags these days, depending on condition. If there will be a lot of rain, or I expect my bag to get jostled significantly, I bring my <strong>Mission Workshop 21L Sancturary</strong> bag. It’s super durable, and has held up to international travel and mistreatment in my often clumsy hands, and stayed strong for the past 6 years or so. In an effort to get even lighter, as well as have something cuter to walk around cities like NYC with, I picked up a <strong>Fjalraven Kånken</strong> bag. At 16L, it’s pretty small, but I can still fit all my packed gear inside. My only complaint with this bag, is that with my stuff in it, it can be difficult to get my laptop out in the TSA line. I never dealt with this problem using my Mission Workshop bag, because it has a folding top, that allows for easy access to the laptop in the back. The Fjalraven is a zipper system at the front of the bag, so I have to roll the top back with it unzipped to pull out my laptop. I’m considering cutting the bag and adding another zipper, but we’ll see. It’s less of a problem with the bag less tightly packed, so it’s likely this will just lead to me packing a little bit less each time, and that’s not so bad.</p>
<p><em>Final recommendation:</em> Years ago I read an article written by a designer who decided to travel without any clothes, save for enough underwear to get her through the trip. She loved the opportunity to hit up a thrift store and buy interesting outfits, which she would re-sell, or donate at the end of her trip. She figured she was saving hassle by not bringing extra clothes, and saving money, potentially, by not needing to check a bag. I love this idea, but as a woman who has a hard time finding well-fitting clothes (I’m 5'10, athletic, and wide-hipped), I don’t want to take that kind of risk. But, if you love shopping, have a frame that is more welcoming to thrift clothes, and feel ok with buying and getting rid of these temporary outfits, then I recommend trying her style of light packing. You might find that the short-lived nature of these clothes inspire you to make riskier or more interesting choices, and maybe even mailing a few pieces back home.</p>
<h2 id="wrap-up">Wrap up</h2>
<p>There are many reasons why I’ve decided to pack as light as I do, and it’s become a thing I both enjoy and find ways to challenge as I continue to travel regularly. Questioning the stuff I own, and finding a way to make cute outfits with limited options is a fun way to make the most of a limited budget, or a temporarily limited wardrobe. A lot of folks I know love to bring large bags with extra shoes, more clothes than they wear, and options for most gear. I’m glad they found what works for them, but I’m also very happy to have figured out a minimal pack that feel like I have enough for a week or two. However you decide to pack, light, heavy, or not at all, I hope you enjoy your travels, take some pictures, and breath.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NYC</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-11-9-nyc-my-second-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-11-9-nyc-my-second-home/</guid>
      <description>New York is my home for two months out of the year, but I only recently became acquainted with it. Growing up in Texas, I got the idea from my dad that NYC was some kind of devil city.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>New York is my home for two months out of the year, but I only recently became acquainted with it. Growing up in Texas, I got the idea from my dad that NYC was some kind of devil city. He regarded it as a liberal place with people who walked too fast, and were too greedy. The first time I visited in my mid-twenties, I realized just how wrong he was.</p>
<h3 id="my-first-visit">My first visit</h3>
<p>At this point, I was liberal myself, and the city didn’t seem particularly evil to me. There were people literally EVERYWHERE, though in less quantities than Taipei and Chennai, both of which I visited before NYC. The density of any of those cities is slightly overwhelming for me, as I’m happier in a group of 2–6 people, but I learned quickly that I can put my headphones on and they disappear. To a degree, music makes the city feel like a river that I’m floating through or a strange movie set. Interactions with strangers aren’t necessary in the way that waving at folks on the street seems normal in Portland or Texas. In a way, I found the anonymity and brusqueness refreshing.</p>
<h3 id="food">Food</h3>
<p>As a food nerd, I also find the ubiquity of delicious meals incredibly appealing, though I will never get used to the constant lines and hype around restaurants who can only hope to fit a handful of people at a time, ensuring long waits. Still, I feast each time I visit my 2nd home. Often I will pick a particular cuisine, and try to find the 5 best examples of its preparation, be it ramen, izakaya food, or southern fried chicken. Food tourism is a major industry from what I can tell. Food isn’t cheap, but then neither is anything else in NYC. I budget to spend $60 a day in NYC on food alone, and many times I’ve blown right by that. I’d imagine if I lived there more regularly, I would cook more often, but the temptations of restaurants and carts is too high for me to pass up during each visit. I’ve yet to dive into the fine-dining scene, as I’m loathe to wear heels or hose, but I’ve heard great things about upscale restuarants. For now, I think I’ll stick to the sub-$10 congee bowl with youtiao.</p>
<h3 id="getting-around">Getting around</h3>
<p>A huge part of my love of the city is the transport. Many of my friends in NYC seem to avoid the subway, opting for Uber, taxis, or bicycles, but I love it. To me, trains are a pinnacle of old, cool technology. They’re dependable (largely), safe (except occasionally from scary folks), and inexpensive. Waiting on the platform, or slumped in a molded plastic seat, I have time to read books, listen to music, and contemplate hard problems at work or in life. In a city that moves so quickly, these brief pauses are my respite. Without them, I don’t think I could handle the bustle or the pace of NYC.</p>
<h3 id="memento-mori">Memento mori</h3>
<p>That said, I think the city wants us dead. The distinct sense I get from NYC is one of antagonism. The people can be ok at times, but the city itself pulses with too much, and too harsh. Not only are there actual dangers in the city, but the sheer speed at which everything is moving ensures that if you stumble emotionally, physically, or in spirit, the weight of the city-as-inexorable-movement will grind you into dust. Perhaps the industry or part of New York you encounter on a daily basis can mitigate this for a time, but by and large, NYC is hard to thrive in. High rents, cold winters, humid-as-hell summers, and complex transit — if you are thinking of visiting or moving from a sleepy locale, test the waters in a few seasons first.</p>
<h3 id="finally">Finally</h3>
<p>For myself, making friends was the most important part of enjoying my time in NYC. They ensure that I have activities in the city or in Brooklyn, as well as support and kind faces. With growing familiarity and the increased time I spend in the city, I now love it as a second home, and am excited to drop in for a few weeks at a time, to partake in the drug of NYC. And I’m equally happy to fly home, disembark from the plane, and breath in the cool, crisp air of Portland.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
