<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>dill &amp; fennel</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/</link><description>Recent content on dill &amp; fennel</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Copyright Brook Shelley 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.brookshelley.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Traveling During a Pandemic: Part Five</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-24-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-five/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-24-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-five/</guid><description>Before it was clear we were headed for a pandemic, I booked a “treat yourself” trip to Japan. After a great first year at Slack, I wanted a nice non-work trip to really relax and refresh before going back into 2020 with a renewed sense of vigor. Previously, I wrote about my time in Asakusa.
Last day in Asakusa What was supposed to be my last day in Asakusa started late.</description></item><item><title>Traveling during a pandemic: part four</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-22-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-four/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-22-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-four/</guid><description>Before it was clear we were headed for a pandemic, I booked a “treat yourself” trip to Japan. After a great first year at Slack, I wanted a nice non-work trip to really relax and refresh before going back into 2020 with a renewed sense of vigor. Previously, I wrote about my time in Onomichi.
Yakitori party/焼き鳥のパーテイ After a drink at my hotel’s bar, I got a hot tip to check out a yakitori place a ten-minute walk away.</description></item><item><title>Traveling during a pandemic: part three</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-19-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-three/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-19-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-three/</guid><description>Before it was clear we were headed for a pandemic, I booked a “treat yourself” trip to Japan. After a great first year at Slack, I wanted a nice non-work trip to really relax and refresh before going back into 2020 with a renewed sense of vigor. Previously, I wrote about my time in Osaka.
Heading south Hopping on a call in the morning with Haley, Drl, and Zech was a nice way to start my last morning in Osaka.</description></item><item><title>Traveling during a pandemic: part two</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-17-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-two/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-17-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-two/</guid><description>Wow, things sure are quiet&amp;hellip;
Before it was clear we were headed for a pandemic, I booked a “treat yourself” trip to Japan. After a great first year at Slack, I wanted a nice non-work trip to really relax and refresh before going back into 2020 with a renewed sense of vigor. Previously, I wrote about packing and my initial few days in Koenji in western Tokyo.
Off to Kyoto Tokyo station and the Tokaido Shinkansen were both relatively empty, which was very odd to experience.</description></item><item><title>Traveling during a pandemic</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-16-traveling-during-a-pandemic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-16-traveling-during-a-pandemic/</guid><description>Wow, things sure are quiet&amp;hellip;
Before it was clear we were headed for a pandemic, I booked a “treat yourself” trip to Japan. After a great first year at Slack, I wanted a nice non-work trip to really relax and refresh before going back into 2020 with a renewed sense of vigor.
Unfortunately, in the following weeks COVID-19 grew at a wild rate, the cases in the United States were clearly skyrocketing despite a complete failure of the CDC and leadership to provide ample testing.</description></item><item><title>Space: it’s the place to be</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-15-space-it-s-the-place-to-be/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-15-space-it-s-the-place-to-be/</guid><description>Welp, time to blast off into self-quarantine.</description></item><item><title>Micropost 2</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-12-micropost-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-12-micropost-2/</guid><description>That big momo energy</description></item><item><title>Micropost 1</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-05-micropost-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-05-micropost-1/</guid><description>This book is great so far! Robin Sloan has posted about it as well.
Unrelated but holy crap, Devs is very, very good.</description></item><item><title>february</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2020-03-01-february/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2020-03-01-february/</guid><description>XOXO it was the month of love&amp;hellip; for my new bike, and my always valentine Snorri. I watched a lot more movies this month than I read books, but that felt alright. Video games were also a theme, with lots of Witcher 3 and Dead Souls to keep me occupied. I also powered through a number of TV shows, like the Misadventures of Romesh Ranganathan and the October Faction.</description></item><item><title>A Twitter Experiment: Using RSS to read-only Twitter</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-02-22-a-twitter-experiment-using-rss-to-readonly-twitter/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-02-22-a-twitter-experiment-using-rss-to-readonly-twitter/</guid><description>The problem I&amp;rsquo;ve been on Twitter for over a decade, and found that lately it&amp;rsquo;s been more depressing and less enjoyable. I follow around five hundred people, of which I&amp;rsquo;d estimate 2-300 actively tweet every month. Because many of the users I follow are friends of mine I want to keep up with their lives and jokes, but that leads me to compulsively check my Twitter client of choice throughout the day on iOS and Mac.</description></item><item><title>january</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2020-01-30-media-diet-for-january/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2020-01-30-media-diet-for-january/</guid><description>2020 began in earnest, and despite it being winter, in the Bay Area it’s delightfully sunny. I spent the first week largely sitting by the window of my apartment, reading and studying Japanese. So far, I really enjoy the slower pace of this decade.
Books Mainline — Deborah Christiansen
A fun throwback to the world of cyber decks and assassins. I wish I’d found this in 1996, but it holds up well.</description></item><item><title>Rewatching Halt &amp; Catch Fire</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-01-09-rewatching-halt-catch-fire/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-01-09-rewatching-halt-catch-fire/</guid><description>The first time When Halt &amp;amp; Catch Fire first aired, I was lucky enough to clue in and watch it weekly on AMC. As a Texan with a dad who occasionally worked in or at least around tech, and then joined the industry myself, it captured the world I grew up in incredibly well. Starting out a little rough, it became a show all about family and how ambition can destroy everything.</description></item><item><title>My Favorite Movies of 2019</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-01-01-my-favorite-movies-of-2019/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-01-01-my-favorite-movies-of-2019/</guid><description>Out of 74 movies, I wanted to pick a few that really stood out, and then talk briefly about a few that I really didn&amp;rsquo;t enjoy. I went to the theater quite a bit this year, as I live pretty close to one with couch-seats and luckily have a few film-buddies to meet up with. Other films that I didn&amp;rsquo;t get a chance to see while they were on the big screen were rented at home or watched through a myriad of streaming services I&amp;rsquo;ve accrued over the years.</description></item><item><title>december</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2019-12-31-media-diet-for-december/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2019-12-31-media-diet-for-december/</guid><description>Books Dept. of Speculation — Jenny Offill
A gorgeous and sad book that captures long relationships so well. I loved for narrator and the strange poetic style of storytelling. I read this in two sittings and was enraptured.
Dead Astronauts — Jeff Vandermeer
This book did some interesting things with time, and some deeply annoying things with text. I feel like I know what he was doing with this book largely, and support his environmental aims (a+ murderous blue fox), but it never really came together for me.</description></item><item><title>What I learned from sending a newsletter this year</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-12-30-what-i-learned-from-sending-a-newsletter-this-year/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-12-30-what-i-learned-from-sending-a-newsletter-this-year/</guid><description>Way back in February of 2019, I sent my first newsletter—a repost of a blog post about learning Japanese, then petered out for a bit. In July, I began sending weekly link emails, which I managed to keep up through the end of the year. It&amp;rsquo;s been quite a fun Sunday activity, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d chat a bit about what the experience of weekly link writing was like.</description></item><item><title>My Favorite Books of 2019</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-12-16-my-favorite-books-of-2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-12-16-my-favorite-books-of-2019/</guid><description>This year I read 55 books and a lot of graphic novels. Fortunately, most of them were pretty great, which made it even harder to pick out my five favorite. I gravitated towards a lot of fantasy and sci-fi in 2019 as a nice way to escape or even think about a potentially scarier future. My plan to keep reading primarily female authors also paid off.
In no particular order, here’s the list:</description></item><item><title>Bellroy Studio Pack Review</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-12-13-bellroy-studio-pack-review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-12-13-bellroy-studio-pack-review/</guid><description>A new backpack for everyday carry, and travel.
First Sight After first getting my new Bellroy sling, I fell in love with the delightful material for these bags. A few months later in Iitoya in Japan, I got to see their new Shift backpack in person, and almost bought one on the spot. that bag was a little larger than I need, but then I saw this. With the launch of the Studio Backpack, Bellroy has made an excellent bag that holds a little or a lot without every looking absurd.</description></item><item><title>november</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2019-11-30-media-diet/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2019-11-30-media-diet/</guid><description>It’s finally chilly hygge-weather in the Bay Area, so I’ve been reading a lot after returning from a long trip to Japan. I hope wherever you are, you’re warm and feel loved.
Books The Starless Sea &amp;ndash; Erin Morgenstern
I read this in a delightful haze during the holiday weekend. I love stories like these, that are also about stories, and books, and love. I remember liking the Night Circus, but I absolutely adore The Starless Sea.</description></item><item><title>2019 iOS Homescreen</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-28-2019-iphone-homescreen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-28-2019-iphone-homescreen/</guid><description>Another year has rushed past, and with it, another iPhone update and some changes to my phone since last year&amp;rsquo;s setup. My use of a single screen of apps continues, with a few major and minor changes alongside.
I&amp;rsquo;ve posted these for the past few years, so if you want to see what apps I was using in 2017, here you go.
Some things change 3 app dock—I moved my Twitter app out of my dock in order to spend less time on Twitter.</description></item><item><title>Favorite Albums of 2019</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-26-favorite-albums-2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-26-favorite-albums-2019/</guid><description>The Playlist Here&amp;rsquo;s all the albums I really loved this year easily accessible as an Apple Playlist.
The Albums 1) Cheap Queen — King Princess
Bless lesbian musicians. King Princess first caught my attention with the song Pussy is God, which damn. This album is a bop.
2) Emily Alone — Florist
A deeply sparse, sad album that I enjoy quite a bit. Florist has always made beautiful songs, but this is a so quiet and so delightful.</description></item><item><title>DevRel Tour Packing List</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-06-devreltour-packing-list/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-06-devreltour-packing-list/</guid><description>As usual, when I go on a DevRel tour, I like to write about what I&amp;rsquo;ve packed. This trip was a 3 week journey from Tokyo, through Kyoto, to Osaka, and back. As I write this, halfway through the trip, I feel very good about the amount of stuff I brought.
Bags RYU Quick Pack 18L Topo Designs Trip Pack Last time I went to Japan, I brought the DSPTCH Waist Bag as my day bag, and my shoulders immediately regretted it.</description></item><item><title>october</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2019-10-31-media-diet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2019-10-31-media-diet/</guid><description>Books To Be Taught, If Fortunate — Becky Chambers
This is one of the best sci-fi short novellas I’ve read in a while. It’s not quite hard SF, but I love all the little details. The characters are great, and just casually queer, and there’s just enough suspense to make it a real page-turner. A triumph.
The Guest Cat — Takashi Hiraide **
Definitely cried reading this one. I’m a sucker for Japanese cat literature for sure.</description></item><item><title>a letter</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-10-08-letter-to-myself/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-10-08-letter-to-myself/</guid><description>(this is a very earnest post, and if you&amp;rsquo;re here for backpacks and travel, maybe skip this one)
Hey Brook,
This letter in a sci-fi tale would come to you out of the ether, dropping onto your iBook G3 on some particularly dark night of the soul. I&amp;rsquo;m you, but 16 years older, and hopefully a little wiser.
(Spoiler alert)
The next few years will be a lot of fun, but also really, really tough.</description></item><item><title>september</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2019-09-30-media-diet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2019-09-30-media-diet/</guid><description>Media diet for September Books Gideon the Ninth — Tamsyn Muir
Queer space necromancers! Queer space necromancers! OMG. This book was utterly bizarre, and a hell of a lot of fun. I’m a fan of low-tech future space stories, where for the most part the book seems more like fantasy than sci-fi, so this book was a joy. Plus there was necromancy! Apparently there are going to be two more books in this series, which is a delightful thing to learn, because I want to stretch out and learn more about this strange universe.</description></item><item><title>xoxo 2019</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-09-10-xoxo-2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-09-10-xoxo-2019/</guid><description>A return to form This year marked my 4th XOXO, and my 3rd at Revolution Hall. Last year was big, which meant it was even harder to wave at, or spend time with the other amazing attendees I knew. This year, it felt just right. I still waved at too many folks, and wished I had time to have a number of small dinners over the next year instead of so many “hey, I see you, sorry I’ve gotta run!</description></item><item><title>masterworks review</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-09-03-masterworks-review/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-09-03-masterworks-review/</guid><description>I wish I knew more about art. Reading the titular story, I found myself reaching for my phone to understand each scene in the strange and delightful post-apocalyptic tale. As I held the painting in my mind, and explored the flooded wastes with Liam, Nell, and Co. I found myself enamored by the framing. How often are our relationships held together by a retelling of an old picture? Are we always trying to build a life out of the classics of our youth?</description></item><item><title>august</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2019-08-30-media-diet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2019-08-30-media-diet/</guid><description>Books The Light Brigade — Kameron Hurley
Definite Catch-22 vibes throughout this book, with a hearty helping of Starship Troopers. If you like time-travel and space military, this is a solid read.
The Psychology of Time Travel — Kate Mascarenhas
Ah, time-travel and lesbians: two of my favorite things. This book was an interesting take on time-travel, and inevitable meeting of your future and past selves. I really enjoyed the small strange moments between characters.</description></item><item><title>wardrobe refresh</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-08-20-wardrobe-refresh/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-08-20-wardrobe-refresh/</guid><description>As my clothes gradually wear out, I’m slowly trying to replace everything with my current favorites. This makes for a very simple wardrobe that works for all 4 seasons.
Lots of this stuff is wool, all of it is pretty durable, and when possible I tried to find vendors that were environmentally friendly and smaller.
Shirts 4 tank tops — These are fantastic tank tops. They wick well, don’t get stinky, and look good enough to wear outside of the gym.</description></item><item><title>july</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2019-07-25-media-diet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2019-07-25-media-diet/</guid><description>Books Dune — Frank Herbert
A classic. I read this when I was a kid, but hadn’t reread it since then. It’s weird, long, and great. The rest of the series is supposed to be bizarre, so I can’t wait. The spice must flow.
Claire DeWitt and the City of the Dead — Sara Gran
An alright mystery book, but more than a few times, I think the author attempted to add grit but just ended up sounding like a very awkward narrator.</description></item><item><title>A Weekly Link Newsletter</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-07-21-newsletter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-07-21-newsletter/</guid><description>It’s official: I’ve joined the newsletter trend in earnest. I’ve had a newsletter for a few months now, but I wasn’t sure what to really do with it. Fortunately, I realized what I love to see the most from some of my favorite newsletters is links to what these authors are reading this week—little jewels from internet wanderings.
My re-launched Dill and Fennel newsletter will have links to some of the more interesting or funny things I’ve seen in the previous week.</description></item><item><title>june</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2019-06-30-media-diet/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2019-06-30-media-diet/</guid><description>Books The Fated Sky — Mary Robinette Kowal
More cool space stuff! I enjoyed the pacing more in this book, and despite the frustration with very 50s attitudes that still pervade the modern world, I enjoyed journeying with these two books to mars.
The Bone Clocks — David Mitchell
A delightful collision of strange characters across time. This book is just fantastical enough to scratch my sci-fi itch, and literary enough to keep me satisfied.</description></item><item><title>iPadOS</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-06-09-ios13/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-06-09-ios13/</guid><description>It’s probably clear by now that I love my iPad Pro. I travel with it, write on it, and practice Japanese on it. When Apple announced iPadOS, it suddenly seemed liked my dream of only using my iPad had come true.
Major updates New home screen With a glance at the home screen, it’s clear that this isn’t iOS 12. Onscreen widgets isn’t exactly revolutionary, but it saves me a slide-over every time I want to check the weather, or which meeting I’m headed to next.</description></item><item><title>on the perfect thing</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-05-27-on-the-perfect-thing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-05-27-on-the-perfect-thing/</guid><description>The search for the best, most optimized, beautiful, light, and pleasing things.
Why do we search? Scrolling through my RSS feeds, I’m reminded daily that so much stuff exists. I subscribe to newsletters for fashion, backpacks, apps, and general tech, and every single one has an endless march through the days of new things. This app has two columns for editing! This backpack is “able to transition from work to play and travel.</description></item><item><title>may</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2019-05-24-media-diet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2019-05-24-media-diet/</guid><description>This was a really great month for books largely because I got really into the Themis Files series. Price’s book on breaking up with your phone also encouraged me to pick up my Kindle more than I refreshed Twitter, and honestly, so far that’s been a positive experience.
Books Noumenon — Marina J. Lostetter
Ah! Another great multi-generational space exploration story. I don&amp;rsquo;t really get why so many sci-fi books are doing this sort of thing lately, but I&amp;rsquo;m into it.</description></item><item><title>on notes and todos</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-05-02-on-notes-and-todos/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-05-02-on-notes-and-todos/</guid><description>The latest episode of Supercomputer inspired me to write about how I work with notes, todos, and reminders every day. Part of the episode was centered on their mutual dissatisfaction with various notes apps, which I totally understand. Over the years, I&amp;rsquo;ve used NVAlt, 1Writer, Bear, Evernote, Notes, and more to keep track of my thoughts, posts, and notes. Brett Terpstra keeps a very good list of all iOS text editors that includes information about their cross-platform functionality.</description></item><item><title>april</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2019-04-27-media-diet/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2019-04-27-media-diet/</guid><description>https://screenanarchy.com/assets_c/2018/02/IFFR2018-review-Niswog-main-thumb-860xauto-70015.jpg
Books The United States of Japan — Peter Tieryas
An alternate history where Japan and Germany won WW2, then proceeded to divvy up North America. Most of the book is set in the 80s, in a world of internet devices, and giant robots, ruled by the Japanese emperor. It&amp;rsquo;s a brutal story at times, but was generally interesting and a good sci-fi time.
If Cats Disappeared from the World — Genki Kawarmura **</description></item><item><title>formula 1</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-04-13-formula-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-04-13-formula-1/</guid><description>When I mention my love of Formula 1 racing, most of the time I hear, &amp;ldquo;is that like NASCAR?&amp;rdquo; This speaks to the sad lack of F1 information and excitement in the states, and it&amp;rsquo;s a bummer. NASCAR is a sport in its own right, but comparing it to F1 is a bit like comparing rotary phones to an iPhone. F1 is fast, the roads twist this way and that, and most importantly the drivers are from across the globe.</description></item><item><title>minimal travel clothing</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-04-08-minimal-travel-clothing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-04-08-minimal-travel-clothing/</guid><description>Ten or so years ago, I realized I hated bringing heavy bags with me everywhere I traveled, so I slimmed down my packing to fit in one small backpack. My wardrobe generally cycles between a few pieces, so it wasn’t much of a stretch to adapt it to a month in Japan or Berlin. I usually write a post-trip gear update, but today is all about clothing.
What’re you wearing?</description></item><item><title>march</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2019-03-24-media-diet/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2019-03-24-media-diet/</guid><description>Books The City in the Middle of the Night — Charlie Jane Anders
A fantastic book about humankind settling on a tidally-locked planet, but instead of seeing how we cope, we learn the stories of their descendants, hundreds of years after our first tentative steps. The light is too bright and hot, and the night too cold and dark. We live on the edge in an eternal dusk/morning light. The two protagonists, Mouth, and Sophie, are on the edges of society, yearning for things they&amp;rsquo;ve lost or can&amp;rsquo;t have, and all that leads towards.</description></item><item><title>travel kit update</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-03-13-travel-kit-update/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-03-13-travel-kit-update/</guid><description>Since 2019, I updated my kit a little bit, but mostly it stayed the same.
One old bag, one new My Ryu Quickpack was a delight once-again, as I used it to transport all my gear to Japan, and then from city to city. Most days it sat in my room as I travelled around with my DSPTCH Waist Bag or just what I could fit in my pockets. Ergonimically, this bag is one of the most comfortable bags I&amp;rsquo;ve owned, but due to its size, I don&amp;rsquo;t like hauling it around all day.</description></item><item><title>february</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2019-02-24-media-diet/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2019-02-24-media-diet/</guid><description>Books Genocidal Organ — Project Itoh
A truly grim thriller about the cost of “fighting terrorism,” and the ability of language to tear apart a country. This feels eerily prescient. I can’t say I enjoyed reading this book, but it’s a nihilistic political commentary that at least adds some color to what politicians might be after when they start wars and conflicts. This book is graphic, violent, and in its way, poignant.</description></item><item><title>slower reading</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-02-10-slower-reading/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-02-10-slower-reading/</guid><description>With the death of Google Reader in 2013 it seems like many folks gave up on RSS. Fortunately, not only is RSS still alive, but it&amp;rsquo;s thriving. Between Newsletters and a return to blogging by many writers, thinkers, and web folks, RSS is an excellent way to find news and joy. While Twitter and other networks flounder, open standards provide a simple way to read. RSS means no trolls and no reply gifs.</description></item><item><title>learning kanji again</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-01-27-learning-kanji-again/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-01-27-learning-kanji-again/</guid><description>My first Japanese class In 1996 I took my first Japanese class at Austin Community College. I was in middle school at the time, and decided to learn how to read Japanese so I could read literature and comics. The class was fun, and also super weird, since I was the only kid there. I took two semesters, but a lot of life happened at once, so I stopped taking Japanese, and didn’t being again until University, five years later.</description></item><item><title>january</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2019-01-24-media-diet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2019-01-24-media-diet/</guid><description>It’s a new year! Time to watch even more shows and movies, and with the rise of bingeable 10 hour TV movies, I have found myself watching fewer of the 90-120 minute variety. With Criteron launching a movie service, maybe that’ll change.
Books The Masked City — Genevieve Cogman
Another romp through alternate worlds with the rebellious librarian Irene, and her Sherlock stand-in pal Vale. The world of this book is largely a strange version of Venice, but more than the first book, other world’s tech is sprinkled throughout.</description></item><item><title>favorite TV shows of 2018</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-01-01-favorite-tv-shows-of-2018/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-01-01-favorite-tv-shows-of-2018/</guid><description>This year I travelled quite a bit—almost 90 hours in the air. When I fly I always have my Kindle, but I usually find myself binge-watching a tv show, and keep my Plex loaded on my iPad with things to see. I watch shows on Netflix and Amazon Prime as well, but the local storage and caching isn’t always dependable for planes, and nothing is more disappointing than getting on a plane and finding out that your shows won’t play.</description></item><item><title>favorite movies of 2018</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-12-31-favorite-movies-of-the-year/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-12-31-favorite-movies-of-the-year/</guid><description>This year started off with one of the goofiest movies I’d see all year: Murder on the Orient Express. I watched it with my friend Magda in Osaka right after the new year, in my “watch bad movies in Japan” tradition. Luckily, I also saw some amazing films:
Hunt for the Wilderpeople
This was the first great movie I saw in 2018—everyone was giving their all, and it was a delight.</description></item><item><title>2018 in Review</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-12-22-year-in-review/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-12-22-year-in-review/</guid><description>Started in Japan Last year, I hopped on a plane to Tokyo before the countdown began, and landed in the evening of the 1st of January. Making my way to my rental apartment in Koenji, the city was quiet as folks celebrated with their family. It was a strange trip. I got to do my hatsumode at Meiji Jingu with thousands of people, and see the Emperor’s second to last speech before his groundbreaking abdication next year.</description></item><item><title>december</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2018-12-20-media-diet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2018-12-20-media-diet/</guid><description>Books Provenance — Ann Leckie
A different planet and culture than the Raadchai from her trilogy, but a very compelling story. I got very confused for a while about who was who, but eventually I sorted it out.
The Dark Archive — Victoria Schwab **
A fun, strange YA book about what happens after death, and the teens who defend the afterlife. There were some cool twists, and story details throughout, but the world building could have been better.</description></item><item><title>my favorite albums of the year</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-12-20-my-favorite-albums-of-the-year/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-12-20-my-favorite-albums-of-the-year/</guid><description>in no particular order On Apple Music
The list Dilly Dally Heaven: I listened to this amazing band’s first album so much in the three years since it came out, and the vocal delivery is raw and beautiful. A true jam.
Ex:Re Ex:Re: A delightfully sad and smart album about lost love, and healing. This was a late-arrival this year, and has already been a constant repeat.
Anna McClellan Yes and No: A similarly raw singing style to Dilly Dally, this is a bummer jam.</description></item><item><title>2018 iPhone Homescreen</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-12-14-2018-iphone-homescreen-update/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-12-14-2018-iphone-homescreen-update/</guid><description>Back to a single screen.
It’s been a year and change since I posted about my iPhone apps and homescreen. I tend to try out new apps pretty often, but now that I use an iPad and an Apple Watch every day, I generally stick with things that support all 3 of my screens well. Some apps have stuck around, but many have been replaced by better (for me) choices.</description></item><item><title>moving to the bay</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-11-21-moving-to-the-bay/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-11-21-moving-to-the-bay/</guid><description>Queers and Steers As a Texan, and a lesbian, I knew eventually I’d end up in California. That’s what we do. We leave Texas, and go west. I’ve spent the past four years hundreds of miles north in Portland, OR working remotely for various companies. I loved the trees, and the few amazing friends I made there, but found it hard to get through the long, lonely winters. It didn’t help that most of my jobs were remote—Portland has a burgeoning tech scene, but in general jobs haven’t kept up with rising cost of living.</description></item><item><title>november</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2018-11-20-media-diet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2018-11-20-media-diet/</guid><description>Books Circe &amp;ndash; Madeline Miller
This book reminded me how much I remember of Greek myth and tragedy. I loved it. Circe is such an excellent protagonist, at the edges of society, ousted from gods and man alike. If you&amp;rsquo;ve read the Odyssey, this is a must read.
Red Clocks &amp;ndash; Leni Zumas
A bit too close to our dystopian reality for my liking, but this was well-written, and full of strong and interesting women.</description></item><item><title>2018 iPad Pro Review</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-11-07-new-ipad-review/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-11-07-new-ipad-review/</guid><description>Today my phone buzzed to tell me my new iPad had arrived at my office. I rushed down to the mailroom, and eagerly ripped open the packaging. For a few years I’ve used an iPad Pro 9.7” as my primary travel computer when I didn’t need to work on Kubernetes/DevOps stuff, and I’ve loved it. Whether I was watching shows on Netflix or Plex that I’d downloaded before a flight, editing my website in Working Copy, or just editing photos and browsing Twitter, this was the machine I wanted to use.</description></item><item><title>october</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2018-10-30-media-diet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2018-10-30-media-diet/</guid><description>Books Sympathy — Olivia Sudjic *
Wow, I loved this book. A story centered around sadness, obsession, and longing—for a family, for a lover, for a place. This was very well-written, and compelling, especially for a first effort. Some of the same Instagram ground is covered in this as is in Ingrid Goes West, but this felt more real. It&amp;rsquo;s also deeply, darkly hilarious, from the description of the awful tech boyfriend, to just how bad families can be for folks.</description></item><item><title>A Review of Invasions by Calvin Gimpelevich</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-10-14-invasions-review/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-10-14-invasions-review/</guid><description>It begins with a rip, the tearing sound of velcro—mix and match nipples kick off this delightfully strange collection of speculative fiction, trans body-horror, and water-logged zombies. Calvin impressed me last year with his part in Meanwhile, Elsewhere, revisited here as the excellent Rent, Don&amp;rsquo;t Sell. This story explores a world in which bodies are traded for a time for fitness or fetish and how trans people deal with this faustian bargain.</description></item><item><title>DSPTCH Waist Bag Review</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-10-04-dsptch-waist-bag/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-10-04-dsptch-waist-bag/</guid><description>Recently, I ordered a medium Sling Pack after deciding I wanted a very small bag to bring with me to meetings or coffee shops where I only needed my iPad and a few other sundries. 11pm is not a great time to make decisions, so I clicked the order button before I checked measurements, and was sad when I realized it didn&amp;rsquo;t actually fit my 9.7&amp;rdquo; iPad. Luckily, I was already flying to San Francisco a week later, and was able to exchange it for the Waist Bag, after trying it on in the store.</description></item><item><title>september</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2018-09-25-media-diet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2018-09-25-media-diet/</guid><description>Books State Tectonics — Malka Older
A fantastic conclusion to the Centenal Cycle Trilogy. I wish I could read a few more books from this universe, which I always figure is a great sign with any speculative fiction series. I keep recommending this trilogy to friends, both as an interesting political system, and as a gripping techno-political thriller with some truly rad female characters. I didn&amp;rsquo;t love every PoV character from State Tectonics as much as I did the previous two books, but that makes sense, as this book was about new beginnings, to a degree.</description></item><item><title>post-xoxo thoughts</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-09-10-xoxo-thoughts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-09-10-xoxo-thoughts/</guid><description>In my previous post, I talked about anticipating XOXO 2018, which ended last night. Today, I am tired, happy, and trying to remember what to do for work when I&amp;rsquo;m not awkwardly wandering around a stadium full of 2000+ people.
So. Many. People. This year I was overwhelmed by the size of XOXO in ways I hadn&amp;rsquo;t been in the past. To be fair, two years ago I was only a year into working from home, whereas now I&amp;rsquo;m 3 years a hermit, but still, 2000 people is a lot.</description></item><item><title>3rd XOXO &amp; 1 Year Later</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-09-05-3rd-xoxo-and-anniversary/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-09-05-3rd-xoxo-and-anniversary/</guid><description>My 3rd XOXO Thinking about the next few days in Portland, I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled beyond measure. So many new and old friends will be in my city, wandering around, making and showing art, and eating tons of food. When I first attended XOXO in 2015 I had no idea what to expect. I&amp;rsquo;d been to SXSW for years, growing-up in Austin, but never before had I felt so surrounded by rad, like-minded people.</description></item><item><title>august</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2018-08-24-media-diet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2018-08-24-media-diet/</guid><description>Books Fingersmith — Sarah Waters
In an odd turn of fate, I&amp;rsquo;d seen the Handmaiden before I read this book, so the English setting was strange compared to the eerie world of Korean director Park Chan-Wook. I knew most of the twists because of the film, but Waters has a deft way with descriptions, and Maud and Sue came alive on the page. It felt like I was reading this for weeks, but that&amp;rsquo;s likely because I devoted little time to reading.</description></item><item><title>smoke gets in your eyes</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-20-smokey-skies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-20-smokey-skies/</guid><description>Due to a series of forest fires, Portland has looked like an alien planet for the past few weeks.
Every day I wake up and google &amp;ldquo;air quality&amp;rdquo; to see just how much I need to stay indoors, next to my air filter. My gym has closed for a few days for two weeks, and walking outside just plain sucks.
The only cool part is the sunsets are ridiculous, and the moon is red at night.</description></item><item><title>powerlifting</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-14-powerlifting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-14-powerlifting/</guid><description>Young Brook Growing up, I never wanted to be big. My parents were both over 6&amp;rsquo; tall, and I worried about being as big as them. Most of my friends ended up being shorter than me, and were usually skinnier too. I was made fun of for being &amp;ldquo;chubby&amp;rdquo; in middle school, and that stuck with me. Being fat or chubby or skinny all rule, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t know that as a kid.</description></item><item><title>two concerts</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-13-august-shows/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-13-august-shows/</guid><description>A few years ago, after moving to Portland, I discovered a secret: you can do almost anything alone. I&amp;rsquo;d lived in Austin for most of my life, and as I quickly learned once moving, making friends in Portland is a long process. So, on a whim, I started seeing movies by myself. I went to dinner alone with a book. I even saw concerts&amp;hellip; solo, and it was fun. I don&amp;rsquo;t know why we all think you have to do these activities with other people, but when you go alone you don&amp;rsquo;t have to wait for anyone to be ready to go, or to leave.</description></item><item><title>the old is new again</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-11-posting-on-my-blog/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-11-posting-on-my-blog/</guid><description>Inspired by both Nick and Matt, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to try my hand at blogging again on this site. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how often I&amp;rsquo;ll post, but at least once a month, I&amp;rsquo;ll do a media diet post, which clips out what I read and watched that month from the long lists I keep. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about other stuff too. We&amp;rsquo;ll see!
I have definitely enjoyed how Matt seems to be posting cool things there instead of Twitter, because it gives me more things to see on RSS.</description></item><item><title>july</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2018-07-24-media-diet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2018-07-24-media-diet/</guid><description>Books Adventure Zone: There Be Gerblins
A masterful adaptation of the podcast D&amp;amp;D romp into a graphic novel. I absolutely loved this. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if this would be as fun if you hadn&amp;rsquo;t listened to the podcast, but if you haven&amp;rsquo;t, get on it&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s free and it&amp;rsquo;s delightful.
La Bastarda — Trifonia Melibea Obono *
A lesbian novel from Equatorial Guinea that tells a short story of a woman abandoned by her father, and orphaned by her mother who finds herself falling for another woman.</description></item><item><title>june</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2018-06-24-media-diet/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2018-06-24-media-diet/</guid><description>Books Swearing Off Stars — Danielle Wong
Started off alright, but quickly telegraphed to an all-to-common &amp;ldquo;I can&amp;rsquo;t really be with you until it&amp;rsquo;s too late&amp;rdquo; lesbian novel. I also kept thinking an editor had asked her to just add tons of adjectives, willy-nilly. It was an odd read, and the time-jumps didn&amp;rsquo;t help. If you can write a lesbian romance in 2017, why would you lean so hard on tropes of one woman dying?</description></item><item><title>may</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2018-05-24-media-diet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2018-05-24-media-diet/</guid><description>Books Lab Rat One — Andrea Höst
Ok, this series is exceedingly straight, and that&amp;rsquo;s a bummer. I wish there was a lot less pining after the sad boy, but the magic and tech continues to be interesting. The pacing is a little lax, and I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten slightly sick of the cycles of &amp;ldquo;power then injury&amp;rdquo; that Cass goes through, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to finish this out.
Caszandra — Andrea Höst</description></item><item><title>Invisible One Mini backpack review</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-05-17-review-invisible-one-mini/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-05-17-review-invisible-one-mini/</guid><description>Bags are my thing. Well, bags and shoes. Traveling as much as I do, having a dependable, comfortable, and sleek bag is pretty important. For the past two or so years, I&amp;rsquo;ve depended on my Topo Designs Trip Pack for short trips, and then nested it inside of my Ryu QuickPack for longer trips abroad. This has worked out well, but walking around Copenhagen, and going through a variety of international airport security, I wondered if I could consolidate to one bag, with an easier way to access my laptop and other stuff.</description></item><item><title>april</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2018-04-17-media-diet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/mediadiet/2018-04-17-media-diet/</guid><description>Books All Systems Red — Martha Wells
Pretty fun book about a &amp;ldquo;murderbot&amp;rdquo; who would rather be watching tv dramas than shooting anything. I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to the next few books.
Stray — Andrea Höst
This was recommended to me by my buddy Nick, and I&amp;rsquo;d avoided it for unknown reasons. Maybe the cover was too low-budget? But, this book is really fun. I think this series kinda qualifies as YA, but the journal nature, as well as the mystery of scifi tech/magic systems got me deep into the world.</description></item><item><title>A review of the Merry Spinster</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-03-13-merry-spinster-review/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-03-13-merry-spinster-review/</guid><description>“Daughters are as good a thing as any…” begins The Merry Spinster by Danny Ortberg’s wild reimagining of the Little Mermaid that ends in such grim fashion as to make the reader nod solemnly and intone, “truly, these are the end of times.” And yet, what a romp of a dark timeline. Unlike Texts from Jane Eyre, his first book of imagined text conversations from literary characters, this reader at least felt prepared for these fables, stories, and tall-tales through study of European folklore.</description></item><item><title>sister spit</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2016-04-16-sister-spit-piece-pre-cunt-up/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2016-04-16-sister-spit-piece-pre-cunt-up/</guid><description>Note: This was a cunt-up piece, so it was delivered in chunks, read out of a hat, interspersed with Cooper Lee Bombardier’s piece about the same time period/culture. As such, it’s a little disjointed. Enjoy~
A time and a place I wasn’t part of, but read about eagerly. The drugs, the fucking, and the sisterhood that I dreamed of from my bed in Texas. I wouldn’t have been accepted, I know, because of who I am.</description></item><item><title>no cis men</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2016-04-15-no-cis-men/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2016-04-15-no-cis-men/</guid><description>no cis men, says the sign on the door and i read, prove yourself are you woman enough to enter this building not woman like dresses but woman like a body you didn’t get for free the feeling that these spaces want to spit us out like we won’t be safe from the pain of judgement because it follows us in and comes out through their eyes
do you see me?</description></item><item><title>pack light and still enjoy the trip</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2016-04-14-pack-light-and-still-enjoy-the-trip/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2016-04-14-pack-light-and-still-enjoy-the-trip/</guid><description>Why I choose to travel with a 16L bag everywhere I go.
The Past Years ago, I stopped checking bags when I flew. I’d seen too many things get lost over the years, my own and other’s, and couldn’t stomach the thought of landing somewhere again, only to lose all my possessions. So, I began using a canvas duffel bag, as well as a small backpack.
The bag is grey, and around 30L in volume, has little toggle closures, and a couple internal pockets.</description></item><item><title>my year-end review of 2015</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-12-19-my-year-end-review-of-2015/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-12-19-my-year-end-review-of-2015/</guid><description>Marginally better! 2015: it sounds like we’re really moving
Score 2015/?</description></item><item><title>NYC</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-11-9-nyc-my-second-home/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-11-9-nyc-my-second-home/</guid><description>New York is my home for two months out of the year, but I only recently became acquainted with it. Growing up in Texas, I got the idea from my dad that NYC was some kind of devil city. He regarded it as a liberal place with people who walked too fast, and were too greedy. The first time I visited in my mid-twenties, I realized just how wrong he was.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts on Grace Hopper Conference</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-10-19-thoughts-on-grace-hopper/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-10-19-thoughts-on-grace-hopper/</guid><description>Arrival
“This conference is GIGANTIC!” was my first thought upon arriving at Grace Hopper. This year’s attendance was around 10,000 folks, mostly women, and the largest conference besides SXSW that I’ve attended. Like many tech conferences, GHC had an invaluable app that showed a stream of comments from attendees as well as a schedule and other information. Once I signed in, I spent a lot of time networking and finding folks from out of town as my chosen track “Open-Source” was largely bereft of personally relevant content.</description></item><item><title>LWT NYC Summit</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-10-05-lesbians-who-tech-nyc-summit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-10-05-lesbians-who-tech-nyc-summit/</guid><description>Due to stress, the talk I am about to give usually overshadows the talks before mine. Fortunately, LWT was such a jam-packed speaker event that I was able to tune into the talks and not get eaten by nerves. There were a neat mix of 5 minute ignite talks about things like tackling systemic oppression, government tech work, and imposter syndrome. Some of these talks were similar to others I’ve heard, and the audience was so different than what I usually experience at a conference that I was a little sad we didn’t get past some of the 101 talks.</description></item><item><title>xoxo 2015</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-09-14-xoxo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-09-14-xoxo/</guid><description>XOXO Fest recap
This is my first XOXO, and as with many festivals or conferences where I know I might be overwhelmed, I was a little apprehensive. It helped so much that we had Slack setup for XOXO months in advance. I met tons of rad people in and around the tech industry while I was online, and then when the XOXO started, I was prepared with a group of new and old friends.</description></item><item><title>on being alone</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2014-3-4-on-being-alone/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2014-3-4-on-being-alone/</guid><description>A bit about this last few months.
It first hit me the night she left. The quiet. Before, there was rustling in the house, subtle signs of her presence, affection in the same space. Now, the night was too quiet, her form did not move with breath next to me. I was alone. My cats tried to fill the void. The wandered, and meowed, and looked for her in closets and cabinets — or so it seemed to me, as I projected my sadness onto them.</description></item><item><title>The Allure of the Minimal and Disconnected</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2013-04-26-the-allure-of-the-minimal-and-disconnected/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2013-04-26-the-allure-of-the-minimal-and-disconnected/</guid><description>The Future Most films that show our future are full of glitz and glamour, a fantastical land of flying vehicles. People live in clean, modern homes, and have their lives radically improved through technology, and want for nothing. Families and workers seamlessly keep in touch, and share parts of their lives with their friends and companions, and generally embrace the technology all around them.
If there is any enemy or ill feeling in the protagonist, it is usually an overlord or corporation that is taking over or slowly consuming their society.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/tv/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/tv/</guid><description> tv list years: 2018 2019
2019 Tidying Up with Marie Kondo Chef &amp;amp; My Fridge Counterpart Doctor Who Into the Dark Dirk Gently Terror in Resonance The Gifted Ugly Delicious Boogiepop Phantom Dororo RerideD: Derrida who leaps through time My Roommate is a Cat Steven Universe Modern Family CANAAN Friends from College Ghost in the Shell SAC Steins; Gate 0 Brooklyn 99 Marvelous Mrs. Maisel Travellers Magicians The Grand Tour The Good Place Sex Education Continuum Dororo Skull-faced Bookseller Honda San Terrace House Patriot Act Russian Doll Umbrella Academy Top Gear Kyousougiga Dennou Coil Desus &amp;amp; Mero Hot Ones Pen15 King of the Hill Difficult People Gravity Falls Billions F1: Drive to Survive The OA Hanna Homecoming What We Do in the Shadows Barry Fleabag Kanata no Astra Arukawa Under the Bridge Carole &amp;amp; Tuesday Keiji Yugami Gundam: Iron Blooded Orphans Succession The Team Mindhunger Shangri-la O Maidens in Your Savage Season Nichijou Dark Patriot Another Period Archer Flowers Great British Bake-off &amp;amp; Bake-Off Professionals Nathan for You Summer Camp Island Moominvalley True Blood 2018 Brooklyn 99 Terrace House: Next Door, New Doors, and Aloha State Dennou Coil Grand Tour Atelier Devil May Crybaby Good Place Magicians The Tunnel The Bridge Girl’s Last Tour Kemono Friends Kokkoku Darling in the Franxx Letterkenny Altered Carbon Counterpart B: The Beginning a place farther than the universe Veep Babylon Berlin Friends from College Chef &amp;amp; My Fridge Wild Wild Country Playground The Americans Adventure Time Bob’s Burgers Steven Universe Gravity Falls Killing Eve Atlanta Baskets The Rain Forbrydelsen The Dark Parts Unknown Worth It FLCL Making It Wrecked The League Burning Love Billions Sharp Objects Innocents The Chris Gethard Show Jack Ryan Hang-ups Midnight Sun Maniac Double-Decker Documental Zombieland Saga Origin Patriot Sabrina (Netflix) Svartsjön Travel Man King of the Hill Nightflyers Patriot Act Jordskott Runaways Bandersnatch</description></item><item><title>about</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/about/</guid><description>brook is a noted sapphist who lives in a forest with her cat snorri. she loves travel, food, and satan.</description></item><item><title>book list</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/books/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/books/</guid><description>years: 2016 2017 2018 2019 2020
2020 12 books A Song for a New Day — Sarah Pinsker
Welp, my second book for the month was another plague book, albeit one that largely took place in the aftermath of a pox. I enjoyed this book quite a bit, even if it was a little too hopeful for my usual taste. Honestly, it was a little refreshing to read a book where cool women make music and care about each other, and hope for the future.</description></item><item><title>movie list</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/movies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/movies/</guid><description>years: 2016 2017 2018 2019 2020
2020 Quantum of Solace
Far less memorable than Casino Royale. The first chase was fun, but a lot of the rest of the film kinda just meanders. I do appreciate the little nods towards older James Bond films though.
Casino Royale
Rewatching this in preparation for the eventual release of the final Daniel Craig bond film. It holds pretty well, save for the hilariously old-looking Sony phones and bootcut khakis.</description></item><item><title>writing</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/writing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/writing/</guid><description>online Ninth Letter
Trans New Wave
Oregon Humanities
Also Fire
The Toast
Queer Spaces
Dating as a Trans Woman
Transmisogyny &amp;amp; Disc Golf Roundtable
Trans in Tech
Uses This
Uses This Interview
Medium
All posts
Little Red Tarot
Tarot as Agency
books F, M, or Other: Quarrels with the Gender Binary
Transfigure
Lean Out
podcasts I Guess We&amp;rsquo;re Grownups Now
Dear Prudence: Sept 12, 2018
Dear Prudence: Nov 2, 2016</description></item></channel></rss>