<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>iPhone on dill &amp; fennel</title>
    <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/iphone/</link>
    <description>Recent content in iPhone on dill &amp; fennel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Copyright Brook Shelley 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 06:34:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/iphone/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2020 Homescreen</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-09-26-2020-homescreen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 06:34:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-09-26-2020-homescreen/</guid>
      <description>2020 Homescreen This year was mostly a nightmare for all the gestures around reasons.
However, for my 2020 homescreen on my iPad and iPhone, it was pretty wild.</description>
      <content:encoded><h1 id="2020-homescreen">2020 Homescreen</h1>
<p>This year was mostly a nightmare for all the <em>gestures around</em> reasons.</p>
<p>However, for my 2020 homescreen on my iPad and iPhone, it was pretty wild. iOS 14 brought the concept of homescreen widgets to iOS after years of waiting, and they&rsquo;re pretty damn good.
<img src="/photos/ioshome2020.jpg" alt=""></p>
<h2 id="another-year">Another year</h2>
<p>Every year for the <a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-28-2019-iphone-homescreen/">past</a> few <a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-12-14-2018-iphone-homescreen-update/">years</a> I’ve written about the apps I’m using and what appears on my iPhone Home Screen. It’s become a fun annual post to think through how the app ecosystem and iOS in general changed over the year. I still use my iPhone quite a bit in quarantine, as it remains the easiest thing to haul around my house for podcast control and random tasks.</p>
<h2 id="more-change">More change</h2>
<p><strong>3 app dock</strong></p>
<p>I kept my 3 app dock from <a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-28-2019-iphone-homescreen/">last year</a>, but replaced Music with Slack. I use Slack pretty constantly for keeping in touch with my friends, and also I work there. Lately, in order to encourage myself to <em>log off</em> from work on my off-hours, I removed my work workspaces from my phone. It’s delightful.</p>
<p>The other two apps are the same—Messages and Reeder. Both of these apps are a lifeline to loved-ones and reading respectively. I subscribed to a few friends’ Twitter feeds and a few newsletters in Reeder using Feedbin, and it’s quieter and <a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-02-10-slower-reading/">slower over there</a>.</p>
<p><strong>No new app icons</strong></p>
<p>An astute reader will see the five app icons on my homescreen and think: “wow, you’ve gotten rid of everything!” And indeed I have! iOS 14 brought the delightful App Library which enabled hiding most apps from the homescreen, relegating them to search and odd Apple-generated categories. I likely have a few <em>more</em> apps on my phone than before, but I never see them unless I need them. I love it.</p>
<p>Overcast keeps getting better, especially with Marco focusing on stability and usability over rushing to get iOS 14 widgets or other whiz bang new things into the app. I like that Marco seems to get that so many of us depend on this app daily, and takes major changes seriously.</p>
<p>iAWriter is where I write. Full stop. I wrote this post in iAWriter, and even wrote about <a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/hugo-and-i-a-writer/"><em>how I write in it</em></a>. It’s outstanding. I would happily pay much more money just to keep this app going. A+.</p>
<h2 id="widgets">Widgets!</h2>
<p>The elephant on my homescreen is the two prominent widgets at the top of the device. With the addition of regularly updating, informative blocks of app, I move my calendar and my music player into this format.</p>
<p>Fantastical is back! The widgets are great, and even though I can’t make it the <em>default app</em> in iOS this year—maybe next year? I think Fantastical still looks kinda weird on the iPad, but since I can view a smaller bit of it actively in a widget, I don’t need to open the full app nearly as often. The customization of the Fantastical widget is delightful, as <a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2020/09/23/fantastical-widgets-ios-14">others have written</a>.</p>
<p>Longplay is a new app this year that focuses on reminding the listener about older, neglected albums in our collection. I think the way it changes around album art is cool looking, and I especially love that it focuses on the <em>album</em> as a coherent whole, unlike many modern music apps that are more geared towards singles and bangers.</p>
<p>On my left screen&hellip; formerly the widget area (is this the name?) lives one app that was previously on my homescreen and another I went back to after an update.
<img src="/photos/iOS14widgets.jpg" alt="">
Things remains the way I get anything done in my life. I love it so much on iPhone, iPad, and Mac. The sync is fantastic, the organization is just-enough, and the keyboard shortcuts are a master class in how to do them right.</p>
<p>Carrot Weather temporarily dethroned Hello Weather due to the addition of widgets. I still don’t love this app or how it displays data, but the widgets are delightfully minimal so I don’t need to look at the whole app often.</p>
<p>Simple is my banking app. It’s important to always have “funny numbers” in your account as a key to appeasing the money demons that ensure a positive ROI. Top tip.</p>
<h2 id="other-notable-apps">Other notable apps</h2>
<p>Working Copy and Secure Shellfish aren’t on my homescreen, but they’re both pretty crucial to a few kinds of server and front-end work that I do for fun on the iPad and iPhone.</p>
<p>Darkroom is the photo editor I moved to after some recent updates made it even better. I still wish it could resize photos on export, instead of just changing the quality of the photo or video, but hopefully later they’ll be able to. In the meantime, I made an iOS shortcut that does the resizing for me, and commits the photo to my blog’s repo.</p>
<h2 id="missing-widgets">Missing widgets</h2>
<p>One day soon, I hope my bank adds a widget, as well as Wealthfront, and perhaps Overcast and Sonos. Tot would also be an excellent widget for quick text entry. I don’t know if I’d keep it up all the time, but my Deliveries app also primarily functions as a read-only list, so it would be ideal for a side-screen widget.</p>
<h2 id="future-hopes">Future hopes</h2>
<p>I’m curious as more developers add widgets if their interest in adding more options for sizing and location. I think it’d be neat to have a single app icon widget, as well as write-capable widgets. Perhaps we’ll see this customization in iOS 15. I think now that the floodgates are open for what TikTok youth are seeing as custom themes, it’ll be hard to stem the tide of interest in actual shareable themes a-la Apple Watch. Further, I think it’d be pretty silly if iOS widgets and Apple Watch widgets didn’t end-up unifying in the future.</p>
<p>Ultimately, I’m super glad I don’t need to keep a ton of apps on my homescreen, and instead can show the apps I use most.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 iOS Homescreen</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-28-2019-iphone-homescreen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-28-2019-iphone-homescreen/</guid>
      <description>Another year has rushed past, and with it, another iPhone update and some changes to my phone since last year&amp;rsquo;s setup.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>Another year has rushed past, and with it, another iPhone update and some changes to my phone since <a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/blog/2018/12/14/2018-iphone-homescreen-update.html">last year&rsquo;s setup</a>. My use of a single screen of apps continues, with a few major and minor changes alongside.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/2019iphone.jpg" alt="2019 iPhone Screen"></p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve posted these for the past few years, so if you want to see what apps I was using in <a href="https://medium.com/@brookshelley/2017-homescreen-ac92817eae60">2017, here you go</a>.</p>
<h2 id="some-things-change">Some things change</h2>
<p><strong>3 app dock</strong>—I moved my Twitter app out of my dock in order to spend less time on Twitter. I figured if I wanted to to launch it I could easily search for it, but perhaps by having it out of reach I wouldn&rsquo;t launch the app out of habit or boredom. This worked pretty well.</p>
<p><strong>Fantastical</strong>—Last year I said &ldquo;This is definitely the app I am most interested in replacing.&rdquo; I replaced it with <strong>iOS Calendar</strong> not too long after writing this post because of the cleaner look, date view icon, and a better visualization of my next meeting on my phone and watch. I also really hate how Fantastical uses space on the iPad. I still hope that someday Apple opens up the ability to change icons based on events or time, but until they do, I&rsquo;ll have a hard time moving away from the default calendar.</p>
<p><strong>Bear</strong>—I moved completely off of Bear in favor of <strong>iAWriter</strong>, largely due to <a href="https://workingcopy.app">Working Copy</a>, which is an excellent Git client for iOS devices, and means I can use iAWriter&rsquo;s file function to open up posts like this one that live in my personal blog&rsquo;s Drafts folder.</p>
<p><strong>Google Maps</strong>—I moved back to <strong>Apple Maps</strong>. In general Apple Maps got a lot better, and works better on my watch. Also, in Japan, Apple Maps often shows results from TabeLog, which tends to have much better local recommendations.</p>
<p><strong>Tweetbot</strong>—I replaced this with the weird beta Twitter app <strong>twttr</strong>. It&rsquo;s hidden in a folder now to encourage me to not use it as often, and that is working pretty well.</p>
<p><strong>Fiery Feeds</strong>—<em><strong>Reeder 4</strong> came out</em> and it&rsquo;s amazing. I moved to Reeder 4 on all of my devices, and I love it. The read later feature has also replaced Safari&rsquo;s read later for me in all instances. I don&rsquo;t use Bionic reading, but it&rsquo;s a neat feature regardless. I continue to use <a href="https://feedbin.com">Feedbin</a> to back my RSS.</p>
<h2 id="some-things-stay-the-same">Some things stay the same</h2>
<p><strong>Overcast</strong> — Overcast is great. This year it just got better, from CarPlay, to the watch, to my phone. I am really excited for Marco to update for more Airplay 2 features as he mentioned in a recent episode of <a href="https://atp.fm/episodes/352">ATP</a>. There are other podcast apps out there, but for smart-speed, playlists, and everything else, there is only Overcast.</p>
<p><strong>Spark</strong>—I kept using Spark this year, especially as they updated for a great black-screened-OLED-friendly dark mode, and <a href="https://sparkmailapp.com/blog/new-design-dark-mode-ios13">rethought their entire interface in 2.5</a>. This is a great email app on all my devices, and has fantastic keyboard support for iPadOS.</p>
<p><strong>Apple Music</strong>—I&rsquo;ve barely opened Spotify all year. Apple Music keeps getting better, and it seems like more of my friends have moved over to it as well.</p>
<p><strong>Things</strong>—This app is how I keep track of all my work and personal tasks. It&rsquo;s incredible. Keyboard shortcuts are available on iOS and Mac, and in general this app is a great example of how a cross-platform app should function.</p>
<p><strong>Apple Photos</strong>—This app got a lot better in iOS 13, and I really enjoy it. Not much else to say.</p>
<p><strong>Slack</strong>—I work at Slack still, and it&rsquo;s still a great app.</p>
<p><strong>Single folder</strong>—65 extra apps live in this folder. They range from rarely-used travel apps for work, to translation apps, to video and banking apps. I don&rsquo;t <em>love</em> all of the apps in this folder, but I regularly go through them to make sure they&rsquo;re still needed.</p>
<h2 id="the-best-of-the-rest">The best of the rest</h2>
<p>A few of the apps that live inside my large catch-all folder and are opened via search.</p>
<p><strong>Working Copy</strong>—This app is amazing. In addition to functioning as a great Git tool, it also has syntax and code-highlighting for tons of languages. I don&rsquo;t work in Working Copy all the time, but when I&rsquo;m iPad-only, I use it quite a bit for work and my personal projects.</p>
<p><strong>Google Fi</strong>—I moved to Google Fi last year from AT&amp;T largely due to the free and easy international roaming. It&rsquo;s great.</p>
<p><strong>Tsurukame</strong>—This is my daily second job. I spend around two hours a day in this app and reading in order to become fully literate in Japanese. As I write this, I&rsquo;m at level 39, and have over 1300 Kanji above Guru level. Learning Japanese is super hard, but worth it.</p>
<p><strong>Plex</strong>—Lots of video sources live here. It&rsquo;s a great app, and I wish other video streaming services would learn from Plex&rsquo;s great example.</p>
<p><strong>1Password</strong>—All my passwords live here, and are super long and complex. Similar to Things, I don&rsquo;t think I could work the same way without 1Password.</p>
<h2 id="wrap-up">Wrap-up</h2>
<p>Last year I suggested my list of apps might not shift much, but five of my major home screen apps changed due to updates and simplicity. I&rsquo;m happy this year with the apps that I use and due to my requirements of quality Apple Watch, Mac, and iPadOS cross-platform functionality the bar is really high for other apps to knock these off of my phone. I&rsquo;m very excited about iOS 14, especially with news that it might be more stable than the particularly rough iOS 13 release. Perhaps Apple will give more features to devs that unlock unimagined new functionality. We&rsquo;ll find out in 6 months.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On notes and todos</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-05-02-on-notes-and-todos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-05-02-on-notes-and-todos/</guid>
      <description>The latest episode of Supercomputer inspired me to write about how I work with notes, todos, and reminders every day. Part of the episode was centered on their mutual dissatisfaction with various notes apps, which I totally understand.</description>
      <content:encoded><p><img src="/photos/iAWriter.jpg" alt="iawriter"></p>
<p>The <a href="https://supercomputer.transistor.fm/#">latest episode of Supercomputer</a> inspired me to write about how I work with notes, todos, and reminders every day. Part of the episode was centered on their mutual dissatisfaction with various notes apps, which I totally understand. Over the years, I&rsquo;ve used <a href="https://brettterpstra.com/projects/nvalt/">NVAlt</a>, 1Writer, Bear, Evernote, Notes, and more to keep track of my thoughts, posts, and notes. Brett Terpstra keeps a <a href="https://brettterpstra.com/ios-text-editors/"><em>very good list</em></a> of all iOS text editors that includes information about their cross-platform functionality. These days, since I mostly use my iPad and iPhone when I&rsquo;m not at <a href="https://slack.com/">work</a>, it&rsquo;s vital that my notes and todo apps live happily on Mac, and iOS.</p>
<h2 id="notes-and-posts">Notes and posts</h2>
<p>Ever since I moved most of my personal computer work to an <a href="http://www.brookshelley.com/blog/2018/11/07/new-ipad-review.html">iPad Pro</a>, I&rsquo;ve wanted to make sure my notes and writing were easily accessible from wherever I happened to compute. I also wanted to post that writing to my <a href="https://www.brookshelley.com">blog</a> which hilariously I first talked about on my now abandoned <a href="https://medium.com/@brookshelley/why-i-built-a-markdown-book-blog-a07e1a6dd163">Medium</a>. Since I post things via Github pages, which is a near-as-makes-no-difference Jekyll instance, I need the ability to push markdown to Github. With <a href="https://workingcopyapp.com/">Working Copy</a>, this is super simple, and if I need to, I can write entire posts in the pretty nice editor that app contains. But, I want more!</p>
<p>To have a great writing experience, with delightful fonts, a pleasing design, and speedy sync, I use <a href="https://ia.net/writer">iAWriter</a>. It&rsquo;s <em>fantastic</em> for notes, long form writing, and even markdown previewing work docs. In the years since the first version of iAWriter launched, it&rsquo;s become an amazing piece of software. I couldn&rsquo;t find the earliest versions, but <a href="https://www.macworld.com/article/2985482/ia-writer-3-0-1-review-mac-app-gets-back-to-basics-for-focused-writing.html">here&rsquo;s the 2015 version 3</a>. Nowadays, iAWriter can talk to the Files app on iOS natively, which means you can open files from Working Copy, which is registered as a Files location, so you can open files from Github repos in iAWriter. Whether I&rsquo;m drafting a blog post, or updating my list of <a href="http://www.brookshelley.com/books">books</a> that I&rsquo;ve read, I open iAWriter first, after pulling the latest version of my repo in Working Copy. For writing and notes I don&rsquo;t plan to store in my repo, iAWriter keeps them on iCloud as <code>.md</code> files so I don&rsquo;t have to worry about portability or missing files. Because these files live in iCloud, they&rsquo;re searchable using Spotlight on both my iOS and Mac devices—no more depending on launching an app to search. It&rsquo;s wild how good this app combination is, and how fast I&rsquo;m able to find and edit things using iAWriter&rsquo;s native Apple integrations.</p>
<p>When I&rsquo;m at meetings at work, I also tend to take notes with a <a href="https://www.lamy.com/en/lamy-safari/">pen</a> and a <a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2019/all_about/weeks/">notebook</a> because it <a href="https://www.npr.org/2016/04/17/474525392/attention-students-put-your-laptops-away">helps retention</a> and looks quite a bit less rude to my coworkers or partners. If something needs to be shared, I type it up in Slack or put it in a Readme on a repo.</p>
<p>But what about my todos?!</p>
<h2 id="todos">Todos</h2>
<p>I work at a company in San Francisco who&rsquo;s goal is to &ldquo;make work life simpler, more pleasant and more productive.&rdquo; I think we&rsquo;re good at it, but I&rsquo;ve found that I need a separate place to keep track of my work tasks, my life tasks, and all the random junk I need quick access to when I&rsquo;m going through my week. <a href="https://culturedcode.com/things/">Things</a> is that app for me. I made a Project for everything I work on, and Areas for things like &ldquo;stuff to buy&rdquo; or &ldquo;stuff to watch&rdquo;.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/projects.png" alt="projects"></p>
<p>My main view is Today, where tasks I need to finish by bedtime live. When the workday ends, anything I haven&rsquo;t accomplished gets moved to tomorrow—this is a conscious choice over having those tasks follow me home. That means that I don&rsquo;t have the psychic dread of &ldquo;more work&rdquo;, but can still look at Things for things like the code to my therapist&rsquo;s office, or a reminder to scoop the cat litter. I love it. Things is the perfect example of just heavy enough feature-wise to handle power-users while only exposing simple features for everyone else. The search is amazing, especially on Mac, where all you need to do is <em>start typing</em>. Sure, there&rsquo;s no location-based reminders, but honestly at a certain point, <em>in my opinion</em> you&rsquo;re just faffing around and avoiding work by adding so many layers to your todo process. Get shit done instead of doing loads of metalwork.</p>
<h2 id="keeping-track-of-all-of-the-things">Keeping track of all of the things</h2>
<p>For me, writing and notes goes in iAWriter, and anything I need to <em>do</em> goes into Things. Sometimes my tasks include a link to a relevant Slack conversation, or email in Spark, or website—and other times it&rsquo;s just a note to take some medicine or drop mail off in the mailbox. My projects groupings mean I know historically what I&rsquo;ve accomplished in various areas or work things, and I don&rsquo;t stress too much planning months in the future. Planning, at least at work, is often a team effort, and there&rsquo;s a calendar or a roadmap that I don&rsquo;t need to duplicate in Things. I note what my responsibilities are, and set due dates or targets for those, and leave the rest to where my work actually lives—Slack. If you want to dive more into GTD or w/e, I recommend <a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20190401160435/http://www.43folders.com/2004/09/08/getting-started-with-getting-things-done">43 Folders</a>, which is possibly now disavowed by Merlin, but is still a very smart look at productivity. Generally, simple systems work well for me, and if I look at something, I should either store it, trash it, or use it.</p>
<p>My systems are super helpful for <em>me</em>, but might not work, or work differently for you. That&rsquo;s totally ok! Hopefully something here was helpful or interesting, and if not, feel free to browse away, and forget~ Work will always be here for you, like a strange nightmare, and how you choose to tackle it is a personal decision.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 iPhone Homescreen</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-12-14-2018-iphone-homescreen-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-12-14-2018-iphone-homescreen-update/</guid>
      <description>Back to a single screen.
It’s been a year and change since I posted about my iPhone apps and homescreen. I tend to try out new apps pretty often, but now that I use an iPad and an Apple Watch every day, I generally stick with things that support all 3 of my screens well.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>Back to a single screen.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/iphone2018.jpeg" alt="iphone"></p>
<p>It’s been a year and change since I posted about my <a href="https://medium.com/@brookshelley/2017-homescreen-ac92817eae60">iPhone apps and homescreen</a>. I tend to try out new apps pretty often, but now that I use an iPad and an Apple Watch every day, I generally stick with things that support all 3 of my screens well. Some apps have stuck around, but many have been replaced by better (for me) choices. Trying to settle into apps that I use for a long stretch is challenging as businesses fail, or apps stagnate, so here we are.</p>
<h2 id="old-apps">Old apps</h2>
<p><strong>Timepage</strong>—without support for the new style of WatchOS complications, I switched to Fantastical again. I don’t <em>love</em> it, but I want to use the same app in both places.</p>
<p><strong>Casts</strong>—replaced with <strong>Overcast</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>Maps</strong>—replaced with <strong>Google Maps</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>Airmail</strong>—replaced with <strong>Spark</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>Twitter</strong>—replaced with <strong>Tweetbot</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>Spotify</strong>—replaced with <strong>Apple Music</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>Instagram</strong>—I quit Instagram around the start of 2018 in a dual-effort to rid myself of FB-owned apps, and to stop using an increasingly user-antagonistic app that really bummed me out more than it made me happy.</p>
<p><strong>Todoist</strong>—replaced with <strong>Things</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>Google Photos</strong>—replaced with <strong>Apple Photos</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>iCloud Drive</strong>—this became <strong>Files</strong>.</p>
<p><strong>Tons of folders</strong>—this felt overwhelming, and eventually I decided against it, and went back to titles instead of emoji, and now whittled my apps down to a single folder.</p>
<h2 id="new-apps">New apps</h2>
<p><strong>Fantastical</strong>—this is an <em>ok</em> calendaring app. I don&rsquo;t love the visual style, or the colors, but compared to my other options this is what I have available. Timepage doesn&rsquo;t have new watch complications. Google Calendar doesn&rsquo;t even have a watch app. iOS Calendar is ok, but doesn&rsquo;t do NLP well, or handle meetings/etc well. This is definitely the app I am most interested in replacing.</p>
<p><strong>Fiery Feeds</strong>—Reeder 4 is perpetually <em>coming soon</em>, so my allegiance to it is on pause until the 4th iteration brings support for my new iPad, and other nice things like full-text display. Fiery Feeds, despite an icon that I vaguely loathe, is a great app with a solid dark mode, and a bunch of cool options. It&rsquo;s very customizable, and can adapt a bit to your style of RSS. I wish it had a Mac app, but AFAIK the only great RSS reader that works everywhere is Reeder.</p>
<p><strong>Spark</strong>—I don&rsquo;t use email as often anymore now that I work at a company that doesn&rsquo;t use email (we really don&rsquo;t). But, when I do, Spark is great. Solid watch app. Solid Mac and iPad support, including keyboard shortcuts. I still hope for iOS dark mode support in the future, because on Mac the style is awesome. The calendar in this app is <em>almost</em> good enough to have me ditch my actual calendar, but unfortunately there&rsquo;s no way for Spark to show its calendar on my watch.</p>
<p><strong>Tweetbot</strong>—<a href="http://apps-of-a-feather.com">RIP third-party Twitter apps</a>. I use this app in defiance of Twitter&rsquo;s bad policy, and honestly the lack of likes and notifications is kind of a feature for me at this point. DMs are vaguely useless, but most of those conversations have moved to my favorite place to chat: Slack.</p>
<p><strong>Google Maps</strong>—I used Apple Maps pretty happily for a while, but eventually I wanted more recommendations and ratings, and I refuse to use Yelp for that. If Apple Maps connected to Foursquare, or supported commute scheduling, I&rsquo;d be back in a heartbeat. Also somehow Google Maps understands that SF trans-bay busses pick up at a temporary terminal, and Apple things they don&rsquo;t exist because the Salesforce garden of hubris is closed.</p>
<p><strong>Things</strong>—I love Things. Years ago when I worked for a certain fruit company, many of my coworkers used Things. I didn&rsquo;t really get it at the time, but also I didn&rsquo;t really get having things _to do_. Things helps me be an adult, and get things done. I run my life out of here, largely, and dump anything from chores to tv show recommendations in here. The new iOS dark mode support is spectacular. Similarly to Spark, the support of a calendar is <em>almost</em> good enough to not use a calendar app, but alas, the watch problem persists. Also the calendar is read-only, which could create an issue.</p>
<p><strong>Apple Music</strong>—I moved over from Spotify, mostly to try it out, and to have access to my music on my watch. It&rsquo;s fine? I don&rsquo;t really know if I prefer this app to Spotify, but it does what I want, plays the music I want to play, and works well on my Sonos and in my car. Recommendations have gotten better, and while I wish it did a better job of knowing which bands I like have new albums, I usually find out. Concert notifications would also be cool, if I were making a feature request. Oh, and also dark mode. Please.</p>
<h2 id="the-best-of-the-rest">The best of the rest</h2>
<p><strong>Slack</strong>—My love for the Slack app is strong. My friends live here. My chosen family lives here. My work lives here. I don&rsquo;t know what I would do without Slack. Before I worked for Slack, my company depended on Slack for everything from deploys, to bugs, to developer relations. Now that I work here, I&rsquo;m so happy how much I can accomplish inside of Slack. There&rsquo;s no way to fully express how much joy I feel doing my work in Slack. Seriously. This app redefines work.</p>
<p><strong>Bear</strong>—I really like Bear. Many notes that have actions end up in Things, but Bear is my dumping ground for workout stats, meeting notes, travel lists, and other assorted ephemera. When I wrote about Bear in 2017, I did more of my long-form writing in it, but now that has mostly moved to iAWriter. Bear always felt a little weird for long-form writing, and iAWriter&rsquo;s new duospaced font is <em>chef&rsquo;s kiss</em>. I still wish I could choose a black theme with a custom highlight color, because I hate orange and gold, but çest la vie.</p>
<p><strong>iAWriter</strong>—this app lives in a folder, but for my iPad and my Mac, it&rsquo;s how I write. The ability to open files that life in Working Copy, that really live in a Github repo that runs this site is ideal The colors are what I would choose if I had full-control. It&rsquo;s truly a masterful writing app.</p>
<h2 id="moving-to-a-search-first-model">Moving to a “search first” model</h2>
<p>When I moved all of my apps to one screen, and began stuffing the majority in a single folder, I wanted to see if I would use search. On my iPad or my Mac, I almost always open apps with Spotlight, but on my iPhone, I usually would flick through screens or folders, aimlessly looking for <em>something to tap</em>, or even hunt for the app I use to book movie tickets. This felt like a waste of time, and further, became a nervous habit. Now that I mostly search for apps, I find myself doing less nervous flicking, and mostly put my phone down when I don&rsquo;t have something to <em>do</em> with it. Out of sight, out of mind seems to be effective for me—maybe that says something about my object permanence? Lol.</p>
<h2 id="wrap-up">Wrap-up</h2>
<p>I really want a new calendar app. I want someone to come into the calendar world and shake it up—or I want Spark or Things to have access to show their calendar on my watch. Or, I want Timepage to update their watch integration. Other than that, I&rsquo;m pretty happy with my setup at this point, and find my phone helpful, pleasant, and additive. I&rsquo;m curious to see how many of these apps I use again a year from now, but I have a feeling the list might not shift much. If you&rsquo;re a phone fidgeter, I definitely recommend putting most of your apps in one folder, and maybe even <a href="https://medium.com/@brookshelley/reclaim-your-time-with-parental-controls-9224612a6c1b"><em>reclaiming your time</em></a>. If you have apps you <em>love</em> that you want to talk about, hit me up @brookshelley on Twitter, or leave a small gift at the base of the largest tree in your town. I will know.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
