<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mediadiet on dill &amp; fennel</title>
    <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/mediadiet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mediadiet on dill &amp; fennel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Copyright Brook Shelley 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/mediadiet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>October</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-11-01-october/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-11-01-october/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s Fall, baybee! Let’s get spooky and watch some horror films. If the smoke outside clears at some point, maybe we can even light a candle and do some magic.
testing
So many live-action shows are being cancelled or postponed, but fortunately Japan is still releasing boatloads of anime with no end in sight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This month Akudama Drive, Jujutsu Kaijin, and Majō Tabitabi all came out, and seem like they’ll be fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m also watching the new season of GBBO in their lock-in, Tehran, and Long Way Up. I also dove into the spooky adaptation of The Turn of the Screw on Netflix called The Haunting of Bly Manor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I doubt we’ll ever get a home release of Tenet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><p>It’s Fall, baybee! Let’s get spooky and watch some horror films. If the smoke outside clears at some point, maybe we can even light a candle and do some magic.
testing
So many live-action shows are being cancelled or postponed, but fortunately Japan is still releasing boatloads of anime with no end in sight.</p>
<p>This month Akudama Drive, Jujutsu Kaijin, and Majō Tabitabi all came out, and seem like they’ll be fun.</p>
<p>I’m also watching the new season of GBBO in their lock-in, Tehran, and Long Way Up. I also dove into the spooky adaptation of The Turn of the Screw on Netflix called The Haunting of Bly Manor.</p>
<p>I doubt we’ll ever get a home release of Tenet.</p>
<h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p><strong>Self-Knowledge</strong></p>
<p>Another School of Life book, this time on life and self-knowing. I enjoyed it quite a bit, with its brisk tour of much of what I’ve covered in therapy over the years.</p>
<p><strong>Earthlings</strong> — Sayaka Murata</p>
<p>Wow, this was initially pretty straightforward, and then went deep into the weird zone. Murata is so good at writing. Between this and the Convenience Store Woman, I think she&rsquo;s one of the best surrealist fiction authors working. Very highly recommended, and hard to put down.</p>
<p><strong>The City We Became</strong> — NK Jemison</p>
<p>Hell yea! A new trilogy from NK Jemison set in our world. I love the idea of cities as sentient beings. I think there’s some really interesting stuff that gets explored here, and I’m excited to see where the next one goes. Other than Wu Tang, fuck Staten Island though.</p>
<p><strong>Can’t Even</strong> — Anne Helen Petersen</p>
<p>Why is burnout such a thing, and how does it effect millennials? What the hell were boomers thinking? All these questions and more are answered thoroughly in this well-researched and often funny book about modern life.</p>
<p><strong>How to Overcome your Childhood</strong></p>
<p>A brisk read on how our childhoods fucked us up, and what to do about it. Food for my therapist and I for sure.</p>
<p><strong>Kissa by Kissa</strong> — Craig Mod</p>
<p>I’ve had a few occasions to sit and chat with Craig over coffee, and this book feels like an extension of those hangouts. This is a delightful travelogue and philosophical essay on exploring the nooks of Japan as they age into a softly-lit Showa patina. This book breathes a countryside stroll in and exhales a perfumes of coffee and toast. A joy.</p>
<p><strong>The Pleasures and Sorrows of Work</strong> — Alain de Botton</p>
<p>At various points de Botton is curiously horned-up, but this is largely an interesting outsider look at various industries. From the drudgeries of accountancy, to the mysteries of flight, there are quite a few strange details in this slim tome.</p>
<p><strong>The Lamb Will Slaughter the Lion</strong> — Margaret Killjoy</p>
<p>A great novella about anarchist punks who summon a demon. This felt like something that could’ve lived in Meanwhile, Elsewhere in the best way. I really loved seeing various trans pinkest in a magical story, and hope the Danielle Cain series keeps going.</p>
<p><strong>The Disaster Tourist</strong> — Yun Ko-eun</p>
<p>A fun look at the nightmarish world of trips and tours. Disaster tours feel like the next evolution of the sex tour—a titillating view of poverty and suffering. There was just enough left out to create a nice bit of mystery, and Yona was a good guide through the complexity of complicity.r</p>
<p><strong>The Overstory</strong> — Richard Powers</p>
<p>This book started-off well, with some vignettes of various characters, then lost me for a while in a very slow build. By page 300 or so, I couldn’t put it down, and didn’t get to sleep until 5am. A delight.</p>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<p><strong>The Phantom Menace</strong></p>
<p>Dammit Blank Check why did I do this to myself in order to listen to your commentary track. Seriously though, the 10 episodes about the only entry in Star Wars that was ever made were excellent. Thank you for the bonkers good time.</p>
<p><strong>Train to Busan Presents: Peninsula</strong></p>
<p>There’s no train in this one, despite the title that I think was used to make sure us goofy Americans realize it’ related to the previous film. I loved the taxi lady. This film had more of a Mad Max vibe than the original which was fun.</p>
<p><strong>Train to Busan</strong></p>
<p>Continuing the zombie movie rewatches, I threw this on in order to remind myself what it was like before watching the sequel that just came out. It’s just as good as I remember it, though I fundamentally don’t like “fast” zombies. Zombies should shamble. The wild melee of this film is a very different kind of fear than the slow horror of inexorable zombie overrunning of your position.</p>
<p><strong>World War Z</strong></p>
<p>A more intense pandemic movie. I’ve watched this three or four times, and it still manages to be one of the more interesting and compelling zombie action films. By throwing out the creeping dread for a much more agoraphobic zombie fear, this movie makes me glad I stay inside.</p>
<p><strong>Blackhat</strong></p>
<p>This movie dares to ask the bold question: “can a himbo code?”
I don’t understand why most of the terrible coding examples are windows INF or registry files, but hey, it’s fun and stupid. I think this was also the first film I saw where it was obvious that US action films are now mostly funded by Chinese financiers.</p>
<p><strong>Collateral</strong></p>
<p>I think I’ve seen this before, but didn’t remember much. I love the extremely tight shots inside the cab, and the real LA traffic vibe. This is the same LA time period as the L Word.</p>
<p><strong>Borat Subsequent</strong></p>
<p>A hoot. This wasn’t nearly as salacious as the build-up implied, but there were some big laughs, and a surprisingly endearing lock-in with some Q Anon weirdos. I wish they’d gotten more Pence action.</p>
<p><strong>Save Yourselves!</strong></p>
<p>The initial cast was a reprise of the friends from Search Party, so one could almost imagine this was an alternate reality retelling. Fortunately, this movie morphs into a cute and weird duo alien invasion story pretty quick instead.</p>
<p><strong>The Trip to Italy</strong></p>
<p>Unlike the first Trip film I’ve never seen this one before. I like how Coogan’s character has changed it up a bit, and generally this film felt friendlier. I’m excited for the next two.</p>
<p><strong>Jennifer’s body</strong></p>
<p>The entire movie I just kept thinking, “what! They’re in this too?!” I missed this movie back in the day and I think it was largely maligned, but it’s a near weird little horror film. It only takes around 15 minutes to get creepy, and then it goes off the rails in the most weird ways. Even JK Simmons was in this! Amy Sedaris! The lesson here is: don’t trust scene kids, just stick with your best friend. The men in this film are the real monsters, obviously.</p>
<p><strong>Vampires vs The Bronx</strong></p>
<p>A fun horror film about gentrification with a great cameos from folks like Zoe Saladaña and The Kid Mero. Truly a great time.</p>
<p><strong>The Assistant</strong></p>
<p>I didn’t know much about this going in, only that it was well-regarded. Julia Garner is outstanding in an incredibly brutal film about a sexually abusive and horrible movie producer that definitely <em>wink wink</em> isn’t based on anyone who is currently serving 23 years in prison.</p></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>September</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-10-01-september/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 23:30:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-10-01-september/</guid>
      <description>September It’s been a wild month here in the Bay Area, with wildfires, smoke, and record-breaking heat. Because I didn’t have much else to do, I read and watched a lot of things.</description>
      <content:encoded><h1 id="september">September</h1>
<p>It’s been a wild month here in the Bay Area, with wildfires, smoke, and record-breaking heat. Because I didn’t have much else to do, I read and watched a lot of things. On the TV front, you should check out Ted Lasso for a kind-hearted, and joyful show. Lovecraft Country is not great on trans or queer issues, but <em>is</em> generally pretty awesome, and the Great British Bake-Off is back and quarantining <em>together</em> to prevent filming stoppage.</p>
<p>I’ve also begun to <a href="https://boxd.it/1cX0X">use Letterboxd</a> if you’re a fan of that site.</p>
<p>Welcome to FALL!</p>
<h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p><strong>Axiom’s End</strong> — Lindsey Ellis</p>
<p>This read like a fun alien movie. Definitely good for a first novel, but there was a lot of rushed action in the 3rd act after a bit of running around. If this series continues, I hope we get to go off-planet a bit as well. I still can’t quite picture the aliens in this book either, fwiw.</p>
<p><strong>Children of Dune</strong> — Frank Herbert</p>
<p>The wildest line in this book is near the end: “There was an adult beefswelling in his loins and he felt his mouth open, holding, clinging to the girder-shape of ecstasy”. This is probably the worst line of sexual prose I’ve ever read. Other than that, fun book! The end really picked-up the action after a lot of early intrigue</p>
<p><strong>How to Be Alone</strong> — Sara Maitland</p>
<p>A very pleasing slim tome on being alone that tackles the challenges and the pleasures of this pursuit. As a woman who lives alone and loves it, I liked seeing my lifestyle discussed here, as well as the gentle encouragements to try camping or traveling alone. I’ve personally found flying to other places by myself to be immensely fulfilling. If you feel as if you can’t survive without constant social input, this book might convince you to dabble in solitude.</p>
<p><strong>Dune: Messiah</strong> — Frank Herbert</p>
<p>Definitely a “kill your heroes” sort of book. After the wild, messianic build-up of Dune, it’s interesting to skip past the jihad of Mua’dib into a world where the dullness and frustrations of being a ruler and a deified person lurk. I think I’d previously tried to read this, but wasn’t able to finish, so I’m glad I made it through this try. This book is definitely heavier and slower than Dune, despite being shorter, but I’ve heard the third and fourth books are more interesting, and I think this is a necessary antidote to the high highs of Dune.</p>
<p><strong>The Lightness</strong> — Emily Temple</p>
<p>Ah, a Buddhist summer camp for bad girls! I enjoyed this tale of friendship and want quite a bit. I’ve enjoyed Buddhist meditation for a few years now so had heard some of the stories at margins of this book, but really it’s more about family and belonging. A great first novel.</p>
<p><strong>The Luminous Dead</strong> — Caitlin Starling</p>
<p>If you enjoy claustrophobic cave diving movies, this book will be up your alley. I love that Starling hinted at a very large galaxy of space exploration, but confined the reader to a single, wild cave. This was the kind of page-turner that kept me up till 4am to find out what happened. Very fun.</p>
<p><strong>The Relentless Moon</strong> — Mary Robinette Kowal</p>
<p>This series is super fun. It feels like cool lady space stuff is in the air lately, as For All Mankind feels a bit similar. I don’t know how I feel about us using resources to go to space vs. trying to preserve the planet, but I’d <em>way</em> rather us go to space than bomb places, so.</p>
<p><strong>A Peculiar Peril</strong> — Jeff Vandermeer</p>
<p>This was a bit of a slog. I generally enjoy the creeping horror and all-around bizarre confusion of a Vandermeer, but I think in his effort to build a YA novel, he may have lost the power of brevity. This book skips around between characters a little too much to build any real connections to any of them. I managed to finish it, but I can’t say I liked it that much. If Volume 2 is shorter, I could be tempted to dive in, simply out of sunk-cost.</p>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<p><strong>Evangelion 1.11 &amp; 2.22</strong></p>
<p>A friend watched Evangelion for the first time recently, and I was reminded I never got around to watching these remakes/retellings. Really, really weird, but in a new ways. I kind of like that they cut out many of the extraneous slice-of-life stuff.</p>
<p><strong>Ava</strong></p>
<p>I love an assassin film, but this one managed to make everything feel a bit smaller and more banal. Pretty forgettable with the stakes of a lifetime drama but the fight scenes of an action film.</p>
<p><strong>Wall E</strong></p>
<p>Super cute and dystopic. I love this movie so much.</p>
<p><strong>Mr. Jones</strong></p>
<p>This was nothing like that Counting Crows song, but it was excellent. I didn’t know this story before watching the film, but fuck. I wish Vanessa Kirby had more to do, but I suppose that’s the issue with historical fiction.</p>
<p><strong>The Long Dumb Road</strong></p>
<p>A great buddy road movie. Planes, Trains, and Automobiles is one of my all-time favorite movies and this channels the delightful failures and wonderful moments of the genre perfectly. I should’ve watched this a while ago.</p>
<p><strong>Blade Runner: 2046</strong></p>
<p>This held up though I wanted more McKenzie Davis scenes. Also! I forgot Ana de Armas was in this. Neat.</p>
<p><strong>Mission Impossible 6</strong></p>
<p>Outstanding! After a little bit of a slump in 5, six was back to the wild heights of 4. The HALO jump was nuts, especially after looking into how they filmed it. I can’t stand Alec Baldwin, but everyone else in this is dope. A+ helicopter scenes as well. There’s car, and motorcycle chases, and even some outstanding Tom Cruise runs.</p>
<p><strong>The Da Vinci Code</strong></p>
<p>A real stinker, but silly enough to watch over a phone call with a pal. Ian McKellan was the best part of this film, with a close second being Bettany’s ability to look tortured and have sexual tension with literally everyone in every scene.</p>
<p><strong>Mission Impossible 5</strong></p>
<p>A fifth movie and a fifth director. Renne is back, which I’d forgotten, and also this movie brings some truly wild times. This is the first time the IMF goes up against the Syndicate, and has a kinda fun Opera battle. There’s no huge building this time, but there was a big swimming scene.</p>
<p><strong>Mission Impossible 4</strong></p>
<p>Benji, you fucking did it—you’re out in the field. I’m pretty glad Simon Pegg became a series regular, and especially glad that barely anyone else from earlier in the series didn’t. I do wish Keri Russell would come back though, bc she’s cool. Also this one has Stellar Skateboard.</p>
<p><strong>Mission Impossible 3</strong></p>
<p>Aw, yea&hellip; JJ Abrams is here with Felicity and that guy that’s in everything he makes! This was a really fun time at the movies. So many printable face masks! Phillip Seymour Hoffman! Tom Cruise running! A terrible love story! Also, who can forget the ridiculous <a href="https://www.firstpost.com/tech/news-analysis/mission-impossible-3-on-nokia-n93-3549677.html">Nokia phones</a> they used in this.</p>
<p><strong>Mission Impossible 2</strong></p>
<p>Definitely not as good as the first. John Woo is great, but some of his signature shots and slo-no effects just come off kinda silly in this.</p>
<p><strong>Mission Impossible</strong></p>
<p>What a blast from the past. The special effects were largely practical, which means they aged well, but the computer interfaces are delightfully 90s. I can’t believe how much this series has upped itself every incarnation, but this first one is still just a nice small-scale spy film.</p>
<p><strong>The Trip</strong></p>
<p>I’ve enjoyed Coogan since the Day Today sketches he did with Chris Morris, so it’s fascinating to see him age and keep doing odd versions of himself on film. Rob Brydon is excellent in this, and I’m reminded I should rewatch the entirety of Gavin &amp; Stacey. If you want to see two middle-aged men making very stupid (but funny) jokes and impressions while sampling haute cuisine in the north of England, this is your chance.</p>
<p><strong>Class Action Park</strong></p>
<p>I don’t know how I survived the 80s and 90s. I did a lot of really, really stupid and dangerous shit, even if I never got to go to Action Park. We had Schiltterbahn where I grew up, which was way less wild, but still pretty dangerous at times. This film does a good job of showing the teen thrills of incredibly shady theme parks.</p>
<p><strong>Boys State</strong></p>
<p>I can’t stand the little conservative assholes. Steven Garcia was chill though. Also, it’s surreal to see how far right everyone went out of an assumption that other kids would be conservative, despite that being somewhat untrue. I went to UT as well, and it was pretty nostalgic to see Clark Field and other spots I spent a lot of time on film.</p>
<p><strong>Jack Reacher</strong></p>
<p>Not the best of the Tom Cruise action franchises, but fun enough. Light on action till the end.</p>
<p><strong>Genocidal Organ</strong></p>
<p>I watched this a while ago before I read the book. It’s kind of a fascinating, if quite gory, look into what we do for “security” and how our definitions of other are constructed.</p>
<p><strong>Nightcrawler</strong></p>
<p>Despite a lack of blue skin or a tail, Gyllenhaal embodied a character just as bizarre and rigidly pursuant of his beliefs. Deeply strange film.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>August</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-09-01-august/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 07:22:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-09-01-august/</guid>
      <description>August I really jammed a lot of movies into the last few months of August, but mostly I watched The Boys and Alone.</description>
      <content:encoded><h1 id="august">August</h1>
<p>I really jammed a lot of movies into the last few months of August, but mostly I watched The Boys and Alone. I’m hopeful Hollywood will give up on theater launches of films so I can watch stuff like Tenet sooner than later. Also, fuck our state’s ability to deal with the wildfires and the damage to folks’ health and us being forced inside. It’s a hella bummer that global warming caused by the global north is slowly making California inhospitable.</p>
<h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p><strong>Hard Boiled Wonderland and the End of the World</strong> — Haruki Murakami</p>
<p>An excellent reread, though Murakami is pretty bad at talking about women.</p>
<p><strong>Goldilocks</strong> — Laura Lam</p>
<p>A little too real at times, this pairs well with Emergency Skin. I think my only complaint was the flashbacks went on a little too long, which slowed down the tension of the present-day story. Mostly I really dug this though.</p>
<p><strong>Harrow the Ninth</strong> — Tamsyn Muir</p>
<p>For a book that was maddeningly confusing for almost its length, I loved it. I literally could not put it down and read the whole thing largely in one go. Beautiful, bizarre, and baffling. I cannot wait for the third book. More. lesbian. necromancers. in. space. please. Oh and for everyone complaining there wasn&rsquo;t enough Sci-fi in Gideon, this book has malevolent planets AND space stations. So.</p>
<p><strong>The Ten Thousand Doors of January</strong> — Alix E. Harrow</p>
<p>A fun portal fantasy set in the early 1900s. This was decidedly a YA book, but moved along quickly and had enough fun world building to make me hope for a sequel. I also appreciated the use of alternate worlds to talk a bit more about race, gender, and sexuality, but hoped that would translate a little more into the main characters desires. As always, my throne for more lesbian protagonists.</p>
<p><strong>How to be Bored</strong> — Eva Hoffman</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve read a lot of books <em>kind of</em> like over the last few years, and this is one of the better-stated and brief ones out there. If you would like to read a book about attention and enjoyment, this is solid. It&rsquo;s high-minded and well-cited without coming off pompous either.</p>
<p><strong>The Sorcerer of the Wildeeps</strong> — Kai Ashante Wilson</p>
<p>Ah, I wish there were more good gay fantasy novels. This was brutal, heart-warming, and confusing at various turns. I loved that the language of the book was an AAVE, along with other patois. My hope is that Wilson writes more set in this world of magic and godlike alien technology.</p>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<p><strong>Violent Cop</strong></p>
<p>This is a rewatch, but I think it’s been at least 15 years since this first time I saw it. Beat Takeshi is a treasure. This movie is delightfully filmed. I kinda love the 80s Japanese film look, which is more reminiscent of TV than film. A classic</p>
<p><strong>An Evening with Beverly Luff Linn</strong></p>
<p>I hope folks had fun making this movie&hellip; it felt like everyone was trying a little to hard. This felt like an extended Tim &amp; Eric skit. Everything was just off.</p>
<p><strong>Sputnik</strong></p>
<p>I thought this would take place in space, but it’s mostly a fairly tight alien captive story. Enjoyable but not too wild or original.</p>
<p><strong>The Rental</strong></p>
<p>Ok, I’m glad I don’t have to stay in any Airbnbs soon after seeing this creepy movie. Whether it’s spycams, or the slow dawning realization that someone is watching, the way the vacation unfolds in this film is super scary.</p>
<p><strong>Alien: Covenant</strong></p>
<p>Ah, I love this ridiculous sequel to Prometheus. I think it captures the creeping horror of Alien and Aliens quite well, and is chock full of cool actors. I hope Scott keeps making solid Alien films for a while to come.</p>
<p><strong>Contact</strong></p>
<p>Still liked this movie, but the weird romance plot was uncomfortable AF. Also the way religion tied into it was hamfisted.</p>
<p><strong>2:22</strong></p>
<p>Watched this so I can enjoy this week’s How Did This Get Made. It wasn’t great, and tried a little too hard to be clever without actually being entertaining.</p>
<p><strong>John Wick 1-3</strong></p>
<p>Rewatched all the John Wick movies out of a desire for action and style, and they delivered. This series isn’t super substantive, but it’s an action movie smorgasbord.</p>
<p><strong>Prometheus</strong></p>
<p>A deeply satisfying addition to the Alien canon. I’ve watched this move a number of times, and it continues to thrill me.</p>
<p><strong>Barista</strong></p>
<p>I don’t watch a lot of documentaries, but this was pretty fun if a little telegraphed. The only downside to this film is now I want coffee, but it’s 1130pm.</p>
<p><strong>Ride Your Wave</strong></p>
<p>The creator of Devilman Crybaby and The Tatami Galaxy made a really delightful anime about adulthood and love. It was gorgeous and pretty touching, even if it made me really wish I could fly somewhere again. There’s also a weird parallel between this show and every season of Terrace House: namely there’s surfing, and firefighters.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>July</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-08-01-july/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-08-01-july/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;july&#34;&gt;July&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s midsummer here in Oakland, and due to the persistence of people’s risky behavior, we’re still very quarantined. At this rate, I might read quite a few more books than I initially imagined I would, as it could be well rinto 2021 before anything changes. I’m still watching quite a bit of TV, and the Formula 1 season that finally started. Seeing folks drive cars all over Europe is quite the treat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><h1 id="july">July</h1>
<p>It’s midsummer here in Oakland, and due to the persistence of people’s risky behavior, we’re still very quarantined. At this rate, I might read quite a few more books than I initially imagined I would, as it could be well rinto 2021 before anything changes. I’m still watching quite a bit of TV, and the Formula 1 season that finally started. Seeing folks drive cars all over Europe is quite the treat.</p>
<h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p><strong>Infomocracy</strong> — Malka Older</p>
<p>A very good re-read. In the lead up to the election, this feels appropriate.</p>
<p><strong>Buddhism for Beginners</strong></p>
<p>A pretty solid introduction formatted as an extended Q&amp;A that covers most ground related to how Buddhist teachings apply to our present time. I think I prefer the other book I read recently, but it was nice to have clarity on a few things I’d heard in teachings at sanghas.</p>
<p><strong>Because Internet: Gretchen McCulloch</strong></p>
<p>A delightful linguistic investigation into the history and present of internet culture, memes, and language. This felt somewhat similar to Lurking insofar as they cover a bit of the same territory, but I think this deeper dive into the language and communication styles that came from Old Internet People is a nice companion to that book. If you&rsquo;re online in any capacity, this is something important to read.</p>
<p><strong>An American Spy</strong> — Olen Steinhauer</p>
<p>Ah, I finally got to a volume I haven&rsquo;t read before—I loved the switch in perspective to the spymaster Zhu. I am pretty curious to see what happens in the final Milo Weaver book, especially with a few years separating it from this hopeful book. Generally, this series felt light enough to get through quickly, but fun, and meaty enough to really sink into during that time.</p>
<p><strong>The Nearest Exit</strong> — Olen Steinhauer</p>
<p>Apparently I read this book before in 2010, but I&rsquo;ve definitely slept since then because most of it was still a surprise to me. The saga of Milo Weaver gets even more twisty in this volume as he tries to quit his job and fix his family. Definitely wishing I could do some traveling of my own after these two spy novels.</p>
<p><strong>Buddhism Without Beliefs</strong> — Stephen Bachelor</p>
<p>A few years ago I started going to a sangha regularly and meditating a lot. While I haven’t kept up with the practice regularly, mediation is a pretty awesome part of my life when I’m able to do it, and I’ve enjoyed the lessons of the four noble truths and eightfold path. The bits of capital B Buddhism I wasn’t amped on were the religious bits, so it’s interesting to read about an agnostic buddhism.</p>
<p><strong>My Soul to Keep</strong> — Yrsa Sigurdadóttir</p>
<p>Another cozy mystery with the lawyer Thora. This went on a little long, but was still twisty enough to be interesting. In a world of Nordic noir, it’s kinda fun to read something where the protagonist isn’t a cop.</p>
<p><strong>The Tourist</strong> — Olen Steinhauer</p>
<p>A fun spy novel with plenty of twists and a good take on &ldquo;the spy that tried to get out&rdquo; trope.</p>
<p><strong>A Memory Called Empire</strong> — Arkady Martine</p>
<p>I have to admit I heard this author read at an event and her style was such I didn’t want to read this book for some time. However, I’m glad I got over that and dove into this fantastical world. Martine deftly wove together the foundation for a really neat space opera, with compelling characters, and a lot of meaty world-building. There was intrigue plenty, and I’m excited for the next book in September.</p>
<p><strong>In Praise of Shadows</strong> — Junichiro Tanizaki</p>
<p>A lot of this book (or possibly long essay) really holds up. I love all the bits about soft lighting and over-illumination killing mystery and beauty, but the parts of skin color and race are definitely not of-the-times. Tanizaki was a strange fellow, but I&rsquo;m glad I read this seminal work.</p>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<p><strong>Money Plane</strong></p>
<p>A true piece of crap. Everyone in this film seemed like they mostly work on Cinemax soft core films.</p>
<p><strong>Spectre</strong></p>
<p>A delightful rewatch.</p>
<p><strong>6 Underground</strong></p>
<p>Continuing my tradition of watching mediocre Netflix thrillers, I think I’m almost done with the current set. Ryan Reynolds is doing his sarcastic guy thing, and there’s tons of fast cuts and action stuff. The first action scene felt exciting for a bit, but by the twelfth hat-on-a-hat and shitty rock song I was hoping for relief. Fortunately it got better later, but I wish this’d been modeled more on Fast &amp; Furious and less on xXx. I wonder if Bezos watched this and thought “I’ve trained for this!”?</p>
<p><strong>Extraction</strong></p>
<p>Thor trades his hammer for guns in this exciting action film without much behind the action. Sometimes you need to watch stuff get blown-up without much plot.</p>
<p><strong>Time to Hunt</strong></p>
<p>Outstanding thriller that kept building and moving throughout. I saw this on a sci-fi list, but for the most part this felt like a slightly alternate reality, vs something in the future. Very fun.</p>
<p><strong>Bad Boys for Life</strong></p>
<p>This series is epically ridiculous, and fun throughout. Everyone seems to be having fun, and there’s a lot of wild action and even a surprise third act trip out of the country.</p>
<p><strong>The Old Guard</strong></p>
<p>Fun but ultimately thin action flick. Solid action near the end, but so much of it felt emotionless in a way that was just not super entertaining.</p>
<p><strong>Greyhound</strong></p>
<p>Tom Hanks has a fantastic presence, but they don’t really develop many other folks in this tense battle movie. Which, hey, that makes sense, since the whole movie they’re just depth charging the shit out of the sea.</p></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-07-03-june/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-07-03-june/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ah, summer! So much reading and a few movies while still hiding out inside from the continuing pandemic. I watched a few notable tv shows as well, like the 3rd season of Dark, and Berlin Station. Lots of comics as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><p>Ah, summer! So much reading and a few movies while still hiding out inside from the continuing pandemic. I watched a few notable tv shows as well, like the 3rd season of Dark, and Berlin Station. Lots of comics as well.</p>
<h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p><strong>The Glass Hotel</strong> — Emily St John Mandel</p>
<p>An interesting twisty novel. This reminded me a bit of how David Mitchell constructs his plots, but slightly more straightforward. I wish we’d gotten a little more Vincent.</p>
<p><strong>The Summer Book</strong> — Tove Jansson</p>
<p>This was a delightfully banal book about a girl and her grandma on an island off the coat of Finland. All the small stories were a joy, and I imagine I&rsquo;ll return to this book often when I need a smile.</p>
<p><strong>The Gentle Art of Swedish Death Cleaning</strong> — Margareta Magnusson</p>
<p>It’s nice reading a book by an older woman who has such a clear love and appreciate for her life, but has accepted the inevitability of death. Far from being grim, this book was a delightful look at what we value and how to make sure no one else has to clean up our mess when we’re gone.</p>
<p><strong>Woman in the Dunes</strong> — Kobo Abe</p>
<p>Abe is one of my favorite authors, and consistently makes me smile with his surreal plots and characters. Woman in the Dunes is not my favorite of his, but is a fascinating look at how our spirit can be ground down by sand and society.</p>
<p><strong>Abolish Silicon Valley</strong> — Wendy Liu</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“Capitalism Is a disease in the venality of Silicon Valley is a morbid symptom, the fingers turning ashen”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>As someone who is somewhat begrudgingly started working in Silicon Valley after studying literature mostly as a way to make ends-meat, this book resonated strongly. The front half establishes Liu’s history, but the back half is the juicy bit. I love reading a hopeful vision of how we might reconfigure society to support humans, and not capital.</p>
<p><strong>Last Rituals</strong> — Yrsa Sigurdadóttir</p>
<p>A solid Scandinavian noir with a nice amount of occult content. I think the translation could’ve likely used work, as some of the phrasing seemed oddly stilted, but I can’t read Icelandic to check up on that.</p>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<p><strong>Bridge of Spies</strong></p>
<p>A solid Spielberg feel-good negotiation thriller. I only knew a little about the U2 bomber and our history of capturing spies until I watched this film and dove into Wikipedia. This movie made me miss Berlin, which I’ve only visited once for a few weeks, but was delightful. If you enjoy the work of Tom Hanks, he does his thing well in this movie.</p>
<p><strong>Gemini Man</strong></p>
<p>I can only imagine a certain “religion” has also cloned Will Smith at some point. This was way more fun than it had a right to be, and weirdly enough the young Will CGI was pretty solid. How long until we see movies with young Cruise, or Washington? Have a bottle of wine and turn your brain off for 2 hours.</p>
<p><strong>‌式日</strong></p>
<p>This was a lot of movie. When I was younger I think I had more patience for particularly slow films, but I ended-up being a little distracted during 式日. I’m glad I finally got to watch it though, as it was pretty interesting seeing Iwai on the other side of the camera. Also I really miss being in Japan now.</p>
<p><strong>Waiting for Guffman</strong></p>
<p>Ah, a classic. It’s wild seeing Fred Willard in this looking so young comparatively. I watched this obsessively in high school and it really, really holds up.</p></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-05-31-may/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-05-31-may/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another month of quarantine means a few movies and books. I also dove into a freshly delivered pile of Monocle and played way too much CoD: Warzone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I also watched something like 5 seasons of Survivor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><p>Another month of quarantine means a few movies and books. I also dove into a freshly delivered pile of Monocle and played way too much CoD: Warzone.</p>
<p>I think I also watched something like 5 seasons of Survivor.</p>
<h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p><strong>Network Effect</strong> — Martha Wells</p>
<p>It’s nice to really stretch my legs in the Murderbot world. I hope Wells writes more novels in this fun universe, and we get to see Murderbot grow further past its general emotional discomfort.</p>
<p><strong>Finna</strong> — Nino Cipri</p>
<p>A fun romp through an IKEA multiverse with a queer couple and a missing grandma. I had fun with this, and the short length meant I blazed through it almost too fast. I hope there’s more from Cipri soon.</p>
<p><strong>Zero History</strong> — William Gibson</p>
<p>I read this slowly to really savor it. The last book in the Blue Ant trilogy is the most oddball and fun, but always comes with the knowledge that I won’t get to adventure with Millgrim and Hollis again until I reread the series yet again in the future. It’s fascinating how thoroughly Gibson identified the coming brand drops, denim obsession, and obsession with quadrocopters. As a sage of the near future, he feels unparalleled.</p>
<p><strong>Spook Country</strong> — William Gibson</p>
<p>A delightful reread of a really fun Gibson near-future/near-past adventure. There are so many moments in this book that make me super jealous I didn’t conceive of them. The Blue Ant trilogy owns bones.</p>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<p><strong>Nightmare on Elm Street</strong></p>
<p>Did you know Depp was in this? I certainly didn’t! This is the second movie I’ve watched because of the podcast <strong>The Scaredy Cats</strong> wherein one host of Reply All tries to help the other host inure himself to horror films. With all of the cultural cachet this movie had, it was interesting to see how quickly they showed Freddy himself. Freddy also seemed shorter than I imagined. I also always find it funny when all the “high school” actors are in their twenties. Why not just set it in college?</p>
<p><strong>Upgrade</strong></p>
<p>An interesting take on the post-human world. It’s a schlocky, funny, gory AF film, and not very into its own violence. Also it was rad to see Betty Gabriel from Get Out again.</p>
<p><strong>Sonic the Hedgehog</strong></p>
<p>Weird how much more low-key enjoyable this was than the last movie I watched. From the delightfully bad puns, to Jim Carrey having way too much fun, to Ben Schwartz just being himself, this was a nice Saturday afternoon romp. I went in expecting basically nothing, and was pleasantly surprised.</p>
<p><strong>The Dead Don’t Die</strong></p>
<p>This movie so badly wanted to be clever, it is the film equivalent to wearing a “funny shirt” from Hot Topic and explaining the joke to everyone before they can even laugh.</p>
<p><strong>The Lodge</strong></p>
<p>One of the better horror films I’ve seen in a while, with a very scary house, and an excellent secluded location.</p>
<p><strong>Saturday Night</strong></p>
<p>A fun documentary with rather overwrought camera-work that shows what preparing for and shooting SNL is like. It’s kinda wild to see the sheer number of writers and staff that make it come alive.</p>
<p><strong>The Exorcist</strong></p>
<p>Pretty creepy, with great special effects considering the time. I always root for the demons in any one of these, and definitely wondered while watching this how many more kids priests hurt than these imagined evil spirits. The devil, it turns out, was the church all along.</p>
<p><strong>Vivarium</strong></p>
<p>Started creepy, got way creepier. I appreciate the unwillingness to tell the viewer what the fuck is happening. This plays out like a great Ursula K Le Guin novel.</p></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-04-30-april/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-04-30-april/</guid>
      <description>My first entire month in quarantine. Plenty of time to read, watch movies, and play Civ 6 (and keep losing). I also picked-up Gran Turismo and raced virtual cars for countless hours.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>My first entire month in quarantine. Plenty of time to read, watch movies, and play Civ 6 (and keep losing). I also picked-up Gran Turismo and raced virtual cars for countless hours. This month felt like a year.</p>
<h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p><strong>Polaris Rising</strong> — Jessie Mihalik</p>
<p>A mix of space caper and Harlequin Romance, there was entirely too much straight sex in this for me. But, if you think “space operas should have more picking out dresses and rough hands on waists,” then this is the book for you.</p>
<p><strong>Zero Sum Game</strong> — SL Huang</p>
<p>Ah a female protagonist who uses her math expertise to leap through windows and shoot bad guys! This book ruled. I’m not sure what this character’s “struggle” is going to be, because in the first book at least she’s a little invincible, but either way it was fun.</p>
<p><strong>The Factory</strong> — Hiroko Oyamada</p>
<p>A strange, short book with some challenging dialogue formatting. I really loved the small vignettes of slightly-slanted banal work life in The Factory. I&rsquo;m excited to read more of Oyamada&rsquo;s work, because despite reading quite a bit of Japanese fiction, I haven&rsquo;t had the chance to read very many Japanese women. I hope that I either get better at kanji to the point I can read from the source, or more translators translate other women.</p>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<p><strong>After the Storm</strong></p>
<p>Koreeda is one of the best directors when it comes to presenting the sadly funny banality of life. I can’t fathom someone else who could present a deadbeat dad and dysfunctional family with such pathos. This isn’t quite as heartrending as Shoplifters, but it comes close.</p>
<p><strong>Game Night</strong></p>
<p>Just a good time. Everyone seemed like they were having a great time, and it hopped along at a good clip while keeping me laughing.</p>
<p><strong>Hustlers</strong></p>
<p>I love a good grift. I’m still low-key mad this wasn’t about a lesbian romance between J Lo and Constance Wu though.</p>
<p><strong>Jumanji: Next Level</strong></p>
<p>Have you ever wanted to see the Rock play Dan Devito? What about Jack Black playing a younger black guy? This movie was more bizarre than the last but hey, it was also fun.</p>
<p><strong>Jumanji: Welcome to the Jungle</strong></p>
<p>The extras’ costuming in this film is deeply strange, with a mix of “Indiana Jones pan-middle-east” and “Mad Max”. This whole film was a glorious mess, and I loved it.</p>
<p><strong>The Guest</strong></p>
<p>This was surprisingly funny and very bizarre. I really enjoy Dan Stevens, ever since his turn as Xavier’s son Legion.</p>
<p><strong>Prisoners</strong></p>
<p>In preparation for the eventual release of the new Dune film I wanted to familiarize myself with Villneuve’s ourve. This is a very good mystery film with a grittier Gyllenhal than his turn at Zodiac.</p>
<p><strong>Rythym Section</strong></p>
<p>A training montage revenge flick that slowly transforms into a pretty thrilling action movie.</p>
<p><strong>Bloodshot</strong></p>
<p>“I don’t mind the scars, I just don’t like the stories they tell.” With a time-to-tanktop of just under 5 minutes, you know from the jump this will be a new Diesel vehicle. This movie had it all: underwater tai-chi, weightlifting, Guy Pierce, and a drinking competition to hone in on Vin’s favorite shot. Of course, as a Chinese-financed movie, there’s no blood or sex or skeletons. Also why didn’t they put that one guy’s eyes in his head instead of on his chest?! “He’s a techie, just like me!”</p>
<p><strong>Radius</strong></p>
<p>Interesting conceptually, but it didn’t really go anywhere besides the concept. It would’ve been better as an anime, lol.</p>
<p><strong>Portrait of a Lady on Fire</strong></p>
<p>Well, fuck. That was gorgeous and sad. This movie built until my heart ached, and wove a story of falling in love.</p>
<p><strong>Crawl</strong></p>
<p>It’s no Underwater, but I guess if you want to see a great reason not to visit Florida, this is a perfect anti-ad.</p>
<p><strong>Underwater</strong></p>
<p>This turned out was cooler that i was expecting. Can’t say much more without spoiling anything.</p>
<p><strong>General Magic</strong></p>
<p>After seeing the fictionalized versions of many of these folks in Steve Jobs, and hearing so many stories about others—some of whom I’ve met—this was a really interesting look at a company that catalyzed much of what we use every day to live online.</p>
<p><strong>Steve Jobs</strong></p>
<p>Oh, hey, it’s Shiv! It’s kind of fascinating that the entire story is told through the lead-up to the presentations that implanted Steve Jobs in so many of our brains. I really enjoyed seeing this, and also think it’s funny this came out only 2 years after the Kutcher film. Also, Fassbender has a way cooler vibe that the actual Jobs&hellip; I mean, he’s Magneto!</p>
<p><strong>The Social Network</strong></p>
<p>One of the wildest things about this movie is the that Facebook’s valuation at the time of the credits rolling was only $25 billion. A few years later, it’s nearly 500 billion. I left Facebook 3 years before this film came out, and briefly returned while in Portland. I get the sense the characters in the film might be less likable in real life.</p>
<p><strong>Apollo 13</strong></p>
<p>Such a fantastic film. It’s surprising how well this held up, with many practical effects and no terrible CGI. It’s been 25 years and this one still had me on the edge of my seat.</p>
<p><strong>Overlord</strong></p>
<p>This felt a bit like a video game. Lots of nazis getting blown up? Weird underground lab? Strange NPCs? Check.</p>
<p><strong>Birds of Prey</strong></p>
<p>It’s a low bar, but this is definitely the best DCU movie since all the serious Nolan Batman films. Not only was it silly fun, it managed to build interesting characters and solid battles that put the overwrought CGI-fest of Avengers to shame. I hope if they make more of these they keep the formula. I really want to see a love story between Poison Ivy and Harley.</p>
<p><strong>1917</strong></p>
<p>A very intense movie but it was also beautiful in its own way. I get why this won awards. Weird cameo by Doctor Strange though.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-31-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-31-march/</guid>
      <description>Books Empress of Forever — Max Gladstone
A fun space romp with a Jobsian lesbian protagonist and a strange cast of characters.</description>
      <content:encoded><h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p><strong>Empress of Forever</strong> — Max Gladstone</p>
<p>A fun space romp with a Jobsian lesbian protagonist and a strange cast of characters. This quickly shifts into a very different book from what it starts as, but I still loved it. More space lesbians, please.</p>
<p><strong>A Song for a New Day</strong> — Sarah Pinsker</p>
<p>Welp, my second book for the month was another plague book, albeit one that largely took place in the aftermath of a pox. I enjoyed this book quite a bit, even if it was a <em>little</em> too hopeful for my usual taste. Honestly, it was a little refreshing to read a book where cool women make music and care about each other, and hope for the future. Thanks Haley for the tip on this one.</p>
<p><strong>Wanderers</strong> — Chuck Wendig</p>
<p>Phew, that was a dark fucking book. With the pandemic going on in the world right now, this wasn’t a very good idea to read, but I’m glad I finished it. Just about every bad thing you can imagine happens in this book, so I have a hard time recommending it, but perhaps for folks who don’t believe in global warming or in the danger of a pandemic, this will give them pause.</p>
<p><strong>Lurking</strong> — Joanne McNeil</p>
<p>A very interesting look at the history of the internet as a user. One of the best non-fiction books I’ve read in a while.</p>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<p><strong>The Martian</strong></p>
<p>Another rewatch. I had a FaceTime call where my friend Lena and I discussed Halt and Catch Fire, which reminded me how much I enjoyed this film, which I took to be about the competence of McKenzie Davis’ character. This was my first time watching this movie in 4K though, which made it look pretty amazing. Also, I always forget Donald Glover was in this.</p>
<p><strong>Skyfall</strong></p>
<p>Perhaps one of the only movies to use a Land Rover Defender in a car chase, this is pure fun. The filming and action scenes were a wild step-up from the previous two films, and the stakes felt high throughout.</p>
<p><strong>Quantum of Solace</strong></p>
<p>Far less memorable than Casino Royale. The first chase was fun, but a lot of the rest of the film kinda just meanders. I do appreciate the little nods towards older James Bond films though.</p>
<p><strong>Casino Royale</strong></p>
<p>Rewatching this in preparation for the eventual release of the final Daniel Craig bond film. It holds pretty well, save for the hilariously old-looking Sony phones and bootcut khakis. I’d forgotten Mads Mikkelsen was in this.</p>
<p><strong>Contagion</strong></p>
<p>I saw this in the theater when it first came out, but I haven’t seen it since then. This felt like a timely movie considering our current circumstances. I forgot Jude Law plays a weird crank reporter.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>February</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-01-february/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-01-february/</guid>
      <description>XOXO it was the month of love&amp;hellip; for my new bike, and my always valentine Snorri. I watched a lot more movies this month than I read books, but that felt alright.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>XOXO it was the month of love&hellip; for my new bike, and my always valentine Snorri. I watched a lot more movies this month than I read books, but that felt alright. Video games were also a theme, with <em>lots</em> of Witcher 3 and Dead Souls to keep me occupied. I also powered through a number of TV shows, like the Misadventures of Romesh Ranganathan and the October Faction.</p>
<h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p><strong>The Longing for Less</strong> — Kyle Chayka</p>
<p>This was far funnier than I expected, and also taught me a lot about a few areas of art and architecture I didn’t know about. A really informative and fun book.</p>
<p><strong>しろくまカフェ　1</strong></p>
<p>私のこれが最初日本語の漫画を読んだ。面白かったよ。次に谷崎の文学を読むww。</p>
<p><strong>Outline</strong> — Rachel Cusk</p>
<p>This was recommended to me, but I can’t say I loved it. The story here read more as a series of strange anecdotes, without a lot of core thread to grasp. There are two more books in this series, but I think I may pass on them.</p>
<p><strong>Agency</strong> — William Gibson</p>
<p>A nearly present-day story of AI, art, and San Francisco. I really enjoyed this Peripheral sequel, though I think on the whole the fashion and strange web world of the previous trilogy was more my speed. I hope we get one more book with Netherton, Ash and company.</p>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<p><strong>Jojo Rabbit</strong></p>
<p>A deeply strange film about learning how to be a person and unlearn fanaticism. There were some pretty excellent cameos in this, and a very dark comedic beat.</p>
<p><strong>Phantom Thread</strong></p>
<p>Wow, this movie was hilarious from top to bottom. A friend (hi Drew) invited me to see it for the first time in 70mm, and all I want to do is channel Woodcock every day. &ldquo;What am I supposed to do with that?&rdquo;. What a joy. I can&rsquo;t wait to watch this again.</p>
<p><strong>First Love</strong></p>
<p>A strange mistaken gangster film. This was much more straightforward than many Takeshi Miike films, but still managed to add in some really bizarre bits, and even some surprises.</p>
<p><strong>Elle</strong></p>
<p>Yow. That was&hellip; a lot of movie. Isabelle Huppert was fantastic, but I don&rsquo;t know if I could recommend it. Definitely one of the stranger Verhoeven movies I&rsquo;ve seen.</p>
<p><strong>Anna</strong></p>
<p>Another lady assassin movie. It was a helluva ride and I enjoyed it. I don’t think it added anything huge to the genre, but I’m just glad to have more cool movies about tough women. That said, I wish Anna had been able to just be with her girlfriend instead of randomly fucking spymasters.</p>
<p><strong>Gennocidal Organ</strong></p>
<p>I read the book this movie is based on last year, and it’s a truly brutal story of linguistics and massive unrest. This movie is grim in a way that feels a little too prescient. Definitely one of the better anime thrillers I’ve seen in a while though.</p>
<p><strong>Psycho Pass Movie Trilogy</strong></p>
<p>After season 3, Psycho Pass had a trilogy of films in Japan. They’re fun continuations of the characters from all three seasons, and a bit of a sequel to the first movie. The future this film presents is pretty grim, but the animation is fantastic.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-01-30-media-diet-for-january/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-01-30-media-diet-for-january/</guid>
      <description>2020 began in earnest, and despite it being winter, in the Bay Area it’s delightfully sunny. I spent the first week largely sitting by the window of my apartment, reading and studying Japanese.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>2020 began in earnest, and despite it being winter, in the Bay Area it’s delightfully sunny. I spent the first week largely sitting by the window of my apartment, reading and studying Japanese. So far, I really enjoy the slower pace of this decade.</p>
<h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p><strong>Mainline</strong> — Deborah Christiansen</p>
<p>A fun throwback to the world of cyber decks and assassins. I wish I’d found this in 1996, but it holds up well. The plot got a little convoluted, but supposedly there’s a very recent sequel, so perhaps there will be payoff.</p>
<p><strong>Uncanny Valley</strong> — Anna Weiner</p>
<p>Ah, the tech industry. I’ve been working in this world for over a decade and this book felt like a survey of it. I know a few people mentioned in the chapters, and am unfortunately very familiar with many of the events. I think Weiner did a great job of capturing the constant, weird feeling of trying to survive and often getting lost in the self-satisfied world of tech founders and “disruption”.</p>
<p><strong>Throne of Glass</strong> — Sarah J. Maas</p>
<p>I was drawn to this book by the front cover and the vague notion that it might be like Gideon the Ninth. It’s not exactly super different, but it’s clearly YA, where Gideon is not. I may continue the series, as it was decently compelling, but I wish it were more genre and less youth.</p>
<p><strong>Unsubscribe</strong> — Jocelyn Glei</p>
<p>Although this book is deep in the details of email, most of it applies just as well to Slack and other forms of messaging. I appreciate her approach to mindful work, as well as how she thinks about the problems of people and communication. A worthwhile read, especially if you struggle with a mountain of other people’s problems</p>
<p><strong>The Walking Man</strong> — Jiro Taniguchi</p>
<p>The art in this manga is gorgeous. I especially love the way the leaves and grass are drawn. The stories are largely dialogue-less vignettes that meander through cities and the countryside, taking it all in. When I open this book, I wish I were in Japan again, following stray cats around town.</p>
<p><strong>Emily Eternal</strong> — M.G. Wheaton</p>
<p>This is an interesting take on apocalyptic fiction. With an AI protagonist and a dying sun, the story careens across the Americas and then even further. There’s a strange love story I didn’t care much for, but otherwise this was a nice romp.</p>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<p><strong>Weathering with You</strong></p>
<p>I found out I don’t need to worry about climate change because it’s just rain, ya know? This film was gorgeous and fun and o loved the cat in it with my entire heart.</p>
<p><strong>Matrix: Reloaded</strong></p>
<p>Really starting the year off right. We talked through most of the exposition, which was like 75% of the movie. I hadn’t seen this since it came out, and it really didn’t hold up.</p>
<p><strong>The Lighthouse</strong></p>
<p>The first thing I noticed in this film was the tight, constrained feel of a square frame with deep black and white images. I immediately had to look around for <a href="https://www.musicbed.com/blog/filmmaking/cinematography/breaking-down-the-cinematography-of-the-lighthouse/">how this was made</a>. The VVitch is one of my favorite movies of all time, and Eggers doesn&rsquo;t disappoint in this haunting film either. The dread builds as the antipathy between the two men grows. A joy.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>December</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-12-31-media-diet-for-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-12-31-media-diet-for-december/</guid>
      <description>Books Dept. of Speculation — Jenny Offill
A gorgeous and sad book that captures long relationships so well. I loved for narrator and the strange poetic style of storytelling.</description>
      <content:encoded><h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p><strong>Dept. of Speculation</strong> — Jenny Offill</p>
<p>A gorgeous and sad book that captures long relationships so well. I loved for narrator and the strange poetic style of storytelling. I read this in two sittings and was enraptured.</p>
<p><strong>Dead Astronauts</strong> — Jeff Vandermeer</p>
<p>This book did some interesting things with time, and some deeply annoying things with text. I feel like I know what he was doing with this book largely, and support his environmental aims (a+ murderous blue fox), but it never really came together for me.</p>
<p><strong>Interference</strong> — Sue Burke</p>
<p>A fun follow-up to a great book from last year. I loved seeing how modern Earth folks mixed with the people on the rainbow bamboo planet. I was surprised to find that we only followed a single generation of characters this time, but I did enjoy how they were more fleshed-out.</p>
<p><strong>This is How You Lose the Time War</strong> — Amal el-Mohtar and Max Gladstone</p>
<p>A deeply strange time-travel romance between two competing spies, Blue and Red. The central conceit of shifting threads of history and letter-leaving was fun, but at times I honestly had no idea what was going on. I really enjoyed this book.</p>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<p><strong>Ford vs. Ferrari</strong></p>
<p>A blast! I love car racing so much, and this film was a gorgeous vision of a famous showdown between an incredible car company, and Ford. I grew up hearing stories about Shelby, and this film brought him to life.</p>
<p><strong>Uncut Gems</strong></p>
<p>This was wild! From front to back this movie was a rollercoaster of poor decision-making and the world of vigs, 3 way parlay, and Kevin Garnet. Adam Sandler showed that he could really act in Punch Drunk Love, and he absolutely owns in Uncut Gems.</p>
<p><strong>One Cut of the Dead</strong></p>
<p>Without spoiling it, all I’ll say is this film went to fun places I didn’t expect, and was a delight throughout.</p>
<p><strong>Psycho Pass</strong></p>
<p>The episodes of this show already feel fairly cinematic, so stretching the show to nearly 2 hours felt right. It was super jarring to hear random English throughout the film though—at the start I thought I was accidentally watching a dub.</p>
<p><strong>Star Wars: Rise of Skywalker</strong></p>
<p>Frankly <a href="https://www.patreon.com/posts/emperor-only-has-32504876">this post from Film Critic Hulk</a> covered my feelings well. I described it as a movie trying to fellate itself. Scenes rarely got to breathe, and the movie felt packed with fan service and confusing backtracking from Last Jedi. Also wow, they just dropped a bunch of character storylines.</p>
<p><strong>Ad Astra</strong></p>
<p>Space Brad Pitt! We’ve sent most leading men to space, but never Pitt (I didn’t check this too carefully). Also this had Donald Sutherland, who is a personal favorite. I appreciate that none of the things in space made sound at least. Sad dads in space. It was pretty, and exciting, but ultimately didn’t really give me much to latch onto.</p>
<p><strong>Ready or Not</strong></p>
<p>Lol can&rsquo;t wait to never get remarried. Rich people are the worst. Also it&rsquo;s a real bummer that &ldquo;satanists&rdquo; get such a bad wrap in a world where the christians are the ones actually harming children. Fuck the <a href="https://overcast.fm/+VX6lxzezs">satanic panic</a></p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-30-media-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-30-media-diet/</guid>
      <description>It’s finally chilly hygge-weather in the Bay Area, so I’ve been reading a lot after returning from a long trip to Japan.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>It’s finally chilly hygge-weather in the Bay Area, so I’ve been reading a lot after returning from a long trip to Japan. I hope wherever you are, you’re warm and feel loved.</p>
<h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p><strong>The Starless Sea</strong> &ndash; Erin Morgenstern</p>
<p>I read this in a delightful haze during the holiday weekend. I love stories like these, that are also about stories, and books, and love. I remember liking the Night Circus, but I absolutely adore The Starless Sea. This is a book for those of us who love exploring, and digging into a fantastical tale.</p>
<p><strong>The Infinite Wait</strong> &ndash; Julia Wertz</p>
<p>My friend Jenny recommended this one a while ago, and I finally got around to reading it. I couldn’t put it down. It’s hilarious, sad, and very close to home. I’d never heard of Wertz until now, but I plan to immediately buy all her comics.</p>
<p><strong>The Future of Another Timeline</strong> — Annalee Newitz</p>
<p>Wow. This book was a triumph, and seriously seals Newitz as a scifi master. I only wish I could explore this world for longer. A perfect blend of history, speculation, and feminism—this book imagines a world in which collective action is possible deep into the past. Dang.</p>
<p><strong>How to Do Nothing</strong> — Jenny Odell</p>
<p>Now that I&rsquo;ve finally finished her book, I can wholeheartedly recommend it. This isn&rsquo;t the self-help palp that so many books about your phone are, but instead a wildly revelatory piece on bioregionalism, art, mystery, and birds. So many cool birds. This is a book I had to sip, because every few pages were full of so many ideas I wanted to savor them. I learned quite a bit from Jenny in these pages, and I am lucky to count her as a friend. Don&rsquo;t worry if it takes you a while to read this, just buy a copy and meander through California through it.</p>
<p><strong>Shadow and Bone</strong> — Leigh Bardugo</p>
<p>This was a neat YA that ended far before I thought it would—my edition had almost 100 pages of previews after the book. I enjoyed the magic system, despite the unfortunate teen romance that tends to plague YA. I&rsquo;ll likely read more of this series, in hopes that it continues to build a cool world.</p>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<p><strong>Knives Out</strong></p>
<p>Sadly, I wasn&rsquo;t feeling great so I missed a bit of this, but I think I got all the important bits. I really want to see this again in the near future. The overall tone of the film was fantastic, and the comedic hits were delightful.</p>
<p><strong>Fast Color</strong></p>
<p>The preview of this movie had me hoping it was a potential adaptation of NK Jeminson&rsquo;s Broken Earth trilogy, but alas, it wasn&rsquo;t. Fortunately, it was still a fun movie about family and mutant powers. I wish there was a little more substance to the whole film, but on the upside, the mood was pretty interesting. Also it&rsquo;s weird seeing a belter as a sheriff (please see the Expanse for more details).</p>
<p><strong>Uncle Boonmee Who Can Recall His Past Lives</strong></p>
<p>I’ve had this on my to-watch list for years, and finally decided to dive in. It was a beautiful and strange mediation on life, death, and family.</p>
<p><strong>Terminator: Dark Fate</strong></p>
<p>A nice return to form. This felt like a nice natural extension to Terminator 2, and while it wasn&rsquo;t a great film by any means, it was a fun romp with lots of goofy jokes, explosions, and Mackenzie Davis.</p>
<p><strong>Edge of Tomorrow</strong></p>
<p>This was a rewatch after a listening to a recent episode of the <a href="https://www.theincomparable.com/theincomparable/485/">Incomparables</a>. I have a special place in my heart for movies where Tom Cruise is supposed to be a tough guy, and if you add in mechanized suits? Hell yes. It’s not the best film, but it’s very fun.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-10-31-media-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-10-31-media-diet/</guid>
      <description>Books To Be Taught, If Fortunate — Becky Chambers
This is one of the best sci-fi short novellas I’ve read in a while.</description>
      <content:encoded><h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p><strong>To Be Taught, If Fortunate</strong> — Becky Chambers</p>
<p>This is one of the best sci-fi short novellas I’ve read in a while. It’s not quite hard SF, but I love all the little details. The characters are great, and just casually queer, and there’s just enough suspense to make it a real page-turner. A triumph.</p>
<p><strong>The Guest Cat</strong> — Takashi Hiraide <a href="#ghost">**</a></p>
<p>Definitely cried reading this one. I’m a sucker for Japanese cat literature for sure.</p>
<p><strong>Revenant Gun</strong> — Yoon Ha Lee</p>
<p>The final book in the Ninefox trilogy, and definitely the horniest one. If you military guys, there’s probably some fun for you in here. For me though, this was a great conclusion to a often confusing and wild series. I still don’t understand all of the math, but I love the world. There were some really interesting character choices here, and even though I wish we’d seen more of Cheris and Jedao chatting, the bits we did get were rad. This series was fantastic overall.</p>
<p><strong>Pattern Recognition</strong> — William Gibson</p>
<p>A reread of a favorite. I might or might not partially owe Cayce for a major style inspiration for my daily wardrobe. This story has a lot of artifacts of the early oughts, but most of it feels delightfully timeless.</p>
<p><strong>Hollow Kingdom</strong> — Kira Jane Buxton</p>
<p>Still not sure how i feel about this book. I think the idea of the book was better than the execution.</p>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<p><strong>In the Shadow of the Moon</strong></p>
<p>A mid-flight watch on my way to Tokyo. Pretty interesting, engaging flick that gets weird.</p>
<p><strong>Parasite</strong></p>
<p>There isn’t a lot I can say about this without spoiling the whole endeavor, but suffice it to say this movie is incredible. There’s <em>so much</em> going on in every shot, and the actors performances are incredible. This is a rare movie that just keeps building and building throughout. Truly one of the best directors working.</p>
<p><strong>What We Do in the Shadows</strong></p>
<p>A rewatch of an utter classic of mockumentary. So many quotable lines and absurdly delightful scenes. The last word in vampire media.</p>
<p><strong>The Art of Self Defense</strong></p>
<p>The dialog delivery was definitely from the Yorgos Lanthimos school of deadpan, and the general vibe was extremely absurdist. I loved this film. Quite a bit of this movie was unexpected, and had me cracking up. A genuinely odd delight.</p>
<p><strong>The Day Shall Come</strong></p>
<p>An utterly bizarre and fantastic satire about the very real lengths the state goes to in order to prop up folks with no real chance of committing “terrorist acts”. It’s worrying watching <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LqUsiV8LPkM">this interview</a> to get more behind the scenes of this film. Morris makes seriously strange stuff, and this is no exception.</p>
<p><strong>High Life</strong></p>
<p>Space dads! I don’t know if this is a genre, but perhaps it should be since Interstellar, High Life, and Ad Astra all appear to answer: “what if dads, but in space”. However there was a <em>lot</em> of assault in this film&hellip; it’s largely about felons being jettisoned into space, and artificial insemination experiments, it turns out. If you like very grim space movies, this might be for you.</p>
<p><strong>Promare</strong></p>
<p>A wild visual ride with a rather bizarre (it’s Trigger, naturally) story of fire people and the folks who fight them. There’s mecha, tons of goofy jokes, and even though it felt a little long, it was fun.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>September</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-09-30-media-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-09-30-media-diet/</guid>
      <description>Media diet for September Books Gideon the Ninth — Tamsyn Muir
Queer space necromancers! Queer space necromancers! OMG. This book was utterly bizarre, and a hell of a lot of fun.</description>
      <content:encoded><h1 id="media-diet-for-september">Media diet for September</h1>
<h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p><strong>Gideon the Ninth</strong> — Tamsyn Muir</p>
<p>Queer space necromancers! Queer space necromancers! OMG. This book was utterly bizarre, and a hell of a lot of fun. I’m a fan of low-tech future space stories, where for the most part the book seems more like fantasy than sci-fi, so this book was a joy. Plus there was necromancy! Apparently there are going to be two more books in this series, which is a delightful thing to learn, because I want to stretch out and learn more about this strange universe.</p>
<p><strong>Raven Strategem</strong> — Yoon Ha Lee</p>
<p>All the world building and deciphering of the strange calendrical system paid off in full in this book. Getting a hint of what Jedao/Cheris might want at the end of Ninefox, this book deals with the aftermath of a dangerously peerless tactician let loose in the galaxy. I enjoyed all the strange details of the hexarchs, and imagining what each moth looked like. It’s been a minute since a sci-fi book got me so excited. This series can feel like a slog at first, but I think it’s worth it.</p>
<p><strong>Ninefox Gambit</strong> — Yoon Ha Lee</p>
<p>This was one of the more challenging sci-fi books I&rsquo;ve read in a while. Ultimately, figuring out what the hell was going on was well worth-it, but the first half or so was a frantic dog paddle to stay afloat. The world of NineFox Gambit is deeply strange, with technology that borders on magic that requires an empire to hold to a strict calendar for it to function. We follow a rad lady, with a homicidal general trapped in her head as she runs what seems like a suicide mission. I&rsquo;m excited to read the rest of this series.</p>
<p><strong>Masterworks</strong> — Simon Jacobs</p>
<p><a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/blog/2019/09/03/Masterworks-Review.html">Long form review</a></p>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<p><strong>Eighth Grade</strong></p>
<p>The idea of this movie made me <em>very</em> anxious. Middle school is rough, and I was on edge for most of the film wondering if something very bad would happen, or if Checkov&rsquo;s AR-15 would reappear. <strong>Spoiler Alert</strong> No. There&rsquo;re definitely some sad moments, and some very tender and sweet ones, but no one big terrible event occurs. This isn&rsquo;t that kind of movie. Instead, Eighth Grade perfectly encapsulates how nervous and awkward we felt in our youth, and just how embarassed we were by our parents. I loved it.</p>
<p><strong>Between Two Ferns</strong></p>
<p>I love the parallel world of these bizarre and failed actors. I haven’t seen very many episodes of the web show, but this was pretty fun.</p>
<p><strong>Aniara</strong></p>
<p>TL;DR: Low-budget sci-fi cruise ship. This movie reminded me of a Twilight Zone episode, at least in its premise. I really enjoy movies where something goes horribly awry, and &ldquo;what if we&rsquo;re stuck in space forever&rdquo; definitely meets that criteria, but unlike the Twilight Zone, there&rsquo;s no big twist, just a slow sadness. There&rsquo;s a certain charm to the fact that it&rsquo;s Swedish as well. Plus, there’s space lesbians. We’re everywhere.</p>
<p><strong>Mega Time Squad</strong></p>
<p>Completely silly and fun. Low-budget time travel movies are often awesome (think Primer), but what if it was also a very low-brow comedy? Sweet as.</p>
<p><strong>Booksmart</strong></p>
<p>Wow, I really should&rsquo;ve watched this in the theater. This movie ruled. Outstanding cast, hilarious from start to finish. I want so many more amazing comedies that center rad women. More. Lesbian. Characters. In. Everything.</p>
<p><strong>Steven Universe: The Movie</strong></p>
<p>I&rsquo;m not super fond of musicals, and this was most certainly a musical. Generally, I&rsquo;ve enjoyed Steven Universe, but more so when it&rsquo;s weird, and not saccharine. This movie leaned more towards the latter, so it was cute, but not really my bag. If singing and supportive friendships are your favorite part of the show, you&rsquo;ll love the movie. TL;DR your ex&rsquo;s polycule adopts you.</p>
<p><strong>Godzilla: King of Monsters</strong></p>
<p>Ridiculous, but exactly what I expected. A bit of Godzilla, a bit of the Core. I&rsquo;m fascinated by the idea that &ldquo;eco-terrorists&rdquo; have wide-reaching military power, lol. Shin Godzilla is still the best movie in the series, hands down, but this was a silly action romp.</p>
<p><strong>MI-5</strong></p>
<p>I fondly remember the British show <em>Spooks</em>, which ended in 2011. This movie was a nice reminder of the great things about that silly spy show.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>August</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-08-30-media-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-08-30-media-diet/</guid>
      <description>Books The Light Brigade — Kameron Hurley
Definite Catch-22 vibes throughout this book, with a hearty helping of Starship Troopers. If you like time-travel and space military, this is a solid read.</description>
      <content:encoded><h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p><em>The Light Brigade</em> — Kameron Hurley</p>
<p>Definite Catch-22 vibes throughout this book, with a hearty helping of Starship Troopers. If you like time-travel and space military, this is a solid read.</p>
<p><em>The Psychology of Time Travel</em> — Kate Mascarenhas</p>
<p>Ah, time-travel and lesbians: two of my favorite things. This book was an interesting take on time-travel, and inevitable meeting of your future and past selves. I really enjoyed the small strange moments between characters.</p>
<p><em>From the Fatherland with Love</em> — Ryu Murakami</p>
<p>One of the more bonkers books that Ryu Murakami has written, it combines both  his fascination with violence with a scathing satire on bureaucracy. I couldn’t put this down and found myself alternatively horrified and laughing.</p>
<p><em>The Book of Joan</em> — Lydia Yuknavitch</p>
<p>This was a very strange, disjointed tale of a post-apocalyptic redemption narrative. I can’t say that I know a lot about Joan of Arc, but I trust that Yuknavitch drew from her history to write this. I can’t decide quite how I feel about this, but I will say that I found the author’s obsession with genitals and gender rather much. Does the author dislike trans people? Was she attempting to suggest that they are leading us to a dark, genderless place? This was unclear. There was a blurb that claimed this author is at the forefront of writing about gender fluidity, and I would say instead, she is mired deep in the past.</p>
<p><em>Magic for Liars</em> — Sarah Gailey</p>
<p>Ah! I loved this book. What a brilliant marriage of noir and magic school. I devoured it in two sittings with a big grin on my face. Gailey is a delight, and after seeing them read the first chapter in person, I couldn’t wait to dive in. I hope they write more novels soon.</p>
<p><em>River of Teeth</em> — Sarah Gailey</p>
<p>What an absurd romp. This would’ve worked better for me if I enjoyed cowboys or the romance of men, but still it was fun enough. I don’t think I’ll read the next few books in this series, but I’m certain my friend in book club will devour them. Well-written and imagined, just not for me.</p>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<p><em>Battle Angel Alita</em></p>
<p>I read this comic when I was younger, and it’s kind of neat to see it made into a live action film. I still can’t get over the uncanny valley eyes that Rose Salazar’s character has though. Overall, this was ￼￼a fun action film.</p>
<p><em>The Predator</em></p>
<p>I’ve seen folks watching this on a bunch of planes in the past year or so, and as a long-time fan of the Predator, I entered into it grudgingly. The first two films were tight thrillers, but at this point, I can’t tell what the series wants to be. If you can watch this for free, I guess it’s ok?</p>
<p><em>Bad Times at the El Royale</em></p>
<p>This was fun enough, with a pretty good ensemble cast. Nothing really stuck out as excellent, and in a few ways it felt like a less-ambitious Tarantino film.</p>
<p><em>The Quake</em></p>
<p>A good reminder that disaster movies don’t need to have the glitz and glam of a big budget Hollywood film. This sequel to The Wave was rather slowly-paced, but exciting as it picked up steam.</p>
<p><em>Killing of a Sacred Deer</em></p>
<p>Wow, this was an eerie film. At this point I’ve enough of Yorgos Lanthimos’ films that I enter into them thinking “what’s the strange twist?” This film delivered on that quite well. I love the strange, flat performance Lanthimos actors provide—they lure you into this world with everything just /a bit/ off. Also the young man in the film was /haunting/.</p>
<p><em>First Reformed</em></p>
<p>I went into this movie thinking &ldquo;it&rsquo;s about religion and maybe climate change&rdquo;. That covers it to a degree, but beyond that is so much truth and sadness. This was a grim, beautiful film that struck me right at the core—both as an ex-religious person, and someone who often mourns for the end of life for so many folks effected by climate change. The movie, at it&rsquo;s core, asks if there&rsquo;s any forgiveness for our destruction of the planet, for our destruction of humanity. I don&rsquo;t have an answer to that question. This film however, was excellent.</p>
<p><em>The Lobster</em></p>
<p>I can now say that I have indeed considered the Lobster. After seeing The Favourite earlier this year, I decided to go back to watch Yorgos Lanthimos‘ other films. I’m glad I did. This was fantastic.</p>
<p><em>The Ceremony (儀式)</em></p>
<p>A bizarre 70s Japanese film about family, duty, and incest. Reading about this film, it seems like much of it was meant to be an indictment of the older generation, as well as the younger generation’s unwillingness to speak out against tradition. As a film, it’s truly strange, but also brutal in its methodical breakdown of the protagonist.</p>
<p><em>Hobbs &amp; Shaw</em></p>
<p>A very silly buddy comedy. They talk about balls a bit too often for a movie with two 50 year old protagonists, but it was fun at times. There’s very little connection between this and Fast &amp; Furious, but if you like Stratham &amp; The Rock, you’ll have fun.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>July</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-07-25-media-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-07-25-media-diet/</guid>
      <description>Books Dune — Frank Herbert
A classic. I read this when I was a kid, but hadn’t reread it since then.</description>
      <content:encoded><h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p><strong>Dune</strong> — Frank Herbert</p>
<p>A classic. I read this when I was a kid, but hadn’t reread it since then. It’s weird, long, and great. The rest of the series is supposed to be bizarre, so I can’t wait. The spice must flow.</p>
<p><strong>Claire DeWitt and the City of the Dead</strong> — Sara Gran</p>
<p>An alright mystery book, but more than a few times, I think the author attempted to add <em>grit</em> but just ended up sounding like a very awkward narrator. Also points off for a trans slur—like, c’mon, I don’t care who your narrator or, or how much of a fuck-up she is, leave us alone.</p>
<p><strong>Paradise Rot</strong> — Jenny Hval</p>
<p>A strange story of roommates, love, and interior mold. I hope Hval writes more strange books.</p>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<p><strong>The Farewell</strong></p>
<p>I cried a lot during this film. Awkwafina did a fantastic job, and it&rsquo;s cool to see a major US release mostly in Mandarin. If you&rsquo;ve recently lost a grandparent, or have gone through family illness, this might just hit you really hard.</p>
<p><strong>Once Upon a Time in Hollywood</strong></p>
<p>This was a very strange movie, even by Tarentino&rsquo;s standards. A mix of fake show clips, stories of a man and his valet, and glimpses into the Manson family. I laughed quite a bit, and generally found this movie to be a blast.</p>
<p><strong>A Vigilante</strong></p>
<p>This was hard to watch. It was very well done, and intensely paced, but the abuse in the films was painful. There’s a grim morality in this film, and a certain catharsis in seeing abusers punished, but fuck.</p>
<p><strong>Thoroughbreads</strong></p>
<p>A fantastically creepy film about ennui and friendship. I loved it.</p>
<p><strong>Spiderman: Far from Home</strong></p>
<p>This is exactly what I want from a superhero movie: fun. The stakes were much smaller than an Avengers movie, despite this film happening in the aftermath of both the “blip” and many deaths, and that’s a good thing. Instead of world-changing events, we got to enjoy Peter and his classmates goofing around in Europe, and the zany world of Mysterio. I loved this movie. The action was exciting, and the jokes were silly and fun.</p>
<p><strong>Hospitalitié (歓待)</strong></p>
<p>A strange movie reminiscent of a short story I read years ago where. house guests slowly take over a family’s home. It’s dark, funny, and a poignant commentary on xenophobia.</p>
<p><strong>Midsommar</strong></p>
<p>Wow. What a gorgeous, twisted, wild film. From the music to the ultra-bright summer of it all, I loved this movie. If you’re quite squeamish, give it a pass. Otherwise, skål!</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-06-30-media-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-06-30-media-diet/</guid>
      <description>Books The Fated Sky — Mary Robinette Kowal
More cool space stuff! I enjoyed the pacing more in this book, and despite the frustration with very 50s attitudes that still pervade the modern world, I enjoyed journeying with these two books to mars.</description>
      <content:encoded><h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p><strong>The Fated Sky</strong> — Mary Robinette Kowal</p>
<p>More cool space stuff! I enjoyed the pacing more in this book, and despite the frustration with very 50s attitudes that still pervade the modern world, I enjoyed journeying with these two books to mars.</p>
<p><strong>The Bone Clocks</strong> — David Mitchell</p>
<p>A delightful collision of strange characters across time. This book is <em>just</em> fantastical enough to scratch my sci-fi itch, and literary enough to keep me satisfied. I hadn’t read Michell in a while, but diving back in was like slipping on a well-fitting shoe. My only complaint is that I got a bit sick of “psycho-“ being applied to every magic thing, as it felt a bit too much like RPG spell naming, lol.</p>
<p><strong>An Elderly Lady Is Up to No Good</strong> — Helene Tursten</p>
<p>Delightfully wicked tales of a murderous octogenarian. I laughed, and cringed in turn. A short, strange read.</p>
<p><strong>The Calculating Stars</strong> — Mary Robinette Kowal</p>
<p>This is an interesting alternate history where a disaster changes the fate of the planet, and accelerates the space race. Unfortunately, no disaster can change the rampant misogyny and racism of the men in power in this world. The protagonist, Dr. York, is a calculator, and dreams of being an astronaut, after years of flying planes as a WASP. I’m excited to read the sequel, but so many of the scenes of men being jerks to everyone else were pretty frustrating.</p>
<p><strong>Exhalation: Stories</strong> — Ted Chiang</p>
<p>Chiang is one of the only authors I’ve read that truly puts the “speculative” into speculative fiction. Combining a curiosity about math, physics, and philosophy, Exhalation’s stories show a very adept storyteller playing with quite a few ideas. Each story is so different, and yet similarly great. I really hope Chiang writes a novel at some point, because I want to roam around his world’s for much longer.</p>
<p><strong>Sourdough</strong> — Robin Sloan</p>
<p>A fun book on getting into a new hobby, and getting out of tech. I’m not a baker, but I really liked how Robin described the baking process. There weren’t many characters with real depth, but our protagonist was fun.</p>
<p><strong>The Book of M</strong> — Peng Shepherd</p>
<p>An interesting take on a plague/zombie-style post-apocalypse. I had trouble putting this book down, and the story kept me reading most of the day. I got to hear Shepherd read from her book at a literary event in the bay, and I’m very glad I did—this book ruled.</p>
<p><strong>Noumenon: Infinity</strong> — Marina J. Lostetter</p>
<p>This series ruled. There were pretty significant characters who were trans, or differently abled, and I feel like they were written pretty dang well. The space exploration and discovery plotlines split and re-intertwined many times, and always kept me fascinated. Definitely one of the most interesting sci-fi series I’ve read in years.</p>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<p><strong>Force Majeure</strong></p>
<p>A slow burn of a movie. Largely, this is about a family, and a father who is kind of a shit. Tormund from GoT shows up. Lots of skiing. Grey fog. Fin.</p>
<p><strong>Ralph Breaks the Internet</strong></p>
<p>This was super cute, with a nice mix of weird jokes and internet references. It’s wild how many amazing actors they got to join in the strange fun. If you liked the first film, you’ll enjoy the new one.</p>
<p><strong>X-Men: Dark Phoenix</strong></p>
<p>This movie wasn&rsquo;t as bad as critics have said, which isn&rsquo;t exactly a ringing endorsement. Out of the<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/X-Men:_The_Last_Stand"> two treatments</a> of the Dark Phoenix, I think this one was better. The story was a bit odd, but overall, it was fun and a lot of shit blew up. B- summer pap.</p>
<p><strong>Starfish</strong></p>
<p>A largely solo trek through grief, loneliness, and the end of the world. The soundtrack to Starfish was excellent, as was the performance of Ginny Gardner. Without spoiling anything, it’s best to say this movie goes in interesting directions and is shot beautifully.</p>
<h2 id="tv">TV</h2>
<p><strong>Good Omens</strong></p>
<p>The best parts of this show were the weirdly delightful friendship scenes between Sheen and Tennant. I hadn&rsquo;t read this book, but the story moved along at a good clip, and remained strange and funny enough to delight me.</p>
<p><strong>Bake-Off: Professionals</strong></p>
<p>I watched two seasons of this show this month—the second season is currently airing. It&rsquo;s got the drama and silliness of GBBO, but with teams of two, and A &amp; B groups that whittle down for a final set of showdowns. Liam does a great job hosting, and just like GBBO this show is a warm and fun thing to watch while unwinding.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-05-24-media-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-05-24-media-diet/</guid>
      <description>This was a really great month for books largely because I got really into the Themis Files series. Price’s book on breaking up with your phone also encouraged me to pick up my Kindle more than I refreshed Twitter, and honestly, so far that’s been a positive experience.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>This was a really great month for books largely because I got really into the Themis Files series. Price’s book on breaking up with your phone also encouraged me to pick up my Kindle more than I refreshed Twitter, and honestly, so far that’s been a positive experience.</p>
<h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p><strong>Noumenon</strong> — Marina J. Lostetter</p>
<p>Ah! Another great multi-generational space exploration story. I don&rsquo;t really get why so many sci-fi books are doing this sort of thing lately, but I&rsquo;m into it. What happens when a ship heads into deep space to explore a distant star? This book. It rules.</p>
<p><strong>Exit Strategy</strong> — Martha Wells</p>
<p>A delightful end to this quadrilogy. I hope we get more Murderbot stories, but even if not, I&rsquo;ve thoroughly enjoyed it.</p>
<p><strong>Rogue Protocol</strong> — Martha Wells</p>
<p>I’m really loving this series. Murderbot meets a new pal on this romp on a research station.</p>
<p><strong>Hatching Twitter</strong> — Nick Bilton</p>
<p>This was a tour of betrayal, man-children, and absurd amounts of money. I’d love to see an Armando Ianucci adaptation of this book—especially the incredibly awkward visits with Zuckerberg. Well-written, and easy to read, this kept me very entertained on my flight.</p>
<p><strong>Artificial Condition</strong> — Martha wells</p>
<p>It’s really nice to dive back into the series, and the MurderBot continues to be a funny narrator a distant space-bound future. I still think it’s a little odd that these were all published as novellas instead of a full-length, but the episodic quality does give me an easy place to pause and get more to drink. I hope we see more of the new ComfortBot.</p>
<p><strong>Only Human</strong> — Sylvain Neuvel</p>
<p>A solid conclusion to an excellent series. It’s too bad there’s not any more to read, but on the upside, it never dipped into uninteresting territory. The tone of this book is a little post-apocalyptic, and I’m a sucker for that kinda thing.</p>
<p><strong>Waking Gods</strong> — Sylvain Neuvel</p>
<p>This is a series that seems to amp up the excitement with each installation. The first book set the stage, and this is the play. There is quite a bit of action, and a lot of fallout from the first book. A great sequel.</p>
<p><strong>Sleeping Giants</strong> — Sylvain Neuvel</p>
<p>Told through a series of interview transcripts, de-briefings, and diary entries, this rad giant robot story managed to suck me in fast. I burned through this book in a couple of days, and loved every minute. I grew up on Robotech, so some of this plot felt familiar, except without all the singing. If you like giant robots, and somewhat mysterious non-governmental entities, this is a series to check out.</p>
<p><strong>The Traveling Cat Chronicles</strong> — Hiro Arikawa</p>
<p>This book was an emotional rollercoaster. I should’ve be surprised, since it’s about a cat—one of the few things that makes me feel all of the emotions, but wow. This book was very, very good from start to finish. I picked it up on a whim, and it’s perhaps my favorite of the year.</p>
<p><strong>How to Break Up With Your Phone</strong> — Catherine Price</p>
<p>A pretty solid book on establishing more thoughtful ways of dealing with our devices. The advice to think about <em>why</em> you’re reaching for your phone when you do is extremely good, and deceptively simple. I’ve found myself trying to just be in a place without immediately flipping though phone screens to kill time, and <em>maybe</em> it’s helping? I’m going to keep on following the advice of this book for a while, and see how it helps or doesn’t. There’s good advice on email and other types of organization in here as well.</p>
<p><strong>Killing Commentadore</strong> — Haruki Murakami</p>
<p>This novel feels like a return to form, and yet also building on themes and ideas Murakami laid down in earlier books. His obsessions with pits, cats, WW2 history, jazz, and simple lunches are all here. I&rsquo;m a little tired of the downtrodden male narrator, but despite being first-person, generally our painter guide moved the story along, interspersed with interesting observations. If you enjoy Murakami, there&rsquo;s much joy here. I hope this author is with us for quite some time to come.</p>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<p><strong>Wandering Earth</strong></p>
<p>This is the second-highest grossing film in Chinese cinematic history. I’ve heard about this book for a while, and conceptually it’s interesting to think about the Earth moving instead of colony ships leaving, but it’s frustrating that Chinese censors meant that the themes of the film are somewhat limited. The end result felt more like The Core than Star Wars, and overall it was rather disappointing.</p>
<p><strong>John Wick 3</strong></p>
<p>Ridiculous from start to finish. The fights were fun, the plot moved forward at a fast clip, and this is one of my favorite silly action franchise.</p>
<p><strong>Lego Movie: Part 2</strong></p>
<p>Fun, but didn’t match up to the sheer weird joy of the first movie.</p>
<p><strong>Detective Pikachu</strong></p>
<p>Hilarious and so, so fun. This was definitely a kids movie, but aimed solidly at kids who’re 28-35 now—my generation has the funds to relive our childhoods in cinema. I played a few Pokémon games, and watched the cartoon for a little while in middle school, and seeing all of the Pokémon I know flitting around the screen was a hoot. Ryan Reynolds did some fantastic Pikachu voice acting, matched by the incredible CGI of his fur. One of the sillier, funnier movies I’ve seen in a minute. “My clues!”</p>
<p><strong>Burning</strong></p>
<p>It’s been years since I read the story that this movie was inspired by, so I barely remember it. The pacing of Burning was slow, but each shot was artful, and each scene a strange delight. Also, the ambling, slightly clueless protagonist seemed to fit right in to Murakami world.</p>
<p><strong>Arctic</strong></p>
<p>This was in a really intense movie about how fucking cold it can get in the Arctic, and how scary it is to be crashed there. I like to think that this is somehow an extension of the Hannibal universe, and that in order to escape capture he became a pilot.</p>
<h2 id="tv">TV</h2>
<p><strong>Ghost in the Shell SAC</strong></p>
<p>I finally finished this series! I stole my haircut (sorta) from the protagonist from Ghost in the Shell, but I’d never made it through the early 2000s anime series. It’s very episodic, and uneven, but there are so many highlights and breathtaking scenes. It’s definitely a classic.</p>
<p><strong>Barry</strong></p>
<p>It’s funny that this show and Patriot exist at the same time, since both tackle duty, and the idea that someone who mostly kills people and carries out clandestine tasks has a fun side. Bill Hader hasn’t ever been a favorite of mine, but I seriously love this goofy show. Everyone, from Henry Winkler, to Stephen Root, to the guy who plays the extremely friendly mafioso is giving their all.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-04-27-media-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-04-27-media-diet/</guid>
      <description>Books The United States of Japan — Peter Tieryas
An alternate history where Japan and Germany won WW2, then proceeded to divvy up North America.</description>
      <content:encoded><p><img src="https://screenanarchy.com/assets_c/2018/02/IFFR2018-review-Niswog-main-thumb-860xauto-70015.jpg" alt="nigh"></p>
<h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p><strong>The United States of Japan</strong> — Peter Tieryas</p>
<p>An alternate history where Japan and Germany won WW2, then proceeded to divvy up North America. Most of the book is set in the 80s, in a world of internet devices, and giant robots, ruled by the Japanese emperor. It&rsquo;s a brutal story at times, but was generally interesting and a good sci-fi time.</p>
<p><strong>If Cats Disappeared from the World</strong> — Genki Kawarmura <a href="#ghost">**</a></p>
<p>I love a good devil’s bargain, and this book is full of them. This was a cute, sweet story about the real things we should value in life, and what we’re willing to sacrifice for life. The small details and strange obsessions reminded me a lot of Haruki Murakami’s style.</p>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<p><strong>Avengers:Endgame</strong></p>
<p>This was like three movies jammed into one. It was fine, but I hope they stop doing the massive super hero stuff for a while.</p>
<p><strong>Hagazussa</strong></p>
<p>Bizarre and utterly obsessed with liquids. Hard to watch, but also beautiful at times.</p>
<p><strong>Still Walking</strong></p>
<p>A delightful meditation on family. I watched an earlier Koreeda movie called <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nobody_Knows_(2004_film)">Nobody Knows</a> just after college, and it destroyed me. I mostly forgot about this director until Shoplifters last year, and damn, I loved that film too. I think i only have the emotional wherewithal to watch something he made every few months, but each time I dive into his world, there’s an incredible depth to how he shows the small ways we love and lose each other. Also it’s wild to see You-san in an acting role, and not on the Terrace House couch.</p>
<p><strong>Little</strong></p>
<p>I don’t know where to start with this weird mess of a movie. It was super funny at times, but left a lot on the cutting floor, had an utterly bizarre trans “joke”, and the worst driving scenes I’ve seen. At the same time, it was goofy, cute, and a man behind us loudly said, “that’s her when she was little”.</p>
<p><strong>Glass</strong></p>
<p>Well, I’ve finished Shyamalan’s weird comic trilogy. I remember watching Unbreakable in the theater at the mall near my house as a kid. I’d don’t know if that mall even exists anymore, but for a while, you could go to the arcade downstairs, and then watch a movie in the theater near the food court. I was straight-up enamored with Shyamalan at the time. Sixth Sense was fresh on my mind, and Unbreakable was bizarre, but hinted at something wild. Subsequent movies took this M. Night from a must watch icon, to an amusing auteur, and I think that’s great. The Happening is a movie I deeply love, but this trilogy never really lived up to either the mystery or weirdness of his best work. I think in an effort to make a meta-comic movie, he made something that ultimately doesn’t deliver much past a so-so premise that heroes <em>do</em> exist. Which, is fine, but isn’t “he was dead the whole time,” or “the plants!”</p>
<p><strong>The Night is Short, Walk on Girl</strong></p>
<p>This movie is gorgeous, which is to be expected from one of <a href="https://www.amazon.com/ART-BOOK-NOW-Yusuke-Nakamura/dp/4864103844">Yusuke Nakamura’s</a> works. The plot is pretty bonkers, and includes everything from strange gods, rare alcohols, and a collection of Classical Japanese porn. If you like this, you might also love <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Tatami_Galaxy">Tatami Galaxy</a> from the same folks. There’s a certain spiritual similarity to Tampopo in this film’s over-the-top appreciation for food and drinks too.</p>
<p><strong>Tampopo</strong></p>
<p>This was a really fun movie about how amazing food can be. Tons of literal and figurative porn scenes about noodles, eggs, and more. The western film style is kinda wacky and silly, but the overall tone was interesting. I was a bit out of it when I watched this film, so I missed some of it, but likely this&rsquo;ll be a rewatch.</p>
<p><strong>Us</strong></p>
<p>Super spooky. I don’t want to spoil anything, but the combination of very good dad jokes, incredibly talented actors, and tight pacing kept this film feeling scary and fun throughout. There’s twists and turns, and a very good boat name or two. See this movie. I’m stoked we get to see more of Peele’s work in the future.</p>
<p><strong>Prospect</strong></p>
<p>What a cool movie. This tense space flick proved that you can do a lot of sci-fi stuff with less budget. I love media about shitty tech, and this is kind of “what happens when you’re a skint space prospector” angle down pat. This could’ve been a weird Cowboy Bebop live action, but instead tackled the idea from a different angle. Sophie Thatcher rules, too. Wherever this was shot, it was gorgeous.</p>
<h2 id="notable-tv">Notable TV</h2>
<p><strong>Fleabag</strong></p>
<p>Season 2 of this amazing show just built on the hilarity and sadness of the first. Waller-Bridges is brilliant, and it’s amazing we get both this show and Killing Eve. Fleabag is a meditation on family, loss, and love. It’s also one of the best shows I’ve ever seen.</p>
<p><strong>Homecoming</strong></p>
<p>The end scenes of every episode give off a really Lynchian vibe. I never listened to this podcast, so I had no idea where the show was going. Julia Roberts is great, and Bobby Canavalle is a delightful villain. The filming was quite nice, with consistently interesting framing.</p>
<p><strong>Hanna</strong></p>
<p>I loved this movie when it came out years ago, with Saiorse Ronan and a Chemical Brothers soundtrack, and this new adaptation was even better. The score was haunting, and the pacing and characters stayed interesting. I’m not sure if there’s anything left for a second season, but I’d love to see more rad, competent Hanna scenes.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-03-24-media-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-03-24-media-diet/</guid>
      <description>Books The City in the Middle of the Night — Charlie Jane Anders
A fantastic book about humankind settling on a tidally-locked planet, but instead of seeing how we cope, we learn the stories of their descendants, hundreds of years after our first tentative steps.</description>
      <content:encoded><h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p><strong>The City in the Middle of the Night</strong> — Charlie Jane Anders</p>
<p>A fantastic book about humankind settling on a tidally-locked planet, but instead of seeing how we cope, we learn the stories of their descendants, hundreds of years after our first tentative steps. The light is too bright and hot, and the night too cold and dark. We live on the edge in an eternal dusk/morning light. The two protagonists, Mouth, and Sophie, are on the edges of society, yearning for things they&rsquo;ve lost or can&rsquo;t have, and all that leads towards. This book was a beautiful meditation on love and community, as well as memory. If you&rsquo;ve read the Steerswoman series, you might find some familiarity, but generally the genre of lost technology and future worlds is incredibly fascinating to me.</p>
<p><strong>Vengeful</strong> — VE Schwab</p>
<p>An interesting sequel to Vicious, the first of the Villains series. Most of the book serves as a prologue for the lighting-fast action at the end of the book, and I’m very excited to see what these characters do next, if she continues for a third installment. I really enjoyed the character June, because who doesn’t love a shapeshifting assassin?</p>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<p><strong>Captain Marvel</strong></p>
<p>Super fun! Brie Larson made for a very compelling super hero, and I love Goose with my whole heart. The 90s throwback setting was a delight, along with its soundtrack. I’m stoked to see what this sets up for future Marvel films, and hopeful that we see the Skrull again (please show up in Runaways).</p>
<p><strong>Flavors of Youth</strong></p>
<p>An alright film about the things we leave behind as we grow older, and the tastes and regrets we have. Most of this film is set in China, which is an interesting place to hear all the characters speak Japanese. There are three vignettes, and none really tugged my heartstrings, but it was still a well done movie.</p>
<h2 id="noteable-tv">Noteable TV</h2>
<p><strong>F1: Drive to Survive</strong></p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve followed F1 racing for years, and love the drama and speed. This series shows the myriad stories and personalities that make these ten teams and twenty drivers so cool. Even if you&rsquo;ve never watched a single race, you might be drawn in by this series. I&rsquo;d forgotten how wild the 2018 season is, and 2019 has only just begun. 19 more races this year to see if someone can finally edge out Ferrari or Mercedes</p>
<p><strong>Pen15</strong></p>
<p>This is an incredible show about middle school, embarrassment, and friendship. It covers so much ground and captures the 90s perfectly. The main actresses (in their 30s) seem to have a blast in every scene, and I bet filming with actual children was a trip. My favorite line was “I found that dress in a river”.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>February</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-02-24-media-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-02-24-media-diet/</guid>
      <description>Books Genocidal Organ — Project Itoh
A truly grim thriller about the cost of “fighting terrorism,” and the ability of language to tear apart a country.</description>
      <content:encoded><h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p><strong>Genocidal Organ</strong> — Project Itoh</p>
<p>A truly grim thriller about the cost of “fighting terrorism,” and the ability of language to tear apart a country. This feels eerily prescient. I can’t say I <em>enjoyed</em> reading this book, but it’s a nihilistic political commentary that at least adds some color to what politicians might be after when they start wars and conflicts. This book is graphic, violent, and in its way, poignant.</p>
<p><strong>Amberlough</strong> — Lara Elena Donnelly <a href="#ghost">**</a></p>
<p>In some ways this reminded me of the show Babylon Berlin—it feels like an alternate reality 20s Germany, replete with spies, dancers, pasties, and patsies. I think it&rsquo;s building up to a longer series, and so much of the plot slowly churned towards an ellipsis of an ending. I liked it, but I&rsquo;m not rushing to read the next one. None of the characters necessarily captured my interest, but it was nice that the protagonists were largely gay. This book answers the question, what if folks wrote new stories with their own characters instead of fanfic.</p>
<p><strong>Reclaiming Your Life from IBS</strong> — Melissa Hunt</p>
<p>My doctor recommended this, and it&rsquo;s largely CBT 101 + some good notes on food and stress. I don&rsquo;t know if it&rsquo;ll be super useful, but we&rsquo;ll see! I don&rsquo;t even know if this is a problem I face, but the doctor said &ldquo;probably&rdquo;, so lol.</p>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<p><strong>Anna and the Apocalypse</strong></p>
<p>A high-school musical with zombies. I really don’t like musicals, to be honest. I’d heard good things about this one though, and wanted to give it a chance. The cast is doing a pretty good job throughout, though the relatively one-dimensional characters of the “hot jock” and the “asshole headmaster” are schlocky. This movie mostly made me want to watch Sean of the Dead again, which used rock music to better effect.</p>
<p><strong>Polar</strong></p>
<p>Mads Mikkelsen got his Takeshi Kitano take-no-prisoners action role. This movie was adapted from a comic, and it feels just like a comic, down to the choppy dialogue, fast-paced action, and dead-simple plot. It’s kinda fun, if you can get over the copious amounts of cartoonish murder.</p>
<p><strong>Piercing</strong></p>
<p>Weird. I read this book probably 10 years ago, and enjoyed it. The movie is a lighter adaptation, as it’s trickier to capture internal dialogue on film. Mia Wasikowska is outstanding as usual. I also enjoyed the general 70s aesthetic, and the cool selection of lingerie. This film only clocks in at about an hour and twenty minutes, but manages to build and release tension a few times.</p>
<p><strong>Spy</strong></p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t know why I slept on this film. I guess I like Paul Fieg movies? This is delightful fare from Melissa Mcarthy, and a solid supporting cast.</p>
<h2 id="notable-tv">Notable TV</h2>
<p><strong>True Detective Season 3</strong></p>
<p>There were plenty of twists, and turns, and emotional volleys in this show. Mahershala Ali and Carmen Ejogo were electric, and despite it not being about anything magic (a girl can dream of ghosts and monsters), it was still gorgeous, sad, and <em>true</em>.</p>
<p><strong>Russian Doll</strong></p>
<p>A Groundhog Day about depression, drugs, sex, and probably psychodynamics. It’s good.</p>
<p><strong>Travellers</strong></p>
<p>I’m sad this got cancelled for season 4, but it’s probably still worth watching for the 3 seasons we got. Time Travelers take over the bodies of folks in present day to prevent an apocalyptic event. Fun sci-fi.</p>
<p><strong>Sex Education</strong></p>
<p>Gillian Anderson &amp; youthful hilarity. Lots of new actors and actresses in this one that I hope we’ll see again soon.</p>
<p><strong>Magicians Season 4</strong></p>
<p>This went from being a very good version of a solid book series, to so much more. Excellent acting. This show balances serious with silly incredibly well.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-01-24-media-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-01-24-media-diet/</guid>
      <description>It’s a new year! Time to watch even more shows and movies, and with the rise of bingeable 10 hour TV movies, I have found myself watching fewer of the 90-120 minute variety.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>It’s a new year! Time to watch even more shows and movies, and with the rise of bingeable 10 hour TV movies, I have found myself watching fewer of the 90-120 minute variety. With Criteron launching a movie service, maybe that’ll change.</p>
<h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p><strong>The Masked City</strong> — Genevieve Cogman</p>
<p>Another romp through alternate worlds with the rebellious librarian Irene, and her Sherlock stand-in pal Vale. The world of this book is largely a strange version of Venice, but more than the first book, other world’s tech is sprinkled throughout. I’m starting to doubt that we’ll get a high-tech book in this series, but I still hold out hope. The language is a little <em>too</em> powerful as a deus machina, but Cogman finds ways Irene can’t deploy it constantly, and still manages to provide a level of tension and excitement.</p>
<p><strong>9th Step Station</strong> — Malka Older &amp; Co.</p>
<p>This read much like a series of Ghost in the Shell. From the NeoTokyo setting, to the ubiquitous cybernetic body mods, I expected Major Kusanagi to pop up at any juncture. That said, it also ruled. It’s been a long time since I read serialized fiction outside of comics, and the episodic nature made for a fun time. Each author added to the tale, instead of distracting with wild stylistic flourishes. I would happily read another series with Emma, Miyako, and the rest. There were less political machinations that I expected, based on other work from Older, but the story was fun, exciting, and well-told.</p>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<p><strong>Close</strong></p>
<p>Noomi Rapace is a cool, collected bodyguard for a kinda shitty heiress who eventually grows to appreciate her help. Shout out to Indira Varma too, who was great in Luther, Game of Thrones, and now as a potentially treacherous stepmom.</p>
<p><strong>IO</strong></p>
<p>Another great eco-pocalypse movie. Limited cast and locations, but a cool premise overall. This movie was short, but definitely hit many of my speculative fiction check marks. I want to ride an ATV now.</p>
<p><strong>Vox Lux</strong></p>
<p>I loved the intense opening scenes of this film, and the scrolling credits—I’ve rarely seen something like this, and it felt brutal and fresh. Sadly the rest of the film felt like an idea that they forgot to film. Was she the devil? Didn’t explore that. Single mom? Didn’t explore that. There was so much buildup with no payoff. Terrorists? Nah. Long song b-roll? Yep. Even Sia couldn’t be bothered to record anything great for this film. Missed opportunity. This could‘be been Wicked and Divine, the movie.</p>
<p><strong>Destroyer</strong></p>
<p>Another film with Tony Kebbell—seeing him in this after seeing him in Hurricane Heist was a wild ride. I think his American accent got better. Also, Kusama seemed pretty obsessed with Kidman’s face throughout this film. This was a intense sad cop/revenge film, with elements from many old sad cop guy films—transformed into something new by letting the old cop be a woman. I really appreciated the Halt &amp; Catch Fire alumni, as well as the always delightful Tatiana Maslany. This movie felt like a different era, and painted LA in a grim, dusty light.</p>
<p><strong>Shoplifters</strong></p>
<p>What a fantastic film. In some ways this reminded me of the anime Tokyo Godfathers—which is also about a group of underground folks taking in a child. The way Shoplifters weaved chosen family in with delightful vignettes and outstanding performances by two children was masterful. This felt like a Japan that rarely appears in cinema—a group of folks struggling with poverty, and not sure how to be part of a society that seems to expect them to join in. I will probably rewatch this, and highly recommend it.</p>
<p><strong>Hurricane Heist</strong></p>
<p>I knew going in that this would be a bonkers film, having listened to the How Did This Get Made episode about it, but wow. Everyone in this film except for Maggie Grace is from England or Australia, and their accents are absurd. I feel like everyone got drunk, decided to use an “Alabama accent” and then a movie happened. Nothing that happened made sense, but also it was a hoot.</p>
<p><strong>Assasination Nation</strong></p>
<p>I’m still not sure what I saw. I <em>think</em> this aims to be a cautionary tale about mob rule, privacy, and misogyny. It’s brutal, graphic, and so full of -isms, I can’t say I recommend it. It’s wild that this movie played in theaters. I’m kinda stoked Hari Nef got to be a mean teen trans lady. By the end there’s a revenge bloodbath that I can’t tell if I was meant to find cathartic, or sad. This is definitely the most misanthropic and nihilistic movie I&rsquo;ve seen in years.</p>
<h2 id="notable-tv">Notable TV</h2>
<p><strong>Tidying Up</strong></p>
<p>The masterfully Capricorn books on tidying-up are now a tv show. I watched all 8 episodes while cleaning my house, in one long fever-dream. Many of the couples are amazing, and at least one felt like they were on the verge of a divorce.</p>
<p><strong>Terror in Resonance</strong></p>
<p>An anime from a few years ago. The story is a relatively common one these days, of youth attempting to “wake up the world” through a pointed terrorism. The music from Yoko Kanno is <em>outstanding</em> but sadly doesn’t appear on streaming services, but is probably somewhere on YouTube.</p>
<p><strong>Into the Dark</strong></p>
<p>A horror-of-the-month series. Each story is a movie-length fright set in the month it premieres, from a murder on Halloween, to a woman dealing with agoraphobia around Thanksgiving. It’s well-shot, and probably worth checking out if you enjoy horror-ish films.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>December</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-12-20-media-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-12-20-media-diet/</guid>
      <description>Books Provenance — Ann Leckie
A different planet and culture than the Raadchai from her trilogy, but a very compelling story.</description>
      <content:encoded><h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p><strong>Provenance</strong> — Ann Leckie</p>
<p>A different planet and culture than the Raadchai from her trilogy, but a very compelling story. I got very confused for a while about who was who, but eventually I sorted it out.</p>
<p><strong>The Dark Archive</strong> — Victoria Schwab <a href="#ghost">**</a></p>
<p>A fun, strange YA book about what happens after death, and the teens who defend the afterlife. There were some cool twists, and story details throughout, but the world building could have been better. Honestly every time I read one of these, I think, &ldquo;wouldn’t this be better if it were gay?&rdquo;, and reader, yes, yes it would. These sorts of books must really speak to teens though, because they portray adults as largely ineffectual idiots, who occasionally get in the way.</p>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<p><strong>The Equalizer: 2</strong></p>
<p>This is apparent the first sequel Denzel has ever made. I’ve loved the genre of Denzel as an ultraviolent avenging angel ever since I saw Man on Fire. Some folks may prefer John Wick, and granted, those movies have a great style, but damn, the Equalizer is a series I hope to see more of in the future.</p>
<p><strong>Death of Stalin</strong> (rewatch)</p>
<p>It’s the season for rewatching films.</p>
<p><strong>Slice</strong></p>
<p>Super goofy horror film with lots of great folks. I think B movies can only rarely be made great from the start, and this one could’ve used a little less effort.</p>
<p><strong>The Fast &amp; the Furious</strong> (rewatch)</p>
<p>A few friends hadn’t watched this before, so we drank a bit, and had a rip-roaring good time seeing this again. Everyone is decked-out in the most late 90s gear, the camera work is bonkers, and the cars are cool, but painted like awful hot wheels. I <em>love</em> this series.h</p>
<p><strong>Hereditary</strong></p>
<p>Granted, the central twist was spoiled for me, but so much of this movie felt joyless. Theoretically this movie should’ve been right up my alley, but honestly I would’ve rather rewatched the VVitch for the umpteenth time.</p>
<p><strong>Widows</strong></p>
<p>This was one of my favorite movies of the year. Wow. A all badass lady heist movie with actual stakes! Everyone delivers in this film, and it was a hoot. A+</p>
<p><strong>Crazy Rich Asians</strong></p>
<p>This was a schlocky romcom about a very rarefied set of Chinese Singaporeans. It was fun enough, and now both of the people I saw it with want to flood the aisle of a building during their wedding. Moms are a lot.</p>
<p><strong>Girl with a Dragon Tattoo</strong> (rewatch)</p>
<p>My partner hasn’t seen these, and I would watch them again basically whenever, so here we are.</p>
<p><strong>Ant Man and the Wasp</strong> (rewatch)</p>
<p>Just as delightful the second go-round. More fun superhero movies please.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-11-20-media-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-11-20-media-diet/</guid>
      <description>Books Circe &amp;ndash; Madeline Miller
This book reminded me how much I remember of Greek myth and tragedy. I loved it.</description>
      <content:encoded><h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p><strong>Circe</strong> &ndash; Madeline Miller</p>
<p>This book reminded me how much I remember of Greek myth and tragedy. I loved it. Circe is such an excellent protagonist, at the edges of society, ousted from gods and man alike. If you&rsquo;ve read the Odyssey, this is a must read.</p>
<p><strong>Red Clocks</strong> &ndash; Leni Zumas</p>
<p>A bit too close to our dystopian reality for my liking, but this was well-written, and full of strong and interesting women. I read this as I was leaving Oregon, and so a lot of it was a little bittersweet. This reads as a more realistic (sadly) handmaid&rsquo;s tale.</p>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<p><strong>Skyscraper</strong></p>
<p>So, so ridiculous and terrible&hellip; but also kind of great? Like, what if Die Hard wasn&rsquo;t as good, and had the Rock in Hong Kong? I watched this so I could listen to this week&rsquo;s How Did This Get Made, and I am glad I did.</p>
<p><strong>The Girl in the Spider&rsquo;s Web</strong></p>
<p>We&rsquo;re on our third Lisbeth actress, and while Claire Foy more than filled the shoes of Rooney Mara, the same can&rsquo;t quite be said for whoever replaced Daniel Craig. This was a fun, twisty movie, that was inadvertently stressful for my partner because of all the snow and ice driving. Lisbeth continues to deliver her brand of justice, while &ldquo;then Lisbeth hacks the thing&rdquo; is a major plot device. Kudos to all the lesbians in this, and the giant case of dildos. Fun movie.</p>
<p><strong>The Guilty</strong></p>
<p>A wild single-room movie, that takes place completely over the phone. I love the narrative device, and the slow, dread-filled pacing. The movie largely takes place in your own imagination, helped along by excellent foley, and voice acting.</p>
<p><strong>The First Purge</strong></p>
<p>Yow, what a good mess. I don&rsquo;t know why I love the Purge films, and to be honest, this one felt a little too real. However, I watched this on Halloween, so it fit my needs of a spooky, scary movie.</p>
<p><strong>Halloween (2018)</strong></p>
<p>This was goofy and fun, while still being a twisty thriller. Ultimately, these are morality tales about private property ownership, lol. A+ to Jamie Lee Curtis, and also all the random bit players. Definitely a good popcorn flick with friends.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-10-30-media-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-10-30-media-diet/</guid>
      <description>Books Sympathy — Olivia Sudjic *
Wow, I loved this book. A story centered around sadness, obsession, and longing—for a family, for a lover, for a place.</description>
      <content:encoded><h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p><strong>Sympathy</strong> — Olivia Sudjic <a href="#les">*</a></p>
<p>Wow, I loved this book. A story centered around sadness, obsession, and longing—for a family, for a lover, for a place. This was very well-written, and compelling, especially for a first effort. Some of the same Instagram ground is covered in this as is in Ingrid Goes West, but this felt more real. It&rsquo;s also deeply, darkly hilarious, from the description of the awful tech boyfriend, to just how bad families can be for folks.</p>
<p><strong>Invasions</strong> — Calvin Gimpelevich</p>
<p><a href="_posts/2018-10-14-invasions-review.md">My review</a>. TL;DR it was great. Buy it.</p>
<p><strong>Love &amp; Estrogen</strong> &ndash; Samantha Allen</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t usually read trans memoir&ndash;and I have a forthcoming piece that challenges and lampoons it to a degree&ndash;but Samantha is a friend and her story is close to my heart because of that. I had the chance to chat with her a lot through the course of part of this love and transition story, and I enjoyed the way she told it. This memoir definitely touched on some of the tropes of the genre, but by also being a wonderful love story, it manages to eschew many more.</p>
<p><strong>The Tea Master &amp; the Detective</strong> &ndash; Aliette de Bodard <a href="#ghost">**</a></p>
<p>This was a fun detective tale with a mysterious Sherlock and a spaceship Watson. The setup never quite paid off with its mystery, but I look forward to reading more hooks in the series. I also worried a bit that it would fetishize or exoticize Chinese culture, but outside of the space-protection tea, it largely doesn&rsquo;t come up.</p>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<p><strong>Halloween</strong></p>
<p>A spooky throwback to get ready for the sequel. I guess they made a bunch of these and they were all garbage, and the new movie aims to erase them. I <em>think</em> somehow the only one I&rsquo;d seen was Season of the Witch, which is the 3rd movie in the original set. The 70s were a weird time, and the amount of nudity random &ldquo;gotta take my clothes off&rdquo; is just yikes. Jamie Lee Curtis did a great job. I&rsquo;m hoping the pacing of the new film is more up to modern standards though, because dang, did this feel dated and slow in a lot of ways.</p>
<p><strong>Hotel Artemis</strong></p>
<p>From the preview, I assumed this would be a John Wick knockoff, but it was fun in its own right. Lots of action, Jenny Slate, and a wide array of solid actors. The future is a dismal one, but hey, that checks out.</p>
<p><strong>Beirut</strong></p>
<p>What if John Hamm&rsquo;s Mad Men character was a state department guy turned negotiator? 70s Beirut is a trip in the way it&rsquo;s presented, and knowing a little history, this seems like a wild but semi-accurate portrayal of all the folks who fought over Lebanon during and after the civil war. This is a tonally dark political thriller, and I dug it.</p>
<p><strong>Venom</strong></p>
<p>What a perfectly odd anti-hero film. I was a big Venom fan as a kid, and this movie delivered everything I wanted in a Venom movie. Fuck the haters, this is a hoot. I don&rsquo;t think this should win any prizes for <em>cinema</em> but it&rsquo;s fun, and provided lots of awkward laughs. The action was exciting, and I can&rsquo;t wait for a sequel full of <em>carnage</em>.</p>
<p><strong>Sicario: Day of the Solado</strong></p>
<p>Another ridiculous action film about &ldquo;the cartels&rdquo; that I can&rsquo;t honestly tell is meant to make folks dislike the US or root for us. If you want to watch Cable/Thanos run around and shoot things, this is probalby a good movie for you. I don&rsquo;t find these very clever, but mostly I wish we got an Equalizer-style movie focused on Benecio Del Toro&rsquo;s character. While I&rsquo;m hoping, perhaps Demián Bichir can be in the third movie.</p>
<p><strong>Mandy</strong></p>
<p>A weirdo pyschadelic mess of a movie. I hate that a woman&rsquo;s death is used as a catalyst, but beyond that this is a bloody, ridiculous revenge flick. The music is great throughout and perhaps we were all delirious, but my theater laughed quite a bit.</p>
<p><strong>Dawn of the Dead</strong> (2004/Rewatch)</p>
<p>I could watch this every year. This is an excellent remake of an excellent zombie film. Everyone gives their all, and so many of the deaths, kills, and twists are perfect. A+ work from before Zach Snyder made cruddy films.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>September</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-09-25-media-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-09-25-media-diet/</guid>
      <description>Books State Tectonics — Malka Older
A fantastic conclusion to the Centenal Cycle Trilogy. I wish I could read a few more books from this universe, which I always figure is a great sign with any speculative fiction series.</description>
      <content:encoded><h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p><strong>State Tectonics</strong> — Malka Older</p>
<p>A fantastic conclusion to the Centenal Cycle Trilogy. I wish I could read a few more books from this universe, which I always figure is a great sign with any speculative fiction series. I keep recommending this trilogy to friends, both as an interesting political system, and as a gripping techno-political thriller with some truly rad female characters. I didn&rsquo;t love every PoV character from State Tectonics as much as I did the previous two books, but that makes sense, as this book was about new beginnings, to a degree.</p>
<p><strong>Convenience Store Woman</strong> — Sayaka Murata <a href="#ghost">**</a></p>
<p>Wow. This book was a lot more bizarre than I expected based on the recommendations I&rsquo;d read—more Abe than H. Murakami. I loved the narrator, and the rich descriptions of convenience store life. This book was hilarious and wild. One of my favorites this year.</p>
<p><strong>Would You Rather</strong> — Katie Heaney</p>
<p>A touching memoir of coming-out and learning that past dating disinterest was just latent sapphism, lol. There&rsquo;s a lot to love about this book, and also quite a bit of cringe. It&rsquo;s a coming-of-age in a way, and overall I&rsquo;d recommend it to young dykes and old, or anyone wondering if their sexuality is &ldquo;real&rdquo;.</p>
<p><strong>Worth the Wait</strong> — Karelia Stetz-Waters <a href="les">*</a></p>
<p>This was a corny AF lesbian romance. Lots of random sex, and a main plot of &ldquo;the cute femme can&rsquo;t come out bc reasons&rdquo;. Nothing groundbreaking, but it was an easy read.</p>
<p><strong>Record of a Spaceborn Few</strong> — Becky Chambers</p>
<p>This was a much slower-paced book than the previous two, and was largely a slice of life about Exodans—the humans who left Earth to take their chances in the universe after Earth became uninhabitable. I enjoyed the various characters, the queer relationships, and the color added to this way of life. Sometimes it&rsquo;s nice to have a space scifi book that isn&rsquo;t full of lasers and danger.</p>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<p><strong>A Simple Favor</strong></p>
<p>What a silly, fun movie. It ends up in kind of a weird, messy state by the end, as if Feig is like &ldquo;wait, what if they don&rsquo;t remember I made Bridesmaids?!?&rdquo;, but I generally enjoyed seeing Blake Lively be a cool babe, while Anna Kendrick does her thing. All the side-characters were fun, and even though it felt long, it was also consistently enjoyable.</p>
<p><strong>Blindspotting</strong></p>
<p>This is the third movie I&rsquo;ve seen this year that was shot in Oakland, and I loved it. There is so much intensity, and so many parts that made me hold my breath, but everyone in this, especially Daveed Diggs, just showed-up and did an outstanding job. The criticism of gentrification in this felt more present and painful than Sorry to Bother You, and the raw emotional energy between family and friends here was so good.</p>
<p><strong>The Nun</strong></p>
<p>Lol, this ridiculous series. My friend got me into this while I was recovering from a surgery last year by asking me to watch all the preceding movies before we went to see one of the Annabelle ones. This series delivers spooky times, jump-scares, and a universe completely devoid of a loving god. I&rsquo;m always down for a movie where the evil folks win, and this series is suitably unclear about who actually comes out on top, so I just claim it for the demons.</p>
<p><strong>The Endless</strong></p>
<p>What a bizarre, fantastic film. I loved the world and magic of this movie, as well as the general sense of eerie inevitably. I&rsquo;m excited to see the previous film as well. The shots of this film are a mix of dutch angles, handheld, and some neat CGI. There&rsquo;s quite a bit of upsetting stuff in this film, but it&rsquo;s also a fun ride.</p>
<p><strong>47 Meters Down</strong></p>
<p>Mandy Moore has never scuba-dived, but on a vacation to Mexico, her asshole friend convinces her to scuba in a cage with sharks to forget a man. It goes about as poorly as you’d think. I loved every claustrophobic minute of this. Fuck the ocean, I’m sticking to the rivers and the lakes that I’m used to.</p>
<p><strong>Mary and the Witch&rsquo;s Flower</strong></p>
<p>A cute anime about a young girl who stumbles into the world of witchcraft. Very reminiscent of Howl&rsquo;s Moving Castle, but with a less encompassing world.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>August</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-24-media-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-24-media-diet/</guid>
      <description>Books Fingersmith — Sarah Waters
In an odd turn of fate, I&amp;rsquo;d seen the Handmaiden before I read this book, so the English setting was strange compared to the eerie world of Korean director Park Chan-Wook.</description>
      <content:encoded><h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p><strong>Fingersmith</strong> — Sarah Waters</p>
<p>In an odd turn of fate, I&rsquo;d seen the Handmaiden before I read this book, so
the English setting was strange compared to the eerie world of Korean
director Park Chan-Wook. I knew most of the twists because of the film, but
Waters has a deft way with descriptions, and Maud and Sue came alive on the
page. It felt like I was reading this for weeks, but that&rsquo;s likely because
I devoted little time to reading. I&rsquo;m glad I finished this, and recommend
it if you love multi-layered, deftly-woven stories.</p>
<p><strong>Empire Ascendant</strong> — Kameron Hurley</p>
<p>A wild second installment in the Mirror Empire trilogy that is so
chock-full of characters and their (spoiler alert) doubles, that I got a
bit confused. There&rsquo;s a glossary and character list in the back, but dang,
this is some GoT stuff. I enjoyed the descent into chaos in this book, and
I&rsquo;m eagerly anticipating the conclusion(?) in the third. Also one of the
only books I know that has a character using ze/hir pronouns, but it also
unhelpfully talks about sex as different from and perhaps less malleable
than gender, so I wouldn&rsquo;t call this a &ldquo;dope representation of trans
folks,&rdquo; so much as &ldquo;well there&rsquo;s some genderqueerness I guess&rdquo;.</p>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<p><strong>Den of Thieves</strong></p>
<p>A heist movie with a pretty solid cast. Gerard Butler plays a shitty, dirty cop well. The plot was decently executed, but it&rsquo;s mostly just a movie with lots of bro posturing and guns. Not a bad way to spend a couple hours on the couch.</p>
<p><strong>Masterminds</strong></p>
<p>A ridiculous heist comedy with Zach Galafanakis, Kristen Wiig, and Jason Sudekis. It&rsquo;s about as ridiculous as you would imagine. A+ romp. Lots of quality physical comedy.</p>
<p><strong>Book Club</strong></p>
<p>Watched this on a whim with a couple friends, and it was kinda great?
I love Candace Bergen from the Murphy Brown
days, and hope I look as good as Diane Keaton when I&rsquo;m older. Silly
popcorn fun. Also I guess I own it now because it wasn&rsquo;t available to rent.</p>
<p><strong>The Meg</strong></p>
<p>Wow. This is my new favorite sea-based movie. What an epically hilarious film.
A+ good job everyone.</p>
<p><strong>Mission Impossible Fallout</strong></p>
<p>A wild, nearly 3 hour ride through a comical series of twists and beards. I
laughed out loud often, both at the unearned gravitas, and actual jokes. I
love this series like Tom Cruise loves being an action hero: deeply, and
passionately.</p>
<p><strong>Ready Player One</strong></p>
<p>I blame my friend Mark, because he chose this for us to watch. It was just
as bad as I thought it would be, but blessedly we could make good jokes
throughout.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>July</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-07-24-media-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-07-24-media-diet/</guid>
      <description>Books Adventure Zone: There Be Gerblins
A masterful adaptation of the podcast D&amp;amp;D romp into a graphic novel. I absolutely loved this.</description>
      <content:encoded><h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p><strong>Adventure Zone: There Be Gerblins</strong></p>
<p>A masterful adaptation of the podcast D&amp;D romp into a graphic novel. I
absolutely loved this. I&rsquo;m not sure if this would be as fun if you hadn&rsquo;t
listened to the podcast, but if you haven&rsquo;t, get on it&hellip; it&rsquo;s free and
it&rsquo;s delightful.</p>
<p><strong>La Bastarda</strong> — Trifonia Melibea Obono <a href="#les">*</a></p>
<p>A lesbian novel from Equatorial Guinea that tells a short story of a woman
abandoned by her father, and orphaned by her mother who finds herself
falling for another woman. The first half was full of build-up and
world-building, but the back half felt like a very rushed piece, as though
Trifonia was hoping to get it all out in a final effort. I enjoyed this
book, but the bits that were glossed over about Okomo&rsquo;s journeys, her
grandfather&rsquo;s death, and other scenes could&rsquo;ve been fleshed-out.</p>
<p><strong>Blackfish City</strong> — Sam J. Miller <a href="#ghost">**</a></p>
<p>This book ruled, and I was super surprised at how much I loved it.
Absolutely riveting, and a blast. The individual characters felt very
distict, and were easy to follow, and the world felt really interesting.</p>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<p><strong>Drive Angry</strong></p>
<p>There are probably worse Nic Cage movies, but this is the worst one I&rsquo;ve
seen. Every scene is painfully bad.</p>
<p><strong>Tomb Raider</strong></p>
<p>Fun, and very surprisingly entertaining for a video game movie. Lots of
&ldquo;oh, I could see how this would play in the game,&rdquo; scenes. Alicia Vikander
is a much better Lara Croft too, imo.</p>
<p><strong>Sorry to Bother You</strong></p>
<p>This is the movie Idiocracy wishes it were. Sorry to Bother You skewers
tech culture, bay-area poverty, racial injustice, and so much more.
Throughout, Tessa, Lakeith, and the rest of the cast deliver awesome
performances. A mix of chilling and laugh-inducing. One of the best films
I&rsquo;ve seen this year.</p>
<p><strong>Tragedy Girls</strong></p>
<p>What a wild, fucked-up movie about social media, murder, and friendship.
Don&rsquo;t do it for the gram.</p>
<p><strong>I, Tonya</strong></p>
<p>Finally watched this with a friend, and wow, it was good but full of very
violent abuse stuff. Growing up in the 80s/90s, Tonya Harding was in a lot
of news, but this definitely filled in a lot of gaps in my knowledge of her
story.</p>
<p><strong>Villainess</strong></p>
<p>What a wonderfully bonkers movie. It kicks off with wild first-person murder
fest, and just goes off-the-rails from there. One of the bloodier and wilder
action films I&rsquo;ve seen in a long time. Loved it.</p>
<p><strong>The Incredibles 2</strong></p>
<p>Watched this a few hours after the first one. The animation has gotten a LOT
better, even though the first one honestly aged pretty well, since they didn&rsquo;t
try to make it photorealistic. The plot was ridiculous again, and they
definitely leaned hard into the &ldquo;men are bad at childcare&rdquo; shit that I
suspected they would. Fun enough though anyways.</p>
<p><strong>The Incredibles</strong></p>
<p>The animation holds up surprisingly well for a few year-old movie, even if
the plot depends on some pretty annoying misogynist tropes. I watched this
to prep for the new movie, and overall it was a fun, if ridiculous, movie.</p>
<p><strong>Ant Man &amp; the Wasp</strong></p>
<p>This was a hoot. Very silly, and pretty PG, but above all else, this felt
like a comic movie. I&rsquo;d compare this to Spiderman Homecoming or a less
stylish Thor Ragnarok. Great summer night movie.</p>
<p><strong>Sicario</strong></p>
<p>What a wild movie, in which I needed to completely suspend all of my
feelings about America, the &ldquo;drug war&rdquo; and Thanos. If you can attempt to
not emotionally connect to the actual monsters in this movie, it&rsquo;s kinda
fun in a &ldquo;tense film where things blow up&rdquo; kind of way.</p>
<p><strong>Gemini</strong></p>
<p>Lesbian murder mystery? Yes. This was fun, even if the music felt super
weird at times. Good bangs. Cool cars. A movie where men are the worst.
Also this seems consistent with the choices and habits of geminis, so, lol.
<em>shots fired</em>.</p>
<p><strong>Jurassic World: Fallen Kingdom</strong></p>
<p>Lol, this movie was absurd. They rushed off the island and so many of the
subplots never really paid off? I can&rsquo;t forget that Pratt is a
conservative, and I didn&rsquo;t really care much about anyone in this film,
except for the dinosaurs. I guess I was rooting for the dinosaurs, and I
figure they probably came out ahead.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>June</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-06-24-media-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-06-24-media-diet/</guid>
      <description>Books Swearing Off Stars — Danielle Wong
Started off alright, but quickly telegraphed to an all-to-common &amp;ldquo;I can&amp;rsquo;t really be with you until it&amp;rsquo;s too late&amp;rdquo; lesbian novel.</description>
      <content:encoded><h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p><strong>Swearing Off Stars</strong> — Danielle Wong</p>
<p>Started off alright, but quickly telegraphed to an all-to-common &ldquo;I can&rsquo;t
really be with you until it&rsquo;s too late&rdquo; lesbian novel. I also kept thinking
an editor had asked her to just add tons of adjectives, willy-nilly. It was
an odd read, and the time-jumps didn&rsquo;t help. If you can write a lesbian
romance in 2017, why would you lean so hard on tropes of one woman dying?
Super annoying. It was a pretty quick read at least. Read for a lesbian
book club.</p>
<p><strong>Little Fish</strong> — Casey Plett</p>
<p>Outstanding and devastating. This is a book full of people I&rsquo;ve known,</p>
<p>slept with, and smiled at across the room. Family is a tenuous thing, and
Little Fish finds space for it throughout. I&rsquo;m not sure what I would&rsquo;ve
made with this years ago, but now, it&rsquo;s a sad and good ache. I hope Casey
keeps writing, and sharing her work with us for years to come. I read this
in one go, and it was a wild ride that had me laughing and crying.</p>
<p><strong>Paprika</strong> — Yasutaka Tsutsui</p>
<p>A fantastically bizarre story of science, dreams, desire, and the smallness
of men. I&rsquo;d seen the anime adapted from this book years ago, so I had some
predisposition towards envisioning characters a certain way, but this book
goes to way different places than I remember the movie going. I liked this
quite a bit, save for the weird shit with sexual assault. Like many books
written by a guy, it shows.</p>
<p><strong>Infidel</strong> — Kameron Hurley</p>
<p>Really loving this series about a tough AF bounty hunter lady named Nyx.
The world-building is pretty interesting, and the story moves forward at a pretty good clip. All-told, this is a fun sci-fi action novel.</p>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<p><strong>Solo</strong></p>
<p>This was probably tied with Last Jedi for my least favorite of the new Star
Wars, but I liked it better than pretty much any of the old or prequel
ones. It was fun, had a few rad women, and didn&rsquo;t go overboard on &ldquo;remember
this?&rdquo; fanservice. I laughed a few times, and I&rsquo;m hoping they make sequels.</p>
<p><strong>Appropriate Behavior</strong></p>
<p>This was a fun movie about being a Persian Bisexual woman in NYC. Shirin
goes through a major breakup, then struggles to date, and heal, while
dealing with a family she doesn&rsquo;t think will understand her queerness, and
the strange world of the NYC queer and poly scene. I laughed out loud
during a lot of this, even as I scratched my head at the confusing
references to trans guys—like, why are they a joke? Overall, I dug this
movie, and hope the director/writer Desiree makes more films soon.</p>
<p><strong>Red Sparrow</strong></p>
<p>I will never believe for one second that the protagonist would fall for Joel
Edgerton&rsquo;s bland spyman. For some reason, I expected this movie to be set
during the cold war, but instead it&rsquo;s vaguely now. This had more sexual
assault than I expected too, which is a fucking bummer. The saving grace in
this film is that by and large Jennifer Lawrence kills or beats all the men
in the movie. I can only hope she gets cast in more movies where she
doesn&rsquo;t have to participate in misogynist porn first.</p>
<p><strong>Unlocked</strong></p>
<p>I&rsquo;m a sucker for middling spy movies, and Noomi Rapace, so I now own this
film. It wasn&rsquo;t great, but it was fun, and dammit, sometimes that&rsquo;s all I
need. TIL Michael Douglas is still around.</p>
<p><strong>xx</strong></p>
<p>Terrible title unless everyone involved had to get a karyotype test to be
involved. Most of the horror was related to having kids, which meant this
movie hit me hard, because kids are the worst and deeply frightening on the
best days.</p>
<p><strong>Ocean&rsquo;s 8</strong></p>
<p>All. Ladies. Heist. A+. I hope everyone involved in this comes out as gay.
Points for literally every outfit, and double points for Rhianna&rsquo;s
devil-may-care overalls, and Cate Blanchett&rsquo;s Carol-as-a-Timelord character.</p>
<p><strong>Oh Lucy!</strong></p>
<p>This movie ruled! The world feels pretty rough these days, and this movie
doesn&rsquo;t shy away from difficult topics, but the overarching feeling of Oh
Lucy is a kind and happy one. It was also cool seeing an actor I&rsquo;ve watched
in lots of Kiyoshi Kurasawa films show up in a very rad role.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-05-24-media-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-05-24-media-diet/</guid>
      <description>Books Lab Rat One — Andrea Höst
Ok, this series is exceedingly straight, and that&amp;rsquo;s a bummer. I wish there was a lot less pining after the sad boy, but the magic and tech continues to be interesting.</description>
      <content:encoded><h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p><strong>Lab Rat One</strong> — Andrea Höst</p>
<p>Ok, this series is exceedingly straight, and that&rsquo;s a bummer. I wish there
was a lot less pining after the sad boy, but the magic and tech continues
to be interesting. The pacing is a little lax, and I&rsquo;ve gotten slightly
sick of the cycles of &ldquo;power then injury&rdquo; that Cass goes through, but I&rsquo;m
going to finish this out.</p>
<p><strong>Caszandra</strong> — Andrea Höst</p>
<p>Ugh, I wanted to enjoy the rest of this story, but this book was so
exceedingly dull. I <strong>loathe</strong> that the main character was setup to not
only get married, but have kids at ~19 years old. Fuck that. This series
started off well, but ended up being even worse than Twilight. Read the
first book, and skip the rest.</p>
<p><strong>Space Opera</strong> — Catherynne M. Valente</p>
<p>Uproariously fun, and silly throughout. Take Douglas Adams, add in some
queerness, and an obsession with Eurovision. Loved this from start to
finish. I devoured the back-half of this book in one sitting at a cafe in
Copenhagen, and found myself crying in the afterword/credits.</p>
<p><strong>Gold, Fame, Citris</strong> — Claire Vaye Watkins</p>
<p>Interesting book about a post-apocalyptic wasteland America and the ideas
of survival and family. I enjoyed this.</p>
<p><strong>Gods, Monsters, and the Lucky Peach</strong> — Kelly Robson</p>
<p>A cool scifi short novel where the future is barren, but at least there&rsquo;s
time-travel. I wanted more world-building, and probably a couple more books
in this story, but that also means I liked this book quite a bit. The back
half of the book felt much faster than the lead-up, and much of the action
was compacted, but it was a fun adventure. This is a solid addition to the
burgeoning eco-scifi genre.</p>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<p><strong>Geostorm</strong></p>
<p>A trash movie in the best way. If you liked watching Jake Gylenhall run
from ice in The Day After Tomorrow, and people saying &ldquo;zap!&rdquo; and
&ldquo;geostorm!&rdquo;, then this movie is for you. Continues the trend of big-budget
action films being largely targeted for non-US success, but that means we
also get some cool co-stars.</p>
<p><strong>In the Fade</strong></p>
<p>One of the saddest movies I&rsquo;ve seen in a long time. It&rsquo;s gorgeous,
well-shot, and soundtracked, but phew, what a brutal movie about the evils
of nazism, and racism.</p>
<p><strong>Avengers: Infinity War</strong></p>
<p>This movie tried to tie together too many disparate stories, to bland
effect. The attempt at some sort of emotional climax was a big wet fart,
despite ten people in the theater I was in yelling at the screen. Like,
<em>spoilers</em> they&rsquo;ll all be back, bc Disney isn&rsquo;t going to kill off their
money-makers. Go rewatch Black Panther of Thor Ragnarok, or like, spend 3
hours outside instead.</p>
<p><strong>Deadpool 2</strong></p>
<p>As fun as Avengers: Infinity War was boring and meh. Full of silly jokes.
There were definitely jokes that were in really poor taste, but pretty
much what I expected.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-04-17-media-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-04-17-media-diet/</guid>
      <description>Books All Systems Red — Martha Wells
Pretty fun book about a &amp;ldquo;murderbot&amp;rdquo; who would rather be watching tv dramas than shooting anything.</description>
      <content:encoded><h2 id="books">Books</h2>
<p><strong>All Systems Red</strong> — Martha Wells</p>
<p>Pretty fun book about a &ldquo;murderbot&rdquo; who would rather be watching tv dramas
than shooting anything. I&rsquo;m looking forward to the next few books.</p>
<p><strong>Stray</strong> — Andrea Höst</p>
<p>This was recommended to me by my buddy Nick, and I&rsquo;d avoided it for unknown
reasons. Maybe the cover was too low-budget? But, this book is really fun.
I think this series kinda qualifies as YA, but the journal nature, as well
as the mystery of scifi tech/magic systems got me deep into the world. A
really nice vacation read.</p>
<p><strong>Lab Rat One</strong> — Andrea Höst</p>
<p>Ok, this series is exceedingly straight, and that&rsquo;s a bummer. I wish there
was a lot less pining after the sad boy, but the magic and tech continues
to be interesting. The pacing is a little lax, and I&rsquo;ve gotten slightly
sick of the cycles of &ldquo;power then injury&rdquo; that Cass goes through, but I&rsquo;m
going to finish this out.</p>
<h2 id="movies">Movies</h2>
<p><strong>The Death of Stalin</strong></p>
<p>Super dark comedy. It has that abusive asshole Jeffrey Tambor, but
otherwise is full of hilariously weird old men. If you like Veep or In the
Thick of It, this is a must-watch.</p>
<p><strong>The Ritual</strong></p>
<p>A very good &ldquo;get lost in the woods&rdquo; movie. Bad things happen to unlikeable
men. A+.</p>
<p><strong>Cabin Fever</strong></p>
<p>I can&rsquo;t tell if this was the original, or if this was a remake, but either
way, it&rsquo;s nice to watch annoying and awful people fall apart. This is a
theme of the previous and next movie.</p>
<p><strong>The Descent</strong></p>
<p>Another &ldquo;maybe these are bad people&rdquo; everything-goes-wrong movie. This was
a rewatch, and yet, the cave scenes still had me feeling super
claustrophobic. It didn&rsquo;t help that I was in the middle of a middle row on
a plane to Portland from Amsterdam when I watched it.</p>
<p><strong>A Quiet Place</strong></p>
<p>A &ldquo;good christian family&rdquo; who <em>loves</em> gender roles has to be <em>vewwwwwy
quiet</em> so they don&rsquo;t get eaten by some kind of creatures. This movie was
silly as fuck. Every time the monster was on screen, someone had to
pantomime &ldquo;be quiet,&rdquo; as if the entire movie hadn&rsquo;t been quiet. Also
<em>spoilers</em> but how the fuck do you get pregnant if you know that a baby is
going to make loud baby noises and get your family killed? And <em>where did
they fuck?</em> Anyways, this is a hate-watch.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
