<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>travel on dill &amp; fennel</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/travel/</link><description>Recent content in travel on dill &amp; fennel</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Copyright Brook Shelley 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>iPad Magic Keyboard Review</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-04-24-ipad-magic-keyboard-review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-04-24-ipad-magic-keyboard-review/</guid><description>Watching friends and reviewers get their new Magic Keyboards in the mail all week was brutal, because every word I read about them, and video I watched just made me want to touch one more. In the time of quarantine, there’s no store to visit to try new products out, so instead we’re left waiting for delivery, and hoping everything lives up to our dreams.
In a sentence: this is my new favorite keyboard.</description></item><item><title>Pandemic travel: 5</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-24-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-five/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-24-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-five/</guid><description>Before it was clear we were headed for a pandemic, I booked a “treat yourself” trip to Japan. After a great first year at Slack, I wanted a nice non-work trip to really relax and refresh before going back into 2020 with a renewed sense of vigor. Previously, I wrote about my time in Asakusa.
Last day in Asakusa What was supposed to be my last day in Asakusa started late.</description></item><item><title>Pandemic travel: 4</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-22-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-four/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-22-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-four/</guid><description>Before it was clear we were headed for a pandemic, I booked a “treat yourself” trip to Japan. After a great first year at Slack, I wanted a nice non-work trip to really relax and refresh before going back into 2020 with a renewed sense of vigor. Previously, I wrote about my time in Onomichi.
Yakitori party/焼き鳥のパーテイ After a drink at my hotel’s bar, I got a hot tip to check out a yakitori place a ten-minute walk away.</description></item><item><title>Pandemic Travel: 3</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-19-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-three/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-19-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-three/</guid><description>Before it was clear we were headed for a pandemic, I booked a “treat yourself” trip to Japan. After a great first year at Slack, I wanted a nice non-work trip to really relax and refresh before going back into 2020 with a renewed sense of vigor. Previously, I wrote about my time in Osaka.
Heading south Hopping on a call in the morning with Haley, Drl, and Zech was a nice way to start my last morning in Osaka.</description></item><item><title>Pandemic travel: 2</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-17-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-two/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-17-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-two/</guid><description>Wow, things sure are quiet&amp;hellip;
Before it was clear we were headed for a pandemic, I booked a “treat yourself” trip to Japan. After a great first year at Slack, I wanted a nice non-work trip to really relax and refresh before going back into 2020 with a renewed sense of vigor. Previously, I wrote about packing and my initial few days in Koenji in western Tokyo.
Off to Kyoto Tokyo station and the Tokaido Shinkansen were both relatively empty, which was very odd to experience.</description></item><item><title>Pandemic travel: 1</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-16-traveling-during-a-pandemic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-16-traveling-during-a-pandemic/</guid><description>Wow, things sure are quiet&amp;hellip;
Before it was clear we were headed for a pandemic, I booked a “treat yourself” trip to Japan. After a great first year at Slack, I wanted a nice non-work trip to really relax and refresh before going back into 2020 with a renewed sense of vigor.
Unfortunately, in the following weeks COVID-19 grew at a wild rate, the cases in the United States were clearly skyrocketing despite a complete failure of the CDC and leadership to provide ample testing.</description></item><item><title>DevRel Tour Packing List</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-06-devreltour-packing-list/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-06-devreltour-packing-list/</guid><description>As usual, when I go on a DevRel tour, I like to write about what I&amp;rsquo;ve packed. This trip was a 3 week journey from Tokyo, through Kyoto, to Osaka, and back. As I write this, halfway through the trip, I feel very good about the amount of stuff I brought.
Bags RYU Quick Pack 18L Topo Designs Trip Pack Last time I went to Japan, I brought the DSPTCH Waist Bag as my day bag, and my shoulders immediately regretted it.</description></item><item><title>Wardrobe refresh</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-08-20-wardrobe-refresh/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-08-20-wardrobe-refresh/</guid><description>As my clothes gradually wear out, I’m slowly trying to replace everything with my current favorites. This makes for a very simple wardrobe that works for all 4 seasons.
Lots of this stuff is wool, all of it is pretty durable, and when possible I tried to find vendors that were environmentally friendly and smaller.
Shirts 4 tank tops — These are fantastic tank tops. They wick well, don’t get stinky, and look good enough to wear outside of the gym.</description></item><item><title>Minimal travel clothing</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-04-08-minimal-travel-clothing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-04-08-minimal-travel-clothing/</guid><description>Ten or so years ago, I realized I hated bringing heavy bags with me everywhere I traveled, so I slimmed down my packing to fit in one small backpack. My wardrobe generally cycles between a few pieces, so it wasn’t much of a stretch to adapt it to a month in Japan or Berlin. I usually write a post-trip gear update, but today is all about clothing.
What’re you wearing? Whether it’s a one week or one month-long trip, I bring the same things each time Including what I’m wearing during the flight, here’s the breakdown:</description></item><item><title>Travel kit update</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-03-13-travel-kit-update/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-03-13-travel-kit-update/</guid><description>Since 2019, I updated my kit a little bit, but mostly it stayed the same.
One old bag, one new My Ryu Quickpack was a delight once-again, as I used it to transport all my gear to Japan, and then from city to city. Most days it sat in my room as I travelled around with my DSPTCH Waist Bag or just what I could fit in my pockets. Ergonimically, this bag is one of the most comfortable bags I&amp;rsquo;ve owned, but due to its size, I don&amp;rsquo;t like hauling it around all day.</description></item></channel></rss>