<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>work on dill &amp; fennel</title>
    <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in work on dill &amp; fennel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Copyright Brook Shelley 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 06:37:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Apple season</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-11-18-apple-season/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 06:37:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-11-18-apple-season/</guid>
      <description>Every fall brings a plethora of shiny new Apple devices, but I don&amp;rsquo;t always partake. For the past few years I&amp;rsquo;ve been content to keep my MacBook 12&amp;quot; and iPad Pro 11&amp;quot; as my computers.</description>
      <content:encoded><p><img src="/photos/macbookm1.jpg" alt=""></p>
<p>Every fall brings a plethora of shiny new Apple devices, but I don&rsquo;t always partake. For the past few years I&rsquo;ve been content to keep my MacBook 12&quot; and iPad Pro 11&quot; as my computers. Each year I bought a new phone, but with a subsidy from work and trade-in value, they were essentially free upgrades.</p>
<p>This year something changed.</p>
<h2 id="enter-the-m1">Enter the M1</h2>
<p>Apple&rsquo;s home grown silicon M1 meant finally a Mac could be as fast as an iPhone and iPad without being an ultra-powerful desktop or a battery hog.</p>
<p>My favorite home computer is my iPad Pro for many reasons: it&rsquo;s small, light, and faster than my laptop. The new MacBook Air and Pro aren&rsquo;t lighter than my iPad, but they are faster, and the battery lasts even longer, so I was sold on the idea of moving over to a new ARM Mac.</p>
<h2 id="macbook-air">MacBook Air</h2>
<p>I thought for all of a few hours before pressing &ldquo;buy&rdquo; on the Air instead of the Pro, as I have always loved the smaller form factor, and rarely need &ldquo;pro&rdquo; features on my computer. This is doubly true now that I&rsquo;m a manager that tinkers with build systems—a process I&rsquo;ve streamlined for iOS, so it&rsquo;ll definitely stretch out and luxuriate on the Mac.</p>
<p>I got the 8gb version with 256gb of storage mostly because it shipped faster and I&rsquo;m impatient, but also because my MacBook 12&quot; also only had 8gb of ram and the limiting factor was rarely memory.</p>
<p>This computer is FAST. It&rsquo;s hard to emphasize just how quick everything feels. You want to open an app? You click it, and boom. Want to put it to sleep, then remember <em>one more thing</em>? Boom, open and on. Want to do literally any encoding or complex stuff? Fast as lightning.</p>
<h2 id="my-use-cases">My use cases</h2>
<p>Chrome users take heed: I&rsquo;m a big Safari proponent, and the only Electron app I use outside of work is Slack. I&rsquo;ve occasionally played with <a href="https://code.visualstudio.com">VSCode</a> or <a href="https://atom.io">Atom</a>, but with <a href="https://nova.app">Nova</a> being one of Gruber&rsquo;s &ldquo;<a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2020/09/24/nova">Mac-assed Mac apps</a>&rdquo; I&rsquo;ve moved over. Nova is fast, it supports Apple Silicon, and it&rsquo;s pretty AF.</p>
<p>The only software I wish worked but doesn&rsquo;t quite yet is <a href="https://brew.sh">Homebrew</a>, Go, and <a href="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</a>. I figure these will all be working within the month or by the end of the year worst-case. Guessing this might be an issue, I moved my site from Github Sites to <a href="https://www.netlify.com">Netlify</a>, simply to have test builds without doing local ones. This also means I can do some neat stuff on my iPad when I don&rsquo;t use my Mac. Not being able to use these tools is way less of an issue than it would&rsquo;ve been previously.</p>
<p>My other most-used apps are iAWriter, Tot, Fantastical. Deliveries, and ImageOptim. The first three are already ported, and I imagine the latter two will follow suit shortly. Honestly though, I only notice that they aren&rsquo;t ported when I open Activity Monitor, since everything is <em>so fast</em> and doesn&rsquo;t look any different even in Rosetta 2.</p>
<p>Without Shortcuts, I don&rsquo;t have a great way to immediately publish new blogposts. What is so nice about sharing into a Hugo workflow on my iPad means I&rsquo;ll either need to reproduce my work in some scripting language, or go through the rigamarole of dropping my text into Nova, and commit and push it. Another alternative is to use MicroPub, but I&rsquo;ve been a little too lazy to <a href="https://github.com/voxpelli/node-format-microformat/issues/5">customize the repo</a> I used to ensure the ensuing file is formatted how I like it. Perhaps in the future someone will update this, or I&rsquo;ll decide to dive deep into creating something.</p>
<h2 id="battery">Battery</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;m still testing this out, but so far I couldn&rsquo;t get the battery to drop much more than 15% during initial setup, Spotlight index, Photo analysis, and downloading and configuring software for 4 hours. More on this in an update in the future.</p>
<h2 id="no-cellular">No Cellular</h2>
<p>There were a lot of rumors hoping that the new Mac portables would include cellular functionality that put it on par with iPads. Unfortunately, there&rsquo;s no such luck this year, which means my iPad will still be my travel computer if we ever get to fly or drive anywhere again. Immediate access to the internet from a device with a keyboard is too delightful to pass up. I could see myself bringing this Mac to a coffee shop or somewhere with known-good wifi though because typing on it is a delight so far compared to my previous MacBook 12&quot;, and comparable with my iPad Pro, albeit with more room for my long fingers.</p>
<h2 id="other-bits">Other bits</h2>
<p>This thing is <em>big</em> to me. I never, ever carry my work laptop (2018 MacBook Pro 13&quot;), and have only used an iPad or the MacBook when away from my desk for a few years now, so the 13&quot; MacBook Air feels like a honker. I think I&rsquo;ll get used to it, but it&rsquo;s still quite the change.</p>
<p>This computer is 0% hot so far, ever. It&rsquo;s also super quiet, since there&rsquo;s no fan, similar to my MacBook. I haven&rsquo;t had much reason to plug things into the ports yet, but I guess having two instead of one is good? Maybe I&rsquo;ll plug it in to charge while also connecting an SD card.</p>
<p>The screen is nice? I don&rsquo;t think it&rsquo;s much different than my MacBook, and I don&rsquo;t think it has the 120hz refresh of the iPad.</p>
<p>The camera is still terrible, which gives a solid leg-up to the iPad for on-the-go video chats. When I&rsquo;m at home I use <a href="https://reincubate.com/camo/">Camo</a> to employ my very good iPhone camera for video.</p>
<p>I like the new keyboard keys, like Spotlight, language-input switching (but not that <em>plus</em> emoji, which is annoying), and dictation. The key travel is improved a bit from the old new portable switches, and satan-willing will be more durable too. No stuck keys yet! <em>knocks on wood super loudly</em></p>
<p>I&rsquo;ll update this post if I think of anything else in the next few days or weeks. If you&rsquo;re on the fence about moving to an M1 Mac and wanna ask me questions, feel free to <a href="mailto:newmac@brookshelley.com">message me</a> or Tweet @brookshelley. This is seriously the fastest, best computer I&rsquo;ve owned in a long time.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Month as a Manager</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-11-12-two-weeks-as-a-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-11-12-two-weeks-as-a-manager/</guid>
      <description>At the beginning of November, with temperatures in the bay chilling, I began to manage a team of four. I’ve managed before in my career, but never an Engineering team.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>At the beginning of November, with temperatures in the bay chilling, I began to manage a team of four. I’ve managed before in my career, but never an Engineering team. I began my new job with a good amount of fear but also hope. Between ample mentorship, and a lot of reading, I had a strong suspicion I would pick things up alright.</p>
<p>My team is four people currently, which feels like the right amount to be able to have regular 1:1s and plan out work. My friends who manage more than 6 people struggle regularly with weeks that mostly fill up with 1:1s and planning, with an annual marathon feedback session. I don’t know how long I can keep my team on the small side, but I don’t plan to hire unless we have a reason to do so. To hell with growth for growth sake, I think.</p>
<p>This month the biggest thing I’ve learned is how tricky it can be to sit back and listen, even when you want to pipe in with a <em>solution</em>. Luckily, my team is smarter and more thoughtful than I am often, so it’s not too hard.</p>
<p>I hope my schedule stays as open as I’ve attempted to keep it. I have not-so-fond memories of a previous job where it seemed like every manager went week to week <em>only</em> attending meetings, and the common refrain was “I didn’t get a chance to work on that, I’ve been in meetings since last week.” Saying “no” seems very, very valuable.</p>
<h2 id="resources-that-have-helped-so-far">Resources that have helped so far</h2>
<p>My boss and a few friends sent me books to read as well as websites to check out, including <a href="https://resilient-management.com">Resilient Management</a> and an excellent series on <a href="https://cate.blog/2017/01/05/things-to-figure-out-as-a-new-manager-part-1-your-schedule/">Cate.blog</a>. I’d previously read or purchased a number of <a href="https://cate.blog/2017/11/23/book-how-fcked-up-is-your-management/">management books</a> on other friend’s recommendations, as well as taking classes throughout my career on the topic. Honestly, going to weekly therapy is also a boon.</p>
<p>I’m also rewatching <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z9UjeTMb3Yk">old Merlin Mann videos</a> on attention and inbox management, as they feel even more pertinent today as a manager than they did as an IC.</p>
<p>So much of how to talk about people as a manager is not dissimilar from being a good partner or friend. Both involve active, empathetic listening, and a decentering of one’s own experiences to coach and mentor other folks instead of just waiting for a chance to tell our own stories. I for sure have a long way to go in all regards as both an woman and a manager, but I feel supported.</p>
<p>Here’s to a whole new career as a leader!</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DevRel Tour Packing List</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-06-devreltour-packing-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-06-devreltour-packing-list/</guid>
      <description>As usual, when I go on a DevRel tour, I like to write about what I&amp;rsquo;ve packed. This trip was a 3 week journey from Tokyo, through Kyoto, to Osaka, and back.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>As usual, when I go on a DevRel tour, I like to write about what I&rsquo;ve packed. This trip was a 3 week journey from Tokyo, through Kyoto, to Osaka, and back. As I write this, halfway through the trip, I feel very good about the amount of stuff I brought.</p>
<h2 id="bags">Bags</h2>
<ul>
<li>RYU Quick Pack 18L</li>
<li>Topo Designs Trip Pack</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="/photos/ryubag2019.jpeg" alt="bags"></p>
<p><img src="/photos/travelbag2019.jpeg" alt="bag2"></p>
<p>Last time I went to Japan, I brought the DSPTCH Waist Bag as my day bag, and my shoulders immediately regretted it. I think my days or a one-shoulder bag with a computer are pretty much over. This time I returned to my tried and true setup. I’ve reviewed or written about both of these bags previously.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/drybags2019.jpeg" alt="drybags"></p>
<ul>
<li>Two Sea-to-summit dry bags</li>
</ul>
<p>These are great for clothes and toiletries, and additionally ensure that even in a downpour I can keep a few things dry.</p>
<ul>
<li>One Topo Designs accessory bag</li>
</ul>
<p><img src="/photos/drybagsinside.jpeg" alt="drybagsinsidebigbag"></p>
<p>This time around, I loaded my toothbrush and some other non-leaky toiletries into this bag because I noticed the metal tip of my electric toothbrush kept <em>almost</em> poking through my dry bag.</p>
<h2 id="clothes">Clothes</h2>
<p><img src="/photos/clothes.jpeg" alt="clothes"></p>
<h3 id="jackets">Jackets</h3>
<ul>
<li>Mission Workshop Torre Windshell</li>
</ul>
<p>My daily jacket. I’ve got two of these and they’re awesome. Not quite waterproof, but warm enough, and water-resistant enough for a drizzle and temperatures between 7-20C (mid-40s to mid-60s F).</p>
<ul>
<li>Arcteryx Cordetta</li>
</ul>
<p>If it rains, I’m covered.</p>
<h3 id="shirts">Shirts</h3>
<ul>
<li>Wool t-shirts from Ryu and Icebreaker</li>
</ul>
<p>A great way to stay dry and warm or cool. These wash easily and are comfy for all-day-travel.</p>
<h3 id="pants">Pants</h3>
<ul>
<li>Two pairs of Outdoor Voices RecTrek pants</li>
</ul>
<p>I wear these to work daily, and they’re pretty ideal. Comfy, flexible, and a bit water-resistant. The pockets are also <em>huge</em> which means my phone fits easily in a front pocket.</p>
<h3 id="shoes-and-socks">Shoes and socks</h3>
<ul>
<li>Blundstones</li>
<li>Bombas no-show</li>
</ul>
<p>These shoes go on and off pretty easily, and look nice enough for business meetings while still feeling good for longer walks. Half of this trip was a vacation, where I wandered around all day, including hiking. I almost went with my new KOIO shoes, but at the last minute, opted for slip-one with a <em>lot</em> of grip.</p>
<h3 id="underwear">Underwear</h3>
<ul>
<li>Wool stuff from Icebreaker</li>
</ul>
<p>Wool is the way to go. I’ve tried other solutions and they were nice enough, but ultimately, wool holds up the best and wicks super well.</p>
<h2 id="tech-gear">Tech gear</h2>
<p><img src="/photos/electronics2019.jpeg" alt="electronics"></p>
<ul>
<li>Kindle Oasis</li>
<li>Battery</li>
<li>USB-C -&gt; C, and Lightning: iPad and iPhone</li>
<li>USB-A -&gt; Watch</li>
<li>USB-A -&gt; Micro: Kindle</li>
<li>iPad Pro 10.5 w/ Smart Keyboard</li>
</ul>
<p>At some point, maybe I can travel with only USB-C cables, but that world doesn’t exist yet. Fortunately my external battery has a USB-C port and a USB-A port, so I use those two to charge my phone and watch at night. On the plane my USB-C to USB-C cable means I can top-up my iPad if I play too many games or get low mid-season of a tv show. It completely boggles the mind why the Kindle isn’t a USB-C device yet. Seriously. It’s 2019.</p>
<h2 id="other-stuff">Other stuff</h2>
<p><img src="/photos/weeks2019.jpeg" alt="weeks"></p>
<ul>
<li>Toiletries</li>
<li>Hobonichi Weeks &amp; Kaweco Al EF fountain pen</li>
<li>お土産</li>
</ul>
<p>The usual assortment of unguents, potions, and a toothbrush, along with my trusty new pen and notebook. I <em>love</em> this Kaweco pen, which is both completely blacked-out, and compact. I also brought some small gifts for 東京と大阪の同僚。</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on GHC</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-10-19-thoughts-on-ghc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-10-19-thoughts-on-ghc/</guid>
      <description>Arrival
“This conference is GIGANTIC!” was my first thought upon arriving at Grace Hopper. This year’s attendance was around 10,000 folks, mostly women, and the largest conference besides SXSW that I’ve attended.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>Arrival</p>
<p>“This conference is GIGANTIC!” was my first thought upon arriving at Grace Hopper. This year’s attendance was around 10,000 folks, mostly women, and the largest conference besides SXSW that I’ve attended. Like many tech conferences, GHC had an invaluable app that showed a stream of comments from attendees as well as a schedule and other information. Once I signed in, I spent a lot of time networking and finding folks from out of town as my chosen track “Open-Source” was largely bereft of personally relevant content. Like most of the tracks, the content was focused around introductory ideas and concepts more suited to students just entering the tech world. GHC also boasted a huge job fair, and walking around was pleasantly surreal as it was comprised of 99% women, unlike just about any large room I’ve been in.</p>
<h3 id="panel">Panel</h3>
<p>My panel was very well received. It took place in an 500 person auditorium (super daunting), but our attendence was closer to 150. I spoke with my book’s editor Elissa Shevinsky, Ellen Spertus from Mills College (late of Google), and Dom DeGuzman from Twilio. Our topic was how to work with and around HR when you are in an oppressed or marginalized group, and despite the rather somber subject, there were laughs and later tears as our attendees came to talk to us and thank us. I was able to discuss the very important role of intersectionality when doing feminist work, and participating in diversity/inclusion discussions. I also brought to light some practical ways to include and help trans folks.</p>
<h3 id="highlights">Highlights?</h3>
<p>Two particular highlights in meeting people were Isis Anchalee, who started #ilooklikeanengineer, and Megan Smith, the CTO of America. There was also an LGBT (though I’m not sure why the G existed for a women’s conference) meetup at the convention center, and the turnout of around 80 women was heartening.</p>
<h3 id="the-future">The future</h3>
<p>Due to the nature of speaking and my suspicion that the conference content wouldn’t be incredibly applicable, I only attended one day of it. From talking to my friends, it sounds like I didn’t miss anything too great. I think Grace Hopper could still become a wonderful conference, but for now it is primarily centered on hiring and introductory talks for white and asian-american cisgender heterosexual women. It’s unfortunate that both the size, and leadership of the conference preclude many sessions that would be beneficial, or smaller talks that could be more intimate and informative. I filled out feedback forms with honest content, and I hope that GHC and Anita Borg take note, and that next year is marginally better.</p>
<p>I’ll end with a quote from a woman who spoke to me tearfully after my talk: “I was so happy to be here at a conference with women, but I’m realizing just how many of us it still leaves out and doesn’t help or include.”</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LWT NYC Summit</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-10-05-lesbians-who-tech-nyc-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-10-05-lesbians-who-tech-nyc-summit/</guid>
      <description>Due to stress, the talk I am about to give usually overshadows the talks before mine. Fortunately, LWT was such a jam-packed speaker event that I was able to tune into the talks and not get eaten by nerves.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>Due to stress, the talk I am about to give usually overshadows the talks before mine. Fortunately, LWT was such a jam-packed speaker event that I was able to tune into the talks and not get eaten by nerves. There were a neat mix of 5 minute ignite talks about things like tackling systemic oppression, government tech work, and imposter syndrome. Some of these talks were similar to others I’ve heard, and the audience was so different than what I usually experience at a conference that I was a little sad we didn’t get past some of the 101 talks.</p>
<p>It’s certainly possible that many of the women and other folks there were hearing about imposter syndrome or trans-inclusiveness for the first time, but I’d love to have more talks that dig into the meat of intersectional feminism in tech.</p>
<h3 id="a-few-talks">A few talks</h3>
<p>In the morning of Friday, there was a neat presentation by Diane Feinberg of Pixar on how they handle lighting and building a scene into something more than just 3D renderings.
The interview right before I spoke was with a senior Amazon employee concerning the NYTimes story, and she was able to add color and detail to both how the story turned out against the actual quotes and information given to the reporter, as well as what she’s changed since then.</p>
<p>After my talk, Edith Windsor was a particular delight, and had more than a few of us tearing up at her description of being a closeted gay woman at IBM in the 60s.</p>
<h3 id="generally">Generally</h3>
<p>I generally enjoyed the conference, but wish the compressed Friday schedule spread more evenly over Saturday and Sunday, instead of making them largely social/hackathon. I was also a little saddened to see banks so heavily represented in the recruiting area, but this is also my first NYC conference, so perhaps that is typical.</p>
<h3 id="tldr">TL;DR</h3>
<p>Overall, I think this is a worthwhile conference, and I am going to try to attend the SF summit as well in February.
Feel free to hit me up with any particular questions you have. They recorded the talks during a live-stream, and you can watch any them at <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vD-nwKUZ3LI">this link</a></p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
