<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>thoughts on dill &amp; fennel</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/thoughts/</link><description>Recent content in thoughts on dill &amp; fennel</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Copyright Brook Shelley 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rewatching Halt &amp; Catch Fire</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-01-09-rewatching-halt-catch-fire/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-01-09-rewatching-halt-catch-fire/</guid><description>The first time When Halt &amp;amp; Catch Fire first aired, I was lucky enough to clue in and watch it weekly on AMC.</description><content:encoded><h2 id="the-first-time">The first time</h2><p>When Halt &amp; Catch Fire first aired, I was lucky enough to clue in and watch it weekly on AMC. As a Texan with a dad who occasionally worked in or at least around tech, and then joined the industry myself, it captured the world I grew up in incredibly well. Starting out a little rough, it became a show all about family and how ambition can destroy everything. H&amp;CF remains one of my favorite shows of all time, and despite it being entirely too emotionally intense to watch again before now, I happily tuned back in this past fall.</p><p><img src="/photos/Halt.jpg" alt="halt and catch fire logo"/><h2 id="a-rewatch-begins">A rewatch begins</h2><p>I&rsquo;d almost forgotten how hopeful the show began. Joe, Cameron, Donna, Boz, and Gordon all dove in and ended up going to an early CES—when AVN still happened next door. As I write this, CES is happening again in Vegas, but the dreams are smaller and<a href="https://daringfireball.net/2020/01/concept_electronics_show">the concepts more far-fetched</a>. In the 80s of this show, the world was about to change completely. We follow a company at the time of IBM&rsquo;s dominance, with a parallel but less successful track than Apple. Word processors barely existed, and computers weighed 30lbs.</p><p>What so quickly began as a dream to make the future of computing turned into just making another IBM clone. What stuck with me in this first season was the crushing sadness of mediocre money. When I watched season one, I was a younger woman with a lot of dreams. Five years later, I&rsquo;ve had a fair amount of failure, and some great success. I work for<a href="https://slackhq.com">an amazing company</a> after<a href="https://www.turbinelabs.io">our Mutiny</a> petered-out. Unlike the Cardiff Electronics or McMillain Utility of H&amp;CF, my next adventure is delightful.</p><p>I still haven&rsquo;t seen another show that so fully captures how difficult it is to build something with the folks you love or how much it hurts to lose them. With a second watch, I brought my feelings and memories of all of the ups and downs, which compounded each wave. Everyone was so young. It felt like this show was about adults when I first saw it, but now they seem like me or even younger. This realization helped me have more compassion for the idiocy and backstabbing as I watched. Before I saw a thoughtless jerk, and now I saw the pain of making tough decisions. When I first watched this show, I had just moved to Portland, Oregon, and now that I&rsquo;m watching it for a second time, I&rsquo;m in the bay—the setting for most of the show. I see many of the backdrops that Joe and Donna see on a daily basis, and it really makes the show come alive.</p><h2 id="a-queer-angle">A queer angle</h2><p>From the first time I saw him on<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pushing_Daisies">Pushing Daisies</a>, I had a feeling<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lee_Pace">Lee Pace</a> was on my team. Last year<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/04/style/gay-actors-on-broadway-lee-pace.html">in the NY Times</a>, he confirmed it. H&amp;CF showed a brief glimpse of the AIDs crisis, and one fleeting queer party at Joe&rsquo;s house. I wish they&rsquo;d let written the show with more queer characters, or done more too how the struggle of gay men in the 80s and 90s, but even these little bits were more than I ever expected from a show about tech. I hope one day a story like this can have queer and trans women too.</p><h2 id="donna-and-cameron">Donna and Cameron</h2><p>By the second season, it seems like the show runners had the same revelation many of my friends watching the show for the first time have: this show is better when it&rsquo;s about Donna and Cameron. The tensions between them, and the challenges of their friendship are the lifeblood of the show. Cameron needs Donna&rsquo;s stability, and Donna wants the respect that everyone has for Cameron&rsquo;s abilities. As Mutiny struggles, and Swap Meet kicks off the tensions almost destroy them, but by the end of the show, they&rsquo;re ready to trust again. Their love and sisterhood are often sad, but ultimately an inspiring look at how two women can go beyond a competition to something lasting.</p><p>I haven&rsquo;t seen Kerry Bishé in much since H&amp;CF, but it seems like she&rsquo;s been busy with<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Happily_(film)">big film projects</a>. Meanwhile, Mackenzie Davis was in an<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/San_Junipero">incredible episode of Black Mirror</a>, the upcoming adaptation of Station Eleven, and the ridiculous new<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Terminator:_Dark_Fate">Terminator film</a>. I don&rsquo;t know if they&rsquo;ll ever work together again, but they were incredible together in this show.</p><h2 id="the-tech">The tech</h2><p>Most of the first few seasons were populated with technology I never got to use as a kid, save for the Apple IIe, but by the third season I saw myself in Donna and Gordon&rsquo;s daughter&rsquo;s eagerly waiting for a chance to play the NES. My parents used to bogart Super Mario Brothers just like Cameron and Gordon did as they played it on their new projection screen. My dad was never a HAM radio guy, but the single-minded love of hobbies mirrored Gordon&rsquo;s. I remember Lotus software, and the rise of laser tag, the thrill of dialing-up to the burgeoning world-wide web. I wish anyone on this show had learned how to touch-type.</p><p>I don&rsquo;t fondly remember the rise of security software, but hey, neither did the show. Watching this show, I saw myself as a kid around with a big set of headphones over my head, and a walkman on my belt. Those were the days. The community of Mutiny was what I found eventually on forums and in queer chat rooms and that too fly true in this show. I even love some of the cars—RIP Joe&rsquo;s 944.</p><h2 id="halt-and-catch-fire-is-incredible">Halt and Catch Fire is incredible</h2><p>This rewatch was inspired by<a href="https://500ish.com/halted-caught-fire-8128de2d111a">a newsletter I read</a>, wherein the writer is afraid to finish the show completely. I understand this feeling completely, as I find myself slowing down while I watch in order to savor every episode. I&rsquo;ll probably rewatch this show a few more times this decade, and I can only hope someone else one day makes a show I&rsquo;ll love as much as this one.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>On the perfect thing</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-05-27-on-the-perfect-thing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-05-27-on-the-perfect-thing/</guid><description>The search for the best, most optimized, beautiful, light, and pleasing things.
Why do we search? Scrolling through my RSS feeds, I’m reminded daily that so much stuff exists.</description><content:encoded><p>The search for the best, most optimized, beautiful, light, and pleasing things.</p><h2 id="why-do-we-search">Why do we search?</h2><p>Scrolling through my RSS feeds, I’m reminded daily that so much<em>stuff</em> exists. I subscribe to newsletters for fashion, backpacks, apps, and general tech, and every single one has an endless march through the days of new things. This<a href="https://www.macstories.net/reviews/ulysses-16-adds-powerful-split-view-editing-on-ipad-plus-ghost-publishing/">app</a> has<em>two columns</em> for editing! This<a href="https://www.carryology.com/liking/industry/best-new-gear-march-2019/">backpack</a> is “able to transition from work to play and travel.”<a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/bombas-socks-review">These</a> are the<em>best socks</em>.</p><p>I could go on.</p><p>The search for the best thing is best represented by the website<a href="https://thewirecutter.com">The Wirecutter</a>, with its incredibly thorough reviews of the<em>best</em> things in almost every category you can imagine. Started by<a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brian_Lam">a guy</a> and his friends to get out of the grind of tech reporting, they began to painstakingly investigate categories of tech, gear, and housewares to recommend one thing you could buy. My friend’s homes are filled with these<em>best</em> things. Hell, mine is too. They’re right most of the time, save for when taste or niche need intervenes. But why do we care?</p><p>Supposedly,<a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/3043858/the-science-of-why-you-should-spend-your-money-on-experiences-not-thing">experiences make us happier than stuff</a>, but we still buy a good amount of stuff. Talking with friends, it seems like most of us like to think we’re getting a deal—by buying the<em>best</em> thing, we’re ensuring that our dollar goes furthest. The single thing we’re buying is categorically superior, and knowing that means we can stop looking, secure in the knowledge that we’ve made the<em>right decision</em>. And yet, I still browse these sites.</p><p>There’s a sense, at least for me, that something could be better. A new thing might suit my needs, or a specific complaint better. Yes, I have a raincoat, but do I have one I can wear near a campfire? Actually,<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/blog/2019/04/08/minimal-travel-clothing.html#jacket">yes, yes I do</a>. In an effort to be minimal in my ownership of things, I’ve also bought quite a few of them. The irony is not lost on me.</p><h2 id="the-happiness-factor">The happiness factor</h2><p>Honestly, I own three backpacks, and three raincoats, because each of them is the<em>best</em> at some aspect of making me smile. There’s no way to quantify this that I’m aware of, but everyone has a thing, or things that are so neat or personal that every use or interaction with them is a small joy. And we all want to<a href="https://konmari.com/products/spark-joy">spark joy</a>, right? As hokey as I’m sure many of you think Konmari’s Shinto-sequel philosophy of things is, it has certainly helped me in pinpointing why I own them. I pared back my clothing, and donated bags of tech detritus. And yet, I still look for new joys.</p><p>Whether it’s a new iOS text editor, or a new pair of lightweight shoes, I browse through my RSS feeds with a delight in seeing fresh things. And fortunately, the delight of looking is relatively free. This daily routine of mine is akin to the window-shopping of old. I’m fascinated by the portrayal of the new things—the praises of their qualities. The search itself makes me happy.</p><h2 id="hobby-hunting">Hobby hunting</h2><p>I’ve found it’s useful to check in every so often on why I do things. Do my habits make me happy? Do I find joy in studying 漢字 every day? Lifting weights? Lightweight packing? Is my search fo the best things also a way to hunt for new hobbies? The answer, for me, to all of those questions is a yes. And frankly I don’t think there’s anything particularly wrong with this search. I do wish that this curiosity could be de-coupled from capitalism, but the world we live in doesn’t seem to wish for the same thing. I think the best we can do is keep on searching if it makes us happy, and share the things we find and the things we own with each other—sharing the joy as well.</p><p>We might all search for our own reasons, but curiosity and interest is a one of the best things of all. When we find satisfaction, the key, I think, is recognizing it, and enjoying it. Until then, happy hunting.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Slower reading</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-02-10-slower-reading/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-02-10-slower-reading/</guid><description>With the death of Google Reader in 2013 it seems like many folks gave up on RSS. Fortunately, not only is RSS still alive, but it&amp;rsquo;s thriving.</description><content:encoded><p>With the death of<a href="https://lifehacker.com/google-reader-is-shutting-down-here-are-the-best-alter-5990456">Google Reader in 2013</a> it seems like many folks gave up on RSS. Fortunately, not only is RSS still alive, but it&rsquo;s thriving. Between Newsletters and a return to blogging by many writers, thinkers, and web folks, RSS is an excellent way to find news and joy. While Twitter and other networks flounder, open standards provide a simple way to read. RSS means no trolls and no reply gifs. It’s you, and the content.</p><h2 id="my-rss-history">My RSS history</h2><p>As a long time nerd and tech news reader, I’ve used RSS steadily since the early 2000s, when MacOS RSS programs like<a href="https://nnw.ranchero.com">NetNewsWire</a> and<a href="https://github.com/ViennaRSS/vienna-rss">Vienna</a> were fresh. I used RSS on Nokia phones, but the iPhone was revelatory.<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2010/11/14/reeder-for-mac/">Version 2.0 of Reeder</a> ensured a unified experience of RSS on my iPhone, my iPad, and my Mac—at the time I predominantly used a MacBook Air and an iPhone 4—which meant that by popping in the URLs of various sites, I could stay up to date at my desk or on the go. I continued to use Reeder until recently, when in preparation for Reeder 4.0 the app’s creator made it free, but stopped regular updates. Throughout this time, my RSS feed list changed, but usually had<a href="https://daringfireball.net">Daring Fireball</a>, whatever<a href="https://desert.glass">Robin Sloan was working on</a>,<a href="https://www.theverge.com">tech news</a>,<a href="https://www.waxy.org">creative</a><a href="https://roadrunnertwice.dreamwidth.org/566524.html">friends</a>, and writing on productivity and<a href="https://www.carryology.com">bags</a>. Some sites<a href="https://Kottke.org">stayed around</a>, and some died down,<a href="https://a.wholelottanothing.org">only to return</a>. It’s always been relaxing to know that my news feed would appear every morning, and update throughout the day, which no social buttons or comments. This was the modern newspaper we were promised. It worked in many apps, tons of them were free, and you could save them until you were ready. Folks have worried about information<a href="https://www.wired.com/2003/08/aggregators-attack-info-overload/">overload since the beginning</a> of RSS, and really, since<a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information_overload">the early 1900s</a>, but I find RSS to be a simple way to store, view, and save stories.</p><h2 id="rss-today">RSS today</h2><p>Almost 20 years into using RSS, I’ve settled into<a href="https://feedbin.com">Feedbin</a> for the backend (and yes, I pay for it), with its excellent web client on my work MacBook Pro. It’s lovingly developed, and has a<a href="https://feedbin.com/blog/2018/09/11/private-by-default/">strong stance on user privacy</a> which I feel like folks rarely do these days. On my iPad and iPhone, I’ve enjoyed<a href="http://cocoacake.net/apps/fiery/">Fiery Feeds</a>, which is independently developed, and even has a<a href="http://blog.cocoacake.net/archives/1205">public feature roadmap</a>. Both of these readers have good dark mode support, keyboard shortcuts, and the ability to sync across platforms.</p><p>I subscribe to newsletters with<a href="https://www.kill-the-newsletter.com">Kill the Newsletter</a>, which lets me see emails as RSS feeds, and gives me less reason to feel beholden to my Inbox. It’s nice.<a href="https://www.shatnerchatner.com">Lots</a> of<a href="https://tinyletter.com/5it">folks</a> have<a href="https://dillandfennel.substack.com">newsletters</a> these days. It’s easy to subscribe and unsubscribe, and it’s even possible to make a decent living<a href="https://craigmod.com/essays/newsletters/">writing emails to hundreds of people</a>. Knowing that on Sundays I’ll have a few new missives in my inbox or RSS feed makes me happy. These writers aren’t hoping for more clicks for a truck or razor brand; posts are either free, or supported through a simple monthly donation. Single authors don’t need hypergrowth, just some loyal readers with a few hundred at $5 a month leading to a decent annual salary. This could be naive, but it feels like most of these Newsletter writers do halfway out of a compulsion to share, and halfway out of the joy of writing.</p><p>Usually when I’m interested in reading something, but don’t have time, I save it to<a href="https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT200294">Safari’s Reading List</a>, which not only saves the site’s URL for later, but saves the page offline, so you can catch up on reading while under the water, or in the air commuting. In the past I liked Instapaper, but found that having a bespoke read-it-later app meant I was too likely to collect old articles that I rarely read. Using Safari means all my saved posts are just a shortcut away when I have Safari open. Sometimes I star something instead—mostly because Feedbin’s site doesn’t have a good Safari Reading List shortcut. Either way, once my feed is marked as read, at some point that day I’ll read the stories and articles I saved.</p><p>In the morning, while I’m getting ready, I usually listen to a podcast or music, and scan through my RSS feed. Even on a heavy news day, I have under 80 articles listed around 8am, and most of them get scrolled-by with nary a glance. This means I can parse what’s happening very quickly while I<a href="https://crema.co/guides/hario-v60-pour-over">pour hot water on bean crumbs</a> and head to the bus stop. Much like reading email, I try to only visit my RSS reader a few times a day, but unlike a social media site, there aren’t features designed to entice me to tap the “more” button like<a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brain_stimulation_reward">a rat in a cage</a>. It’s pleasant. It’s slow. It has the people and things I choose in it.</p><h2 id="the-future-of-social-reading">The future of social reading</h2><p>I still use Twitter, but find myself typically talking about and sharing stories and interesting things in private Slack instances with people I care about or work with. This means I get to have a pleasant chat about a<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/books">new book</a> without seeing twenty posts about the world ending. I still see news, but with much less repetition and FUD. If a feed doesn’t<em>spark joy</em>, I let it go. SMTP and RSS may be old, but theirs’ is a lasting peace, and I hope if you haven’t delved into them recently, you revisit these tools. This year I am trying to slow down, take joy in rest, and find kindness for myself. I want a better world, and to fight for it, I need time away from the firehose. In RSS, I’ve found a serene pond.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Learning kanji again</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-01-27-learning-kanji-again/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-01-27-learning-kanji-again/</guid><description>My first Japanese class In 1996 I took my first Japanese class at Austin Community College. I was in middle school at the time, and decided to learn how to read Japanese so I could read literature and comics.</description><content:encoded><p><img src="/photos/kanji.jpg" alt="kanji"/><h2 id="my-first-japanese-class">My first Japanese class</h2><p>In 1996 I took my first Japanese class at Austin Community College. I was in middle school at the time, and decided to learn how to read Japanese so I could read literature and comics. The class was fun, and also super weird, since I was the only kid there. I took two semesters, but a lot of life happened at once, so I stopped taking Japanese, and didn’t being again until University, five years later. We used the<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Yookoso-Invitation-Contemporary-Japanese-Learning/dp/0072971207">Yookoso!</a> textbook, and I crammed when I needed to. Outside of watching tv, barely had any practice outside of class. I wanted to visit Japan really bad, but for the time, paying rent was hard enough.</p><h2 id="post-college-life">Post-college life</h2><p>Eventually, I made it to Tokyo—Narita airport a few times, and finally to the city itself. I was both surprised how much I remembered, and depressed at how little I could read. It made sense though. I hadn’t studied in earnest in years, and I can’t say rote memorization was ever my strong suite. I started going to Japan a bit more regularly, and tried to practice, but focused on speaking over anything else. This eventually became more frustrating, because while I could type into Google translate, I never quite knew if the Kanji was correct. Izakayas—one of my favorite places to go—were especially challenging, because outside of saying 「すみません、ぼんじりがありますか?」(Excuse me, do you have chicken tail?) with different food names I knew, ordering was a bear.</p><h2 id="buckling-down">Buckling-down</h2><p>This year I’m going back to Japan again. At the prompting of my friend Jo, who spent a while living in Japan, I dug into<a href="https://www.wanikani.com">Wanikani</a> to formalize study of kanji. I realized that I would never get better at Japanese without memorizing kanji, which would also unlock a better vocabulary. Learning any language is a wild challenge, and with ~1800 kanji to go I feel deeply skeptical that I’ll ever be fluent. I’m glad trying, and as it stands currently I’m on a four-day streak. I also signed-up for a beta app called<a href="http://kanji.garden">Kanji Garden</a>, which has a slick interface. I pushed a bit hard the first few days of using that app, and have ~180 characters I’m reviewing. I remember a decent amount from my days of college classes, but hadn’t officially learned the kon’yomi and on’yomi readings, so it feels a bit like square one.</p><h2 id="頑張って">頑張って！</h2><p>Hopefully, this time next year as I prepare to go to Japan yet another time, I feel prepared to actually read quite a bit. It seems like if I really try to study every day, I’ll make some progress. I’m hopeful, and kind of excited for a future Brook that isn’t wandering around Koenji functionally illiterate.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Moving to the bay</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-11-21-moving-to-the-bay/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-11-21-moving-to-the-bay/</guid><description>Queers and Steers As a Texan, and a lesbian, I knew eventually I’d end up in California. That’s what we do.</description><content:encoded><h2 id="queers-and-steers">Queers and Steers</h2><p>As a Texan, and a lesbian, I knew eventually I’d end up in California. That’s what we do. We leave Texas, and go west. I’ve spent the past four years hundreds of miles north in Portland, OR working remotely for various companies. I loved the trees, and the few amazing friends I made there, but found it hard to get through the long, lonely winters. It didn’t help that most of my jobs were remote—Portland has a burgeoning tech scene, but in general jobs haven’t kept up with rising cost of living. Working remotely meant rent was easier to pay, but that most of my world existed elsewhere. This all changed when<a href="https://www.turbinelabs.io">my last company</a>, my favorite job ever, shut down and went to work for<a href="https://slack.com">Slack</a>. I joined in the fun. Working for Slack, for me, also meant moving to the bay.</p><h2 id="fast-as-you-can">Fast as you can</h2><p>From the time I knew I had a job at Slack, to moving was all of two weeks. I started as soon as I could to ensure I didn’t run out of cash, and with the help of a moving company, all my stuff was packed-up and shipped the Saturday before my second week of work. Sunday meant driving Snorri, my friend<a href="https://twitter.com/local___honey">Amanda</a>, and some clothes for 10 hours to my new home<a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emeryville,_California">near an IKEA</a>. It was a pretty drive, despite all the wild rain, and switchbacks. Snorri yelled intermittently.</p><p><img src="/photos/driving.jpeg" alt="driving"/><p>Eventually, we arrived, quickly looted an IKEA for a few chairs, and set up my weird apartment. My stuff wouldn’t arrive for 2 weeks, so I was living that cool spy life until then.</p><p><img src="/photos/spylife.jpeg" alt="spy life"/><h2 id="a-month-flew-by">A month flew by</h2><p>This week is my 5th at Slack, and I’ve already learned so much. My coworkers are rad as hell, the office is unbelievable, and for the first time in years I get to work on a product I’ve used since its inception—one that I earnestly love to use. Slack is where my friends live, where I talk to my chosen family. Slack is how I interact, increasingly, with every app that I use. It’s still amazing to me that I get to work there, and influence how API features and partnerships are built out. Seriously. Wow.</p><p>Snorri is still settling in, it feels like, especially due to his insistence that daylight savings doesn’t exist, and we must still eat breakfast at dawn. I think he misses his friend, Prince, but hopefully he’ll get a new one sooner than later. For a little while, I worried he’d get sick because he wasn’t eating much, but now he seems to love a variety of wet food, and even his<a href="https://www.amazon.com/dp/B0146QXOB0?tag=thewire06-20&amp;linkCode=xm2&amp;ascsubtag=AgEAAAAAAAAAAPcR">fancy cat fountain</a>. He’s still getting used to me working out of the house every day, and seems to relish my semi-shut-in status while the smoke from the horrific fires in California rage in the north and south of my new state.</p><h2 id="bay-life">Bay life</h2><p>I’m looking forward to exploring the city more, finding tons of plants to outfit my place, and enjoying regular sunlight soon. It’s great to know so many of my friends live here, and now I can see them more than the once a month I spent here before moving to the bay. In addition to just wandering, I hope to get a few museum memberships, and get involved in the arts and music scene in a way I didn’t feel able to in Portland. I’ll miss the evergreens, and my friends, but so far this feels like a very good move.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Post XOXO thoughts</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-09-10-xoxo-thoughts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-09-10-xoxo-thoughts/</guid><description>In my previous post, I talked about anticipating XOXO 2018, which ended last night. Today, I am tired, happy, and trying to remember what to do for work when I&amp;rsquo;m not awkwardly wandering around a stadium full of 2000+ people.</description><content:encoded><p>In my<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/blog/2018/09/05/3rd-xoxo-and-anniversary.html">previous post</a>, I talked about anticipating XOXO 2018, which ended last night. Today, I am tired, happy, and trying to remember what to do for work when I&rsquo;m not awkwardly wandering around a stadium full of 2000+ people.</p><h2 id="so-many-people">So. Many. People.</h2><p>This year I was overwhelmed by the size of XOXO in ways I hadn&rsquo;t been in the past. To be fair, two years ago I was only a year into working from home, whereas now I&rsquo;m 3 years a hermit, but still, 2000 people is a<em>lot</em>. It felt like 100-200 people were folks I either knew from Twitter, friends, or Slack, and the &ldquo;should I wave or say hi?&rdquo; feeling that keeps me from going to parties was<em>hugely</em> amplified here. Fortunately, there were good talks, and things that weren&rsquo;t socially awkward to attend. Also, as always, having a friend or two around is a good salve fo my anxiety, and leaving the venue often to eat was vital.</p><h2 id="cool-stuff">Cool stuff.</h2><p>The games were neat. I only played Plunge, but watching Neo Cab, and untitled goose game was fun. Also, Laura Hall&rsquo;s very good ARG was silly good, with a chill payoff at the end. I felt lucky to do it early, before the 60+ person line after the Andys announced its existence on stage. Open Mike Eagle, Demi, and Janelle Shane gave particularly fun talks. I often felt like the bird in a psychological experiment that dies between two equidistant food bowls, but often just gave-in and stayed at the same thing for a while to avoid zipping to-and-fro.</p><p>The friends I caught up with were a huge highlight, especially folks I got to eat with and wander around with. It&rsquo;s really helpful to have a small crew that are a known quantity, so when I was out of energy, I knew what to expect. I hosted two friends this time as well, and coming home with them was like returning home with some family. I made the choice more than once to eschew an activity for some time with a few people, and that felt very rewarding.</p><h2 id="next-year">Next year</h2><ul><li><p>I hope the size of XOXO goes down again next year.
If this means more sponsorship, community funding, and other methods for a quarter -> half of the attendees to not pay for a ticket.</p></li><li><p>I also hope that there is a little less parallel programming that isn&rsquo;t recorded.
Needing to use the restroom, take a break, or eat food often felt like a frustrating trade-off with wanting to see a friend talk or perform.</p></li><li><p>Karaoke was good, but the very talented musicians who performed drastically altered the room.
Next year, more than one karaoke room could be rad.</p></li><li><p>I loved the free soda, but paid alcohol system, especially because it discouraged heavy drinking, I think.</p></li><li><p>The bathrooms were about what I expected for a stadium, but I hope next year they&rsquo;re a little less brutalist/low-ceilinged.</p></li><li><p>I don&rsquo;t know if Revolution Hall is a better venue, but I definitely missed the outside yard area, because grass fields are nicer than concrete pavilions.</p></li></ul><p>Ultimately, I don&rsquo;t envy the Andys any of the planning, listening, or responding they&rsquo;ve spent years doing, and think they&rsquo;ve put together an extremely good, complicated event. I will probably try to attend again in 2019, circumstances permitting. Community is hard. I think it&rsquo;s worth it.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>3rd XOXO &amp; 1 Year Later</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-09-05-3rd-xoxo-and-anniversary/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-09-05-3rd-xoxo-and-anniversary/</guid><description>My 3rd XOXO Thinking about the next few days in Portland, I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled beyond measure. So many new and old friends will be in my city, wandering around, making and showing art, and eating tons of food.</description><content:encoded><h2 id="my-3rd-xoxo">My 3rd XOXO</h2><p>Thinking about the next few days in Portland, I&rsquo;m thrilled beyond measure. So many new and old friends will be in my city, wandering around, making and showing art, and eating tons of food. When I<a href="https://medium.com/xoxo/xoxo-2b353d686df9">first attended XOXO in 2015</a> I had no idea what to expect. I&rsquo;d been to SXSW for years, growing-up in Austin, but never before had I felt so surrounded by rad, like-minded people. The talks were incredible, the social hangouts were silly fun, and the love at the festival was palatable. At the risk of being too sincerely stoked, XOXO is one of the best things I&rsquo;ve ever attended. In the year after my first XOXO, I was lucky to join the XOXO Outpost, which later became<a href="https://enthusiasmcollective.com">The Enthusiasm Collective</a>, and my office away from home. The calibre of people I&rsquo;ve gotten to know through XOXO, not least of all,<a href="https://waxy.org">Andy Baio</a> &amp;<a href="http://goodonpaper.com">Andy McMillan</a>, is absurd.</p><p>Three years later, I&rsquo;m gearing-up to host<a href="https://usesthis.com/interviews/haley.rose.smith/">two</a><a href="https://usesthis.com/interviews/helen.shewolfe.tseng/">friends</a>, and see dozens more. Thursday means registration and my first chance to see Cameron Esposito live. Friday, I&rsquo;ll be with Haley &amp; Andy at table 13 of [Level Eater&rsquo;s] special XOXO edition, and then seeing Darth, Helen, and Jenn present Art + Code. Saturday means<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/friendshipping/id971362201?mt=2">Jenn &amp; Trinn</a> performing Friendshipping (not that<a href="http://www.mrm.org/friendshipping">Friendshipping</a>), and<a href="https://neocabgame.com">Neo Cab</a>. Sunday promises amazing tales from<a href="http://www.demiadejuyig.be">Demi</a> and Claire (<a href="https://clairelevans.com">https://clairelevans.com</a>). Finally there&rsquo;ll be a closing party with a surprise musical guest, and I can&rsquo;t wait.</p><h2 id="one-year-later">One Year Later</h2><p>Today marks the one year anniversary of my<a href="https://medium.com/@brookshelley/one-month-in-279323105fba">coolest body mod</a>. I don&rsquo;t have much to say beyond this being an extremely vital part of many folks lives, and a procedure that<em>absolutely</em> should be covered by medical insurance (single-payer national insurance, obviously). My quality of life has grown immensely since last September, and not being weighed-down by parts of my body have led me to deeply enjoying<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/blog/2018/08/14/powerlifting.html">powerlifting</a>, and getting naked in semi-public places—shout-out to hot springs &amp; weird parties. Major shout-out to my employer,<a href="https://www.turbinelabs.io">Turbine Labs</a> for being badasses who fought to ensure I&rsquo;d have this coverage, and gave me a month off from work to heal. I couldn&rsquo;t have done it without their support.</p><h2 id="this-fall">This Fall</h2><p>If you see me at XOXO, wave and say hi. I&rsquo;ll also be in San Francisco a couple times in September, including at<a href="https://chaosconf.splashthat.com">Chaos Conf</a>, and later in the year at<a href="https://events.linuxfoundation.org/events/kubecon-cloudnativecon-north-america-2018/attend/">KubeCon &amp; Envoy Conf</a> which promises to be better than the last Seattle KubeCon, during which a terrible man was elected to the presidency. I look forward to not sobbing uncontrollably in the Modern Art Museum and then smoking too many cigarettes this year. I don&rsquo;t know what else might happen before 2018 closes out, but I&rsquo;m excited and have a great feeling about this Fall.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Smoke gets in your eyes</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-20-smokey-skies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-20-smokey-skies/</guid><description>Due to a series of forest fires, Portland has looked like an alien planet for the past few weeks.
Every day I wake up and google &amp;ldquo;air quality&amp;rdquo; to see just how much I need to stay indoors, next to my air filter.</description><content:encoded><p>Due to a series of forest fires, Portland has looked like an alien planet for the past few weeks.</p><p><img src="/photos/aqi.png" alt="aqi search"/><p>Every day I wake up and google &ldquo;air quality&rdquo; to see just how much I need to stay indoors, next to my air filter. My gym has closed for a few days for two weeks, and walking outside just plain sucks.</p><p>The only cool part is the sunsets are ridiculous, and the moon is red at night.</p><p>I really hope these fires aren’t an every year occurrence, but I’m not that hopeful, since global warming continues apace. Guess I’ll buy more indoor air filters and a Bane mask.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Powerlifting</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-14-powerlifting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-14-powerlifting/</guid><description>Young Brook Growing up, I never wanted to be big. My parents were both over 6&amp;rsquo; tall, and I worried about being as big as them.</description><content:encoded><h2 id="young-brook">Young Brook</h2><p>Growing up, I never wanted to be big. My parents were both over 6&rsquo; tall, and I
worried about being as big as them. Most of my friends ended up being shorter
than me, and were usually skinnier too. I was made fun of for being &ldquo;chubby&rdquo; in
middle school, and that stuck with me. Being fat or chubby or skinny all rule,
but I didn&rsquo;t know that as a kid. I just thought I was broken, bc I didn&rsquo;t have
a flat chest or whatever the other kids did at 12. I used to worry about my
weight all the time, and no matter what I ate, or didn&rsquo;t eat, I kept some
love-handles. Eventually I got used to my body, and now I love it. There&rsquo;s a
longer story there, but generally not wanting to be &ldquo;big&rdquo; kept me away from
weights, and on a bike.</p><h2 id="present-day">Present day</h2><p>I still keep track of my weight, but on a longer time-scale, and these days,
it&rsquo;s less about getting down to a number, and more in line with general
health-tracking. I did yoga regularly for around three years, but I never felt
stronger, just usually more calm, which rules too. Last summer, I read<a href="https://www.thehairpin.com/2017/08/the-myths-of-bodyweight-training/">The Myth of Bodyweight Training</a> and then a bunch of posts from Casey about powerlifting,
and thought, &ldquo;ok, I&rsquo;ll try this&rdquo;. I heard about<a href="http://boldandbadass.com">Bold &amp; Badass</a> from some<a href="https://2018.xoxofest.com">XOXO</a> friends, and went in for a session. Then I
went back, and back, and back. I took off some time last year due to an
unrelated surgery, and a trip to Japan in January, but since February, I&rsquo;ve
gone two days a week on average, with July and August being closer to three,
and four most days. It feels great, and I feel both stronger and happier while
there and on rest days. The focus and calm I found during yoga is present during
powerlifting, but I can also track progress, which I enjoy because
I&rsquo;m a nerd.</p><h2 id="wtf-is-powerlifting">WTF is &ldquo;powerlifting&rdquo;?</h2><p>Simply put: bench-pressing, squatting, and deadlifting. I usually do accessory
workouts and a lot of stuff that gets my heart-rate up for cardio health, but
those three lifts are the crux of powerlifting, and in competition, the total
of the 3 weights lifted are what your&rsquo;e judged on. It rules. There&rsquo;s so much
complexity and muscle memory involved in doing these lifts well, and it&rsquo;s
really helpful to have a trainer, and start very light. But, once you get the
hang of it, you end up lifting more than you would ever imagine.</p><h2 id="gains">Gains?</h2><p>I still remember my first sessions bench-pressing ~80lbs, squatting ~100lbs,
and deadlifting 65lbs (the bar + 10lbs on each side to lift it up). These days
I&rsquo;m very proud to be bench-pressing 175, squatting 245, and deadlifting 345.
It&rsquo;s been a<em>lot</em> of work to get to this point, but I can see the progress. My
gym is doing a summer of strength at this point, and that means a specific
linear training regimen that means each time I lift with my arms (bench/OHP),
I add 2.5lbs, and each time I lift with my legs (squat/DL), I add 5 lbs.
Once we get to a place where we can&rsquo;t do a 3rd set of 5, after first trying for
a third set of 5-10 for as many weeks as possible, we unload by 10% and start
over. It&rsquo;s freeing knowing what I&rsquo;m going to lift before I start each day, and
having the encouragement of all the awesome folks in my gym as we all strive
to improve our personal numbers. Our competition is with ourselves, largely,
and that&rsquo;s the most fun kind, in my opinion.</p><h2 id="lifting-is-silly">Lifting is silly</h2><p>I want to be clear that the benefits to my mental and physical health also come
with a new type of self-aware humor about the whole thing. Gyms are weird, and
lifting heavy stuff is particularly silly. I&rsquo;m lucky that a lot of my coworkers
also love powerlifting and Olympic weightlifting (clean &amp; jerks, and snatches),
so we can laugh even as we cheer each other on. Being able to enjoy things, and
laugh at/with them is super important to me. Plus, have you seen the long socks
for sumo? JK, they rule.</p><h2 id="getting-started">Getting started</h2><p>If you&rsquo;re stoked on lifting at all, and you&rsquo;re in Portland, come join me at
Bold &amp; Badass, or find a body-positive gym in your area. If you read this, but
still have zero interest, then&hellip; thanks for reading?</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>NYC</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-11-9-nyc-my-second-home/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-11-9-nyc-my-second-home/</guid><description>New York is my home for two months out of the year, but I only recently became acquainted with it. Growing up in Texas, I got the idea from my dad that NYC was some kind of devil city.</description><content:encoded><p>New York is my home for two months out of the year, but I only recently became acquainted with it. Growing up in Texas, I got the idea from my dad that NYC was some kind of devil city. He regarded it as a liberal place with people who walked too fast, and were too greedy. The first time I visited in my mid-twenties, I realized just how wrong he was.</p><h3 id="my-first-visit">My first visit</h3><p>At this point, I was liberal myself, and the city didn’t seem particularly evil to me. There were people literally EVERYWHERE, though in less quantities than Taipei and Chennai, both of which I visited before NYC. The density of any of those cities is slightly overwhelming for me, as I’m happier in a group of 2–6 people, but I learned quickly that I can put my headphones on and they disappear. To a degree, music makes the city feel like a river that I’m floating through or a strange movie set. Interactions with strangers aren’t necessary in the way that waving at folks on the street seems normal in Portland or Texas. In a way, I found the anonymity and brusqueness refreshing.</p><h3 id="food">Food</h3><p>As a food nerd, I also find the ubiquity of delicious meals incredibly appealing, though I will never get used to the constant lines and hype around restaurants who can only hope to fit a handful of people at a time, ensuring long waits. Still, I feast each time I visit my 2nd home. Often I will pick a particular cuisine, and try to find the 5 best examples of its preparation, be it ramen, izakaya food, or southern fried chicken. Food tourism is a major industry from what I can tell. Food isn’t cheap, but then neither is anything else in NYC. I budget to spend $60 a day in NYC on food alone, and many times I’ve blown right by that. I’d imagine if I lived there more regularly, I would cook more often, but the temptations of restaurants and carts is too high for me to pass up during each visit. I’ve yet to dive into the fine-dining scene, as I’m loathe to wear heels or hose, but I’ve heard great things about upscale restuarants. For now, I think I’ll stick to the sub-$10 congee bowl with youtiao.</p><h3 id="getting-around">Getting around</h3><p>A huge part of my love of the city is the transport. Many of my friends in NYC seem to avoid the subway, opting for Uber, taxis, or bicycles, but I love it. To me, trains are a pinnacle of old, cool technology. They’re dependable (largely), safe (except occasionally from scary folks), and inexpensive. Waiting on the platform, or slumped in a molded plastic seat, I have time to read books, listen to music, and contemplate hard problems at work or in life. In a city that moves so quickly, these brief pauses are my respite. Without them, I don’t think I could handle the bustle or the pace of NYC.</p><h3 id="memento-mori">Memento mori</h3><p>That said, I think the city wants us dead. The distinct sense I get from NYC is one of antagonism. The people can be ok at times, but the city itself pulses with too much, and too harsh. Not only are there actual dangers in the city, but the sheer speed at which everything is moving ensures that if you stumble emotionally, physically, or in spirit, the weight of the city-as-inexorable-movement will grind you into dust. Perhaps the industry or part of New York you encounter on a daily basis can mitigate this for a time, but by and large, NYC is hard to thrive in. High rents, cold winters, humid-as-hell summers, and complex transit — if you are thinking of visiting or moving from a sleepy locale, test the waters in a few seasons first.</p><h3 id="finally">Finally</h3><p>For myself, making friends was the most important part of enjoying my time in NYC. They ensure that I have activities in the city or in Brooklyn, as well as support and kind faces. With growing familiarity and the increased time I spend in the city, I now love it as a second home, and am excited to drop in for a few weeks at a time, to partake in the drug of NYC. And I’m equally happy to fly home, disembark from the plane, and breath in the cool, crisp air of Portland.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Thoughts on GHC</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-10-19-thoughts-on-ghc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-10-19-thoughts-on-ghc/</guid><description>Arrival
“This conference is GIGANTIC!” was my first thought upon arriving at Grace Hopper. This year’s attendance was around 10,000 folks, mostly women, and the largest conference besides SXSW that I’ve attended.</description><content:encoded><p>Arrival</p><p>“This conference is GIGANTIC!” was my first thought upon arriving at Grace Hopper. This year’s attendance was around 10,000 folks, mostly women, and the largest conference besides SXSW that I’ve attended. Like many tech conferences, GHC had an invaluable app that showed a stream of comments from attendees as well as a schedule and other information. Once I signed in, I spent a lot of time networking and finding folks from out of town as my chosen track “Open-Source” was largely bereft of personally relevant content. Like most of the tracks, the content was focused around introductory ideas and concepts more suited to students just entering the tech world. GHC also boasted a huge job fair, and walking around was pleasantly surreal as it was comprised of 99% women, unlike just about any large room I’ve been in.</p><h3 id="panel">Panel</h3><p>My panel was very well received. It took place in an 500 person auditorium (super daunting), but our attendence was closer to 150. I spoke with my book’s editor Elissa Shevinsky, Ellen Spertus from Mills College (late of Google), and Dom DeGuzman from Twilio. Our topic was how to work with and around HR when you are in an oppressed or marginalized group, and despite the rather somber subject, there were laughs and later tears as our attendees came to talk to us and thank us. I was able to discuss the very important role of intersectionality when doing feminist work, and participating in diversity/inclusion discussions. I also brought to light some practical ways to include and help trans folks.</p><h3 id="highlights">Highlights?</h3><p>Two particular highlights in meeting people were Isis Anchalee, who started #ilooklikeanengineer, and Megan Smith, the CTO of America. There was also an LGBT (though I’m not sure why the G existed for a women’s conference) meetup at the convention center, and the turnout of around 80 women was heartening.</p><h3 id="the-future">The future</h3><p>Due to the nature of speaking and my suspicion that the conference content wouldn’t be incredibly applicable, I only attended one day of it. From talking to my friends, it sounds like I didn’t miss anything too great. I think Grace Hopper could still become a wonderful conference, but for now it is primarily centered on hiring and introductory talks for white and asian-american cisgender heterosexual women. It’s unfortunate that both the size, and leadership of the conference preclude many sessions that would be beneficial, or smaller talks that could be more intimate and informative. I filled out feedback forms with honest content, and I hope that GHC and Anita Borg take note, and that next year is marginally better.</p><p>I’ll end with a quote from a woman who spoke to me tearfully after my talk: “I was so happy to be here at a conference with women, but I’m realizing just how many of us it still leaves out and doesn’t help or include.”</p></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>