<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>thoughts on dill &amp; fennel</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/brookshelley/tags/thoughts/</link><description>Recent content in thoughts on dill &amp; fennel</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Copyright Brook Shelley 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.brookshelley.com/brookshelley/tags/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>on the perfect thing</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/brookshelley/posts/2019-05-27-on-the-perfect-thing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/brookshelley/posts/2019-05-27-on-the-perfect-thing/</guid><description>The search for the best, most optimized, beautiful, light, and pleasing things.
Why do we search? Scrolling through my RSS feeds, I’m reminded daily that so much stuff exists. I subscribe to newsletters for fashion, backpacks, apps, and general tech, and every single one has an endless march through the days of new things. This app has two columns for editing! This backpack is “able to transition from work to play and travel.</description></item><item><title>NYC</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/brookshelley/posts/2015-11-9-nyc-my-second-home/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/brookshelley/posts/2015-11-9-nyc-my-second-home/</guid><description>New York is my home for two months out of the year, but I only recently became acquainted with it. Growing up in Texas, I got the idea from my dad that NYC was some kind of devil city. He regarded it as a liberal place with people who walked too fast, and were too greedy. The first time I visited in my mid-twenties, I realized just how wrong he was.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts on Grace Hopper Conference</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/brookshelley/posts/2015-10-19-thoughts-on-grace-hopper/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/brookshelley/posts/2015-10-19-thoughts-on-grace-hopper/</guid><description>Arrival
“This conference is GIGANTIC!” was my first thought upon arriving at Grace Hopper. This year’s attendance was around 10,000 folks, mostly women, and the largest conference besides SXSW that I’ve attended. Like many tech conferences, GHC had an invaluable app that showed a stream of comments from attendees as well as a schedule and other information. Once I signed in, I spent a lot of time networking and finding folks from out of town as my chosen track “Open-Source” was largely bereft of personally relevant content.</description></item></channel></rss>