<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>newsletter on dill &amp; fennel</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/newsletter/</link><description>Recent content in newsletter on dill &amp; fennel</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Copyright Brook Shelley 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/newsletter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>links week nineteen</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-05-10-links-week-nineteen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-05-10-links-week-nineteen/</guid><description>Ten loaves of sourdough! That’s how many loaves I have made thus far during the pandemic (or pan-demic if you’ll excuse my pun). Have you found a fulfilling hobby? Gotten really good at a driving simulator? Taken up amateur plumbing? I went out last weekend for the first time, albeit just down the street to sit in a friend’s yard, far from said friend. It was pretty nice, and I keep thinking I should perhaps do a little more biking and walking, but then I see a dozen people walking around massless, and I get some combination of furious and scared all over again.</description></item><item><title>links week eighteen</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-05-03-links-week-eighteen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-05-03-links-week-eighteen/</guid><description>Happy May! We made it through an April that lasted conservatively one thousand years. I hope you&amp;rsquo;re well, and finding new ways of living and thriving as we settle in for Summer.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been cleaning, rearranging, and making lots of bread—I think I&amp;rsquo;ve finally sorted out my Sourdough woes.
One thing I can recommend for anyone looking to clean up a little are a bunch of little velcro strips to manage those cables.</description></item><item><title>links week fifteen</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-04-12-links-week-fifteen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-04-12-links-week-fifteen/</guid><description>Welcome to your weekly installment of “what’s Brook reading and clicking on now?” The quarantine here in the Bay Area is 4 weeks on, I think, and today I briefly saw a friend outside while dropping off groceries. It was nice. I hope you’ve had some distant human contact this month too. I’ve also been buying wine from Ordinaire, along with various tinned fishes, because this shit sucks, but wine and mackerel are delightful.</description></item><item><title>links week fourteen</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-04-05-links-week-fourteen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-04-05-links-week-fourteen/</guid><description>This week I spent some time thinking about hoarding.
Specifically, toilet paper hoarding. I&amp;rsquo;ve yet to venture out this week to the grocery, but the TP situation in my house is on its way to dire. I was able to procure napkins a week ago, so&amp;hellip; needs must.
The only hoarding I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to do, back when it was just called &amp;ldquo;collecting&amp;rdquo; was of alcohol. I&amp;rsquo;m a little proud of my strange Shochu collection, largely enabled by my friends over at Umami Mart (who&amp;rsquo;re still doing curbside pickup in the East Bay, btw).</description></item><item><title>links week thirteen</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-29-links-week-thirteen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-29-links-week-thirteen/</guid><description>Ah, I’ve returned to the Americas. This week, Japan started quarantining as well, so I just missed the cutoff there and was largely able to enjoy wandering around like usual. I still tried to socially distance while I was in Tokyo and Osaka however, and I even blogged about it in five parts. Overall, it was a strange trip, but a fun one. I hope I get to travel back to Japan again in November after the quarantine ends.</description></item><item><title>links week eleven</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-15-links-week-eleven/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-15-links-week-eleven/</guid><description>Welcome to a new world without toilet paper. Seriously, it’s fucking depressing seeing pictures of grocery stores post-hoarding. I hope everyone reading this cares for your fellow humans more than building a fort out of sanitizer and toilet paper.
Here’s a cat to help you feel better:
https://twitter.com/artgillespie/status/1238266163294957568?s=20
Sorry for starting on a bummer note, but it’s kinda wild out there, eh? I hope you’re taking care of yourself, washing your hands for 20 seconds, using lotion to protect your skin, and breathing deeply.</description></item><item><title>links week eight</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-02-23-links-week-eight/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-02-23-links-week-eight/</guid><description>This was the week I left Twitter for a while. Honestly it wasn’t so bad, once I got over the twitchy “gotta open Twitter” feeling. I’ll write more about that experience soon, with some light suggested reading and a few tips. My main takeaway so far is that I spent a lot of time opening and closing and reopening Twitter for the last 10 years.
Here are a few things I would’ve sent:</description></item></channel></rss>