<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>newsletter on dill &amp; fennel</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/newsletter/</link><description>Recent content in newsletter on dill &amp; fennel</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Copyright Brook Shelley 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/newsletter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dill &amp; Fennel 11-1-20</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-11-01-dill-fennel-11-1-20/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-11-01-dill-fennel-11-1-20/</guid><description>Good morning race fans (jk I know like only one of you likes Formula 1). Spooky season is over. I hope you had the maximal amount of fun you could have while staying inside your pod, and away from unknown candy.</description><content:encoded><p>Good morning race fans (jk I know like only one of you likes Formula 1). Spooky season is<em>over</em>. I hope you had the maximal amount of fun you could have while staying inside your pod, and away from unknown candy. I forgot to refill my candy stash, so all I had was some old weed chocolate and some date rolls. Needs must! Whether you have sober candy or weed candies, this will make you laugh:</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Thinking about the guy that put cheese in a chocolate fountain<a href="https://t.co/jZQ1krWcvI">pic.twitter.com/jZQ1krWcvI</a></p>&mdash; Parker (@panoparker)<a href="https://twitter.com/panoparker/status/1321927976318099456?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 29, 2020</a></blockquote><script async= src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"/><p>Now that it’s November we can all celebrate the reason for the season—my birthday. Traditionally, others eat turkey and pumpkin pie for my birthday, but I always have a yakitori or caviar feast. However you celebrate, you have ~3 weeks to plan. Good luck!</p><p>Here’s some<em>inspiration</em></p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Joel Osteen Inspiration Cube<a href="https://t.co/XYZUyGHWfc">pic.twitter.com/XYZUyGHWfc</a></p>&mdash; A British Druid (Chilly) (@dudeweedmemes)<a href="https://twitter.com/dudeweedmemes/status/1321282165494239234?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 28, 2020</a></blockquote><script async= src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"/><p>And now, the<em>links</em></p><h2 id="links">Links</h2><ul><li>Did you go to dance parties in the 90s? Perhaps you live for house music now&hellip; but are you aware of the very important<a href="https://mixmag.net/feature/the-gentrification-of-jungle">Black history of Jungle?</a>. Electronic music, like most great things, was taken to the highest heights by black folks around the world.</li><li><a href="http://www.stilldrinking.org/the-problem-with-bill-gates">Fuck the super rich</a>. I’ll be the first to admit that I am<em>sitting pretty</em>, but fortunately the amount in my bank account means when I support non profits and friends that support is a significant portion of my finances. Billionaires and trillionaires like Mr. Gates could eliminate poverty in the United States and still be rich.</li><li>I thought<a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/family/archive/2020/10/people-who-prioritize-friendship-over-romance/616779/">this piece on friendship over romance</a> was interesting, though I’m still not sure how I feel about some of their conclusions. I am glad they dove into the queerness of many friendships though. I think prioritizing your friends is always a great plan.</li><li>If you’ve been around the Bay Area, or used the app Signal, you’ve likely heard<a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2020/10/26/taking-back-our-privacy/amp">this guy’s name</a>. My friend who’ve worked with him weren’t huge fans, and his continued insistence on dreadlocks is a huge red flag, but I’m glad we get some solid encryption out of his weirdness.</li><li>Just trust me,<a href="https://www.designboom.com/art/motoi-yamamoto-salt-floating-garden-labyrinth-aigues-mortes-france-05-23-2016/">this is gorgeous</a>.</li><li>(CW for discussion of COVID stuff)<a href="https://fivethirtyeight.com/features/what-a-summer-of-covid-19-taught-scientists-about-indoor-vs-outdoor-transmission/">This piece on FiveThirtyEight</a> covers what we now know about COVID-19 transmission. Remember when we were all boiling our toilet paper? Wild times.</li><li>In case you missed this ultra bizarre former church for sale, I present to you,<a href="https://waxy.org/2020/10/the-house-on-blue-lick-road/">The House on Blue Lick Road</a>. What a wild story.</li><li>I don’t understand this trend, but I guess if you want to have a second belly full of beer, you can:</li></ul><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">I saw this online and can't get it out of my head so I'll leave it here for the haters<a href="https://t.co/z2COlrC5R7">pic.twitter.com/z2COlrC5R7</a></p>&mdash; Katie Dippold (@katiedippold)<a href="https://twitter.com/katiedippold/status/918687618207903745?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 13, 2017</a></blockquote><script async= src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"/><h2 id="closing">Closing</h2><p>Phew, that was a lot of links! The colder weather has me amped and full of excitement, not to mention Monday being the first day of my new job as Ms. Manager. Can you believe someone is paying me to care about, support, and listen to four amazing engineers? Go figure!</p><p>The days are way shorter now, which means it’s a good time to light some candles and just really relax through the end of 2020. This week promises to be high-stress for all of us, but I’ll be sure to put in some fun links next week regardless. The early voting in Texas is very exciting, and I’m so, so happy to see so many friends and loved-ones get involved in GOTV and voter protection work. Our fight for a better world will last longer than our lives, but it’s so crucial. Care for yourself, care for each other, and I’ll see you on the other side!</p><p>Love and solidarity from your friend, Brook. Keep up the great work, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Dill &amp; Fennel 10-25-20</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-10-25-dill-fennel-10-25-20/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-10-25-dill-fennel-10-25-20/</guid><description>Happy Sunday! It’s Portugal GP time in the Formula one world, and potentially a record-breaking victory for Lewis Hamilton, beating the previous “most 1st place victories” record set by Schumacher last decade.</description><content:encoded><p>Happy Sunday! It’s Portugal GP time in the Formula one world, and potentially a record-breaking victory for Lewis Hamilton, beating the previous “most 1st place victories” record set by Schumacher last decade.</p><p>If that all seems like Greek to you, perhaps I can interest you in the funniest video I saw this week:</p><div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hq8DgpgtSQQ" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen= title="YouTube Video"/></div><p>Ok, wipe the tears of joy/anger/surprise off your face, and let’s<em>get to those sweet, sweet links</em>.</p><h2 id="links">Links</h2><ul><li>Superconductors are pretty wild, and<a href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/physicists-discover-first-room-temperature-superconductor-20201014/">this room-temperature one</a> is even wilder! There’s only one minor catch—you have to crush the material using diamonds. Looking forward to a future where there’s tiny incredibly pressurized diamond vises inside my phone. That’s how physics work, right?</li><li>Some cool new research on choice suggests that<a href="https://hub.jhu.edu/2020/10/02/babies-prefer-what-they-choose-even-when-random/">our choices influence our preferences</a> by virtue of choosing. So much of how human behavior shakes-out ends up being way, way less smart and free than I’d like to think of myself. We’re just weird, wet meat sacks full of chemical and bacterial influence. Go figure.</li><li>Have you read or heard about the absolute fuckery of Foxconn in Wisconsin? Here’s a story of how corruption, greed, and just a<a href="https://www.theverge.com/21507966/foxconn-empty-factories-wisconsin-jobs-loophole-trump">big old grift fucked-over an entire state</a>. The level of research and the amount of time spent checking in on the “progress” of these factories is wild! This week’s Vergecast had an interview with the writer as well, and apparently he just hung out in Wisconsin for four entire months. That’s dedication.</li><li>If you’re like me, you might need a drink after those links! Celebrate with some<a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gammel_Dansk">Gammel Dansk</a> (old danish). I love this bitter dram whether with snacks or on the rocks. I was introduced to it during a really amazing meal that Mae in Portland did with a now defunct Portland Scandinavian restaurant. I think this liquor was the alcohol pairing for course 10 out of 11, right before we had some coffee to wake us up. I can’t remember what food it was paired with, just that I loved this stuff. It’s hard to find, but if you can get some, be sure to. I think my pal Brian brought me some from Denmark.</li><li>Ever find yourself driving around wondering “hey what happens if someone shoots an RPG at me?!” Well, here’s the<a href="https://twitter.com/JonHawkes275/status/1302874438149570560?s=20">trick to beat those little buggers</a>. I love how this armor is almost like a chain-length fence for misses. Low-tech the best answer sometimes.</li><li>Instead of going to war though, what if we fed our neighbors, and<a href="https://www.bonappetit.com/story/a-restaurant-for-a-chipmunk">enjoyed their snacks vicariously</a>. I love small woodland creatures, and the idea of them sitting at a small picnic table brings me a large amount of joy.</li><li>Finally, I’ll leave you with a really neat piece on an amazing musician named<a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2020/10/19/adrianne-lenkers-radical-honesty">Adrianne Lenker</a> (you might know her from Big Thief). She just released<a href="https://www.adriannelenker.com">two albums</a> that are pretty damn good. Seriously, check her out if you need some jams</li></ul><h2 id="closing">Closing</h2><p>This week was finally a bit chilly, which makes me deeply excited for the coming Winter. Just imagine, a brisk morning with a warm cup of coffee! Candles! Festive hats! Decorative gourds!<a href="https://www.saltedtv.com/recipes/uunipuuro-finnish-porridge-by-daniel-oseas">Finnish rice porridge</a>. Warm up those mulling spices, and let’s get excited.</p><p>Have you seen any fun, spooky films? What are your favorite fall traditions?<a href="mailto:newsletter@brookshelley.com">Let me know</a> &lt;3</p><p>Also, you’ve voted, right? Against prop 22 and for Biden? Good. Thanks! We’ve got one more of these newsletters before a very tense week, and I want you to know I’m also fully clenched, waiting. We’ll get through this! Keep loving, and keep fighting, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Dill &amp; Fennel 10-18-20</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-10-18-dill-fennel-10-18-20/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-10-18-dill-fennel-10-18-20/</guid><description>Another week is in the can, midway through spooky season. I’m seeing some really wild Halloween decorations in my neighborhood, but am still waiting to see the glorious arrival of the Home Depot 12’ skeleton:</description><content:encoded><p>Another week is in the can, midway through spooky season. I’m seeing some really wild Halloween decorations in my neighborhood, but am still waiting to see the glorious arrival of the Home Depot 12’ skeleton:</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Who is he<a href="https://t.co/GJ6EszRzaa">pic.twitter.com/GJ6EszRzaa</a></p>&mdash; Taylor Lorenz (@TaylorLorenz)<a href="https://twitter.com/TaylorLorenz/status/1316947468102307841?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 16, 2020</a></blockquote><script async= src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"/><p>Her arrival will be heralded by the sounds of trumpets.</p><p>Are you decorating this year? Are you going to dress up? Are you planning to use a Halloween candy chute, or shoot children with jelly-filled paintballs? The spookiest thing to me is still<em>asymptomatic super-spreaders</em>. I don’t think that would make a very good horror film, but outside of Vampires vs. the Bronx and the Haunting of Bly Manor, I haven’t felt much desire to watch one of those. I<em>am</em> due for a rewatch of<a href="https://www.hulu.com/series/over-the-garden-wall-7955110c-56cb-45b1-9eae-68550344128b">Over the Garden Wall</a> though.</p><h2 id="links">Links</h2><ul><li>Shout out to all my friends who’ve made mistakes at Home Depot:</li></ul><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Y’all, please watch this. I’m hollering omg 😂😂😂😂😂😂<a href="https://t.co/a7bPSt1FVT">pic.twitter.com/a7bPSt1FVT</a></p>&mdash; Cameron (@SirCamCarter)<a href="https://twitter.com/SirCamCarter/status/1314675341168910337?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 9, 2020</a></blockquote><script async= src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"/><ul><li>Can you believe the sequel to Borat is almost here? Let’s<a href="https://theoutline.com/post/5407/borat-where-are-they-now">revisit this article</a> by friend of the letter Joe which itself is revisiting the side-characters of Borat. A side note: everything of Joe’s I’ve read was delightful, and I keep randomly stumbling onto them, laughing, and then seeing his byline. Joyful surprise writer of the century.</li><li>Speaking of friends who write, Craig Mod just released his tome on Kissaten, and even though it sold out immediately, he’s doing a second run. Keep<a href="https://shop.specialprojects.jp">this in your bookmarks</a> so you can get one—it’s worth it.</li><li>The<a href="https://marker.medium.com/remote-work-is-killing-the-hidden-trillion-dollar-office-economy-5800af06b007">many symbiotic industries in our cities</a> are really struggling right now. Shoe-shiners, laundromats, airport vendors, etc are all just hoping they can make it until we go back to work in an office. I can’t help but think we might be approaching a permanent change in work as opposed to a two year hiatus. Time will tell.</li><li>It really rules to see<a href="https://www.vulture.com/article/sohla-el-waylly-profile.html">someone so talented thriving</a> despite the racism and inequality of her former workplace. This profile of Sohla El-Waylly was a great read, and I can’t wait to see all her new videos.</li><li>Times are hard, but take it from me, sometimes you’ve just gotta dance alone in your apartment or house:</li></ul><div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9uSWfQzjahY" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen= title="YouTube Video"/></div><h2 id="closing">Closing</h2><p>I have too many clams. This is a weird problem to have, but my most recent order from<a href="https://www.seaforager.com">my fishmonger</a> contained what seems like hundreds of the little shelled suckers, and despite enjoying clams, I have no way to share them. May we all be blessed with such issues of bounty.</p><p>I hope you’ve voted! We got our mail-in/drop-off ballots last week, and there are a<em>lot</em> of propositions in California. I found<a href="https://progressivevotersguide.com">this guide</a> very helpful, and you might as well if you’re still not sure what dots to fill in.</p><p>It’s almost November, and since this is a special small group, I’m happy to announce I’m starting my new gig as Ms. Manager at my company on the 2nd. The team I’ll manage is such a kind and smart crew that I’m super lucky to hang out with. I can’t wait! If you have tips on management, or just wanna show off your isolation Halloween costume, please<a href="mailto:hello@brookshelley.com">say hi</a>. Until next week, keep voting, keep fighting, and stay safe space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Dill &amp; Fennel 10-11-20</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-10-11-dill-fennel-10-11-20/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-10-11-dill-fennel-10-11-20/</guid><description>Let’s get SPOOKY!
Bat Cow pic.twitter.com/NvOm5OBHEB
&amp;mdash; Evil Midweek Cutie⛧ (@lindseybieda) October 8, 2020 We’re only a few days away from what could be a pretty exciting Apple event!</description><content:encoded><p>Let’s get SPOOKY!</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="in" dir="ltr">Bat Cow<a href="https://t.co/NvOm5OBHEB">pic.twitter.com/NvOm5OBHEB</a></p>&mdash; Evil Midweek Cutie⛧ (@lindseybieda)<a href="https://twitter.com/lindseybieda/status/1314019257500479488?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 8, 2020</a></blockquote><script async= src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"/><p>We’re only a few days away from what could be a pretty exciting Apple event! If you’ve waited for a while to get a new phone, or really want something smaller,<a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2020/10/02/iphone-12-top-features/">you might just be in luck</a>. Whether the rumors amount to anything, Apple is definitely launching something on Tuesday. I’ll be tuning in.</p><p>More than the phone even, I’m excited to see if they actually ship a computer with their own silicon. It seems like the main feature will be performance, with a side of excellent battery life. I can’t wait.</p><p>Other than tech shit, this week was nice and chill. The smoke outside continues to plague my bike rides, and the plague is a constant worry, but those are almost background pain at this point.</p><p>I hope you’re taking it easy as well, and that you have a neighbor who gives you bonus fruits from their trees! Thanks Haley for the amazing passion fruit!</p><p>This week should be good, so let’s get to it:</p><h2 id="links">Links</h2><ul><li>It’s always good to start off your Sunday with a little bit of dancing:</li></ul><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">thread of moments from the star wars weekends dance offs at disney world because I CANT BELIEVE THIS WAS A REAL THING THAT ACTUALLY HAPPENED<a href="https://t.co/odwaFnQ5Rs">pic.twitter.com/odwaFnQ5Rs</a></p>&mdash; caitlin (@SITHLEIAS)<a href="https://twitter.com/SITHLEIAS/status/1313240578566492161?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 5, 2020</a></blockquote><script async= src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"/><ul><li>But remember, while you dance (outside) be sure to wear a<a href="http://toolsandtoys.net/tom-bihn-v3-three-layer-cloth-face-mask/">good mask</a> and stay well-away from your fellow Ewoks.</li><li>I just learned that my way too brilliant coworker Bert<a href="https://bert.org/2020/10/01/pressing-yubikeys/">made a finger to tap his Yubikey</a>. This is just the kind of disturbingly smart shit I love. I’m reminded of my friend Mark’s somewhat abandoned project to make a “cloud finger” that would open the garage door to our office a few years ago. Why touch things with your meat fingers, when you can make a single-use robot?</li><li><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/10/06/qiui-smart-chastity-sex-toy-security-flaw/">This</a> gives platform lock-in a whole new meaning. The real dominatrix was insecure APIs the whole time.</li><li>It’s pretty frustrating that anti-privacy advocates in Europe are using the specter of child predation to try to<a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2020/10/orders-top-eus-timetable-dismantling-end-end-encryption">destroy end-to-end encryption</a>. Instead of cursing us with no way to securely communicate, what if those legislators worked on houselessness and ending the wars they started in the global south?</li><li>Sorry, that last one was heavy, so maybe we should play a<em>folk</em> game:</li></ul><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Here’s a thread of all the folk game tiktoks I’ve been collecting for the past few months! Starting with a great use of high stakes<a href="https://t.co/nr37kwdjO5">pic.twitter.com/nr37kwdjO5</a></p>&mdash; Danny Hawk (@HawkDanny)<a href="https://twitter.com/HawkDanny/status/1313881230312714241?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 7, 2020</a></blockquote><script async= src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"/><ul><li>I’ll leave you with one of<a href="https://hailaker.bandcamp.com/album/holding">my favorite albums this year</a>.</li></ul><h2 id="closing">Closing</h2><p>In preparation for<a href="https://www.npr.org/2020/10/04/920038799/candy-chutes-could-save-halloween-during-the-coronavirus-pandemic">sliding candy down chutes</a> into the waiting baskets of masked trick-or-treaters, have you chosen a costume? I get this sense<a href="https://www.halloweencostumes.com/mens-tiger-king-trainer-costume.html">this one</a> will be popular, even though Tiger King feels like it came out two-thousand years ago.</p><p>My friend Laura has a<a href="https://tinyletter.com/31daysofhalloween">way spookier newslettter</a> that she only runs during October but is a daily treat this month. I hope you read it too.</p><p>So far<em>deathwatch</em> 2020 hasn’t offered anybody any big winnings, but I know many stay hopeful. The fly this week reminded us that these men are actual pieces of shit.</p><p>If you feel up for getting involved a bit and supporting trans rights,<a href="https://transgenderlawcenter.org/events/spark-sponsors">this event</a> next week should be good. My friend Haley took me to it last year and I had a great time.<a href="mailto:hello@brookshelley.com">Let me know</a> if you want to join!</p><p>It’s a few weeks until the election, and I just voted. I hope you do too (<a href="https://progressivevotersguide.com">this guide was helpful</a>). Keep fighting, keep loving, and I’ll see you next week, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Dill &amp; Fennel 10-4-20</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-10-05-dill-fennel-10-4-20/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 07:50:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-10-05-dill-fennel-10-4-20/</guid><description>Dill &amp;amp; Fennel 10/4/20 October is full of surprises and delights so far. I feel like so many of us have held our collective breath, waiting for folks who so flagrantly flaunt the recommendations of doctors and scientists to reap what they’ve sown.</description><content:encoded><h1 id="dill--fennel-10420">Dill &amp; Fennel 10/4/20</h1><p>October is full of surprises and delights so far. I feel like so many of us have held our collective breath, waiting for folks who so flagrantly flaunt the recommendations of doctors and scientists to reap what they’ve sown. The reaping began on Thursday night.</p><p>After the low of the debate this week, which I ended-up watching after swearing I wouldn’t, Thursday was a breath of fresh air. The news is coming fast and very obscured by a fog of misinformation and lies, but I am reloading pretty constantly. I hope we figure out what the actual timeline of events was eventually.</p><p>But, you don’t read this newsletter for schadenfreude, right? Let’s get to those juicy, juicy links:</p><h2 id="links">Links</h2><ul><li>We’ll start with a very long read on the potential<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2020/jun/18/end-of-tourism-coronavirus-pandemic-travel-industry">end of tourism as an industry</a>. It’s pretty clear that nonstop cruise ships and careless gawkers are tearing apart cities and the natural environment, so it’ll be curious to see if any of that recovers from the COVID-19 shutdown. I think it’s super important for folks to travel to other countries with an open mind, but that seems pretty counter to traveling with a ship full of people just like you.</li><li>I’m pretty excited about this upcoming executive directed Nathan Fielder show:</li></ul><div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/w7aSybHRa6s" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen= title="YouTube Video"/></div><ul><li>Also I wish this were true:</li></ul><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">I don’t want to be alarmist, but my sources inside Walter Reed are telling me that Trump has been having diarrhea for 13 hours straight. “The entire bed is saturated. The floor is covered. It’s even going up the walls. They had to bring in contractors to replace the sheetrock.”</p>&mdash; maple cocaine (@maplecocaine)<a href="https://twitter.com/maplecocaine/status/1312491103979892739?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 3, 2020</a></blockquote><script async= src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"/><ul><li>Have you watched Pen15 yet? If not, I highly recommend giving it a go. Not only is it a hilarious and brutally real portrayal of the time period I grew up in, but it’s even a great portrayal of<a href="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/davidmack/pen15-gabe-gay-storyline">growing up gay</a>. There is a fair amount of second-hand embarrassment, but even if that’s not your thing, I hope you give it a go. I can’t wait for part two of season two!</li><li>Here’s a great read on<a href="https://www.theconsciouskid.org/white-fragility/">white fragility</a>, the all-to-easy to fall into condition for my fellow white folks. I think it’s pretty important to remember that our discomfort pales in comparison to the real threats and pain felt by folks of color around us. This same “I’m hurt that you’re hurt” bullshit extends to queerness and transness as well. Learning and growing is painful, but it’s worth it.</li><li>These are by far the worst sexts I’ve ever read:</li></ul><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Also the sexts in question are just... what?<a href="https://t.co/zTyuRwkJ2w">https://t.co/zTyuRwkJ2w</a><a href="https://t.co/cCisiKqVdi">pic.twitter.com/cCisiKqVdi</a></p>&mdash; Claire Perry (@sclaire_perry)<a href="https://twitter.com/sclaire_perry/status/1312235858981015552?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">October 3, 2020</a></blockquote><script async= src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"/><ul><li>I love this piece on<a href="https://readymag.com/readymag/readme/define_and_conquer/">online writing</a>, though I guess it’s also an advert for the CMS it’s created in. There’s a real The Outline vibe to this, but I found some good tips on typography and spacing amidst all the wackiness. I’ve finally gotten<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com">my site</a> into good shape, but every time I read something like this, I start to inch towards my sass file all over again.</li><li>Wow, it’s time to order<a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/">next year’s Hobonichi Techo</a>. I’ve used one of those diary/journals for the past 3 years, and I dearly love it. There’s a satisfaction to writing down my thoughts and the day’s events on paper. This journal pairs nicely with a<a href="https://www.lamy.com/en/lamy-safari/">good fountain pen</a> because of the high-quality thin paper that doesn’t bleed.</li></ul><h2 id="in-closing">In closing</h2><p>With a month that is so full of wild news, I hope you’re able to take some time to breath and go on a nice ride or walk to clear your head. You’re not alone in this, and Snorri and I are also hiding out, and staying hunkered-down until we have a vaccine. Stay safe, satay healthy, and keep fighting, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Dill &amp; Fennel 9-27-20</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-09-28-dill-fennel-9-27-20/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 02:01:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-09-28-dill-fennel-9-27-20/</guid><description>Dill &amp;amp; Fennel 9-27-20 Everybody watch out, I own a laser now. Far from being a futuristic laser pistol, it’s a much more banal home hair removal laser.</description><content:encoded><h1 id="dill--fennel-9-27-20">Dill &amp; Fennel 9-27-20</h1><p>Everybody watch out, I own a laser now. Far from being a futuristic laser pistol, it’s a much more banal home hair removal laser. As a trans lady, the ‘ol hormones left me with some annoying dark facial hair that I’ve mostly blasted off, but in quarantine time I’ve been unable to finish my treatment. So, if you hear some yowls coming from emeryville, that’s just me.</p><p>This weekend is also a great breadmaking weekend here. I’ve really figured out my bread recipe after months, and this is looking awesome.</p><p>Finally, it’s also time for the Formula 1 race in Russia￼, which hopefully will lead to a more interesting championship fight. I’m still excited for Lewis to clinch more lifetime records, as he clearly deserves all of them. However, I’m also excited to see some up-and-coming racers really making a name for themselves. I hope in the near future though we see more women and people of color in racing generally.</p><p>Let’s get on with&hellip;</p><h2 id="links">Links</h2><ul><li>Do you love design research? Then<a href="https://www.nngroup.com/articles/accordion-icons/">you’re in luck</a>! Apparently it’s all about the caret and not the hamburger icon for accordions. Who knew!</li><li><a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1QdWn7PCDqNUQvzmPaJPMEYqsXKAVcuE0MPxcJVdaKjw/edit#">This document</a> is a really awesome, and super worrying survey of the climate crisis we’re facing. I still believe somehow we will convince humanity to change tack and save our place on this planet, but it’s going to be rough.</li><li>Remember when<a href="https://www.newstatesman.com/science-tech/social-media/2020/09/rich-famous-onlyfans-changing-sex-workers-left-behind-bella-thorne-caroline-calloway-beyonce">OnlyFans was just for cool sex workers</a> and real, real horny content? It turns out ex-Disney stars and other random celebrities have invited and rather ruined it for the rad folks who were making money on it before. Bummer. Listen, if you’re an influencer, stick to Instagram. Fuck off everyone who is like “oh I’ll just sell my nudes” as like a fun hobby—it’s a real job, and it’s real hard.</li><li>Second New Statesman link this week, but<a href="https://www.newstatesman.com/science-tech/social-media/2020/08/better-goodreads-possible-bad-for-books-storygraph-amazon">this one</a> is about a rad new book site called Storygraph. I’ve played around with it for a while this week, and it’s so much better than Goodreads, especially since it isn’t beige or owned by Amazon.</li><li>Have you ever been interviewed by someone with a real shitty agenda?<a href="https://www.newstatesman.com/international/2020/09/judith-butler-culture-wars-jk-rowling-and-living-anti-intellectual-times">Judith Butler teaches a masterclass</a> in this interview on how to parry and riposte just such a poor interview. I remember a lot of things Butler wrote being used against trans women in the early 2000s, but it’s really nice to see them come back to restate and clarify their support of trans women and other trans folks.</li><li>Free is<em>rarely</em> free, and if you aren’t paying for your hosting or web software, you’re often the<a href="https://themarkup.org/blacklight/2020/09/22/blacklight-tracking-advertisers-digital-privacy-sensitive-websites">product they’re really selling</a>. I’d encourage you to think long and hard about supporting cool companies like<a href="https://feedbin.com">Feedbin</a>, and<a href="https://www.fastmail.com">Fastmail</a>, or even just using and contributing to excellent open-source projects like Hugo. This newsletter is sent via<a href="https://buttondown.email">Buttondown</a>, for instance, because it’s well-made, and seems to take privacy and quality seriously instead of focusing on up-and-to-the-right growth.</li></ul><h2 id="in-conclusion">In conclusion</h2><p>It seems like we’re going to deal with COVID for another year at best, which is pretty frustrating. I hope you’re registered to vote, and are involved in local politics as well. We need better leadership, an more representation from folks of color, women, queers, and younger people. It’s super obvious that a country run by rich white people in their 70s is just going to such, so I hope we can pushing for something better.</p><p>I definitely have had a hard time with so much of the news and the utter lack of justice for black folks murdered by police, especially Breonna Taylor. This can’t continue.</p><p>I am in this with you, and I care. Let’s keep fighting together as long as we can. Keep safe, keep resisting, and see you next week, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Dill &amp; Fennel 9-20-20</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-09-20-dill-fennel-9-20-20/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 22:05:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-09-20-dill-fennel-9-20-20/</guid><description>Dill &amp;amp; Fennel 9-20-20 Finally, a brief respite in the smoke! I got to go on a nice long bike ride around the lake as soon as the air hit green.</description><content:encoded><h1 id="dill--fennel-9-20-20">Dill &amp; Fennel 9-20-20</h1><p>Finally, a brief respite in the smoke! I got to go on a nice long bike ride around the lake as soon as the air hit green. The rest of the week could’ve been spent outside, but I mostly just worked-out and play video games. Oh well.</p><p>The news of RBG’s death last night made me pretty sad, but also reminded me that a future that’s better than any past we’ve had depends on each and every one of us resisting and working towards it. It’s very helpful when folks dedicate their lives towards causes, but if everyone puts in like 10% effort we’d be in a better place, I think. So, VOTE. Donate. I’m on the host committee this year for the Trans Law Center’s gala, so it would be dope if you<a href="https://app.mobilecause.com/e/YB54-Q?vid=br1bq">attended or threw in some cash</a>.</p><p>Otherwise, I’m playing lots of Dark Souls (yes, the first one), and cooking, and trying to learn how to mop effectively. It turns out after 35 years of life, I might actually be someone who cleans regularly. I still miss being able to hire a housekeeper though.</p><p>Let’s get on with the links!</p><h2 id="links">Links</h2><ul><li>Ann Helen Petersen, recently of the Burnout article that went around wrote about<a href="https://elemental.medium.com/your-surge-capacity-is-depleted-it-s-why-you-feel-awful-de285d542f4c">surge capacity</a>. We’ve all been operating in bursts since March 2020, in addition to the nexus of challenges and pains that we’re dealing with normally.</li><li>Have you heard how everyone is<em>fleeing the cities</em> for the suburbs? It<em>turns out</em> that<a href="https://www.curbed.com/2020/8/31/21404333/suburbs-housing-boom-urban-exodus-coronavirus">just isn’t true</a>. There’s so much fearmongering these days, but despite rents falling a bit in cities like San Francisco, folks’ reasons for staying in the cities are the same as their reasons for moving there in the first place. For me at least, moving somewhere without queer or trans rights just<em>isn’t an option</em>.</li></ul><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Thread of the most beautiful Libraries of the World<br><br>1. The Royal Portuguese Cabinet of Reading , Rio De Janeiro.<br>Credit: Alamy<a href="https://t.co/Y1d3rENLkc">pic.twitter.com/Y1d3rENLkc</a></p>&mdash; Joaquim Campa (@JoaquimCampa)<a href="https://twitter.com/JoaquimCampa/status/1294522730021367808?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 15, 2020</a></blockquote><script async= src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"/><ul><li>I dove back into the sand world of Dune recently, and as a long time fan of the first book and the Lynch film, I am glad to be sorta-kinda<a href="https://theoutline.com/post/5333/dune-revival-2018-david-lynch">in the “Dune fandom”</a>. I’m hopeful the new film doesn’t truly fuck up Dune, but we’ll see.</li></ul><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Look, even if I’m not a fan of his, I’m amped for Timmy Chalet’s big desert adventure.<br>(also rereading the novels for good measure)</p>&mdash; brook shelley (@brookshelley)<a href="https://twitter.com/brookshelley/status/1303783966067929088?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 9, 2020</a></blockquote><script async= src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"/><ul><li>This remains<a href="https://theoutline.com/post/5495/how-to-beat-linked-in-the-game">one of the funniest things I’ve read in a while</a>. Joe is a great writer, and a good friend. I don’t think he’s ever endorsed me for anything on LinkedIn, but if I knew how to endorse people, I would endorse him for “humorous content”, and “looks good in a Miata”.</li><li>Speaking of Joe, he texted me a<a href="https://mango.pdf.zone/finding-former-australian-prime-minister-tony-abbotts-passport-number-on-instagram">very good link</a> the other night, and it had me dead from laughter. The rollercoaster of this “hack” and the eventual conclusion is a delight throughout. Good job MangoPDF. Good job.</li><li>Finally, let’s talk about<a href="https://www.bbc.com/future/article/20190206-what-the-meat-paradox-reveals-about-moral-decision-making"><em>eating meat</em></a>. Yea, that’s right, putting dead animal parts into our mouth holes. It’s weird, but also totally normal. It<em>turns out</em> most of us don’t like to consider how those animal parts get into our mouth holes from fields and trees. I eat a very plant-heavy diet these days, and try to consume only animals I would or have killed. I can’t say you have to live your life this way by any means, but I<em>do</em> think it’s worth considering the impact your diet has on the world and on specific animals.</li></ul><h2 id="in-closing">In closing</h2><p>The best time to start meditating is yesterday, and the second best time is today, to paraphrase something half-remembered. If you can take some time to just breathe, it’s a neat, free way to feel just a little bit better. If you have a little bit more money and time, therapy is also excellent. We’ll be in this kinda shit for a while to come, it seems like, and I know I’ve benefited from support and these two practices.</p><p>Hopefully some of the links this week made you laugh a bit, because laughter is dope. I hope wherever you’re reading this from you’ve got a nice day ahead of you. Stay safe, keep fighting, and I’ll see you next week, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Dill &amp; Fennel 9-13-20</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-09-13-dill-fennel-9-17-20/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 20:55:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-09-13-dill-fennel-9-17-20/</guid><description>Dill &amp;amp; Fennel 9-13-20 Greetings from the surface of Mars! Wednesday in the Bay Area was deeply scary and awful, but the smoke has stayed here albeit in a lower-to-the-ground fashion all week.</description><content:encoded><h1 id="dill--fennel-9-13-20">Dill &amp; Fennel 9-13-20</h1><p>Greetings from the surface of Mars! Wednesday in the Bay Area was deeply scary and awful, but the smoke has stayed here albeit in a lower-to-the-ground fashion all week. I haven’t really been outside since two Wednesdays ago, and I hate it.</p><p>Keep folks in Oregon in your thoughts too, because their air quality is even worse than ours, and friends around Portland are preparing to potentially evacuate. It’s a scary time!</p><p>I know you don’t come here for sad news, but that’s what I’ve got to lead with today, sorry!</p><p>In positive news, it’s the Tuscan GP weekend in F1, and the track is super fast and wild. I don’t think it’ll be a big passing track, but qualifying was super close. Also Monday is a fairly interesting conversation for your host, me, so light a candle or something for that. More news to come, hopefully.</p><p>For now though, let’s<em>link it up</em>.</p><h2 id="links">Links</h2><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">My econ professor said “beef” 125 times in a single lecture. Here are all of them<a href="https://t.co/MZZ1cfA0pe">pic.twitter.com/MZZ1cfA0pe</a></p>&mdash; Tino Cardasis (@CardasisTino)<a href="https://twitter.com/CardasisTino/status/1209200726959894528?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">December 23, 2019</a></blockquote><script async= src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"/><ul><li>File this under “hilariously silly,” but supposedly satanists are handing out<a href="https://www.thesun.co.uk/news/4394932/illuminati-satanists-are-handing-out-of-cursed-rosary-beads-to-unsuspecting-catholics-leaving-them-haunted-by-evil-spirits-warns-chief-exorcist/">“cursed” rosary beads</a> to unsuspecting Catholics. Hail Satan! While I’m not sure that curses actually work, I’m all the way here for cursing people. Placebos<em>are</em> effective, so perhaps placebo curses are also effective? Let’s curse the bastards.</li><li>Speaking of curses, are you cursed with specialist knowledge you can’t communicate? Steven Pinker has<a href="https://fs.blog/2016/03/stephen-pinker-tells-us-why-our-professional-writing-sucks-and-what-to-do/">some tips</a>! This was a pretty interesting read on how to write for you audience, instead of your coworkers when writing technically. I personally loathe super-jargon-y writing, of which there is a ton in tech. So, I hope you absorb this for anything you write, and aim towards digestible, interesting writing.</li><li>This last week, for no apparent reason I started rewatching all the Mission Impossible films from the beginning. I find Tom Cruise pretending to be deeply straight quite amusing, and was convinced by my pal Drew that watching him run is also a delight. I think the 4th movie is my favorite so far, but hilariously I found out that MI3 was<a href="https://www.firstpost.com/tech/news-analysis/mission-impossible-3-on-nokia-n93-3549677.html">released on the Nokia N93</a> which is featured in the film. I’m all about stupid merchandising tie-ins, and this one is perfect. Imagine watching Tom Cruise run around on a 2.4’<a href="https://www.gsmarena.com/nokia_n93-1551.php">240x320px screen</a>. This was a time period where I was importing Nokia phones from Asia and Europe to use myself, so I definitely wanted this absurd phone for myself. I wonder<a href="https://www.ebay.com/itm/Nokia-N-Series-N93-Silver-Unlocked-Smartphone/143623148929?hash=item21709b5581:g:zTAAAOSwPpZaIEbg">if EBay has one with MI3 loaded?</a></li><li>This week, I was also thinking about how Q Anon is just an updated version of anti-Semitic blood libel bullshit. Turns out,<a href="https://www.justsecurity.org/72339/qanon-is-a-nazi-cult-rebranded/">I wasn’t the only one</a>. I find this stuff seriously disturbing, in addition to being utterly absurd. I genuinely wish people would find a way to disown Zionist crap, and embrace Jewish people and perhaps even the Jewish faith.</li><li>This week marked the 19th anniversary of 9/11, and<a href="https://www.opednews.com/articles/American-Muslims-19-years-by-Abdus-Sattar-Ghaza-Activist_Alliances_American-Muslim-Voice_Anti-Muslim-200911-172.html">anti-Muslim sentiment is still a huge problem</a>. My Muslim friends have described the<a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2012/05/was-there-really-a-post-9-11-backlash-against-muslims/256725/">abuse</a> and<a href="https://www.pri.org/stories/2016-09-12/data-hate-crimes-against-muslims-increased-after-911">hatred</a> they felt in the ensuing 19 years, and It makes me sick. No one should be persecuted or hated for their faith or culture. Learn about Islam, and care for the Muslim folks around you. Stand up to the bullies and bigots, because our planet is too small to be a narrow-minded asshole.</li><li>Let’s learn to<a href="https://blog.longnow.org/02020/07/20/six-ways-to-think-long-term-a-cognitive-toolkit-for-good-ancestors/">think long-term</a>. This planet will outlast the human race, possibly, but most certainly a struggle and hope for rights and a better world will outlast those of us reading this in 2020. It’s a great idea to<a href="https://charleseisenstein.org/essays/building-a-peace-narrative/">think of a peace narrative</a>, and commit to efforts that will last for generations. I personally find a great deal of solace in being part of a multi-generational effort to win rights and support for LGBTQIA folks around the world. Find your cause, be it environmental, or social, or both, and get involved. The planet will appreciate it, as will many generations to come.</li><li>To finish out this week, let’s consider how wild it is that<a href="http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/health/790609.stm">so many people die on stairs</a>. There are<em>way</em> more deaths on stairs than due to shark attacks, but a movie about falling down the stairs would be pretty boring. Unless&hellip; what if the stairs were<em>haunted</em>? Spooky, killer stairs. I dunno. Just spitballing here.</li></ul><h2 id="in-closing">In closing</h2><p>Let’s have a better week than last week! Reach out to a friend or two you haven’t talked to in a while, and say hi. Tell them you care, and you’re thinking of them. We’ll get through this present series of crisis, and I personally think part of doing so is deepening the community we’ve built. Hug a friend (safely), pet, or partner and think of the things in your life you’re grateful for and the things you love.</p><p>Silly, or poignant, there are so many amazing works of art and media in the world. Are you reading or watching anything fun?<a href="mailto:hello@brookshelley.com">Let me know</a>.</p><p>Also, happy Apple announcement week to those of you who eagerly anticipate spending money at the altar of Apple, Inc. It should be a wild ride.</p><p>This week’s email was a bit all over the place for me emotionally, but that’s where I’m at, so sorry/not-sorry. As always though, take care, and keep fighting, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Dill &amp; Fennel 9-6-20</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-09-06-dill-fennel-9-6-20/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 19:44:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-09-06-dill-fennel-9-6-20/</guid><description>Dill &amp;amp; Fennel 9-6-20 Well, it’s hot again in the Bay Area, on top of this wild smoke we’ve got everywhere.</description><content:encoded><h1 id="dill--fennel-9-6-20">Dill &amp; Fennel 9-6-20</h1><p>Well, it’s hot again in the Bay Area, on top of this wild smoke we’ve got everywhere. I’m pretty tired of it, for one, especially since I mostly want to hike and ride my bike right now. I<em>did</em> manage to go outside a little today to repot a LOT of plants. More on that later, but here’s one pretty plant from my house to tide you over.</p><p>I hope you’re finding things to keep you occupied—there’s plenty of new stuff on the various streaming platforms, and I’ve personally enjoyed the new Wallander and Away.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Tired: young pope<br>Wired: young wallander</p>&mdash; brook shelley (@brookshelley)<a href="https://twitter.com/brookshelley/status/1302086809304915968?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 5, 2020</a></blockquote><script async= src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"/><h2 id="links">Links</h2><ul><li>I’m pretty glad to see a bunch of idiots’ boats sinking, though I hope they pay to remove them from the lake.</li></ul><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Pro-Trump boats take on water during Lake Travis parade<br><a href="https://t.co/CX49uWF2SS">https://t.co/CX49uWF2SS</a><a href="https://t.co/w9iGnO23HU">pic.twitter.com/w9iGnO23HU</a></p>&mdash; Austin Statesman (@statesman)<a href="https://twitter.com/statesman/status/1302331295339556866?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 5, 2020</a></blockquote><script async= src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"/><ul><li>Speaking of idiots, there are a bunch of evangelicals who are now<a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/2020/08/26/1007611/how-qanon-is-targeting-evangelicals/">Q Anon delusion believers</a>. I’m torn between being extremely worried about how scary these folks are, and amused at just the outlandish things they believe.</li><li><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/shittyrobots/comments/iizzfz/idk_where_this_belongs_but_thought_this_sub_might/">Just look at this bonkers robot!</a></li><li>For too long our tiniest furry friends have gone without a good place to buy vinyl, but<a href="https://www.thenational.ae/arts-culture/art/ricotta-records-tiny-record-store-by-anonymouse-pops-up-in-sweden-1.1059889"><em>no more</em></a>. I love everything about this, to be honest. Small joy.</li><li>This&hellip; this is a good sheep:</li></ul><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">I watched this like 20 times already this evening and I am about to watch it again<a href="https://t.co/JuZ7pLeaO5">pic.twitter.com/JuZ7pLeaO5</a></p>&mdash; James Vincent (@jjvincent)<a href="https://twitter.com/jjvincent/status/1302045212387217415?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 5, 2020</a></blockquote><script async= src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"/><ul><li>On the note of the tv show Away, one plot point is whether or not space blindness will effect astronauts as they make their way to Mars, so of course I<a href="https://www.sciencealert.com/we-finally-know-why-astronauts-lose-their-vision-in-space-and-it-s-bad-news-for-mars-missions">read more about it</a>.</li></ul><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Forest recordings from around the world. 🌳🌲🌳🌲<a href="https://t.co/LhsHyRMsKs">https://t.co/LhsHyRMsKs</a><br><br>Via Things magazine<a href="https://t.co/ycoYNb9rbm">pic.twitter.com/ycoYNb9rbm</a></p>&mdash; Present &amp; Correct (@presentcorrect)<a href="https://twitter.com/presentcorrect/status/1301836837774819328?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 4, 2020</a></blockquote><script async= src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"/><h2 id="in-closing">In closing</h2><p>Well, it’s time for me to get back to reading Dune: Messiah, and watching Young Wallander while I try to stay cooled-off and out of the smoke. Happy Labor Day! Please check your voter registration, and make sure to vote for local progressive candidates in November (or whenever mail-in ballots show up). If you’re reading this, I miss you, and I hope we can get a beer sometime soon.<a href="mailto:newsletter@brookshelley.com">Reach out</a> if you want to show off your indoor forest. Stay safe and keep fighting, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Dill &amp; Fennel 8-30-20</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-08-30-dill-fennel-8-30-20/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 19:10:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-08-30-dill-fennel-8-30-20/</guid><description>Dill &amp;amp; Fennel 8-30-20 Welcome to my delayed last newsletter of the month. I had some pals by yesterday to sit at a distance in my courtyard and when the last one went home, I fell right asleep.</description><content:encoded><h1 id="dill--fennel-8-30-20">Dill &amp; Fennel 8-30-20</h1><p>Welcome to my delayed last newsletter of the month. I had some pals by yesterday to sit at a distance in my courtyard and when the last one went home, I fell right asleep. It’s such a nice thing to see friends right now, especially when you can share some wine and lots of laughs.</p><p>This week is a mix of weird and sad as usual. I’m working on some longer form posts for brookshelley.com in the coming week about backpacking and mechanical keyboards, so keep your eyes peeled for those too.</p><h2 id="links">Links</h2><ul><li>What if environmentalism but also<a href="https://www.counterpunch.org/2020/06/26/the-big-green-lie/">racist and xenophobic</a>? Unsurprisingly the global north doesn’t want to talk about our role in destroying the planet through unreasonable use of resources. It’s just so much easier to blame the “other” of the global south for having children, or daring to build industry. The sooner we see Earth as a planet we all need to share equally, the better in my mind.</li><li>Speaking of resources, I watched quite a bit of the TV show Alone over the past few weeks in preparation for a<em>podcast</em> and I wondered, “how easy would it be for them to harvest salt from the ocean to season their dang food?” The answer, it turns out, is both<a href="https://www.outdoorrevival.com/instant-articles/harvesting-salt-from-the-ocean-a-great-skill-to-learn.html">not too hard</a>, and very challenging to do in a survival situation. I super hope on some season someone becomes a master of seasoning.</li><li>If you were a kid in the 80s, you might remember these fantastic toys from MASK, and apparently huge dead stock crates still exist of them:</li></ul><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Amazing warehouse find of sealed cased<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/MASK?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#MASK</a> toys in Antofagasta, Chile. From reports the majority of pieces have all already been sold at upwards of $100 US a piece. What I wouldn't give to get a<a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Meteor?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#Meteor</a> from this lot.<br><br>Follow the insanity on FB here;<a href="https://t.co/ZcQDJCbjun">https://t.co/ZcQDJCbjun</a><a href="https://t.co/lWcLkhlE9s">pic.twitter.com/lWcLkhlE9s</a></p>&mdash; 🇨🇦Social Beasting (@CybertronBeast)<a href="https://twitter.com/CybertronBeast/status/1299053766466043905?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 27, 2020</a></blockquote><script async= src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"/><ul><li>The MASK toys led me down a bit of a curiosity hole, and I found out a<a href="https://tfwiki.net/wiki/Rubsign">cool feature of Transformers</a> was<em>actually</em> a way of verifying toys weren’t<a href="http://www.collectiondx.com/toy_line/bootleg">bootleg</a>. Honestly, bootleg toys are super weird and cool. I fondly remember shopping at dollar stores and shitty grocery stores that mostly stocked these knock-offs. If you’re still a fan of Transformers, like I know my friend Justin is, you might enjoy looking at<a href="http://www.transrepro.com/">these reproduction parts</a> made by a guy with a passion for recreation. The world of toys is&hellip; something I try to avoid spending money on, but it’s certainly tempting to help 35 year-old Brook live the dreams of poor kid Brook.</li><li>Do you like cats? Do you like poems? Here’s some very old Chinese poems from a person who hired a cat to kill his pests, and ended-up as we all do, falling in love:</li></ul><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">decided to do a separate thread for this so here we go: how Song dynasty poet Lu You poem-liveblogged his descent from cat owner to cat slave 800 years ago<br><br>The year is 1183. Down On His Luck scholar-official Lu You gets a cat because rats keep munching on his books. 1/?<a href="https://t.co/MdMgVdiY5V">pic.twitter.com/MdMgVdiY5V</a></p>&mdash; XIRAN, Chinese History Meowmer (@XiranJayZhao)<a href="https://twitter.com/XiranJayZhao/status/1299148337774354432?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 28, 2020</a></blockquote><script async= src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"/><h2 id="in-closing">In closing</h2><p>Sorry about the delay! I am writing this conclusion while I watch the Belgian Grand Prix, grateful that F1 has managed to race despite not having a<em>bubble</em>. This week was long, but next week I’m on<em>vacation</em>! I’m excited, even if I don’t get to do much outdoor adventuring due to the smoke that blankets so much of California right now. I hope you too get to take a vacation soon—you deserve it. For now though, stay safe, keep fighting and I’ll see you next week, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Dill &amp; Fennel 8-23-20</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-08-23-dill-fennel-8-23-20/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 20:39:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-08-23-dill-fennel-8-23-20/</guid><description>Dill &amp;amp; Fennel 8-23-20 Ah, breathe deep the fires of California. Just in case you needed another reason to stay inside and wear a mask, dry thunderstorms have delivered.</description><content:encoded><h1 id="dill--fennel-8-23-20">Dill &amp; Fennel 8-23-20</h1><p>Ah, breathe deep the fires of California. Just in case you needed another reason to stay inside and wear a mask, dry thunderstorms have delivered. I don’t know how you feel about this but it’s pretty depressing and scary to me.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="und" dir="ltr"><a href="https://t.co/ZmCjVZyNEV">pic.twitter.com/ZmCjVZyNEV</a></p>&mdash; Matt Haughey 😷 (@mathowie)<a href="https://twitter.com/mathowie/status/1296501978755997696?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 20, 2020</a></blockquote><script async= src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"/><p>Sorry to kick off with a bummer! I hope you’re ok with occasionally being sad together before we dig into the joyful weirdness of links. Thanks friends.</p><h2 id="links">Links</h2><ul><li>Now that it’s reached the end of an 8 year run, I can safely send you to the delightful series<a href="http://ohumanstar.com/comic/chapter-1-title-page/">Oh Human Star</a>. Perhaps someone can share with me a good way of keeping track of your progress through a web comic, but I’ve been reading this via a manual updated bookmark for a while. It’s cool, it’s queer, and Blue is a really nice human.</li><li>As a stock market player/money-haver who previously worries about having food to eat and electricity as a kid, it’s very apparent to me how huge a gap there is between the rich and the poor. Here’s more about<a href="https://inthesetimes.com/article/stock-market-real-economy-disconnect-unemployment-poverty-coronavirus-trump">that horrific reality</a>. What if we all committed to addressing this wealth and economy gap in our lifetimes?</li><li>WOW, I hope you like uncontrollable bathroom problems! Remember Olestra?<a href="https://priceonomics.com/the-failure-of-the-fat-free-revolution/">Remember that whole nightmare?</a> I certainly do. For some reason (diet culture) my family was really into Wow chips, even once it was somewhat obvious that they were going though us like<a href="https://www.livestrong.com/article/13727278-tips-lose-weight-after-quarantine/">konjac</a>. Man, the 90s were weird.</li><li>Speaking of things I can’t digest, albeit in this case delicious ones, why not try some<a href="https://www.atlasobscura.com/articles/how-to-make-so-cheese">ancient Japanese cheese?</a>. I<em>love</em> these culinary trips into history, especially when they actually look delicious. Beer recipes from thousands of years ago? Count me in! And yet, they still won’t let us<a href="https://allthatsinteresting.com/egyptian-sarcophagus-red-juice">drink the mummy juice</a>.</li><li>If, like me, you’ve taken to reading during the quarantine you may have encountered<a href="https://www.penguin.co.uk/articles/2020/june/how-to-ignore-phone-while-reading-books.html">this roadblock</a>. Spoiler: it’s your phone. IMO turn off all your notifications always, because if someone needs you they’ll call you. My friend<a href="http://helentseng.com">Helen</a> gave me<a href="https://phonebreakup.com">this book</a> a year or two ago, and it was pretty helpful in finding new ways to be a little more at peace with my devices.</li></ul><h2 id="in-closing">In closing</h2><p>What’s one thing you want to do this week that makes you happy? For me, it’s making rice pudding. I love rice pudding and I’ve never cooked it, so I’m pretty amped. Oh, and I’m baking more bread, obviously. I also<em>treated</em> myself to a game from my wish list: Farcry 5. I’ve heard it’s deeply strange and I can’t wait to dive in.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">If you need me, please go fuck yourself<a href="https://t.co/8ewMMjYlTg">pic.twitter.com/8ewMMjYlTg</a></p>&mdash; Mark Mahoney (@markmahoney)<a href="https://twitter.com/markmahoney/status/1292569441465597952?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 9, 2020</a></blockquote><script async= src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"/><p>I hope whatever you do that brings you joy can capture your attention and heart for even a few minutes. As always, stay safe and keep fighting, space cowgirls~.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Dill &amp; Fennel 8-17-20</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-08-16-dill-fennel-8-17-20/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 19:50:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-08-16-dill-fennel-8-17-20/</guid><description>Dill &amp;amp; Fennel 8-17-20 This weeks email was written an entire day early as I plan to head up a mountain and camp for a night.</description><content:encoded><h1 id="dill--fennel-8-17-20">Dill &amp; Fennel 8-17-20</h1><p>This weeks email was written an entire day early as I plan to head up a mountain and camp for a night. It&rsquo;s going to be<a href="https://weatherwest.com/archives/7427"><em>hot</em></a> so I hope the mountain is a little cooler. This will be round one of camping during quarantine, and my first camping trip since 2017! I&rsquo;ve finally found friends who are equally interested in camping and hit me up when they want to do so. It rules.</p><p>With a VP candidate announced, and the USPS falling apart, it&rsquo;s beginning to look at lot like<em>election season</em>. Please vote (for Biden). I know, he&rsquo;s not great, but he&rsquo;s all we&rsquo;ve got this time. Next time, let&rsquo;s primary the awful old white men.</p><p>With that weather and politics update out of the way, let&rsquo;s get to these links.</p><h2 id="links">Links</h2><p>I love these eggs.</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Many people have been using quarantine as a time to perfect their bread or coffee making skills, but I personally have taken this as an opportunity to make increasingly unsettling eggs<a href="https://t.co/7mefhS5ffB">pic.twitter.com/7mefhS5ffB</a></p>&mdash; Anna Hughes (@AnnaGHughes)<a href="https://twitter.com/AnnaGHughes/status/1294270430518312966?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">August 14, 2020</a></blockquote><script async= src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"/><ul><li>Somehow I haven&rsquo;t read<a href="https://bookshop.org/books/trick-mirror-reflections-on-self-delusion/9780525510567">Trick Mirror</a> yet, despite loving everything Jia Tolentino writes or says<a href="https://www.interviewmagazine.com/culture/ask-a-sane-person-jia-tolentino-book-2020-hope">during interviews</a>. This is a bracing set of answers that feel pretty close to how I&rsquo;m feeling these days. Also I have a soft spot for Canadian ex-pats who grew up in Texas.</li><li>Frequently linked author Robin Sloan has a new story online that he<a href="https://www.robinsloan.com/books/annabel-scheme-serial/">built a whole reading platform</a> around. It&rsquo;s pretty fun and weird, like most of his writing. Recommended.</li><li>Also if you&rsquo;re reading this and you haven&rsquo;t dived into the world of Gideon and Harrow,<a href="https://us.macmillan.com/books/9781250313225">please do</a>. Lesbian. Necromancy. In. Space. Enough said.</li><li>I deeply respect swifts` attitudes toward the ground, which is roughly,<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/07/29/magazine/vesper-flights.html">&ldquo;fuck the ground&rdquo;</a>. Honestly if I could fly, I might feel the same. Also you&rsquo;ve gotta love a bird that was once &ldquo;called the “Devil’s bird,” perhaps because those screaming flocks of black crosses around churches seemed pulled from darkness, not light.&rdquo;</li><li>Ugh, first it was walking and jumping, and now robots have<a href="https://gizmodo.com/this-lightning-fast-robotic-tongue-ensures-youll-snatch-1844726672">fast, sticky tongues</a>. Honestly though, perhaps the robots should inherit the world after-all.</li></ul><p>Shout out to friend of the &lsquo;letter Drl who made me aware of this epic TikTok thread with this delight:</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">82. THIS IS CALLED “G-NOTING” BTW<a href="https://t.co/qPwLcA86n6">pic.twitter.com/qPwLcA86n6</a></p>&mdash; my life with the grill pill kult (@3liza)<a href="https://twitter.com/3liza/status/1088001781534154752?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">January 23, 2019</a></blockquote><script async= src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"/><h2 id="in-closing">In closing</h2><p>Stay cool out there friends! This year is far from over, and there&rsquo;s a lot to get done, think about, and protect our neighbors and ourselves from. Thanks for sticking with me throughout this time, and I hope I can keep bringing you funny, weird, and thought-provoking links indefinitely. As always, stay safe and keep fighting, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Dill &amp; Fennel 8-9-20</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-08-09-dill-fennel-8-9-20/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 10:44:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-08-09-dill-fennel-8-9-20/</guid><description>Dill &amp;amp; Fennel 8-9-20 How’s your August going? Are you doing any hiking or swimming? Planning any solo adventures? I’m planning a backpacking trip in the near future that has me pretty stoked, especially because of all the gear I get to buy and try out.</description><content:encoded><h1 id="dill--fennel-8-9-20">Dill &amp; Fennel 8-9-20</h1><p>How’s your August going? Are you doing any hiking or swimming? Planning any solo adventures? I’m planning a backpacking trip in the near future that has me pretty stoked, especially because of all the gear I get to buy and try out. I’m a sucker for gear,<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-16-traveling-during-a-pandemic/">obviously</a>. I spent all of Saturday finishing the latest Tamsyn Muir book,<a href="https://bookshop.org/books/harrow-the-ninth/9781250313225">Harrow the Ninth</a>, and eating oysters with a couple pals at an outdoor distance (hi Christine and Anna).</p><p>I also almost forgot to write this week’s email, as I decided to redo the CSS for my website<em>yet again</em> and watch the movie Prometheus after waking from my book stupor. Luckily, I remembered right before bed, so apologies if this is a bit loopy.</p><h2 id="links">Links</h2><ul><li>Let’s talk about<a href="https://aeon.co/essays/how-attachment-theory-works-in-the-therapeutic-relationship"><em>attachment theory</em></a>, baybee, let’s talk about you and your therapist. I’ve happily gone to therapy for the past decade, and if you haven’t found a therapist you like, perhaps read this and then just go find one.</li><li>One of the loveliest ways to fix broken things is with gold&hellip; even if the broken thing is a<a href="https://thekidshouldseethis.com/post/kintsugi-court-victor-solomon-video">basketball court</a>.</li><li>Did you play with LEGO as a kid? Do you still enjoy it as an adult? You might love this deep-dive into<a href="https://www.designedbycave.co.uk/2020/LEGO-Interface-UX/">LEGO instrument panels</a>. For my part, I’ve only bought one lego item since the quarantine began, because I fear if I buy more I will have a house filled with whimsical cities and vehicles at an upsetting rate.</li><li>Do you edit photos for a blog? You might enjoy<a href="https://www.subtraction.com/2020/08/06/exactpic-a-shortcut-for-precise-image-outputs-on-ios/">Khoi Vinh’s photo resize shortcut for iOS</a>. Personally, it’s a little too heavy for my use, so I<a href="https://www.icloud.com/shortcuts/c759c619e2d7405d9bbb6bc49808f5b8">made my own</a>. Maybe between the two of these you can find something you like.</li></ul><h2 id="in-closing">In closing</h2><p>I can’t believe summer is almost over! I think I talked about this last week too, but it’s wild to me that summer has largely happened indoors, with nary a lake or pool in my life. I’m pretty excited about the opportunity to go camping soonish though, because I’ve really missed being able to hike and camp since leaving Texas and my outdoor pals behind. Hopefully in the coming weeks I’ll have some exciting (but not too exciting) photos and stories to share from<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-08-07-a-few-weeks-with-a/">my new camera</a>. As always, stay safe, keep fighting, and I’ll see you next week space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Dill &amp; Fennel 31</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-08-02-dill-fennel-31/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 07:40:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-08-02-dill-fennel-31/</guid><description>Dill &amp;amp; Fennel 31 Another weekend is upon us! Blessed weekend! It’s August, can you believe it?! I read some old journal entries today from the before times and it’s funny to see how much my life and activities were the same as they are now.</description><content:encoded><h1 id="dill--fennel-31">Dill &amp; Fennel 31</h1><p>Another weekend is upon us! Blessed weekend! It’s August, can you believe it?! I read some old journal entries today from the<em>before times</em> and it’s funny to see how much my life and activities were the same as they are now. When this pandemic is wrapped-up, I know I’ll appreciate a quick visit to a wine bar much more, at least for a few weeks. This week also marked the end of my second month of 3x a week workout classes, which I<em>think</em> is making a difference in my energy and emotional health. Have you gotten some exercise recently? Even some stretches can be nice, trust me. Either way, let’s both take a deep inhale&hellip;</p><p>&hellip;and a big exhale.</p><p>There now, you’re ready for<em>these links</em>.</p><h2 id="links">Links</h2><ul><li>This week marked the<a href="http://www.thehugoawards.org/hugo-history/2020-hugo-awards/">2020 Hugo awards</a>, which means if you enjoy sci-fi and haven’t read a ton this year, you’ll have quite a bit of excellent stuff to catch up on. My plan is to read<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Emergency-Skin-Forward-collection-Jemisin-ebook/dp/B07VFMFPP4">Emergency Skin by N.K. Jemison</a> this weekend.</li><li>You may have heard about QAnon, the weird new conspiracy cult that popped-up over the past few years, but did you know how it’s<a href="https://melmagazine.com/en-us/story/qanon-conspiracy-cult-losing-family">destroying families</a>? It turns out when you believe absolutely ridiculous theories, your friends and family tend to steer clear. I’m very curious, and more than a little scared to find out how this whole Q thing shakes out.</li><li>Listen, it might be a rather solitary fall out there, but there’s no reason for you not to look your best.<a href="https://tienda.baumm.com/us/camperas/">These jackets</a> are a great way to say “fuck it, I dress for me!”</li><li>If you’ve already read all the Hugo-nominated novels and novellas, perhaps you might want to follow BDG’s example and<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WEWEdIcx1DI&amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;t=1381">drown your sorrows in Halo</a>. As a one-time reader of Magic the Gathering and Battletech novels, I think I’ll give them a wide-berth, but your mileage may vary.</li><li>This week marked the often bizarre (thanks a lot go-go juice)<a href="https://www.theverge.com/interface/2020/7/30/21346575/tech-antitrust-hearing-recap-bezos-zuckerberg-cook-pichai">anti-trust hearing</a>with the leaders of Google, Apple, Facebook, and Amazon. There’s a lot to worry about with the consolidation of power and influence in these tech titans, and<a href="https://www.offscreenmag.com/blog/issue-23-editors-note">I’m not the only one</a> considering how COVID isolation bolsters it.</li><li>Finally, I decided to pick up a<a href="https://www.dpreview.com/reviews/ricoh-gr-iii">fancy new camera</a> to give myself even more reason to go outside and explore a little during this quarantine. It’s been pretty fun, even if most of the photos I’ve taken are of my cat, Snorri.</li></ul><h2 id="in-closing">In closing</h2><p>With the summer dwindling and a very cozy fall in our near future, I hope you’re taking care of yourself, and stockpiling wool blankets and candles. I’m pretty excited for a few books and shows that will launch in the coming months, not to mention the rest of the F1 season still to come. I’m not fully sure what it’ll feel like to keep going with this largely self-quarantined life until next year, but we’ll all learn together, one week at a time. Take care, and enjoy a lazy Sunday for me, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Dill &amp; Fennel 30</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-07-26-dill-fennel-30/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 07:25:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-07-26-dill-fennel-30/</guid><description>Dill &amp;amp; Fennel 30 This weekend was pretty nice in the Shelley house—we started early by taking Friday off to volunteer for the Women’s Foundation (Snorri mostly yelled), and spent the rest of our time laying around (Snorri), and playing Good Sudoku.</description><content:encoded><h1 id="dill--fennel-30">Dill &amp; Fennel 30</h1><p>This weekend was pretty nice in the Shelley house—we started early by taking Friday off to volunteer for the Women’s Foundation (Snorri mostly yelled), and spent the rest of our time laying around (Snorri), and playing<a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/good-sudoku-by-zach-gage/id1489118195">Good Sudoku</a>. I’ve also thought about getting back into shooting photos and biking around, which could be a fun adventure. In preparation, I even picked-up a<a href="https://www.dpreview.com/reviews/ricoh-gr-iii">new camera</a>, so expect better pictures of my cat and neighborhood soon. Can you believe there’s only one more week in July? I wish I could go swimming somewhere, but I don’t think it’s in the cards.</p><p><img src="/photos/snorrisleep.jpg" alt="sleepysnorri"/><h2 id="links">Links</h2><ul><li>Enter the world of<a href="https://www.freightwaves.com/news/qa-inside-the-high-stakes-world-of-clandestine-crude-shipping">clandestine shipping</a>. I’m fascinated by what feels like<em>real spy shit</em> but is a lot of staring at satellite imagery all day. Maybe spy shit is boring most of the time?</li><li>Fuck the Kochs and their<a href="https://www.inthepublicinterest.org/wp-content/uploads/ITPI_USPSPrivatization_July2020.pdf">war against our country</a>. Personally, I depend on the USPS for so much stuff, and I believe having a national mail service is vital to any thriving nation. Perhaps we should instead not require the post office to turn a profit? Thank your postal worker in the meantime, because they’re literally risking their lives to serve us.</li><li>For a long time we’ve know that tipping is a bad deal for everyone, but did you also know it has<a href="https://www.politico.com/magazine/story/2019/07/17/william-barber-tipping-racist-past-227361">origins in white supremacy</a>? Turns out. I wish we had zero sales tax (it’s regressive), and a high living wage for all workers that didn’t need to go to healthcare. I’m trying to think a little bit about a positive future in the ruins of pre-covid world, especially after reading<a href="https://monocle.com/magazine/issues/134/">50 folks in Monocle thinking big</a>.</li><li>Finding yourself with free time, and thinking about doing your own thing? Top tip:<a href="https://jmduke.com/2020/06/26/atypical-success">find a small niche</a>. I love and use a few products made by very small teams, and find the prospect of making a chill “lifestyle” company pretty interesting. Perhaps one day when I’m interested in trying something new, I’ll try my hand at atypical success.</li></ul><h2 id="in-closing">In closing</h2><p>Think about the apps and services you depend on, and the ones you truly love. Who’re the made by?<a href="https://ia.net/writer">My writing tool</a>, which I dearly love, is made in Tokyo and Switzerland, for instance. Also, have you seen anything amazing lately? Movie, tv, or in life? I’d love to<a href="mailto:brookshelley@gmail.com">hear about it</a>. As always, stay safe, and keep fighting! I’ll see you next week space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Fennel &amp; Dill 29</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-07-19-fennel-dill-29/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 08:27:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-07-19-fennel-dill-29/</guid><description>Fennel &amp;amp; Dill 29 Happy March 141st! Time continues to show up for me in the cycles of life—laundry, therapy, medicine, and plant watering.</description><content:encoded><h1 id="fennel--dill-29">Fennel &amp; Dill 29</h1><p>Happy<a href="https://calendar2020.noj.cc">March 141st</a>! Time continues to show up for me in the cycles of life—laundry, therapy, medicine, and plant watering. With news that most schools will open virtually in the fall, I get the sense that “summer” for kids will continue well into 2021, albeit without pool parties. It’s a weird, life-defining time. Snorri and I are weathering things well, and possibly even thriving. As my friend Lena said yesterday, “I’m an indoor cat”. I wish sunbeams, lights to chase, and regular feedings upon my fellow indoor cats.</p><p>With cases spiking, I hope you’re staying safe, wearing a mask, and keeping to yourself largely. I personally wish we could literally quarantine everyone for three weeks, because that seems like it would end the whole disease, but instead&hellip;</p><p><em>gestures broadly</em></p><h2 id="links">Links</h2><ul><li>Take a trip with me to the 90s, and learn about the<em>wonders</em> of Crystal Pepsi, won’t you?</li></ul><div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/JJYsS82khTc" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen= title="YouTube Video"/></div><ul><li>Wait, you want more training? Why not learn how to be a buffet employee? You see, in the before times, buffets were a place you could eat as much low-quality food as you could stomach for like, $5. If you ever find yourself in the past, make sure you load up on “expensive” meats first, before diving into the world of carbs. Sometimes you may even happen upon “sushi”. It’s wild. Good luck!</li></ul><div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dw-axqRpQo8" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen= title="YouTube Video"/></div><ul><li>This week when I was deep in thought, I started digging back into the delights and confusion of Buddhist writing. A particular favorite is a Norwegian guy that my old sangha leader would read from often:<a href="https://www.insightmeditationcenter.org/wp-content/uploads/documents/iah/IssueAtHand4thEd.pdf">Gil Fronsdal</a>. That link will get you one of his books, and if you<a href="https://www.abhayagiri.org/books/545-beginning-our-day-volume-one">look around online</a>, maybe you’ll find a lot of other excellent things to read about dukka and the second arrow.</li><li>Philip Glass is a gift, and this tweet destroyed me:</li></ul><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="und" dir="ltr"><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/ThrowbackThursday?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#ThrowbackThursday</a><a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/dance?src=hash&amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">#dance</a><a href="https://t.co/honepDVqK8">pic.twitter.com/honepDVqK8</a></p>&mdash; Philip Glass (@philipglass)<a href="https://twitter.com/philipglass/status/1283854000392151041?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 16, 2020</a></blockquote><script async= src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"/><p>Today in news, famous white lady author gets drunk, and tweets:</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Drunk</p>&mdash; Susan Orlean (@susanorlean)<a href="https://twitter.com/susanorlean/status/1284288455862779907?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">July 18, 2020</a></blockquote><script async= src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"/><p>Drunk tweets are one of the best things about Twitter, tbh.</p><h2 id="in-closing">In closing</h2><p>This week’s newsletter was hopefully a bit more ridiculous and upbeat than usual. I know I needed a laugh, and I hope you enjoyed one too. I’m thinking about a vacation from work in August perhaps, since I found out yesterday my writing retreat in Japan is cancelled. Have you done something nice that took you away from the daily grind? Let me know so I can steal your ideas, lol. As always, keep fighting, and I’ll see you next week space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Fennel &amp; Dill 28</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-07-12-fennel-dill-28/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-07-12-fennel-dill-28/</guid><description>Another week, and another Formula One race in Austria. For the first time in the over 70 year history of this race series two races occurred at the same track.</description><content:encoded><p>Another week, and another Formula One race in Austria. For the first time in the over 70 year history of this race series two races occurred at the same track. The first race included loads of suspension and tire issues due to curbs, and this weekend included with a veritable lake on the track. If you’ve never watched car racing, I recommend Netflix’s excellent<a href="https://www.netflix.com/title/80204890?s=i&amp;trkid=0">behind-the-scenes series</a>. Outside of high speed racing, my week was a bit of a let-down, as I found out I didn’t get a position at work I’d interviewed for on Wednesday. Chin up though, I have to think, as there will be more opportunities to come. Hopefully your week had some nice news instead!</p><h2 id="links">Links</h2><ul><li>It’s hard to explain exactly what is so delightful about the world of strange ports and connectors, but this thread is a<em>journey</em>.</li></ul><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">OK SO you know how I talk a lot about weird misuses of connectors on aliexpress and such?<br><br>I have found the worst one. Brace yourself, this is NSFW...</p>&mdash; foone (@Foone)<a href="https://twitter.com/Foone/status/1264925104175112192?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">May 25, 2020</a></blockquote><script async= src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"/><ul><li>This week I learned a lot more than I ever thought I would<a href="https://hyakumonogatari.com/2013/08/30/tanuki-no-kintama-tanukis-giant-balls/">about tanukis</a>, the raccoon dog native to Japan.</li></ul><p>Here’s a raccoon chaser for that wild article:</p><div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/eesxH2-8Jlo" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen= title="YouTube Video"/></div><ul><li>Did you see “the letter” this week? The sad, out of touch, last-gasp of milquetoast “intellectuals” who can’t be bothered to care about the hoi polloi? Regardless (or “irregardless”, lol, that’s another story from this summer), this<a href="https://www.theverge.com/21320338/letter-harpers-writers-free-speech-canceled-social-media-illiberalism">piece by Sarah Jeong</a> is an excellent look at Harper’s garbage missive.</li><li>I can’t believe I only<em>just this week</em> discovered David Rees’<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Going-Deep-David-Rees-Season/dp/B00M50KCGA">Going Deep</a> tv show and it’s excellent investigation of the<a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slow_loris">slow loris</a>. If you want to see David talk about his career and the ups and downs of being a cartoonist and comedian, this<a href="https://xoxofest.com/2016/videos/david-rees">excellent talk from XOXO 2016</a> will fill that desire.</li><li>Finally, and inexplicably, I leave you with this:</li></ul><div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wZpO_-HAeQU" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen= title="YouTube Video"/></div><p>Thanks again for reading, and spending your summer indoors virtually with my internet history and curiosity. August is fast approaching, but the weather outside is still gorgeous here. I hope you’re able to spend a few hours in the sun this weekend, quietly appreciating the distance from other people, and maybe reading a good book. As always, stay safe and keep fighting, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Fennel &amp; Dill 27</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-07-05-fennel-dill-27/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-07-05-fennel-dill-27/</guid><description>Well, the long weekend and constant fireworks in Oakland threw me for a loop! I lost track of the days and thought it was Saturday, and I still had an entire evening to prepare this email for you.</description><content:encoded><p>Well, the long weekend and constant fireworks in Oakland threw me for a loop! I lost track of the days and thought it was Saturday, and I still had an entire evening to prepare this email for you. Alas! Here’s a rare evening edition my newsletter.</p><h2 id="links">Links</h2><ul><li>This account is utterly bizarre and so are<a href="https://www.nps.gov/media/photo/gallery.htm?pg=6476370&amp;id=5A1B20E2-AA1D-434F-A62E-44497ADF7F68">these warnings</a>. There’s a strangely surreal aspect to a lot of the governments social media, that I can’t tell whether I find charming or depressing.</li><li>If you’re worried about radiation, you could get a dosimeter, but why not<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/shortcuts/2017/jan/08/colour-changing-cats-warn-radioactive-waste-nuclear-plants-distant-descendants">breed cats to change colors instead</a>?</li><li>if you need something great to read during the quarantine, why not dive into this short fiction from Murakami<a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2020/06/08/confessions-of-a-shinagawa-monkey">about a monkey</a>.</li><li>Building<a href="https://thebaffler.com/latest/chatbots-at-the-end-of-the-world-connolly">customer service robots while the world burns?</a> That’s par for the course in Silicon Valley. That, and continuously attacking a journalist for reporting on the industry. It would be pretty amazing if folks decided to work on global warming or other pressing global crises, but until then, I guess returning my yoga pants will be better.</li><li>I finished watching Berlin Station this week, and also decided to read<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Olen_Steinhauer">the writer</a> of the show’s book series about CIA Tourists.</li><li>Does anyone know why it’s called “chankonabe/ちゃんこ鍋”？I can’t for the life of me find out the etymology of that dish. If you know,<a href="mailto:brookshelley@gmail.com">hit me up</a>.</li><li>In honor of July 4th, do everyone a favor and read about the<a href="https://www.brookings.edu/blog/up-front/2020/02/27/examining-the-black-white-wealth-gap/">racial wealth gap</a>. American capitalism is a pernicious force of white supremacy, and we’ve got to change things.</li></ul><p>Thanks again for bearing with me this evening and being patient for these links. I hope your week is relaxing, and you are able to stay inside/social distance and avoid the spike of COVID that’s ravaging most of the states. Keep fighting, and see you next week, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Fennel &amp; Dill 26</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-06-30-fennel-dill-26/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-06-30-fennel-dill-26/</guid><description>The bay this week was thankfully cooler than the past month. My body was thankful for the heat respite, and Snorri was cuddlier as a result.</description><content:encoded><p>The bay this week was thankfully cooler than the past month. My body was thankful for the heat respite, and Snorri was cuddlier as a result. This week felt long, after having Juneteenth off last week, but next Friday we observe Independence Day, so it’s another short week. I can’t say I’m looking forward to the even more ubiquitous fireworks, but hopefully the cops will finally run out.</p><p>I spent a lot of time watching tv this week, and enjoying good<a href="https://www.masterofmalt.com/whiskies/ichiros-malt-and-grain-whisky/">Japanese Whiskey</a>. Hopefully you had some fun things to occupy your time as well. Oh, and I also spent an inordinate amount of time trying to fix my bike chain and rear derailleur—bike shops have 10 day waits, so needs must. I turns out I’ve forgotten most of my bike mechanic skills.</p><p>What skills have you forgotten/tried to learn?</p><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">he lives in my head rent free<a href="https://t.co/nciTZhpRrb">pic.twitter.com/nciTZhpRrb</a></p>&mdash; em BLM (@jacquenergy)<a href="https://twitter.com/jacquenergy/status/1275546106500386817?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 23, 2020</a></blockquote><script async= src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"/><h2 id="links">Links</h2><ul><li>Two more comics to start us off:<a href="https://imagecomics.com/comics/series/gideon-falls">Gideon Falls</a>, which is pretty damn creepy, and<a href="https://imagecomics.com/comics/releases/adventureman-1">Adventureman</a>, which fortunately seems to be about a woman. The comics world is finally reckoning with predation and abusive men, which hopefully means even more great people will be able to produce content instead. Comics, other than distribution, seem to be ideally suited for quarantine creation, and it would be rad to see a new set of voices show up in print soon.</li><li>Speaking of fancy whiskey, before this quarantine Chinese and American customers were swiftly burning through the<a href="http://archive.is/sGUeM">stocks of all the greatest bottles</a>. I’ve heard from friends in Japan that it’s not even possible to buy a lot of great whiskeys there unless you know someone at the distillery. Production is likely ramping-up to meet demand, but it might be 5 or more years before we see the results. I plan to still enjoy Japanese whiskey then too. My favorite remains<a href="https://distiller.com/spirits/nikka-coffey-grain-whisky">Nikka Coffey Grain</a>, except when I’m in Japan and can consistently get this<a href="https://distiller.com/spirits/nikka-taketsuru-pure-malt-17-year">17 year delight</a>.</li><li>I dove headlong into a new tv show from HBO Europe this week: Beforeigners, which was as fun and silly as the name. Ostensibly, it’s a detective show, but the primary conceit is that folks keep popping up in the ocean from ancient Norse villages. I learned about a lot of<a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Russefeiring">strange</a> rituals and<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thorir_Hund">characters from Snorri’s book</a> Heimskringkla. I also love that Vikings called Jesus,<a href="http://vikinganswerlady.com/hvitkrst.shtml">“the white christ”</a>. Showing up in a new country and saying “this is your new religion” is a total dick move, in my opinion. I wonder if any sci-fi about this exists, wherein aliens pop down to earth to convert everyone to worship space Hubbard?</li></ul><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">if you really want to torture yourself with food, watch the dotch show. the best cooking show, globally. you get so invested in the food you are hollering at the tv by the end of it<a href="https://t.co/pEkC9qvw6q">pic.twitter.com/pEkC9qvw6q</a></p>&mdash; BAKOON (@BAKKOOONN)<a href="https://twitter.com/BAKKOOONN/status/1276289849050292224?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">June 25, 2020</a></blockquote><script async= src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"/><ul><li>This is the third time I’ve brought up alcohol in this email, but this one is about<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-06-23/are-people-drinking-more-booze-during-coronavirus-apparently-not">drinking<em>less</em></a>. I think I’m likely drinking more than usual, but maybe that just balances out everyone else who apparently can only drink at bars.</li><li>On Friday night, I was waxing rhapsodic about the magazine Giant Robot (RIP), and then decided to check out what they’d blogged about since shutting down their print run.<a href="https://www.giantrobot.com/blogs/giant-robot-store-and-gr2-news/poston">This piece</a> by Eric Nakamura about his dad, Bob, returning to the internment camp he was forced into by xenophobic and racist white Americans during WWII was sad and beautiful.</li></ul><p>Well, it’s time for me to return to my world of tv amateur bike wrenching, and<a href="https://womensfoundationoforegon.org">funding cool non-profits</a>. I hope you are also watching the<a href="https://www.netflix.com/title/80100172?s=i&amp;trkid=0">new season of Dark</a>, and enjoying the summer wherever you are reading this. Stay safe and keep fighting, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Fennel &amp; Dill 25</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-06-21-dill-fennel-25/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-06-21-dill-fennel-25/</guid><description>It’s a foggy, overcast Saturday as I write this newsletter. Yesterday, my company gave Juneteenth off as time to volunteer and remember, and I spent most of the day with the Women’s Foundation of Oregon discussing budgets and our COVID relief fund.</description><content:encoded><p>It’s a foggy, overcast Saturday as I write this newsletter. Yesterday, my company gave<a href="https://www.vox.com/identities/2018/6/19/17476482/juneteenth-holiday-emancipation-african-american-celebration-history">Juneteenth</a> off as time to volunteer and remember, and I spent most of the day with the Women’s Foundation of Oregon discussing budgets and our<a href="https://womensfoundationoforegon.org/explore-our-grantmaking/our-grantmaking/covid-19-rapid-response-fund">COVID relief fund</a>. As a Texan, I grew up hearing about Juneteenth, but still hadn’t fully understood Texas as “part of the south” until a few years ago, since Austin had firmly insulated itself from owning our history. Take some time to read about Juneteenth, and why its the real Independence Day for our country.</p><p>(Insert picture of Snorri)</p><p>My good friend Snorri stood on my shoulder for this part, so I figured I should add a photo of him saying hi. Do you have a pet?<a href="mailto:brookshelley@gmail.com">Send me a photo</a> of your pet being cute. I’m heartened by how many friends have adopted pets during this quarantine, and it feels like almost every week there are new cats showing up in our cats channel at work. I’m still studying how Snorri handles being permanently shelter-in-place for tips on how to deal with COVID. Mostly, it seems like the key is naps and purring.</p><p>Let’s get to the links!</p><h2 id="links">Links</h2><ul><li>These<a href="https://www.wired.com/2017/01/how-i-got-my-attention-back/">two</a><a href="https://www.wired.com/story/six-weeks-100s-miles-hours-glorious-boredom-japan/">essays</a> from Craig Mod are a very interesting look at attention and hiking. If you’re anything like me, it’s pretty hard to look away from the constant pull of the news and minute-to-minute narration of current events Twitter brings us every day. I’ve still largely stuck to my<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-02-22-a-twitter-experiment-using-rss-to-readonly-twitter/">RSS Twitter diet</a>, which I still recommend, but I still load the news up on Google or Apple a few times a day. It’s super important to stay informed, but I think it’s worth thinking about the cycles of meaningless scrolling we all get into.</li></ul><div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Pa7Jw9k3b-A" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen= title="YouTube Video"/></div><ul><li>The man above makes what I call “BeEDM”. I’m fascinated by the combination of shed-made electronic music, with beekeeping. If bees aren’t your thing, you can instead<a href="https://www.midisprout.com">make music from your plants</a>. Honestly, I think it’s hard to beat music that cats make.</li></ul><blockquote class="twitter-tweet"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">a sunday morning meditation ✨<a href="https://t.co/hEAc6hgY7r">pic.twitter.com/hEAc6hgY7r</a></p>&mdash; qrtr pounder (@qrtrmusic)<a href="https://twitter.com/qrtrmusic/status/1178301414906445824?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">September 29, 2019</a></blockquote><script async= src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"/><ul><li>Robin Sloan is on a roll lately! This<a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/books/archive/2020/05/conspiracy-museum/610984/">piece in the Atlantic</a> was a delight, and he’s also serializing some fiction in the local paper every day too. The guy also makes a<a href="https://fat.gold">pretty solid olive oil</a>, which I received yesterday for the first time, and immediately poured on my sourdough.</li><li>I planned to send a few comic recommendations, but one of the folks who I’ve been reading lately was revealed to be a predator this week, so I’ll only give you one recommendation. The creator of Blade of the Immortal has two new series, and one of them is all about female assassins:<a href="https://kodanshacomics.com/series/die-wergelder/">Die Wergelder</a>. It rules. The other series is on my to-watch list, as the<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wave,_Listen_to_Me">anime just aired</a>.</li></ul><p>Well, the clouds have parted, and Saturday is looking sunny and nice. I think after I take today’s loaf out of the oven, I’ll go on a bike ride with a few friends at a distance and maybe pick up<a href="https://fieldworkbrewing.com">some beer</a>. I hope your Sunday is lovely, and your week is fully of love, solidarity, and rest. Stay safe, and keep fighting, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Fennel &amp; Dill 24</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-06-14-fennel-dill-24/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-06-14-fennel-dill-24/</guid><description>&lt;p>It’s been a rough week for so many folks I love due to police violence and a Friday rollback of national trans healthcare. I hope you’re taking care of yourself, and your loved ones. Reach out, and stick together, even if we’re far away from each other.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll keep sending out these link emails every week though, as I think it’s important to read and see things that can surprise, delight, or teach us even as we mourn and fight.&lt;/p></description><content:encoded><p>It’s been a rough week for so many folks I love due to police violence and a Friday rollback of national trans healthcare. I hope you’re taking care of yourself, and your loved ones. Reach out, and stick together, even if we’re far away from each other.</p><p>I’ll keep sending out these link emails every week though, as I think it’s important to read and see things that can surprise, delight, or teach us even as we mourn and fight.</p><h2 id="links">Links</h2><ul><li>I wish William Gibson was a little less prescient sometimes.<a href="https://thequietus.com/articles/28340-william-gibson-agency-interview">This interivew</a> with the author talks about his latest work, and the eeriness of his writing about “the jackpot”. I recently reread Gibson’s Blue Ant trilogy, which was coincident with a growth in stealth brands, surveillance culture, and AR. I think it will ultimately hold up a bit better for me than the Peripheral or Agency, but it’s nice to see him still so masterfully creating fiction.</li></ul><blockquote><p>Corners of the internet continue to operate slowly.</p></blockquote><ul><li>I posted<a href="http://luckysoap.com/statements/handmadeweb.html">a link</a> last week that<a href="https://thecreativeindependent.com/people/on-observing-time/">this article</a> led me to. I really appreciate the idea of going a little slower online, and hope that this series of links every week is part of that.</li></ul><div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/NArUd2vMgA8" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen= title="YouTube Video"/></div><ul><li>With some good music queued up, let’s read about<a href="https://craigmod.com/essays/software_slump/">slow software</a>. I don’t agree with everything Craig concludes here, but I appreciate his digging into what makes software good and bad, and the thread he started of software folks enjoy. I sincerely hope that WWDC in two weeks brings ARM chips to the Mac, and with it, better speed and battery life. Times are rough in so many ways, but there’s still a surprising amount of interesting technology being released and neat software to play around with too.</li><li>Gretchen McCullouch chronicled her experience with the<a href="https://the-toast.net/2015/08/26/wired-style-a-linguist-explains-vintage-internet-slang/">Wired Style Guide</a> for the Toast a few years before<a href="https://gretchenmcculloch.com/book/">her book</a> launched. Reading this took me way back to the earlier days of the internet in a similar fashion to the book<a href="https://www.c-span.org/video/?470007-1/joanne-mcneil-discusses-lurking">Lurking</a>. In a lot of ways, I think I miss the time where sites were static, and the social net was IRC, forums, and email. I’m curious to see what the next ten years looks like: what is Web 4.0? Web 10.0?</li><li>On Friday, I wrote about my<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-06-12-stoked-on-survivor/">newfound love for the tv show Survivor</a>. It’s a very silly show, but powering through seasons is giving me a lot of joy right now.</li></ul><p>What is bringing you joy lately? Baking? Pets? The idea that we can have more police-free autonomous zones?<a href="mailto:brookshelley@gmail.com">Let me know</a>. I’ll be biking a bit this weekend to enjoy the blue skies in the bay, so if you see me<em>wave at a distance</em> and be sure to take care of yourself too. The best way to fight state violence is starting with sleep, water, and love for each other that they can’t take from us. Stay safe, stay strong, and keep fighting, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Fennel &amp; Dill 23</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-06-07-fennel-dill-week-23/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-06-07-fennel-dill-week-23/</guid><description>This is my eleventh week in quarantine, since I was in Japan when the Bay Area shut down. COVID is still scary, but it’s been an even harder week due to police violence against black Americans, murdering multiple people and assaulting countless more.</description><content:encoded><p>This is my eleventh week in quarantine, since I was in Japan when the Bay Area shut down. COVID is still scary, but it’s been an even harder week due to police violence against black Americans, murdering multiple people and assaulting countless more. Fuck the cops. Fuck the violent, racist state.</p><p>With that said, I will go ahead and share some links, as usual, with a few that may help you grapple with what’s happening right now. Take care of yourself, your friends and family, and especially be in solidarity with black and brown folks who’re consistently targeted by state and individual white supremacist violence.</p><h2 id="links">Links</h2><ul><li>Here’s a book on<a href="https://robindiangelo.com/publications/">White Fragility</a>. Read it if you’re white, or have white folks around you or in your family. I’m picking up a copy on recommendation of some rad folks I know.</li><li>Here’s<a href="https://harukanakamurapianoensemble.bandcamp.com/album/hikari">an album</a> I’m listening to a lot these days while I try to sit and feel things.</li></ul><div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/N7TkK2joi4I" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen= title="YouTube Video"/></div><ul><li><p>When I lived in Portland, I spent a lot of time going to a sangha with other folks where we meditated and learned about Buddhism. I can’t say that I always loved it, but it was definitely helpful. If you live in the East Bay, or just want to go to one regularly,<a href="https://eastbaymeditation.org/programs/zoom-links/">here’s some classes</a> to check out.</p></li><li><p>If you want to imagine the future, a great way to start is by reading black women and<a href="https://www.yesmagazine.org/social-justice/2020/04/24/how-black-women-are-reshaping-afrofuturism/">Afrofuturism</a>. So much of sci-fi is white and colonialist as fuck, and exposing myself to authors who are neither white or men is something I’ve really valued over the past five years.</p></li><li><p>This week I wrote about my<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-06-01-adventures-in-baking/">baking adventures</a>. It’s been a really nice thing to make bread constantly in order to feed myself, and have a small project that delivers little victories every so often.</p></li><li><p>While working on my site over the past few weeks, I thought a lot about the<a href="http://luckysoap.com/statements/handmadeweb.html">handmade web</a> of the past—before the time of large social networks with shitty policies. If you haven’t built your own website or newsletter in a while, maybe give it a go. It’s pretty fun.</p></li></ul><p>I know the note at the top was somber, but it’s time for being somber. Thank you to anyone who is donating, supporting folks, protesting, or otherwise involved in this pivotal moment in US history. I fully believe that if we stick to this fight, we can change things. If you’re reading this, even if I don’t know you, just know I care about you, and I appreciate your attention. Thanks for being part of this slow newsletter social world. Keep resisting, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Fennel &amp; Dill 22</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-06-07-fennel-dill-week-22/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-06-07-fennel-dill-week-22/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a busy week! At my company, we had Monday and Friday off, and most of our staff took off the entire week.</description><content:encoded><p>It&rsquo;s been a busy week! At my company, we had Monday and Friday off, and most of our staff took off the entire week. I decided to work through the week for some reason, and ended-up getting a lot done! Suffering from a bout of creative excitement, I also<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-05-30-blog-redesign/">redesigned my site</a> to try to beat the<a href="https://web.dev/measure/">Google performance measure</a> and load fully under two seconds. Yes. I&rsquo;m a frontend pervert. At one point I almost ditched the entire site and rebuilt it in<a href="https://rachelandrew.co.uk/css/">CSS grid</a>, but cooler heads prevailed (I got a little drunk and decided to just finish the redesign instead).</p><p>Did you know we have a<a href="https://www.cityofberkeley.info/Marina_Home/">cool marina</a> near our IKEA? My pal André showed it to me in a socially distant bike ride, and it&rsquo;s super fun to ride to, despite the slightly crowded trails. I&rsquo;m trying to balance my desire to never leave the house with my need for exercise, so we&rsquo;ll see how many times I head to the marina in the coming weeks.</p><p>I hope you&rsquo;re also not leaving the house much, but you do you.</p><p>Here&rsquo;s some<em>links</em>!</p><h2 id="links">Links</h2><ul><li>I think it&rsquo;s summer now? It&rsquo;s definitely hot, and so I&rsquo;ve started reading more Scandinavian fiction to keep the heat low in my head at least. Let&rsquo;s dive into the<a href="https://bookshop.org/books/the-summer-book/9781590172681">world of Tove Jansson</a> together, shall we?</li><li>Whether you&rsquo;re baking a lot now or not, I bet you don&rsquo;t know what makes b<a href="https://www.seriouseats.com/2010/06/what-is-the-difference-between-baking-powder-and-baking-soda-in-pancakes.html">aking soda and baking powder</a> different. There&rsquo;s your exciting cocktail fact for the week.</li><li>I&rsquo;m hiding this one 3 links in to try to fool a friend (hi Drew) into<a href="https://csswizardry.com/2020/05/the-fastest-google-fonts/">reading it</a>. It&rsquo;s all about making Google Fonts faster, and since I know you all love performance fuckery, you&rsquo;ll get a kick out of it.</li><li>Every time I return from Japan, I think &ldquo;why do our trains suck so much?!&rdquo; In comparison with most of Europe and Asia, the United States lags far behind on train transport, but<a href="https://www.wired.com/story/lawmaker-wants-fast-trains-rev-us-economy/">perhaps not for long</a>. I really hope I get to see high-speed rail in the states while I&rsquo;m young.</li><li>Finally, here&rsquo;s America&rsquo;s number one Merlin<a href="https://audioboom.com/posts/7593305-merlin-mann">talking about his favorite Elliot Smith</a> song.</li></ul><p>I did a lot less fun link excavating this week because&hellip; well, have you seen the news? All I&rsquo;ll say about it is: Black lives matter, and cops should be held accountable for their atrocities &amp; Section 230 makes the social web work.</p><p>I hope you have some time away from the horrors and sad things of the world, and can take care of yourself, your family, and your friends this week. I&rsquo;m rooting for you, and I&rsquo;ll see you next week, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Fennel &amp; Dill 21</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-06-07-fennel-dill-week-21/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-06-07-fennel-dill-week-21/</guid><description>Welp, first sunburn of the quarantine for this gal. I spent the afternoon in a friend’s yard (hi André and Haley) and forgot my skin has been softened by indoor lighting for months.</description><content:encoded><p>Welp, first sunburn of the quarantine for this gal. I spent the afternoon in a friend’s yard (hi André and Haley) and forgot my skin has been softened by indoor lighting for months. On the upside, it was gorgeous outside, and I’m glad I got to sit in the sun.</p><p>Since I’ll be indoors for a while healing-up, a lot of todays’s links are indoor kid interests. So if you’re like me, I think you’ll enjoy these:</p><h2 id="links">Links</h2><ul><li>First, here’s a<a href="https://www.girlwalkallday.com/chapters-page">gorgeous dance movie</a> that I’ve had on my to-watch list for a while. It’s surreal to watch right now, since it involves a lot of public contact and even a subway ride in NYC, but it’s a nice reminder of the fun times.</li><li>Next, lets do a<a href="https://io9.gizmodo.com/a-guide-to-dune-s-strange-and-intense-religions-1843460283">deep-dive into the religions of Dune</a>. I personally love the oddball Bene Gesserit, and one of my regrets of my previous startup selling to another company is our next code sprint title series could’ve been Dune names. Alas.</li><li>If reading about Dune makes you want to ship some of the characters, make sure you don’t make them<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/05/23/business/omegaverse-erotica-copyright.html">awkwardly lupine</a>. There’s a lawsuit brewing at the intersection of fan fiction and self-published ebooks that will help establish case law around shared universes. I get t feeling the Omegaverse (read the above to know more) will stay open to all.</li><li>This next one is a twofer on grammar. Why do we<a href="https://slate.com/human-interest/2016/05/all-your-questions-about-pronoun-deletion-and-the-inexorable-death-of-the-universe-answered.html">delete initial pronouns in English</a> lately? And how does that same deletion<a href="https://nihongoperapera.com/dirty-japanese-guide-subjects-and-deletions.html">function in Japanese</a>? I journal quite a bit and speak Japanese decently, so I’ve run into this concept of deletion and assumed context sentences often. I think it’s a pretty fascinating concept.</li><li>Here’s something else to watch:<a href="https://kotaku.com/8-great-anime-series-for-people-who-don-t-like-anime-1843616852">anime for folks who haven’t seen anime</a>. I’ve seen quite a few if these and can vouch for them.</li><li>Finally, let’s talk “warshers” and “diddles” in the<a href="http://www.washers.org/terms.html#diddle">most high-stake professional sport in America</a>.</li></ul><p>This image is care of Joe—thanks Joe! It’s an emoji keyboard from a<a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/retrobattlestations/comments/gph0lk/alps_kanji_keyboard_exotic_peripherals_week/">Reddit on strange peripherals</a>.</p><p><img src="https://i.redd.it/3vs4r3ci8m051.jpg" alt="keyboard"/><p>Well, that’s it for this week. I’ve spent a lot of this weekend already playing a silly war game with friends, and it’s highly likely I’ll keep that going. More bread making as well. I hope you have a chill short week, and don’t randomly set off fireworks like all my neighbors&hellip; yikes.<br>
See you next week, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Fennel &amp; Dill 20</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-06-07-fennel-dill-week-twenty/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-06-07-fennel-dill-week-twenty/</guid><description>Trying out a new name for this that isn’t just “links”. Fennel and dill are two of my favorite flavors, but also a terrible combination.</description><content:encoded><p>Trying out a new name for this that isn’t just “links”. Fennel and dill are two of my favorite flavors, but also a terrible combination. They also happen to be my utterly bizarre chest-piece tattoo. If you follow this newsletter but haven’t ever met me in person, just know I have a<em>lot</em> of botanical tattoos.</p><p>My snacking game is strong now that I know how to make my own tortillas on demand, and endless sourdough. However, it’s been a while since I had some of these little treats, and I am officially missing tater tots:</p><div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Xi28pEbMdTw" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen= title="YouTube Video"/></div><p>Maybe I’ll try to cook some up sometime. It seems pretty challenging though. Putting this on a list that also includes homemade lefse and ableskiver.</p><p>Do you<em>you</em> like refrigerators?</p><div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TiC8pig6PGE" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen= title="YouTube Video"/></div><p>I love the<a href="http://www.cc.com/shows/detroiters">Detroiters</a>-level excellence of this ad. It’s utterly brilliant to just show the man I presume owns the shop slowly walking towards the camera. This is cinema.</p><p>If that wet your whistle, let’s dive in for a full link immersion.</p><h2 id="links">Links</h2><ul><li>Have you seen the very good Middleditch &amp; Schwartz special yet? If you need more of those two funny fellows, try this video of them playing a Jackbox game:</li></ul><div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/32lPJ3QeIuQ" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen= title="YouTube Video"/></div><ul><li><p>Perhaps videos aren’t your thing, and you’re more of a reading fan. Reading is my favorite thing, and one of my only consistent hobbies, so it was awesome to find<a href="https://lithub.com/26-books-from-the-last-decade-that-if-you-havent-read-you-should/">this list</a> via<a href="https://www.robinsloan.com">Robin Sloan</a> of excellent books you’ve likely not read, recommended by authors who are also rad.</p></li><li><p>Have you still managed to avoid the siren song of Animal Crossing? I keep oversleeping/baking instead of buying turnips, so unlike some people I know, I’m not yet in a post-money economy. I’ve got bills to pay! Even still, I find this quarantine-time<a href="https://twitter.com/animalcrossing/status/1261295269338992640?s=20">live playing of the theme song</a> just delightful.</p></li><li><p>I’m a big Formula 1 fan, which you might not know, but one of my least favoriting things about it is the lack of women driving in the sport. Luckily, there are efforts to sponsor and develop professional drivers, and I hope eventually Formula 1 teams and sponsors get over their misogyny and have<a href="https://wseries.com">some of these awesome women</a> drive in the most prestigious series.</p></li></ul><p>Meanwhile, deep into quarantine I’ve continued to bake up a storm, and I think this is my best boule so far!</p><p><img src="https://www.brookshelley.com/photos/boule.jpg" alt="boule"/><p>I’ve got another one in the oven this morning, and I hope it turns out well. Also if you’re the sort of person who practices witchcraft, or otherwise wants to send some good vibes my way&hellip; Friday could be very interesting. Hopefully I can share more, and it’s good news. Short version is I’m trying to do something very neat at work.</p><p>I hope however you spend your next week, it’s a good one, and as always, I’ll see you next week, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>links week nineteen</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-05-10-links-week-nineteen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-05-10-links-week-nineteen/</guid><description>Ten loaves of sourdough! That’s how many loaves I have made thus far during the pandemic (or pan-demic if you’ll excuse my pun).</description><content:encoded><p>Ten loaves of sourdough! That’s how many loaves I have made thus far during the pandemic (or pan-demic if you’ll excuse my pun). Have you found a fulfilling hobby? Gotten really good at a driving simulator? Taken up<a href="https://www.cowaymega.com/product/coway-bidetmega-400/">amateur plumbing</a>? I went out last weekend for the first time, albeit just down the street to sit in a friend’s yard, far from said friend. It was pretty nice, and I keep thinking I should perhaps do a little more biking and walking, but then I see a dozen people walking around massless, and I get some combination of furious and scared all over again.</p><p>Here’s hoping this week’s links will give you some chill times, and maybe even some laughs instead. Here’s some mood music:</p><div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/6hwqjZAs" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen= title="YouTube Video"/></div><h2 id="links">Links</h2><ul><li><p>Do you miss clubbing? Just getting hopped up on some fundrugs™ and shaking your booty in hopes you might get to swap spit with a cutie? Well, sans the spit bit, you might be in luck if<a href="https://www.core77.com/posts/98066/No-Social-Distancing-Required-Personal-Protective-Suit-Concept-Designed-for-Nightlife">you can make one of these</a>. I love this bonkers concept, because it imagines a world in which people are somehow ok with wearing spacesuits to go to a bar.</p></li><li><p>I don’t think any friends have taken me up on this, but I for sure wish they would try to cut their own hair with a shop vac.<a href="https://gizmodo.com/i-cut-my-hair-with-a-vacuum-cleaner-and-oh-man-i-think-1843204420">I love it</a>.</p></li><li><p>If the previous song is over, here’s a bit more mall music to tide you over as you read these next few pieces:</p></li></ul><div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/R7k-dw24XXI" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen= title="YouTube Video"/></div><ul><li>The fantastic essayist Rebecca Solnit covered everything from pandemic profiteering to the hope that we come out of this with a<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/apr/07/what-coronavirus-can-teach-us-about-hope-rebecca-solnit">greater respect and understanding of our interconnectedness</a>.</li></ul><blockquote><p>I have often thought that the wave of privatisation that has characterised our neoliberal age began with the privatisation of the human heart, the withdrawal from a sense of a shared fate and social bonds. It is to be hoped that this shared experience of catastrophe will reverse the process.</p></blockquote><p>Here’s so music to bring you back from the depths that essay may have taken you through:</p><div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tMMowlS-i1s" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen= title="YouTube Video"/></div><p>Finally, I want to leave you with the single best video series I’ve seen in a while—a cat sleeping on a piano while their owner gently plays, the hammers massaging them.</p><div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/2mxM-HR5ysM" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen= title="YouTube Video"/></div><p>I hope these links have brought you some joy, and led you through a few interesting paths. I’m off to enjoy Sonic the Hedgehog in preparation for listening to this week’s Flop House. You can follow along with my cinematic misadventures<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/movies">here</a>, or<a href="https://www.letterboxd.com/brookshelley/films/">here</a>. If it’s sunny today, try to sit by a window or go on a chill socially distant walk. I went on my first bike ride since February yesterday, and though it was short, it really helped me feel a little more ok. It’s hard to remember, at least over here, that despite this feeling like forever, it’s only been two months. For how ever much time we have in lockdown, I’ll keep sending emails to you every week, and keep on baking very, very surprisingly good sourdough. See you next week, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>links week eighteen</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-05-03-links-week-eighteen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-05-03-links-week-eighteen/</guid><description>Happy May! We made it through an April that lasted conservatively one thousand years. I hope you&amp;rsquo;re well, and finding new ways of living and thriving as we settle in for Summer.</description><content:encoded><p>Happy May! We made it through an April that lasted conservatively one thousand years. I hope you&rsquo;re well, and finding new ways of living and thriving as we settle in for Summer.</p><p>I&rsquo;ve been cleaning, rearranging, and making lots of bread—I think I&rsquo;ve finally sorted out my Sourdough woes.</p><p>One thing I can recommend for anyone looking to clean up a little are<em>a bunch</em> of<a href="https://www.amazon.com/VELCRO-Brand-Reusable-Fastening-Organizing/dp/B001E1Y5O6">little velcro strips</a> to manage those cables. These little fellows are super versatile, reusable, and the package will probably last the rest of your life. What value!</p><p>If you haven&rsquo;t installed a desk and a nice office chair yet, I can heartily recommend doing so. I was sitting at my dining room table until Friday, on a modern but unsupportive kitchen chair. Ow. Now I have a Herman Miller Sayl, and a cool little desk to keep my stuff away from the &ldquo;food zone&rdquo;.</p><p>As we go through this week, I hope you have as much energy as all these cool ladies:</p><div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dCO0DXAc0tk" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen= title="YouTube Video"/></div><p>Cool, right? Here&rsquo;s some links:</p><h2 id="links">Links</h2><ul><li>Do you like memes? Do you like AI?<a href="https://imgflip.com/ai-meme?fbclid=IwAR2Z87afCI_yG2HsTyRgoa1yp5MytCPW2OB-X_TkttmJegoHnYp9BGolTg0">Boom</a>. Someone put these two forces together, and it&rsquo;s an eerie laugh riot. A coworker never really understands memes, so I can&rsquo;t wait to just start sending him these.</li><li>Did you know Jia Tolentino is younger than me? I sure didn&rsquo;t! I haven&rsquo;t read Trick Mirror yet, but she&rsquo;s pretty damn cool, I think.<a href="https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/culture-features/jia-tolentino-interview-trick-mirror-962686/">This interview</a> gave me a lot of insight into her world, and more interest in picking it up.</li></ul><p>The next few links are related to a mindset for quarantine and the pandemic. Don’t worry if you feel like skipping them. I found them supremely helpful, but your mileage may vary:</p><ul><li>First, it seems that<a href="https://www.raptitude.com/2020/04/take-the-long-view/">taking the long view</a> on terrible events may help us put our own suffering and frustration in context. Terrible things have happened to so many of us, and more will happen in the future, but the span of time we’re alive is vast compared to these months of difficulty.</li><li>As a life post-pandemic begins, we should “prioritise people and societies, ecologies and environments, ahead of profit and productivity.” It’s not only possible for us to use this global crisis as a catalyst, I believe it’s absolutely vital. There is no “normal” to return to, because “normal” was always fucking terrible for millions. Let’s build a world we will be proud to hand off to the future inhabitants of Earth.</li></ul><p>Finally, I blogged about this before, but there’s a whole troupe of bloggers doing a regular column over at<a href="https://indoor-voices.blogspot.com/">Indoor Voices</a>, but one of the coolest ones is Coffeecore:</p><p><img src="https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-ob-X-j_hHS8/XqkGuwjkc1I/AAAAAAAAK4w/oGC5MO2D6QkSBCvIzp_zH5uQjmeqW109ACLcBGAsYHQ/s1600/sailorroundwindow.gif" alt="coffeecore"/><ul><li>The recommended soundtrack for Coffeecore:</li></ul><div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Eybv5_Ubvts" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen= title="YouTube Video"/></div><p>Whether or not you like coffee,<a href="https://indoor-voices.blogspot.com/2020/05/coffeecore-on-city.html">this story</a> will get you out of the house and sipping iced lattes, cups of black drip, and other delights in your mind.</p><h2 id="comics">Comics</h2><p>During this copious indoor time, I’ve enjoyed reading quite a few<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/books">books</a>, and a bunch of graphic novels, manga, and comics. Unfortunately, Marvel and a few other publishers decided to pause a number of series like<a href="https://imagecomics.com/comics/releases/decorum-1">Decorum</a> and<a href="https://bookshop.org/books/injection-volume-1/9781632154798">Injection</a>.</p><p>If you need a few volumes to read during this pause, I recommend these three:</p><p><a href="https://bookshop.org/books/die-volume-1-fantasy-heartbreaker/9781534312708">Die</a><a href="https://bookshop.org/books/city-1/9781945054785">City</a><a href="https://bookshop.org/books?keywords=Dorohedoro">Dorohedoro</a></p><p>Also, all the new X-Men Dawn of X/House of X stuff is great as well, but those series are stuck on issue 10 until Marvel sorts out their single distributor issue.</p><p>Are you reading anything great? Any old favorite manga or graphic novels I should check out?<a href="mailto:brookshelley@gmail.com">Let me know</a>. I hope the coming week is full of small pleasures, and delights. See you next week, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>links week seventeen</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-04-26-links-week-seventeen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-04-26-links-week-seventeen/</guid><description>This is the week of the Magic Keyboard which I’m using to write this email. If you’re curious, or considering picking one up, the linked review should help you decide.</description><content:encoded><p>This is the week of the<em><a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-04-24-ipad-magic-keyboard-review/">Magic Keyboard</a></em> which I’m using to write this email. If you’re curious, or considering picking one up, the linked review should help you decide. For something more exhaustive, perhaps check out this longer look:</p><div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RRjMDoAVGrg" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen= title="YouTube Video"/></div><p>In other news, my company has extended our work from home until at least September, which means I’m going to see so many more movies, and play so much Gran Turismo. I think Snorri will also be stoked to have a human pillow for longer.</p><p>I’ve been cooking a lot since getting back from Japan, and this week I made a lot of fresh tortillas, which it turns out are<a href="https://www.kingarthurflour.com/recipes/simple-tortillas-recipe">very, very easy to make</a>. If you want them to even better, you’ll have to invest in lard.</p><p>Had enough tortillas? Here’s some dessert:</p><h2 id="links">Links</h2><ul><li>First, here’s a long video that explores how we ended-up in our precarious economic condition. Spoiler alert: our capitalism isn’t working:</li></ul><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tJoe_daP0DE">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tJoe_daP0DE</a></p><ul><li>Perhaps that was a little depressing and long. Have you seen Terrace House? Have you played Animal Crossing? This video was made just for you:</li></ul><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y5APepiEyLI">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y5APepiEyLI</a></p><ul><li>More of a sports person? Maybe you’re into shooting hoops, and the playground is where you<em>spent most of your days</em>. How about a hoop you can’t miss a shot on?</li></ul><p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vtN4tkvcBMA&amp;feature=emb_title">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vtN4tkvcBMA&amp;feature=emb_title</a></p><ul><li>Feeling upbeat? Enjoying the vibe? I am too, which is why I plan to enjoy it, take care of the planet, and<a href="https://onezero.medium.com/may-we-live-long-and-die-out-6d8688a4b0a3">die without children</a>. I can’t say that I necessarily prescribe to this philosophy, but for various reasons I plan to enjoy my life with my friends and pets, and then leave the world better off than I found it, hopefully.</li><li>Paul Ford wrote a lovely piece about what we can<a href="https://www.wired.com/story/stones-clocks-what-we-should-actually-leave-behind/">leave behind as a society</a> that might actually stand the test of time. Folks are a bit maudlin these days, but I’ll be damned if they’re not writing really incredible essays.</li></ul><p>It’s almost May, can you believe it? This spring is flying by, despite being mostly confined to my apartment. On Saturday a bunch of dinguses at my apartment decided to have a party, with more than 10 people just laughing it up in the courtyard, and I just don’t get it. I know it sucks for a lot of folks to be alone right now, but for fuck’s sake, don’t have a party! Are you doing with this quarantine ok? Finding anything fun to do? Making great food? Angry about your careless neighbors?<a href="mailto:brookshelley@gmail.com">Drop me a line</a>. Stay safe, and I’ll talk to you next week space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>links week sixteen</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-04-19-links-week-sixteen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-04-19-links-week-sixteen/</guid><description>This week marked my first sourdough loaves, which were delicious and a bit flat. It turns out having a scale is crucial, and hopefully next week I will get to address that lack.</description><content:encoded><p>This week marked my first sourdough loaves, which were delicious and a bit flat. It turns out having a scale is crucial, and hopefully next week I will get to address that lack. I also got a few of my hobby shipments in, which meant building a tiny Porsche and beginning a small robot. Being stuck indoors all day alone is a great excuse for rediscovering things I enjoyed when I was a weird shut-in kid. I feel super lucky most of my hobbies involve being alone indoors, save for driving, which I also enjoyed this weekend in an undisclosed touge road.</p><p>How’s your week? I hope you too have been finding hobbies to tide you over, and tv shows to binge. I’m back on my Terrace House habit again, mostly so I can co-watch with friends (hi Mehan and Soleil). It’s sad knowing the filming is paused due to the pandemic, but hopefully one day we’ll get new episodes.</p><p>In the meantime, all I can give you is a few links a week:</p><ul><li>First, if you want to follow in my LEGO footsteps, you might enjoy<a href="https://www.lego.com/en-us/themes/speed-champions">these little cars</a>. They’re pretty quick to put together and showed me how far sets have come since I was a kid.</li><li>What makes<a href="https://melmagazine.com/en-us/story/how-did-x-become-the-most-edgy-letter">the letter ‘X’ so horny</a>? That’s right, we went from LEGO to the horniest bit of the alphabet. The history is rather religious, and somewhat surprising. Let’s not forget about<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Triple_X_syndrome">triple-x syndrome</a> or the most important XXX of all time:</li></ul><div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Spx-Mx3xhYY" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen= title="YouTube Video"/></div><ul><li>If you’re my age, you likely remember when we were banned from citing the internet in papers, especially the dreaded online encyclopedia<a href="https://www.wired.com/story/wikipedia-online-encyclopedia-best-place-internet/">Wikipedia</a>. Fortunately, it kept getting better, and is now a fantastic place to learn a bit and find primary and secondary sources for all sorts of wild stuff. I’ve had friends engaged in edit wars over famous trans video game characters, and many other topics. If you’ve never had the chance to go down a Wikihole, I recommend you just start clicking inside of articles, and don’t stop till you get hungry. It’s a fun maze to lose yourself in.</li><li>This week I learned about two important memes:<a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/russian-butt-slapping-championship">Russian Butt Slapping</a>, and<a href="https://knowyourmeme.com/memes/slapping-bags-of-soil">Soil Slapping</a>. It turns out you can slap a lot of things, but butts and soil are probably the best. I hope one day we can all slap someone’s butt competitively again.</li><li>Remember<a href="http://sidetalkin.com/">Sidetalkin’</a>?<a href="https://overcast.fm/+W3OaQhh3s">Panic sure does</a>. The nineties were so weird.</li><li>Finally, here’s a short story about<a href="http://clarkesworldmagazine.com/kritzer_11_15/">cooking during a pandemic</a>. It was written way before this whole think kicked off, and was eerily prescient.</li></ul><p>How&rsquo;re you keeping busy?<a href="mailto:brookshelley@gmail.com">Drop me a line</a> and let me know! This weekend I&rsquo;ll make more tortillas, watch more Terrace House, and finish building my small robot.</p><p>Stay safe, get some sun, and see you next week space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>links week fifteen</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-04-12-links-week-fifteen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-04-12-links-week-fifteen/</guid><description>Welcome to your weekly installment of “what’s Brook reading and clicking on now?” The quarantine here in the Bay Area is 4 weeks on, I think, and today I briefly saw a friend outside while dropping off groceries.</description><content:encoded><p>Welcome to your weekly installment of “what’s Brook reading and clicking on now?” The quarantine here in the Bay Area is 4 weeks on, I think, and today I briefly saw a friend outside while dropping off groceries. It was nice. I hope you’ve had some distant human contact this month too. I’ve also been buying wine from Ordinaire, along with various tinned fishes, because this shit sucks, but wine and mackerel are delightful.</p><p>Also delightful?<em>Detroiters</em>—a show about a small Detroit advertising firm by Tim Robinson, also know for<em>I Think You Should Leave</em>. I’m savoring this show, but tonight I watched an absurd episode that was all about riding that hog.</p><p>I found out last week after a few somewhat failed photo links that my setup blocks “hot links”, something that one reader (hi Drew) commented on with:</p><blockquote><p>“lol, wild that that’s enabled by default? Is hotlinking still an internet crime in 2020?</p></blockquote><p>I hereby swear to avoid hot linking, unless it’s a lovely chorizo.</p><p>Ok, let’s get down to it: here’s the links!</p><ul><li><p>I often find myself with little chunks of text, links or errata that I need to store temporarily, or add too here and there. Luckily, there&rsquo;s now<a href="https://thesweetsetup.com/apps-were-trying-tot/">an app for that named Tot</a>. It&rsquo;s not a notes app, per se, but more like ephemeral sticky notes. I created a global shortcut, so I can always throw things into Tot, and sharing it out, or copying it elsewhere is super simple. If you work with strings, links, or junk, this is a great app. I haven&rsquo;t put it on my phone at this point, but I also feel less need to store things that way on iOS.</p></li><li><p>Speaking of random junk, do you find outdoor advertisement to be annoying? In my opinion outdoor ads are the shitty banner ads of the real world, and I wish they didn&rsquo;t exist. There&rsquo;s<a href="https://www.equaltimes.org/the-growing-global-movement-to-end">a global movement to ban them</a>, and I really hope somehow they succeed.</p></li><li><p>This week I spent some time thinking about<a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/54202/weird-history-pogs">Pogs</a>, those little milk-caps that folks who&rsquo;re in their mid-30s fell in love with as kids. It turns out their history is more complicated than I thought, but I&rsquo;m still unable to find out if there was a regulation slammer size.</p></li><li><p>Here&rsquo;s a brief plug for very good coffee that shows up in your mailbox:<a href="https://www.yesplz.coffee">YesPlz</a>. I have consistently enjoyed this stuff ever since my old boss (hi David) turned me on to them. The beans come from a guy named Tonx, who previously ran a coffee service with the same name. Previously I bought Ethiopian beans from Four Barrel or Sightglass, but YesPlz has taken over as my only coffee supplier, especially during this pandemic.</p></li><li><p>Now that you&rsquo;re hopped-up on caffeine, time to do<a href="https://howlowcanyourlogo.com">some terrible work</a>. That&rsquo;s right, it&rsquo;s a competition to make a shitty logo. I&rsquo;ve done a few of these in the past, and I really, really love making nightmarish designs. Here&rsquo;s what I came up with:</p></li><li><p>This week&rsquo;s long read is about my favorite Swedish-speaking Finnish lesbian cartoonist,<a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2020/04/06/inside-tove-janssons-private-universe">Tove Jansson</a>. If you haven&rsquo;t ever read Moomin, I highly<a href="https://shop.moomin.com/collections/books/books-books-in-english">recommend it</a>. There are tv shows as well. Often overlooked, but a real treat, are<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fair_Play_(novel)">her novels</a>.　I&rsquo;m also low-key fascinated by how obsessed Japan is with Moomin.</p></li></ul><p>I hope that&rsquo;s given you a few weird places to play online for the next week. How&rsquo;re you doing? Are you up to anything cool or fun?<a href="mailto:brookshelley@gmail.com">Drop me a line</a> and say hi if you feel like it. As always, stay healthy and happy—see you next week, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>links week fourteen</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-04-05-links-week-fourteen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-04-05-links-week-fourteen/</guid><description>This week I spent some time thinking about hoarding.
Specifically, toilet paper hoarding. I&amp;rsquo;ve yet to venture out this week to the grocery, but the TP situation in my house is on its way to dire.</description><content:encoded><p>This week I spent some time thinking about hoarding.</p><p><img src="https://www.brookshelley.com/photos/cool.jpeg" alt="cool hoarders"/><p>Specifically, toilet paper hoarding. I&rsquo;ve yet to venture out this week to the grocery, but the TP situation in my house is on its way to dire. I was able to procure<em>napkins</em> a week ago, so&hellip; needs must.</p><p>The only hoarding I&rsquo;ve managed to do, back when it was just called &ldquo;collecting&rdquo; was of alcohol. I&rsquo;m a little proud of my strange Shochu collection, largely enabled by my friends over at<a href="https://umamimart.com">Umami Mart</a> (who&rsquo;re still doing curbside pickup in the East Bay, btw).</p><p><img src="https://www.brookshelley.com/photos/shochucollection.jpeg" alt="shochu collection"/><p>As you can tell from the photo, I&rsquo;m prepared. You can also tell that Snorri is quite glad I&rsquo;m constantly around right now, since he gets a 24/7 warm body to sleep on, and climb on. He&rsquo;s only demanded things a few times.</p><p>Much of this quarantine has felt similar to my normal life, albeit with a touch more agoraphobia than usual. I spent a lot of time when I wasn&rsquo;t at work sitting at home in the<em>before times</em> and I&rsquo;m fortunate it&rsquo;s to my liking. I guess I miss seeing people occasionally, or going to restaurants a little, but we&rsquo;ll see if even I hit my limit. I spent around 4 years leaving my house minimally when I lived in Portland, and now I also have the aid of a therapist and medicine, so.</p><p>If your situation is different or tougher, I send you my love and a 6m distant hug. I know a few folks who&rsquo;re sick right now, and I hope they heal up again quick.</p><p>If you&rsquo;re like me, you&rsquo;re online a lot right now to distract and entertain yourself, so I will do what I can to add some levity. Here&rsquo;s the links:</p><h2 id="links">Links</h2><ul><li>Can you<em>believe</em> it&rsquo;s been 30 years since<a href="https://store.catalystgamelabs.com/pages/search-results-page?collection=shadowrun&amp;page=1&amp;rb_product_type=Rulebooks">Shadowrun</a> first launched? Frankly, I&rsquo;m a little shocked. This is a bit like those &ldquo;Nevermind came out longer ago from now than Led Zepplin&rsquo;s II&rdquo; for me. I&rsquo;ve only played a handful of games in those 30 years, because it seems hard to convince folks<em>not</em> to play D&amp;D, but I spent hours and hours reading the second-edition sourcebooks when I was a kid. Yes, I was the kind of child that read RPG sourcebooks alone. I still do.</li><li>Keeping things in the<em>past</em> I present to you an<a href="https://worldwideweb.cern.ch">emulator of the original NEXT browser</a> brought to my attention by<a href="www.craigmod.com">Craig Mod</a> during a private live-streamed design of a website he did yesterday. I think it&rsquo;s a bit cool how many folks have started ambient live-streams of various activities. It feels like a very low-key way to hang out with people.</li><li>Another blast from the past—wow this week—is You Look Nice Today. They&rsquo;ve<em>returned</em> with<a href="https://www.californiaking.org">California King</a> and have stayed funny and delightful. I don&rsquo;t think I&rsquo;d seen much of Scott since the old days of YLNT, but I&rsquo;m always down for<em>yet another</em> Merlin man joint. If you decide to listen to the archives of YLNT, perhaps keep in mind that they&rsquo;ve grown a bit as people, and you might hear some less than ideal content in the old ones. Que sera sera.</li><li>During a foraging session, I managed to buy some whole wheat starter, but no yeast. No matter, I&rsquo;ve begun to make a<a href="https://www.theperfectloaf.com/7-easy-steps-making-incredible-sourdough-starter-scratch/">starter</a>. This feels a little prairie home for me, but I&rsquo;m looking forward to<em>more bread</em> because going out to buy fresh baguette every few days is not a good quarantine habit, I&rsquo;ve found. I&rsquo;ll report back on the bread in the future.</li><li>Finally, I share with you a regular &lsquo;ol blog from<a href="https://indoor-voices.blogspot.com/">a few writers similarly stuck into their homes</a>.</li></ul><p>Thanks to those of you who&rsquo;ve emailed me in the past few weeks to chat or comment on the email! I really love reading stuff from y&rsquo;all, and will try to reply back most of the time. I know folks who&rsquo;ve subscribed are a bit scattered around the globe, so it&rsquo;s nice to get the chance to catch-up through the asynchronous magic of email and RSS. If any of you keep a blog or have a newsletter, definitely let me know. I&rsquo;m logging off for now to go watch the second season of Ozark and whittle down a bit of that shochu collection. See you next week, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>links week thirteen</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-29-links-week-thirteen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-29-links-week-thirteen/</guid><description>Ah, I’ve returned to the Americas. This week, Japan started quarantining as well, so I just missed the cutoff there and was largely able to enjoy wandering around like usual.</description><content:encoded><p>Ah, I’ve returned to the Americas. This week, Japan started quarantining as well, so I just missed the cutoff there and was largely able to enjoy wandering around like usual. I still tried to socially distance while I was in Tokyo and Osaka however, and I even<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-16-traveling-during-a-pandemic/">blogged about it</a> in five parts. Overall, it was a strange trip, but a fun one. I hope I get to travel back to Japan again in November after the<a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/family/archive/2020/03/coronavirus-social-distancing-over-back-to-normal/608752/">quarantine ends</a>.</p><p>I hope you’ve been enjoying your time at home, with your loved ones and pets, or if you’re still going in to work, thank you for helping take care of the rest of us. I went grocery shopping today, and everyone was thanking the employees for their service the whole time, which was nice to hear. I sincerely hope this whole thing leads us to believing in socialized medicine for everyone, because this most certainly won’t be the only medical crisis we face in the next 50 years. Hopefully if you’re reading this, you also agree.</p><ul><li>Now that you’re stuck at home, maybe you can try<a href="https://www.flowbee.com/Questions.htm">cutting your own hair</a>. My entire childhood included haircuts from my dad in the garage with one of<a href="https://haircut.com/products/clear-model-by-robocut-1040-w-power">these</a>. I hated the sound of the shopvac, but I suppose it saved us money as a family. We were definitely style innovators in the 90s.</li><li>Jenny wrote this essay before the quarantine, but it’s certainly more true now than ever that we’re<a href="https://www.theparisreview.org/blog/2020/01/15/the-myth-of-self-reliance/">unable to be self-reliant</a>. We’re all in this together, it turns out.</li></ul><div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/5Cdv932eoU0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen= title="YouTube Video"/></div><ul><li>I write most things these days on an iPad, and the new<a href="https://techcrunch.com/2020/03/24/review-100000-miles-and-one-week-with-an-ipad-pro/">2020 iPad Pros just launched</a>. Whether I’m traveling, or sitting at home with my iPad plugged in to a monitor, it’s an amazing computer. With the launch of iOS 13.4, Apple reinvented the mouse cursor in a<a href="https://www.wired.com/story/ipad-trackpad-cursor/">whole new, fun way</a>.</li></ul><p><img src="https://www.brookshelley.com/photos/ipad_home.jpg" alt="my iPad at home"/><ul><li>While I’m at home, I’m rediscovering some nerdy teen hobbies, like<a href="https://newtypehq.com/products/hg-msz-006a1-zeta-plus-unicorn-ver?variant=14548538327089#">Gunpla</a>. Despite a #gunpla channel at work, I’d resisted the siren song of plastic models until I faced the prospect of months alone at my apartment. I’m kind of excited to have some time to really devote to reading and making tiny robots.</li><li>I’ve got a big queue of books to get through, and this week I’m enjoying the sci-fi<a href="https://www.maxgladstone.com/writing/empress-of-forever/">tale of a lesbian tech CEO</a> which I’m reading along with my book club. It’s a fun romp through space with a strange cast of characters.</li><li>Finally, do you miss folks laughing at your jokes at work? No fear! You can<a href="https://www.myinstants.com/instant/laugh-track/">summon laughter at will with this button</a>. There’s also<a href="http://www.instantrapairhorn.com">an instant rap air horn</a>, naturally.</li></ul><p>It’s scary out there, so I hope you’re staying safe and managed to find some toilet paper amidst the bizarre hoarding. It’s too bad more bathrooms here don’t have<a href="https://washlet.totousa.com">washlets</a>. Maybe you’re watching<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=acTdxsoa428">Tiger King</a>,<a href="https://deadline.com/2020/03/coronavirus-trolls-world-tour-invisible-man-the-hunt-emma-debut-on-demand-in-home-theatrical-window-collapse-1202884570/">hoping more films go straight to Netflix or Apple TV</a>, or just collecting as many bells as you can to pay off that bastard Tom Nook—however you spend your week, keep washing your hands, and checking in with your loved ones. See you next week, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>links week twelve</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-21-links-week-twelve/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-21-links-week-twelve/</guid><description>Hello from a 200mph Nozomi Shinaksen train on my way to Tokyo! This train still feels like the future, and it’s especially wild that people are riding it and no one seems particularly worried.</description><content:encoded><p>Hello from a 200mph Nozomi Shinaksen train on my way to Tokyo! This train still feels like the future, and it’s especially wild that people are riding it and no one seems particularly worried.</p><p>Onomichi—where I was for the past few days—was gorgeous! Truly in rare form. If you’d like to read about that and see some photos of my hiking and exploring, you know<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-19-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-three/">where to go</a>.</p><p>I spent<em>four hours</em> on the phone today with Chase bank trying to move my flight forward a few days to try to ensure that I won’t be trapped outside of California. Were it not for Snorri, I might consider trying to just work and hide out in Japan during this pandemic, but for both him and my work, it’s probably good to head home. Knock on some wood for me, or send good travel vibes—whatever your method of magic may be.</p><p>You’re probably not here to read about my Japanese vacation travails though, so without further ado, here’s the links:</p><p><a href="https://mobile.twitter.com/davdchristmas/status/1239196410857340933">https://mobile.twitter.com/davdchristmas/status/1239196410857340933</a></p><ul><li>You might know that I’m a racing fan, and especially love Formula 1 racing, but currently all the races this season are cancelled. Bummer. To get my high-octane thrill, I’ve resorted to watching<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=W3hEfwmzgDI">matchbox cars</a> thanks to my friend Stephan, and even<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DG1cFm3dsaU">sim racing with actual F1 drivers</a>. YouTube is often a shitshow of terrible videos, but this week it’s a true savior with all of its odd niches. Maybe you’ll find a cool substitute for something you miss on there as well.</li><li>A few weeks ago, when we could still<em>gather</em>, I saw Kyle Chayka and Robin Sloan discuss Kyle’s new book. It was pretty fun, albeit sparsely attended. If you haven’t read<em>Longing for Less</em>, perhaps this will<a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2020/02/03/the-pitfalls-and-the-potential-of-the-new-minimalism">convince you to pick up a a copy</a> from an independent bookstore. Robin even recommends a few other books in<a href="https://www.robinsloan.com/newsletter/march-2020/">his latest newsletter</a>.</li><li>I’m fascinated with the idea of<a href="https://www.robinsloan.com/notes/but-and/">“but/and”</a>. I’m not sure if it’ll catch on, but/and it’s cool.</li><li>Do you love museums? Do you love cats?<a href="https://www.boredpanda.com/cats-sneaking-security-ken-chan-gosaku-hiroshima-onomichi-city-museum-of-art/">Then you’re in luck</a>!</li></ul><p><a href="http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/11/25183825/Cat-Came-Back-2.png">http://cdn8.openculture.com/2018/11/25183825/Cat-Came-Back-2.png</a></p><ul><li>Are you as amped about Animal Crossing: New Horizon as I am? Make sure you’re prepared if you plan to<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/3/19/21185977/animal-crossing-new-horizons-local-multiplayer-island-sharing">share your island with your family</a>. There are benefits, but as a woman who lives alone, I certainly would prefer to keep my island of Lesbos to myself. Reply to this email if you want my friend code though :D</li></ul><p>The train is about to pull into the station in Tokyo, and then I’ll hop onto the metro line to Asakusa. Drop me a line and tell me something you’ve loved this week. I’ll share some good things again next week if you’d like me to pass them along. And as always, wash your hands and see you next week, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>links week eleven</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-15-links-week-eleven/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-15-links-week-eleven/</guid><description>Welcome to a new world without toilet paper. Seriously, it’s fucking depressing seeing pictures of grocery stores post-hoarding. I hope everyone reading this cares for your fellow humans more than building a fort out of sanitizer and toilet paper.</description><content:encoded><p>Welcome to a new world without toilet paper. Seriously, it’s fucking depressing seeing pictures of grocery stores post-hoarding. I hope everyone reading this cares for your fellow humans more than building a fort out of sanitizer and toilet paper.</p><p>Here’s a cat to help you feel better:</p><p><a href="https://twitter.com/artgillespie/status/1238266163294957568?s=20">https://twitter.com/artgillespie/status/1238266163294957568?s=20</a></p><p>Sorry for starting on a bummer note, but it’s kinda wild out there, eh?
I hope you’re taking care of yourself, washing your hands for 20 seconds, using lotion to protect your skin, and breathing deeply. In this midst of the wild times, I bring you links and love from a train in Japan traveling 200 miles per hour. Everyone is wearing masks, and it’s gently raining outside of the window as we pass Mount Fuji.</p><p>Ok, here’s the links:</p><ul><li>It turns out, on some sites it’s<a href="https://www.cjr.org/first_person/the-infinite-scroll.php">ads all the way down</a>. I personally use<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bltoTMJZetc">an adblocker</a> for many, many reasons. It really helps with page load times too. If you’re feeling fancy, you can<a href="https://pi-hole.net">install one on your router</a>, or use something like an Eero that can handle blocking for you with no installation.</li><li>This piece was written<a href="https://www.brightwalldarkroom.com/2020/01/08/i-think-you-should-leave/">for our current world</a> about the Netflix show<em>I Think You Should Leave</em> and using Tim Robinson’s absurdist comedy to cope with dread. I loved this show, and have watched it more than once at this point. If you like it, I also recommend<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xMW-SzZKJ-Q"><em>Nathan for You</em></a> and<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=T2dSE6_utcE"><em>Review</em></a>, both of which are equally strange and oddly comforting. I know for some of you reading this, your empathy extends to fictional characters on tv, and makes watching “cringe” shows essentially impossible, but if you are like me, and enjoy some good old-fashioned schadenfreude&hellip; “Absurdist humor is a means to express the core disillusionment that lies at the heart of the millennial generation”.</li></ul><p><img src="https://cdn.shortpixel.ai/client/q_glossy,ret_img,w_1024/https://www.brightwalldarkroom.com/wp-content/uploads/2020/01/i-think-you-should-leave2-e1578519100351.jpg" alt="no good car ideas"/><ul><li>A<a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2020/03/12/814414450/comic-i-spent-a-day-in-coronavirus-awareness-mode-epidemiologists-how-did-i-do">comic about trying really, really hard not to touch your face</a>. I always think “hot hands!” which helps a little. A habit I picked up from conferences, which are always hotbeds of illness, is to never touch my face or food until I’ve washed thoroughly. It even helps to wash during “transitions,” like, getting home, going to the restroom, etc. Soap: it’s really good.</li><li>This link might be a little odd considering we’re all working from home indefinitely, but here’s a bit about how folks are using mute and noise-cancelling to<a href="https://getpocket.com/explore/item/hit-the-mute-button-why-everyone-is-trying-to-silence-the-outside-world">escape the world around them</a>.</li><li>Today, I’m off to Kyoto, which is trying to attract tourists currently through an<a href="https://japantoday.com/category/features/travel/Kyoto-starts-new-%27Empty%27-tourism-campaign-to-attract-tourists-during-coronavirus-outbreak">odd campaign</a>. I’m only there for one night, to enjoy a hotel room designed by<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yamantaka_Eye">EYヨ</a>. It promises to be an interesting experience. Hopefully I’ll have photos to share with you next week. Here’s<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fUSGujidgns">one of my favorite albums by Boredoms</a>, the band that アイ started.</li><li>Finally, for you documentation nerds out there, I think this is a pretty interesting solution for folks who like<a href="https://hackmd.io/">using Github and Markdown to write</a>. It’s not particularly mobile-friendly, but theoretically one could edit and write in a markdown tool of choice, then use this app to do the collaboration bits. I still don’t really like Google Docs, and I fear for the future of Dropbox Paper, so I’m glad to see more work on open standards.</li></ul><p>That’s it from me today in 日本. I hope your Saturday is quiet and relaxing, and you’re able to have a great big belly laugh every day this week. Love yourself, and those around you, and as always—see you next week, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>links week ten</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-08-links-week-ten/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-08-links-week-ten/</guid><description>This email comes to you from a rainy port city, where I am spending time on strategy and vision for the Women’s Foundation of Oregon.</description><content:encoded><p>This email comes to you from a rainy port city, where I am spending time on strategy and vision for the Women’s Foundation of Oregon. Spending the weekend with a room full of amazing women from all over the state comprising our board was incredible. My heart is full, and I’m hopeful for the work we can accomplish in the coming years.</p><p>Next week I’ll be in yet another city on the other side of the globe, and despite the prevalent fear of disease right now, I’m excited to be on the road again, testing my travel packing and gear.</p><p>Whether you’re also traveling, or spending some time working from home this week, here are some links to keep you curious:</p><ul><li>On the topic of travel, did you know that scientists can’t agree on<a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/no-one-can-explain-why-planes-stay-in-the-air/">how planes stay in the air</a>? There are theories that mostly work, but all of them are missing some part. Honestly, it’s probably just an aeromancer on each plane.</li><li>Remember Fraidycat from last week? Robin wrote a bit more about how<a href="https://www.robinsloan.com/notes/master-tapes/">he’s enjoying it</a>, and how the creator of the site just wants to be left alone.</li><li>Here’s a heartening tale of a company that raised their<a href="https://kottke.org/20/02/what-happened-to-the-company-that-raised-minimum-wage-to-70kyr">minimum wage to 70k a year</a>. A lot of folks wanted them to fail, and thereby prove that the system works better when some people live in poverty, but it turned out folks do better work when they’re less stressed about money. I mean, c’mon.</li><li>Do you like books? Do you like arbitrary tournaments? Boom, here’s<a href="https://themorningnews.org/tob/2020/golden-state-v-oval-v-we-cast-a-shadow.php">both at once</a>. I love these silly march-madness-esque book-offs. I’ve only read a few books on this list, so I can’t wait to read more. Hopefully this tournament adds a few items to your to-read list too.</li><li>Speaking of good books, I’m loving<a href="https://theoutline.com/post/8756/q-and-a-joanne-mcneil-lurking-book-how-person-became-user">Lurking</a>, which outlines the growth of the social web, and how people became<em>users</em>. I remember many of the events in this book very well, and Joanne interviewed folks that I know to write it, so it hit me at home. I usually don’t like non-fiction, Lurking moves through ideas in such an entertaining fashion that I forgot my preference.</li></ul><p>Today I saw cherry blossoms all over the city, and it got me excited for the new season! Japan traditionally has 24 seasons, and we just entered 啓蟄 which is when all the little critters crawl out to celebrate and move about. Personally, I’m very excited to be one of the animals exploring the world during this season, dutifully avoiding crowds. As I saw someone say online last week: “Avoiding crowds? I’ve been preparing for this my entire life.” Jokes aside, I hope you and yours stay safe and happy during what is a scary time. And as always, see you next week, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>links week nine</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-01-links-week-nine/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-01-links-week-nine/</guid><description>This weekend is a bit sad, as it would have marked my countdown to a two week vacation in Japan, but due to coronavirus I had to cancel the trip.</description><content:encoded><p>This weekend is a bit sad, as it would have marked my countdown to a two week vacation in Japan, but due to coronavirus I had to cancel the trip. Perhaps I’ll do something else, but right now I’m just worried for my friends and coworkers abroad and at home. Keep your hands washed, your spirits up, and your days full of love.</p><p>I did plan a second trip this year in November for the amazing<a href="https://studiodradiodurans.com/collections/retreats/products/focus-yoshino-retreat-2020-apply">Focus retreat put on by Craig Mod</a>. If you’re reading this, you might enjoy it, so I recommend<a href="https://studiodradiodurans.com/collections/retreats/products/focus-yoshino-retreat-2020-apply">applying</a>.</p><p>Snorri is currently sitting on my shoulder, and I’m taking his plaintive cries as a, “get to the links!” so I will:</p><ul><li><a href="https://craigmod.com/roden/036/">This is a wide-ranging newsletter installment</a> from one of my favorite newsletter writers recently. I particularly enjoyed this quote about developing our ideas and giving them real space:</li></ul><blockquote><p>If an idea is any good, chances are you shouldn’t just be tweeting it, but rather giving it a more solid, fleshed out form as a blog post or essay or zine or whatever. This is out of respect for the idea itself. What I find most dangerous about Twitter is that it can generate similar chemical feelings to having done “the work,” when in fact, you haven’t done the work. You’ve just micro-plastic’d idea potential.</p></blockquote><ul><li>There are so many ways to delete your tweets. I like<a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/jumbo-privacy-security/id1454039975">Jumbo</a>, but perhaps you’re<a href="https://www.freecodecamp.org/news/how-to-delete-your-past-tweets-in-bulk-and-for-free-save-yourself-from-your-past-self-f8844cdbda2/">into</a><a href="https://gist.github.com/robinsloan/3688616">scripts</a> or just want to artisanally<a href="https://micahflee.com/2019/06/semiphemeral-automatically-delete-your-old-tweets-except-for-the-ones-you-want-to-keep/">prune</a>. Take this opportunity, if you want, to<a href="https://tokimeki-unfollow.glitch.me/">unfollow people</a> who no longer bring you joy. I’m still off of Twitter and I think it might just stick.</li><li>If you’ve been on the internet your whole life, or even just a lot of the adult parts, you perhaps carry shame from something you did or said.<a href="https://www.thecut.com/2020/02/emily-gould-gawker-shame.html">Emily Gould tackles hers from her time at Gawker</a>.</li><li>Chances are, you’ve worked in an open-plan office during your career. It<em>turns out</em> these are just about the<a href="https://www.inc.com/geoffrey-james/its-official-open-plan-offices-are-now-dumbest-management-fad-of-all-time.html">worst idea since Six Sigma</a> or trust falls. I don’t think cubicles are the solution either, but what if at some point we could have offices again?</li><li>Do you love cool women and skateboarding? Yea, me too! You might<a href="https://www.oh-so.co/shop">dig this magazine</a> in that case. Personally, I’ve got a serious backlog of<a href="https://www.offscreenmag.com">Offscreen</a> and<a href="https://monocle.com">Monocle</a>, so I can’t quite subscribe right now, but it looks dope.]</li><li>I’m also reading<a href="https://www.kylechayka.com/book/">The Longing for Less</a> this weekend, which I got to hear a discussion about between Robin Sloan and the author, Kyle Chayka this week at the cute<a href="https://www.booksinc.net/SFOpera">Opera Plaza Books Inc</a>. If you’ve been around minimalism at all, or are curious about it, it’s well worth a read. It’s a critical survey and personal journey through music, writing, architecture, and hellish instagram minimalism.</li><li>Finally, I hope you get a chance to<em><a href="https://www.eattheball.com/">eat the ball</a></em>. Eat. The. Ball.</li></ul><p>Hopefully this deluge of links gives you something nice to read and explore as you take time for yourself this week. The times may be scary, but there are so many neat people and things around too, and I am personally trying to stay focused on that. See you next week, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>links week eight</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-02-23-links-week-eight/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-02-23-links-week-eight/</guid><description>This was the week I left Twitter for a while. Honestly it wasn’t so bad, once I got over the twitchy “gotta open Twitter” feeling.</description><content:encoded><p>This was the week I left Twitter for a while. Honestly it wasn’t so bad, once I got over the twitchy “gotta open Twitter” feeling. I’ll write more about that experience soon, with some light suggested reading and a few tips. My main takeaway so far is that I spent a lot of time opening and closing and reopening Twitter for the last 10 years.</p><p>Here are a few things I would’ve sent:</p><h2 id="tweets-that-werent">Tweets that weren’t</h2><p>I really love high fidelity but I can’t quite get behind the idea that Zoe kravitz’ character doesn’t know how gorgeous she is.</p><p>&ldquo;Daddy, I want an election!&rdquo; Except Bloomberg is the daddy and the child in this situation.</p><p>I love watching Tortoise play!<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/EwJf5fw57Yo" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen= title="YouTube Video"/></div></p><p>Woke up like this:</p><p>You’re probably here for the links though, aren’t you?</p><h2 id="links">Links</h2><ul><li><a href="https://www.vulture.com/2020/02/alexis-pereira-viral-essay-twitter-joke-diary.html">This is what happens</a> when you succeed at tweeting something funny.</li><li>Last month I joined quite a lot of folks in the Bay Area in<a href="https://www.thenation.com/article/culture/culture-anna-wiener-uncanny-valley-review/">reading Anna Weiner’s Uncanny Valley</a>. I don’t think it’s an incredible tell-all, but it was certainly entertaining.</li><li>What is porn like for folks who can’t see?<a href="https://slate.com/culture/2020/02/pornhub-audio-description-interview-accessibility.html">This interview</a> is fairly revealing.</li><li>Were you ever broke? How about poor? There’s a pretty big difference, and<a href="https://longreads.com/2018/06/12/the-difference-between-being-broke-and-being-poor/">this comic</a> helps illustrate what it looks like at the grocery store.</li><li>Finally, if you’ve ever had the delight of shopping at Berkeley Bowl, you owe Glenn Yasuda thanks.<a href="https://sf.eater.com/2020/2/20/21145724/glenn-yasuda-berkeley-bowl-obituary">Let’s remember him.</a></li></ul><p>I’m all out of links, and off to get my first haircut in the new year. Enjoy your week, and I’ll see you next weekend, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>links week seven</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-02-16-links-week-seven/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-02-16-links-week-seven/</guid><description>First of all, look at this DUCK!
https://twitter.com/hartyt_/status/1228149203261698048?s=21
I’m writing this intro at my dining table, while someone cleans my house.</description><content:encoded><p>First of all, look at this DUCK!</p><p><a href="https://twitter.com/hartyt_/status/1228149203261698048?s=21">https://twitter.com/hartyt_/status/1228149203261698048?s=21</a></p><p>I’m writing this intro at my dining table, while someone cleans my house. Hiring a house-cleaner is one of the most awkward and also incredible things I’ve done in the past few years. I learned it’s a lot cheaper than I thought it would be—in Portland it cost 60 bucks a session. I haven’t figured out how to not feel like I’m in the way the whole time, or how to comfort Snorri, but at least my house is pretty damn clean for a few days.</p><p>It’s cloudy outside today, but I still plan to venture to a pop-up Yakitori thing put on by some pals at<a href="https://www.instagram.com/torimancal/">鳥万</a>. Feeling hungry? Feast on these links:</p><ul><li>If you ever want to explore the fantastic electronics market of Shenzhen,<a href="https://bunniefoo.com/bunnie/essential/essential-guide-shenzhen-web.pdf">this guide is a must read</a>. I&rsquo;ve never been, but I&rsquo;ve heard it handily beats out Akihabara for wacky and delightful electronic goods.</li><li>While we&rsquo;re on the topic of China, this Chinese fashion designer blew me away with<a href="https://coolhunting.com/style/penultimates-dazzling-diy-influenced-collection/">this collection</a>. I love the utterly bizarre combination of patterns and body-horror.</li><li>You probably saw this online this week, but this guy&rsquo;s daughter rocked the world with the creation of<a href="https://twitter.com/craigcalcaterra/status/1227594895747141632?s=12">long Chile and Ohio 2</a>.</li><li>Oh, you don’t know<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fg4Dyx3XXDg">about squeakin’?</a>?!</li><li>If you’ve ever talked to a person in tech, you may have heard, “you should learn to code. This refrain sometimes come from a good place, but also feels like “hey dumdum, just make a software!” I really like the way that Robin Sloan reframed it this week as: “learn to be a home cook”. We usually don’t learn how to cook so we can open a Michelin-started restaurant, but instead so we can feed ourselves.<a href="https://www.robinsloan.com/notes/home-cooked-app/">What does this look like when the oven is computers?</a></li><li>If you’re a podcast fan, perhaps some of the shows you love are celebrating ten years of recording. One of my favorites is the extremely nerdy<a href="https://overcast.fm/+kMZLu2m8">The Incomparables</a>. Every episode is a discussion of comics, movies, books, or something equally nerdy. There are lots of drafts, and I have genuinely enjoyed laughing along with them since 2010. MBMBAM will also hit 500 soon. Feeling a little old, lol.</li></ul><p>I hope you enjoyed today&rsquo;s whirlwind tour of<em>links</em>. The cleaning is still going on here near the IKEA, and I&rsquo;m getting peckish. Tomorrow is a holiday here, luckily, and I plan to do very little. I hope you have a long weekend too, and tomorrow will be a day of rest and relaxation. See you next week, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>links week six</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-02-09-links-week-six/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-02-09-links-week-six/</guid><description>Shochu, CSS, and “enough”
This week marked the inaugural Figma conference, which I was able to attend through my employer. It was neat to be surrounded by designers from all over the world, and think about how to solve bigger problems than just “how to make people click”.</description><content:encoded><p><strong>Shochu, CSS, and “enough”</strong></p><p>This week marked the inaugural<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xL_ruBAwVmo">Figma conference</a>, which I was able to attend through my employer. It was neat to be surrounded by designers from all over the world, and think about how to solve bigger problems than just “how to make people click”.</p><p>I also got to meet up with<a href="https://craigmod.com/roden/035/">Craig Mod</a> of hiking, ebook, and Leica writing renound—he’s a delight. At a certain point in life I realized most of the people I dig know each other, so it wasn’t a surprise he knew the<a href="https://waxy.org/">Andys</a> and<a href="https://twitter.com/hoverbird">Patrick</a>. We got to talk about the realities of living in Japan as a white American, as well as creating our own families outside of the heteronormative frame.</p><p>Overall, it was a nice week. How was yours? Reply if you feel like sharing.</p><p>And now, the links:</p><ul><li>Remember<a href="https://eev.ee/blog/2020/02/01/old-css-new-css/">the time before CSS</a>? The simple text-mostly world of blue underlined and tables? This is the internet I cut my teeth on, and learned how to code into.</li><li>In the world of tech and productivity, everyone is pushing harder and harder to get more done. What if instead of efficiency, we looked<a href="https://www.treehugger.com/energy-efficiency/forget-efficiency-it-time-get-serious-about-sufficiency.html">towards<em>sufficiency</em></a>?</li><li>On the same note, this article is a meditation on<a href="https://pjrvs.com/enough">having enough</a>.</li><li>If you’ve been outside in the states at all, you’ve likely noticed the preponderance of huge, lumbering SUVs in the past two decades.<a href="https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/m7q7eb/electric-or-not-big-suvs-are-inherently-selfish">Vice dug into why they exist</a>, and I have a feeling you won’t be surprised much by who drives them.</li><li>Need something to watch? This week I saw<a href="https://www.netflix.com/title/80187302">The Stranger</a> on Netflix, with Richard Armitage from a very good season of Spooks, and<a href="https://www.macrumors.com/2020/02/07/apple-tv-plus-mythic-quest-now-available/">Mystic Quest: Raven’s Banquet</a>.</li></ul><p>Whether or not you’re celebrating the annual chocolate and mistake-a-thon that Valentine’s Day is, I hope you treat yourself to something nice to drink or eat. See you next week space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>links week five</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-02-03-links-week-five/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-02-03-links-week-five/</guid><description>A fiscal happy new year to you! I still don&amp;rsquo;t really understand how fiscal years work, but in addition to a lunar new year, Snorri and I celebrated the beginning of FY21, and the 6th anniversary of my employer this weekend.</description><content:encoded><p>A fiscal happy new year to you! I still don&rsquo;t really understand how fiscal years work, but in addition to a lunar new year, Snorri and I celebrated the beginning of FY21, and the 6th anniversary of my employer this weekend. Thrills and chills.</p><p>Doesn&rsquo;t it already feel like spring? Just a little bit? At least in the bay, the plant outside are flowering, and it&rsquo;s already a little warm-is. This is my second year of not really having a winter, and I find the whole thing deeply confusing. On the upside, I never needed to add anything beyond a<a href="https://www.tannergoods.com/products/merino-watch-cap">beanie</a> and a<a href="https://www.parachutehome.com/products/waffle-robe">bathrobe</a> to my wardrobe.</p><p>On to the links!</p><ul><li>The well-regarded Mac and iOS calendar app Fantastical released a somewhat<a href="https://www.macstories.net/reviews/the-new-fantastical-review/">controversial new version</a> this week that adds a ton of great stuff, but also moves to a subscription. I think I&rsquo;ll pay for this, especially because it means I can now create Zoom video links without needing to use Chrome. I&rsquo;d reverted to using the basic calendar app on all my devices until now, but Fantastical 3 adds just enough polish and feature magic to get my cash.</li><li>Do you ever think about the future of the internet?<a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2020/01/before-zuckerberg-gutenberg/603034/">This article from the Atlantic</a> takes lessons from the printing press to assert we&rsquo;re likely wrong. I still think in general there will be a mix of democratizing and open publishing and the horrible continuation of the advertising gristmill.</li><li>Frankly, if<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2020/1/29/21113421/soft-robot-hands-sweat-overheating-research">sweaty robots</a> are the future, count me out.</li><li>Need a little pick-me-up? Perhaps you&rsquo;d enjoy some<a href="https://tinyspells.xyz">tiny spells</a>.</li><li>My friend Casey gave a seminar on writing recently, and luckily for us, she shared<a href="https://caseyplett.wordpress.com/2020/01/31/notes-from-my-seminar-at-usask/">her notes</a>. If you care at all about writing, it&rsquo;s worth a read.</li></ul><p>As always, may your week be filled with the appropriate amount of hydration, rest, and merriment. See you next week, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>links week four</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-01-26-links-week-four/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-01-26-links-week-four/</guid><description>redesigns and long reads. I got to see William Gibson this week in the city, and listening to his southern drawl discuss the intricacies of stubs and alternate realities.</description><content:encoded><h2 id="redesigns-and-long-reads">redesigns and long reads.</h2><p>I got to see William Gibson this week in the city, and listening to his southern drawl discuss the intricacies of stubs and alternate realities. Once I finish<a href="https://www.fantasticfiction.com/c/deborah-christian/mainline.htm">Mainline</a>, I can’t wait to dive into<a href="https://onezero.medium.com/william-gibson-takes-aim-at-the-silicon-valley-he-helped-create-in-an-exclusive-excerpt-of-agency-97c3604fbcde">Agency</a>. Maybe every generation has a real feeling of living in the future, but between tech news and world news, things are a little too reminiscent of sad cyberpunk. This is why I read fiction—at least there we can have heroes.</p><p>And now, the links:</p><ul><li>No family? If you’re in Japan, you can<a href="https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2018/04/30/japans-rent-a-family-industry">rent one</a>. I wonder if this would save me money on therapy, or leave me even more psychically confused?</li><li>Two sites I read have recently gone through a redesign (much like mine), and it’s fun to see how they<a href="https://frankchimero.com/blog/2020/gardening-vs-architecture/">thought about it</a>. Even when the site update isn’t a bit overblown it can be<a href="https://www.animefeminist.com/the-great-anifem-makeover-is-here/">very interesting</a>.</li><li>In addition to redesigning our personal websites (you started blogging, right? It’s good for you), perhaps we should find other ways to<em><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/11/24/opinion/world-wide-web.html">fix the web</a></em>.</li><li>One friend who blogs blessed us this week with a survey of the<a href="https://roadrunnertwice.dreamwidth.org/579803.html">feral cats of their neighborhood</a>.</li><li>Finally, here’s<a href="https://nplusonemag.com/issue-36/essays/my-instagram/">a longer read about Instagram</a>. More than a few friends consider Instagram to be their nice, chill place online—a place for soothing images and creativity. I wish it had stayed that way for me, but alas, between ads, and folks aiming to take the exact same photo or get<em>really stoked</em> on exercise, I found it uncomfortable at best. For me, Slack is largely the place I see friend’s photos. I hope that at some point a non FB company will try to solve the friends + friends of friends photo sharing problem.</li></ul><p>This year I decided to upgrade my coffee at home a bit more than before, and my latest acquisition is all about<a href="https://www.hario.jp/seihin/productdetail.php?product=XGS-60TB">drinking coffee by the window</a> and reading books. Prior to this coffee server, I would drip directly into a Zojirushi vacuum thermos, but I prefer the look at ease of carrying that this brings. It’s never a bad idea to add a little class to one’s weekend, I think. On that note, I would encourage you to take a few deep breaths, and think about simple ways you can make your days off even more relaxing and delightful.</p><p>Enjoy your Sunday, and I’ll see you next week space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>links week three</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-01-19-links-week-three/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-01-19-links-week-three/</guid><description>January is nearly over! I had a delicious meal last night of pork cartilage soup (豚軟骨汁) and dug into an old classic sci-fi book on recommendation from Robin Sloan’s newsletter.</description><content:encoded><p>January is nearly over! I had a delicious meal last night of pork cartilage soup (豚軟骨汁) and dug into an<a href="https://www.fantasticfiction.com/c/deborah-christian/mainline.htm">old classic sci-fi book</a> on recommendation from Robin Sloan’s newsletter. It’s weird and fun so far. I also started back at the gym last week, which left me hobbling around as my body complains about all the rowing I did. At least it’s next to my office!</p><p>Enough about that, here’s more links:</p><ul><li>Throw on the<a href="https://music.apple.com/us/album/who-knows/1479120003?i=1479120009">new Alice Boman</a> while you read, or even after, on a long walk.</li><li>Anne Helen of burnout fame wrote elegantly this week about how we manage to<a href="https://annehelen.substack.com/p/the-wages-of-productivity">always be working, and never actually resting</a>.</li><li>Feel inspired to waste some time? This week I learned you can subscribe to the<a href="https://mjtsai.com/blog/2020/01/16/youtube-rss-feeds/">RSS feed of videos on YouTube</a> instead of bothering with YouTube’s terrible interface.</li><li>Maybe we should start thinking<a href="https://austinkleon.com/2020/01/06/circular-time-vs-linear-time/">more about seasons and less about years</a>. I’m really enjoying this winter, partially because I’m trying to embrace the good things about it.</li><li>Remember Yo? Perhaps there was<a href="https://laughingkaiju.com/yo-really/">something good there</a> after all.</li><li>A cool cartoon with a mean gauged-ear<a href="https://www.polygon.com/2020/1/8/21057255/infinity-train-book-2-new-episodes-tulip-jesse-mt-mystery">queer-coded protagonist</a>? Sign me up!</li></ul><p>Well, it’s time for me to head back into my 80s sci-fi world before going to watch<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Weathering_with_You">Weathering with You</a>. Have a great week, and I hope you spend your MLK Jr. day thinking about ways to enact anti-racism in your daily life.</p><p>See you next week space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>links week two</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-01-12-links-week-two/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-01-12-links-week-two/</guid><description>We’re halfway through with the first month of 2020, and the sun has been out a lot this week in the bay.</description><content:encoded><p>We’re halfway through with the first month of 2020, and the sun has been out a lot this week in the bay. Luckily, I got some new sunglasses so I’m feeling great about the whole thing.</p><p>Have you already mastered all of your New Year’s resolutions? Mine was the same as it is every year: “do more of what you love and less of what you hate”. So far, so good.</p><p>One of the things I love is writing, so I’ll keep on doing it. Another is the television program<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-01-09-rewatching-halt-catch-fire/">Halt and Catch Fire</a>, which I wrote about so that I could combine pleasures. If only I’d managed to eat prosciutto while writing, I would’ve likely passed out from delight.</p><p>Two new things I’m trying this year: going to the gym next to my office, and washing my face. I was a big powerlifter for over a year in Portland, but never found my rhythm here in the bay due to a weird commute. Fortunately, the gym next to my office seems great for lifting, and since it’s literally a few feet from the bus home, I think I’ll be able to use it at least a few times a week. Time will tell. As for washing my face? I’ve never really done it, so I’m not sure what I’ll get out of the whole endeavor, but I’m<em>aging</em> so I figured no time like the present.</p><p>Ok, sorry for the rambling, I know you’re here for&hellip; the links:</p><ul><li>It’s chilly out in the northern hemisphere, so perhaps you’d enjoy a sauna or hot tub dip. If you’re not quite sold on them yet,<a href="https://www.crunchyroll.com/anime-news/2019/05/16/sauna-enthusiasm-manga-sadou-steams-up-a-live-action-tv-drama">Sadou</a>, the delightful program about a sauna a lover is really delightful. I’m not sure if there are subtitles out there yet, but if you can speak Japanese, or just enjoy a show where you don’t know what’s being said, I highly recommend taking a look.</li><li>While we’re on the topic of Japan, how about a man who bakes<a href="https://theoutline.com/post/7571/meet-lord-rod-the-sweet-potato-king-of-yokohama-japan?zd=1&amp;zi=uyn27jjq">sweet potatoes on the back of his custom Miata</a>? My friend Joe writes some truly engaging essays, and this one is especially fun.</li><li>If you prefer animated shows,<a href="https://www.animefeminist.com/winter-2020-premiere-reviews/">this season of anime</a> is promising, especially<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Keep_Your_Hands_Off_Eizouken">Eizouken</a>. There are some stinkers too, but hopefully you can avoid those.</li><li>Currently I’m reading a few things, and you might like them. First, a<a href="https://www.offscreenmag.com/">magazine about life</a> and often about turning things off and going out into the world. Next, a book that teaches you how to<a href="https://jkglei.com/unsubscribe/">get better at time and communication</a>. Finally, I am exploring the world of<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Throne_of_Glass">assassins with Celaena</a> and an assortment of dull men.</li></ul><p>Hopefully these links keep you warm this week, and you’re able to find time for yourself and the things you love. Until next week!</p><p>See you space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>links week one</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-01-05-links-week-one/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-01-05-links-week-one/</guid><description>Links: Week One It’s 2020! Welcome to the new decade. Imagine for a moment the news hasn’t already been wild, and step into a this list of joy and edutainment instead.</description><content:encoded><h1 id="links-week-one">Links: Week One</h1><p>It’s 2020! Welcome to the new decade. Imagine for a moment the news hasn’t already been wild, and step into a this list of joy and edutainment instead. A lot of links this week are to older projects for folks I’ve mentioned before, because I just got back from a long holiday of reading and watching things on tv, so I rediscovered some old favorites. I also redesigned<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com">my website</a>, and moved it from Jekyll to Hugo, which meant some painful time with Go templating. Yikes.</p><p>Without further ado, release the links!</p><ul><li>My friend Andy ran another conference before the delightful XOXO, and the talks are still archived for your edification.<a href="https://vimeo.com/63008757">This one from Robin Sloan</a> is a delight. From a different year of build,<a href="https://vimeo.com/33919422">Craig Mod talks about books</a> and their future. 2019 was a banner year for both of their newsletters, and if you haven’t seen them, here’s<a href="https://craigmod.com/ridgeline/">Craig’s</a> and here’s<a href="https://desert.glass">Robin’s</a>.</li><li>If you enjoyed watching Craig Mod’s talk, and you want to read more, his<a href="https://craigmod.com/journal/ebooks/">work on ebooks holds up well</a>. As a person who reads every day on a Kindle, I have hope that perhaps the love of text and reading experience will one day fully enter the digital realm. Until then, I’ll keep vacillating between books and ebooks.</li></ul><p>/Walking.jpeg</p><ul><li>During the break I picked up a rad re-release of a classic manga called<a href="https://www.greenapplebooks.com/book/9781912097364">“The Walking Man”</a>, and it’s both gorgeous and delightfully banal. The book is mostly about a man walking quietly through urban Japan. That’s it. Sometimes he climbs trees.</li><li>During the holiday I also got to spend a lot of time with my friend Julian, who writes<a href="https://maudlinhouse.net/i-am-a-beautiful-bug/">excellent short fiction</a> and a column about<a href="https://entropymag.org/the-care-and-feeding-of-your-sex-change-dan-ortberg-discusses-the-important-matter-of-soup/">gender and food</a>. We ate quite a bit of food, and rang in the new year at a party where everyone wore wigs. A+ would hang out again.</li></ul><p>All right, thanks for reading along, and being part of my<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-12-30-what-i-learned-from-sending-a-newsletter-this-year/">newsletter journey over this last year</a>. If you’re still hungry for more newsletter<em>content</em>, I recommend learning about life and birds with<a href="https://tinyletter.com/night_heron">Morgane, the night heron</a>.</p><p>See you next week, space cowgirls~</p></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>