<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>newsletter on dill &amp; fennel</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/newsletter/</link><description>Recent content in newsletter on dill &amp; fennel</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Copyright Brook Shelley 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/newsletter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fennel &amp; Dill: Week 21</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-06-07-fennel-dill-week-21/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-06-07-fennel-dill-week-21/</guid><description>Welp, first sunburn of the quarantine for this gal. I spent the afternoon in a friend’s yard (hi André and Haley) and forgot my skin has been softened by indoor lighting for months. On the upside, it was gorgeous outside, and I’m glad I got to sit in the sun.
Since I’ll be indoors for a while healing-up, a lot of todays’s links are indoor kid interests. So if you’re like me, I think you’ll enjoy these:</description></item><item><title>Fennel &amp; Dill: Week 22</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-06-07-fennel-dill-week-22/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-06-07-fennel-dill-week-22/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a busy week! At my company, we had Monday and Friday off, and most of our staff took off the entire week. I decided to work through the week for some reason, and ended-up getting a lot done! Suffering from a bout of creative excitement, I also redesigned my site to try to beat the Google performance measure and load fully under two seconds. Yes. I&amp;rsquo;m a frontend pervert.</description></item><item><title>Fennel &amp; Dill: Week Twenty</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-06-07-fennel-dill-week-twenty/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-06-07-fennel-dill-week-twenty/</guid><description>Trying out a new name for this that isn’t just “links”. Fennel and dill are two of my favorite flavors, but also a terrible combination. They also happen to be my utterly bizarre chest-piece tattoo. If you follow this newsletter but haven’t ever met me in person, just know I have a lot of botanical tattoos.
My snacking game is strong now that I know how to make my own tortillas on demand, and endless sourdough.</description></item><item><title>links week nineteen</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-05-10-links-week-nineteen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-05-10-links-week-nineteen/</guid><description>Ten loaves of sourdough! That’s how many loaves I have made thus far during the pandemic (or pan-demic if you’ll excuse my pun). Have you found a fulfilling hobby? Gotten really good at a driving simulator? Taken up amateur plumbing? I went out last weekend for the first time, albeit just down the street to sit in a friend’s yard, far from said friend. It was pretty nice, and I keep thinking I should perhaps do a little more biking and walking, but then I see a dozen people walking around massless, and I get some combination of furious and scared all over again.</description></item><item><title>links week eighteen</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-05-03-links-week-eighteen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-05-03-links-week-eighteen/</guid><description>Happy May! We made it through an April that lasted conservatively one thousand years. I hope you&amp;rsquo;re well, and finding new ways of living and thriving as we settle in for Summer.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been cleaning, rearranging, and making lots of bread—I think I&amp;rsquo;ve finally sorted out my Sourdough woes.
One thing I can recommend for anyone looking to clean up a little are a bunch of little velcro strips to manage those cables.</description></item><item><title>links week seventeen</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-04-26-links-week-seventeen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-04-26-links-week-seventeen/</guid><description>This is the week of the Magic Keyboard which I’m using to write this email. If you’re curious, or considering picking one up, the linked review should help you decide. For something more exhaustive, perhaps check out this longer look:
In other news, my company has extended our work from home until at least September, which means I’m going to see so many more movies, and play so much Gran Turismo.</description></item><item><title>links week sixteen</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-04-19-links-week-sixteen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-04-19-links-week-sixteen/</guid><description>This week marked my first sourdough loaves, which were delicious and a bit flat. It turns out having a scale is crucial, and hopefully next week I will get to address that lack. I also got a few of my hobby shipments in, which meant building a tiny Porsche and beginning a small robot. Being stuck indoors all day alone is a great excuse for rediscovering things I enjoyed when I was a weird shut-in kid.</description></item><item><title>links week fifteen</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-04-12-links-week-fifteen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-04-12-links-week-fifteen/</guid><description>Welcome to your weekly installment of “what’s Brook reading and clicking on now?” The quarantine here in the Bay Area is 4 weeks on, I think, and today I briefly saw a friend outside while dropping off groceries. It was nice. I hope you’ve had some distant human contact this month too. I’ve also been buying wine from Ordinaire, along with various tinned fishes, because this shit sucks, but wine and mackerel are delightful.</description></item><item><title>links week fourteen</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-04-05-links-week-fourteen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-04-05-links-week-fourteen/</guid><description>This week I spent some time thinking about hoarding.
Specifically, toilet paper hoarding. I&amp;rsquo;ve yet to venture out this week to the grocery, but the TP situation in my house is on its way to dire. I was able to procure napkins a week ago, so&amp;hellip; needs must.
The only hoarding I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to do, back when it was just called &amp;ldquo;collecting&amp;rdquo; was of alcohol. I&amp;rsquo;m a little proud of my strange Shochu collection, largely enabled by my friends over at Umami Mart (who&amp;rsquo;re still doing curbside pickup in the East Bay, btw).</description></item><item><title>links week thirteen</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-29-links-week-thirteen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-29-links-week-thirteen/</guid><description>Ah, I’ve returned to the Americas. This week, Japan started quarantining as well, so I just missed the cutoff there and was largely able to enjoy wandering around like usual. I still tried to socially distance while I was in Tokyo and Osaka however, and I even blogged about it in five parts. Overall, it was a strange trip, but a fun one. I hope I get to travel back to Japan again in November after the quarantine ends.</description></item><item><title>links week twelve</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-21-links-week-twelve/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-21-links-week-twelve/</guid><description>Hello from a 200mph Nozomi Shinaksen train on my way to Tokyo! This train still feels like the future, and it’s especially wild that people are riding it and no one seems particularly worried.
Onomichi—where I was for the past few days—was gorgeous! Truly in rare form. If you’d like to read about that and see some photos of my hiking and exploring, you know where to go.
I spent four hours on the phone today with Chase bank trying to move my flight forward a few days to try to ensure that I won’t be trapped outside of California.</description></item><item><title>links week eleven</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-15-links-week-eleven/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-15-links-week-eleven/</guid><description>Welcome to a new world without toilet paper. Seriously, it’s fucking depressing seeing pictures of grocery stores post-hoarding. I hope everyone reading this cares for your fellow humans more than building a fort out of sanitizer and toilet paper.
Here’s a cat to help you feel better:
https://twitter.com/artgillespie/status/1238266163294957568?s=20
Sorry for starting on a bummer note, but it’s kinda wild out there, eh? I hope you’re taking care of yourself, washing your hands for 20 seconds, using lotion to protect your skin, and breathing deeply.</description></item><item><title>links week ten</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-08-links-week-ten/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-08-links-week-ten/</guid><description>This email comes to you from a rainy port city, where I am spending time on strategy and vision for the Women’s Foundation of Oregon. Spending the weekend with a room full of amazing women from all over the state comprising our board was incredible. My heart is full, and I’m hopeful for the work we can accomplish in the coming years.
Next week I’ll be in yet another city on the other side of the globe, and despite the prevalent fear of disease right now, I’m excited to be on the road again, testing my travel packing and gear.</description></item><item><title>links week nine</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-01-links-week-nine/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-01-links-week-nine/</guid><description>This weekend is a bit sad, as it would have marked my countdown to a two week vacation in Japan, but due to coronavirus I had to cancel the trip. Perhaps I’ll do something else, but right now I’m just worried for my friends and coworkers abroad and at home. Keep your hands washed, your spirits up, and your days full of love.
I did plan a second trip this year in November for the amazing Focus retreat put on by Craig Mod.</description></item><item><title>links week eight</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-02-23-links-week-eight/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-02-23-links-week-eight/</guid><description>This was the week I left Twitter for a while. Honestly it wasn’t so bad, once I got over the twitchy “gotta open Twitter” feeling. I’ll write more about that experience soon, with some light suggested reading and a few tips. My main takeaway so far is that I spent a lot of time opening and closing and reopening Twitter for the last 10 years.
Here are a few things I would’ve sent:</description></item><item><title>links week seven</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-02-16-links-week-seven/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-02-16-links-week-seven/</guid><description>First of all, look at this DUCK!
https://twitter.com/hartyt_/status/1228149203261698048?s=21
I’m writing this intro at my dining table, while someone cleans my house. Hiring a house-cleaner is one of the most awkward and also incredible things I’ve done in the past few years. I learned it’s a lot cheaper than I thought it would be—in Portland it cost 60 bucks a session. I haven’t figured out how to not feel like I’m in the way the whole time, or how to comfort Snorri, but at least my house is pretty damn clean for a few days.</description></item><item><title>links week six</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-02-09-links-week-six/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-02-09-links-week-six/</guid><description>Shochu, CSS, and “enough”
This week marked the inaugural Figma conference, which I was able to attend through my employer. It was neat to be surrounded by designers from all over the world, and think about how to solve bigger problems than just “how to make people click”.
I also got to meet up with Craig Mod of hiking, ebook, and Leica writing renound—he’s a delight. At a certain point in life I realized most of the people I dig know each other, so it wasn’t a surprise he knew the Andys and Patrick.</description></item><item><title>links week five</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-02-03-links-week-five/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-02-03-links-week-five/</guid><description>A fiscal happy new year to you! I still don&amp;rsquo;t really understand how fiscal years work, but in addition to a lunar new year, Snorri and I celebrated the beginning of FY21, and the 6th anniversary of my employer this weekend. Thrills and chills.
Doesn&amp;rsquo;t it already feel like spring? Just a little bit? At least in the bay, the plant outside are flowering, and it&amp;rsquo;s already a little warm-is. This is my second year of not really having a winter, and I find the whole thing deeply confusing.</description></item><item><title>links week four</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-01-26-links-week-four/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-01-26-links-week-four/</guid><description>redesigns and long reads. I got to see William Gibson this week in the city, and listening to his southern drawl discuss the intricacies of stubs and alternate realities. Once I finish Mainline, I can’t wait to dive into Agency. Maybe every generation has a real feeling of living in the future, but between tech news and world news, things are a little too reminiscent of sad cyberpunk. This is why I read fiction—at least there we can have heroes.</description></item><item><title>links week three</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-01-19-links-week-three/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-01-19-links-week-three/</guid><description>January is nearly over! I had a delicious meal last night of pork cartilage soup (豚軟骨汁) and dug into an old classic sci-fi book on recommendation from Robin Sloan’s newsletter. It’s weird and fun so far. I also started back at the gym last week, which left me hobbling around as my body complains about all the rowing I did. At least it’s next to my office!
Enough about that, here’s more links:</description></item><item><title>links week two</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-01-12-links-week-two/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-01-12-links-week-two/</guid><description>We’re halfway through with the first month of 2020, and the sun has been out a lot this week in the bay. Luckily, I got some new sunglasses https://twitter.com/brookshelley/status/1215889336874332161?s=21, so I’m feeling great about the whole thing.
Have you already mastered all of your New Year’s resolutions? Mine was the same as it is every year: “do more of what you love and less of what you hate”. So far, so good.</description></item><item><title>links week one</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-01-05-links-week-one/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-01-05-links-week-one/</guid><description>Links: Week One It’s 2020! Welcome to the new decade. Imagine for a moment the news hasn’t already been wild, and step into a this list of joy and edutainment instead. A lot of links this week are to older projects for folks I’ve mentioned before, because I just got back from a long holiday of reading and watching things on tv, so I rediscovered some old favorites. I also redesigned my website, and moved it from Jekyll to Hugo, which meant some painful time with Go templating.</description></item></channel></rss>