<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>blog on dill &amp; fennel</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/categories/blog/</link><description>Recent content in blog on dill &amp; fennel</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Copyright Brook Shelley 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.brookshelley.com/categories/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2019 iOS Homescreen</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-28-2019-iphone-homescreen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-28-2019-iphone-homescreen/</guid><description>Another year has rushed past, and with it, another iPhone update and some changes to my phone since last year&amp;rsquo;s setup. My use of a single screen of apps continues, with a few major and minor changes alongside.
I&amp;rsquo;ve posted these for the past few years, so if you want to see what apps I was using in 2017, here you go.
Some things change 3 app dock—I moved my Twitter app out of my dock in order to spend less time on Twitter.</description><content:encoded><p>Another year has rushed past, and with it, another iPhone update and some changes to my phone since<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/blog/2018/12/14/2018-iphone-homescreen-update.html">last year&rsquo;s setup</a>. My use of a single screen of apps continues, with a few major and minor changes alongside.</p><p><img src="/photos/2019iphone.png" alt="2019 iPhone Screen"/><p>I&rsquo;ve posted these for the past few years, so if you want to see what apps I was using in<a href="https://medium.com/@brookshelley/2017-homescreen-ac92817eae60">2017, here you go</a>.</p><h2 id="some-things-change">Some things change</h2><p><strong>3 app dock</strong>—I moved my Twitter app out of my dock in order to spend less time on Twitter. I figured if I wanted to to launch it I could easily search for it, but perhaps by having it out of reach I wouldn&rsquo;t launch the app out of habit or boredom. This worked pretty well.</p><p><strong>Fantastical</strong>—Last year I said &ldquo;This is definitely the app I am most interested in replacing.&rdquo; I replaced it with<strong>iOS Calendar</strong> not too long after writing this post because of the cleaner look, date view icon, and a better visualization of my next meeting on my phone and watch. I also really hate how Fantastical uses space on the iPad. I still hope that someday Apple opens up the ability to change icons based on events or time, but until they do, I&rsquo;ll have a hard time moving away from the default calendar.</p><p><strong>Bear</strong>—I moved completely off of Bear in favor of<strong>iAWriter</strong>, largely due to<a href="https://workingcopy.app">Working Copy</a>, which is an excellent Git client for iOS devices, and means I can use iAWriter&rsquo;s file function to open up posts like this one that live in my personal blog&rsquo;s Drafts folder.</p><p><strong>Google Maps</strong>—I moved back to<strong>Apple Maps</strong>. In general Apple Maps got a lot better, and works better on my watch. Also, in Japan, Apple Maps often shows results from TabeLog, which tends to have much better local recommendations.</p><p><strong>Tweetbot</strong>—I replaced this with the weird beta Twitter app<strong>twttr</strong>. It&rsquo;s hidden in a folder now to encourage me to not use it as often, and that is working pretty well.</p><p><strong>Fiery Feeds</strong>—<em><strong>Reeder 4</strong> came out</em> and it&rsquo;s amazing. I moved to Reeder 4 on all of my devices, and I love it. The read later feature has also replaced Safari&rsquo;s read later for me in all instances. I don&rsquo;t use Bionic reading, but it&rsquo;s a neat feature regardless. I continue to use<a href="https://feedbin.com">Feedbin</a> to back my RSS.</p><h2 id="some-things-stay-the-same">Some things stay the same</h2><p><strong>Overcast</strong> — Overcast is great. This year it just got better, from CarPlay, to the watch, to my phone. I am really excited for Marco to update for more Airplay 2 features as he mentioned in a recent episode of<a href="https://atp.fm/episodes/352">ATP</a>. There are other podcast apps out there, but for smart-speed, playlists, and everything else, there is only Overcast.</p><p><strong>Spark</strong>—I kept using Spark this year, especially as they updated for a great black-screened-OLED-friendly dark mode, and<a href="https://sparkmailapp.com/blog/new-design-dark-mode-ios13">rethought their entire interface in 2.5</a>. This is a great email app on all my devices, and has fantastic keyboard support for iPadOS.</p><p><strong>Apple Music</strong>—I&rsquo;ve barely opened Spotify all year. Apple Music keeps getting better, and it seems like more of my friends have moved over to it as well.</p><p><strong>Things</strong>—This app is how I keep track of all my work and personal tasks. It&rsquo;s incredible. Keyboard shortcuts are available on iOS and Mac, and in general this app is a great example of how a cross-platform app should function.</p><p><strong>Apple Photos</strong>—This app got a lot better in iOS 13, and I really enjoy it. Not much else to say.</p><p><strong>Slack</strong>—I work at Slack still, and it&rsquo;s still a great app.</p><p><strong>Single folder</strong>—65 extra apps live in this folder. They range from rarely-used travel apps for work, to translation apps, to video and banking apps. I don&rsquo;t<em>love</em> all of the apps in this folder, but I regularly go through them to make sure they&rsquo;re still needed.</p><h2 id="the-best-of-the-rest">The best of the rest</h2><p>A few of the apps that live inside my large catch-all folder and are opened via search.</p><p><strong>Working Copy</strong>—This app is amazing. In addition to functioning as a great Git tool, it also has syntax and code-highlighting for tons of languages. I don&rsquo;t work in Working Copy all the time, but when I&rsquo;m iPad-only, I use it quite a bit for work and my personal projects.</p><p><strong>Google Fi</strong>—I moved to Google Fi last year from AT&amp;T largely due to the free and easy international roaming. It&rsquo;s great.</p><p><strong>Tsurukame</strong>—This is my daily second job. I spend around two hours a day in this app and reading in order to become fully literate in Japanese. As I write this, I&rsquo;m at level 39, and have over 1300 Kanji above Guru level. Learning Japanese is super hard, but worth it.</p><p><strong>Plex</strong>—Lots of video sources live here. It&rsquo;s a great app, and I wish other video streaming services would learn from Plex&rsquo;s great example.</p><p><strong>1Password</strong>—All my passwords live here, and are super long and complex. Similar to Things, I don&rsquo;t think I could work the same way without 1Password.</p><h2 id="wrap-up">Wrap-up</h2><p>Last year I suggested my list of apps might not shift much, but five of my major home screen apps changed due to updates and simplicity. I&rsquo;m happy this year with the apps that I use and due to my requirements of quality Apple Watch, Mac, and iPadOS cross-platform functionality the bar is really high for other apps to knock these off of my phone. I&rsquo;m very excited about iOS 14, especially with news that it might be more stable than the particularly rough iOS 13 release. Perhaps Apple will give more features to devs that unlock unimagined new functionality. We&rsquo;ll find out in 6 months.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Favorite Albums of 2019</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-26-favorite-albums-2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-26-favorite-albums-2019/</guid><description>The Playlist Here&amp;rsquo;s all the albums I really loved this year easily accessible as an Apple Playlist.
The Albums Cheap Queen — King Princess Bless lesbian musicians. King Princess first caught my attention with the song Pussy is God, which damn. This album is a bop.
Emily Alone — Florist A deeply sparse, sad album that I enjoy quite a bit. Florist has always made beautiful songs, but this is a so quiet and so delightful.</description><content:encoded><h2 id="the-playlist">The Playlist</h2><p><a href="https://music.apple.com/us/playlist/favorites-of-2019/pl.u-vp3jjIrk0xN">Here&rsquo;s all the albums I really loved this year</a> easily accessible as an Apple Playlist.</p><h2 id="the-albums">The Albums</h2><ol><li><strong>Cheap Queen</strong> — King Princess</li></ol><p>Bless lesbian musicians. King Princess first caught my attention with the song Pussy is God, which damn. This album is a bop.</p><ol start="2"><li><strong>Emily Alone</strong> — Florist</li></ol><p>A deeply sparse, sad album that I enjoy quite a bit. Florist has always made beautiful songs, but this is a so quiet and so delightful.</p><ol start="3"><li><strong>Interloper</strong> — Momma</li></ol><p>Just the right amount of harmonies and hooks to draw you into a strange and fun indie rock band.</p><ol start="4"><li><strong>Family Tree</strong> — Oh Land</li></ol><p>A gorgeous album from a Danish former dancer. I just love her voice—from the start the album has a haunting beauty.</p><ol start="5"><li><strong>Scholars</strong> — Buke &amp; Gase</li></ol><p>I&rsquo;ve had every album Buke &amp; Gase put out on repeat for some time after their release, and dearly love their jangly, angular rock. This album doesn&rsquo;t disappoint.</p><ol start="6"><li><strong>Beast on Beast</strong> — Gabby&rsquo;s World</li></ol><p>This is the first band I&rsquo;ve listened to that has gone through three name changes, from Eskimeaux, to Ó, then finally Gabby&rsquo;s World. I&rsquo;ve loved them the whole time, and find this to be especially good sad subway music for when you&rsquo;re a little bummed and riding home at night.</p><ol start="7"><li><strong>Placeholder</strong> — Hand Habits</li></ol><p>A complex jam album with fantastic guitars and vocals weaving in and out of downtempo songs.</p><ol start="8"><li><strong>Memory Streams</strong> — Portico Quartet</li></ol><p>I first heard this band at a vinyl bar in Oakland, and their latest album rules.</p><ol start="9"><li><strong>Trust In The Lifeforce Of The Deep Mystery</strong> — The Comet Is Coming</li></ol><p>Fantastic end of the world music. This is really strange, funky jazz, and I dig it. Many mornings start off with this album and some coffee.</p><ol start="10"><li><strong>Nowhere Now Here</strong> — MONO</li></ol><p>I&rsquo;ve been stoked on MONO since high school, and was lucky enough to see them perform many times at Emo&rsquo;s (RIP) in Austin. They just keep on making fantastic music that vacillates softer beautiful sounds and driving melodies. Whether you&rsquo;re walking around the city or taking a train to another city, this album creates a gorgeous soundtrack for your life.</p><ol start="11"><li><strong>Patience</strong> — Manequin Pussy</li></ol><p>A chill mix of punk and indie rock jams. I think I first saw this band at a show/benefit for Bernie Sanders that I didn’t know was a benefit. It was a super washed crowd, but Manequin Pussy owned bones. This record rules.</p><ol start="12"><li><strong>Crush on Me</strong> — Sir Babygirl</li></ol><p>I’m really enjoying the new influx of queer and lesbian pop music these days. This album is infectiously catchy and often hilarious. Put it on and enjoy the short bouts of sun this winter.</p><ol start="13"><li><strong>Miss Universe</strong> — Nilüfer Yanya</li></ol><p>I&rsquo;m not sure how to describe this album, but it&rsquo;s a jam. A bit of r&amp;b, a bit of indie rock, and a lot of really solid tunes. I&rsquo;ve put this album on a repeat a few times this year.</p><ol start="14"><li><strong>Hifalutin</strong> — Lowly</li></ol><p>Super dance-y-yet-downtempo album. I can throw this on for a variety of moods, and it seems to always suit them. There’s something about Denmark that must inspire people to make brilliant music—this album was recorded in a small warehouse near Aarhus.</p><ol start="15"><li><strong>Weird</strong> — Juliana Hatfield</li></ol><p>Oh hey, an album that feels like I do sometimes: “I&rsquo;m staying in/My hair’s not right/And if I go out/Somebody might
Take me for a functioning/Human being”. I’m sure I heard Hatfield before this album, but this is the one where she came together for me as an artist.</p><ol start="16"><li><strong>Fibs</strong> — Anna Meredith</li></ol><p>This album is a solid jam. Anna Meredith&rsquo;s compositions feel important, weird, and powerful. I often listen to this album in the morning to wake up and feel better about the day.</p><ol start="17"><li><strong>Four of Arrows</strong> — Great Grandpa</li></ol><p>For a sophmore effort this is a really fun, mature album. I like that they&rsquo;ve moved from more straightforward poppy indie music to a little more melodic rock.</p><ol start="18"><li><strong>Two Hands</strong> — Big Thief</li></ol><p>Honestly, the fact that Big Thief put out<em>two</em> incredible albums this year is wild to me. I love both of their 2019 records, but Two Hands especially keeps going back on the stereo. It&rsquo;s gorgeous. Jia Tolentino wrote about them recently, and I recommend<a href="https://www.newyorker.com/culture/cultural-comment/the-ordinary-brilliance-of-big-thief">reading her piece</a>.</p><ol start="19"><li><strong>Any Human Friend</strong> — Marika Hackman</li></ol><p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;ve got BDE/I think it&rsquo;s a venereal disease&rdquo;. Ugh. This album is an instant lesbian classic. I&rsquo;ve loved every album Hackman has put out, with That Iron Taste immediately pulling me in, and constantly being on rotation. I got to see her perform in Portland a few years back, and the show was outstanding. Between her soft vocal delivery, which whispers with poetry and sensuality, and the brutally raw lyrical content&hellip; just wow.</p><ol start="20"><li><strong>Lost Wisdom Pt.</strong> — Mount Eerie</li></ol><p>After the utter devastation of his past two albums, this truly sad album about an impending divorce with beautiful guest vocals from Julie Doiron almost comes as a relief. This is a tragedy I can almost understand, feelings I have felt. Microphones and Mount Eerie have held me through many hard times, and this album is an excellent entry into their discography.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>DevRel Tour Packing List</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-06-devreltour-packing-list/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-06-devreltour-packing-list/</guid><description>As usual, when I go on a DevRel tour, I like to write about what I&amp;rsquo;ve packed. This trip was a 3 week journey from Tokyo, through Kyoto, to Osaka, and back. As I write this, halfway through the trip, I feel very good about the amount of stuff I brought.
Bags RYU Quick Pack 18L Topo Designs Trip Pack Last time I went to Japan, I brought the DSPTCH Waist Bag as my day bag, and my shoulders immediately regretted it.</description><content:encoded><p>As usual, when I go on a DevRel tour, I like to write about what I&rsquo;ve packed. This trip was a 3 week journey from Tokyo, through Kyoto, to Osaka, and back. As I write this, halfway through the trip, I feel very good about the amount of stuff I brought.</p><h2 id="bags">Bags</h2><ul><li>RYU Quick Pack 18L</li><li>Topo Designs Trip Pack</li></ul><p><img src="/photos/ryubag2019.jpeg" alt="bags"/><p><img src="/photos/travelbag2019.jpeg" alt="bag2"/><p>Last time I went to Japan, I brought the DSPTCH Waist Bag as my day bag, and my shoulders immediately regretted it. I think my days or a one-shoulder bag with a computer are pretty much over. This time I returned to my tried and true setup. I’ve reviewed or written about both of these bags previously.</p><p><img src="/photos/drybags2019.jpeg" alt="drybags"/><ul><li>Two Sea-to-summit dry bags</li></ul><p>These are great for clothes and toiletries, and additionally ensure that even in a downpour I can keep a few things dry.</p><ul><li>One Topo Designs accessory bag</li></ul><p><img src="/photos/drybagsinside.jpeg" alt="drybagsinsidebigbag"/><p>This time around, I loaded my toothbrush and some other non-leaky toiletries into this bag because I noticed the metal tip of my electric toothbrush kept<em>almost</em> poking through my dry bag.</p><h2 id="clothes">Clothes</h2><p><img src="/photos/clothes.jpeg" alt="clothes"/><h3 id="jackets">Jackets</h3><ul><li>Mission Workshop Torre Windshell</li></ul><p>My daily jacket. I’ve got two of these and they’re awesome. Not quite waterproof, but warm enough, and water-resistant enough for a drizzle and temperatures between 7-20C (mid-40s to mid-60s F).</p><ul><li>Arcteryx Cordetta</li></ul><p>If it rains, I’m covered.</p><h3 id="shirts">Shirts</h3><ul><li>Wool t-shirts from Ryu and Icebreaker</li></ul><p>A great way to stay dry and warm or cool. These wash easily and are comfy for all-day-travel.</p><h3 id="pants">Pants</h3><ul><li>Two pairs of Outdoor Voices RecTrek pants</li></ul><p>I wear these to work daily, and they’re pretty ideal. Comfy, flexible, and a bit water-resistant. The pockets are also<em>huge</em> which means my phone fits easily in a front pocket.</p><h3 id="shoes-and-socks">Shoes and socks</h3><ul><li>Blundstones</li><li>Bombas no-show</li></ul><p>These shoes go on and off pretty easily, and look nice enough for business meetings while still feeling good for longer walks. Half of this trip was a vacation, where I wandered around all day, including hiking. I almost went with my new KOIO shoes, but at the last minute, opted for slip-one with a<em>lot</em> of grip.</p><h3 id="underwear">Underwear</h3><ul><li>Wool stuff from Icebreaker</li></ul><p>Wool is the way to go. I’ve tried other solutions and they were nice enough, but ultimately, wool holds up the best and wicks super well.</p><h2 id="tech-gear">Tech gear</h2><p><img src="/photos/electronics2019.jpeg" alt="electronics"/><ul><li>Kindle Oasis</li><li>Battery</li><li>USB-C -> C, and Lightning: iPad and iPhone</li><li>USB-A -> Watch</li><li>USB-A -> Micro: Kindle</li><li>iPad Pro 10.5 w/ Smart Keyboard</li></ul><p>At some point, maybe I can travel with only USB-C cables, but that world doesn’t exist yet. Fortunately my external battery has a USB-C port and a USB-A port, so I use those two to charge my phone and watch at night. On the plane my USB-C to USB-C cable means I can top-up my iPad if I play too many games or get low mid-season of a tv show. It completely boggles the mind why the Kindle isn’t a USB-C device yet. Seriously. It’s 2019.</p><h2 id="other-stuff">Other stuff</h2><p><img src="/photos/weeks2019.jpeg" alt="weeks"/><ul><li>Toiletries</li><li>Hobonichi Weeks &amp; Kaweco Al EF fountain pen</li><li>お土産</li></ul><p>The usual assortment of unguents, potions, and a toothbrush, along with my trusty new pen and notebook. I<em>love</em> this Kaweco pen, which is both completely blacked-out, and compact. I also brought some small gifts for 東京と大阪の同僚。</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>A letter</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-10-08-letter-to-myself/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-10-08-letter-to-myself/</guid><description>(this is a very earnest post, and if you&amp;rsquo;re here for backpacks and travel, maybe skip this one)
Hey Brook,
This letter in a sci-fi tale would come to you out of the ether, dropping onto your iBook G3 on some particularly dark night of the soul. I&amp;rsquo;m you, but 16 years older, and hopefully a little wiser.
(Spoiler alert)
The next few years will be a lot of fun, but also really, really tough.</description><content:encoded><p>(this is a very earnest post, and if you&rsquo;re here for backpacks and travel, maybe skip this one)</p><p>Hey Brook,</p><p>This letter in a sci-fi tale would come to you out of the ether, dropping onto your iBook G3 on some particularly dark night of the soul. I&rsquo;m you, but 16 years older, and hopefully a little wiser.</p><p>(Spoiler alert)</p><p>The next few years will be a lot of fun, but also really, really tough. You will lose friends and family to cancer, then to divorce and&hellip;</p><p>You transition. You finally do it, and it goes mostly ok! You don&rsquo;t talk to family anymore, but you probably saw that coming, and it&rsquo;s fine because you have friends who love and support you.</p><p>Your finances will get worse for a while. Really bad. You&rsquo;re going to spend a little while sleeping in your car and on folks&rsquo; couches. It sucks. You&rsquo;ll smoke too many cigarettes, and do some ridiculous stuff.</p><p>It works out.</p><p>Eventually, you get a job with folks who you really like, and they encourage you. You join a company that is doing amazing stuff with messaging (kind of like IRC, but way, way cooler—you&rsquo;ll see). After a year, you get a little bit of stock, and finally pay off your student loan debt that you&rsquo;ll have ground down for 13 years. It will feel great.</p><p>You&rsquo;ll see a therapist, and a doctor, and a dentist with a regular cadence. It will help. I promise.</p><p>You&rsquo;ll love, you&rsquo;ll lose, and you&rsquo;ll get back on that horse. Ultimately, you&rsquo;ll do a<em>lot</em> of reading and spend a lot of time with your best friend, a cat named Snorri. You and Snorri will travel from Austin, to Portland, to Oakland, with a<em>ton</em> of flights in between to Europe, Asia, Canada, and NYC.</p><p>I know what it feels like a lot of nights right now. It sucks. It&rsquo;s real, and you&rsquo;ve had a hard time. Most people you know won&rsquo;t get it, and you deserve better. When you get older you&rsquo;ll know more people who&rsquo;ve also gone through a lot of shit, and they&rsquo;ll be good listeners, and you&rsquo;ll listen a lot too. Don&rsquo;t stop loving, and don&rsquo;t stop trying to be open with your friends. It pays off more often than not. Your biggest asset is your heart. Don&rsquo;t lose it.</p><p>I love you, and I can&rsquo;t wait for you to get to where I am now. For all the good times, and the bad ones, just know I&rsquo;m here in the future cheering you on.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>XOXO 2019</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-09-10-xoxo-2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-09-10-xoxo-2019/</guid><description>A return to form This year marked my 4th XOXO, and my 3rd at Revolution Hall. Last year was big, which meant it was even harder to wave at, or spend time with the other amazing attendees I knew. This year, it felt just right. I still waved at too many folks, and wished I had time to have a number of small dinners over the next year instead of so many “hey, I see you, sorry I’ve gotta run!</description><content:encoded><h2 id="a-return-to-form">A return to form</h2><p>This year marked my 4th XOXO, and my 3rd at Revolution Hall. Last year was<em>big</em>, which meant it was even harder to wave at, or spend time with the other amazing attendees I knew. This year, it felt just right. I still waved at too many folks, and wished I had time to have a number of small dinners over the next year instead of so many “hey, I see you, sorry I’ve gotta run!” However, I got to spend time with a smallish group of friends, see all the talks I wanted, and even play some<a href="http://www.killerqueenblack.com">amazing</a><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IJ_I8SSVKto">new</a><a href="https://play.date">games</a>.
If you’ve never been to XOXO, and you make things on the internet, and enjoy building relationships, this is a great place for you.</p><h2 id="day-one">Day one</h2><p>As usually, the first day of the conference was a social one—with Glitch doing an<a href="https://glitch.com/~appy-hour">Appy Hour</a>, and Panic showing off the<a href="https://play.date">Playdate</a>. It was super cool seeing all the strange community games and creations of Glitch users, along with a few presentations, and the Playdate is something I can’t wait to own. Topped-off with a dinner at Kachka, a lot of upcoming games, and one of the<a href="https://www.polygon.com/videos/2019/9/9/20849172/unraveled-how-to-calculate-pet-hp-hit-points">most hilarious videos</a> I’ve seen in a while, wherein Brian Gilbert attempts to calculate his pet’s HP, Friday was a delight. The weather held, the<a href="https://twitter.com/brookshelley/status/1171647388001406976?s=21">toilets were uniquely chill</a>, and the layout of the festival ensure I could wander and find neat things.</p><h2 id="day-two">Day two</h2><p>One of the first pieces of advice I’d give anyone going to a multi-day festival is “don’t drink too much on the first night”. I didn’t take my own advice. I wasn’t ill, but a combination of 3 glasses of wine and too little sleep meant 10am felt<em>very</em> early. Thankfully my hotel had Proud Mary coffee, and XOXO had Deadstock. A breakfast sandwich from Fried Egg I’m in Love completed my resurrection.</p><p>Day two felt a little longer, as I sat through every talk, alternately crying and laughing. A definite emotional rollercoaster. Helen and Hrishikesh were excellent hosts, and seeing their banter develop over the weekend makes me hope they host again next year. I missed the Andy’s camaraderie at times, but I hope<em>only</em> being responsible for the whole festival was a nice change from also MCing.</p><p>Lunch was Basilisk. Unbeatable fried chicken I eat every time I visit Portland. Yes, even when I’m there for hours.</p><p>Favorite talks from Saturday: Harry Brewis (very funny guy who I didn’t know anything about beforehand), Hundred Rabbits (delightful French Canadian vegan sailors), and Soleil Ho (what happens when you become the representation?!).</p><p>After a quick dinner, I sat down for a night of unforgettable podcasts. I watched a man interview a chainsaw, and was utterly destroyed by Demi and Miel with special guests Neil and Mike doing Ray Parker Jr’s Ghostbuster song. The number of folks I heard singing “bustin’ makes me feel good” after this podcast taping tells me I wasn’t alone.</p><h2 id="day-3-closing-time">Day 3 (Closing time)</h2><p>Coffee. Sandwich. Almost there. I was wiped at this point, but the talks were delightful. Mikki Kendall, Jenny Odell, and Rhea Butcher were my favorites from Sunday. A great mix of comedy and art. Food highlights were Navarre (another favorite), and dinner at Sardine Head. OMG Sardine Head. Oxidated white wine. Salt-cured anchovy. Dang.</p><p>The karaoke list was full by the time my friends and I got back from dinner, and a cab ride that included an episode of<a href="https://twitter.com/brookshelley/status/1170902500083322880?s=21">King of the Hill</a>. It was fun watching various speakers and friends sing Pavement, Lizzo, and of course, the Ghostbuster’s theme. I ended my night with my friends Jenny and Joe, drinking on the balcony at my hotel. Our friend André’s room was right by the balcony, and he wandered out mid-way through. That moment of kismet was generally how the whole conference felt—friends wandering by, saying hi, and going on adventures.</p><h2 id="a-great-year">A great year</h2><p>XOXO at its best feels like what I imagine a community<em>should</em> feel like. It’s full of new people, old people, dear friends, and acquaintances. If XOXO was every day, I would lose my mind, but once a year, it feels incredible to be surrounded by so many people I care about, as we’re inspired together by talks, art, and each other. I’m so glad I got to go to Portland, for the first time as a non-resident, for XOXO. I can’t wait for another year of this magical festival, and hope many of the same folks will get to attend. My only regret is that I can’t somehow bring Snorri with me too. He’d hate it.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Masterworks review</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-09-03-masterworks-review/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-09-03-masterworks-review/</guid><description>I wish I knew more about art. Reading the titular story, I found myself reaching for my phone to understand each scene in the strange and delightful post-apocalyptic tale. As I held the painting in my mind, and explored the flooded wastes with Liam, Nell, and Co. I found myself enamored by the framing. How often are our relationships held together by a retelling of an old picture? Are we always trying to build a life out of the classics of our youth?</description><content:encoded><p>I wish I knew more about art. Reading the titular story, I found myself reaching for my phone to understand each scene in the strange and delightful post-apocalyptic tale. As I held the painting in my mind, and explored the flooded wastes with Liam, Nell, and Co. I found myself enamored by the framing. How often are our relationships held together by a retelling of an old picture? Are we always trying to build a life out of the classics of our youth? There’s a survey of life, and an exploration of lost moments in these vignettes.</p><p>The opening tale of this collection plants us in Ohio, a place, we see, where even supportive friends or loved ones can’t save you from the yawning abyss. The suburban Olive Garden echoes in my mind with all the breadsticks I absorbed through my high school years. These youth were me, and the chasm felt real then too. From there, we follow a mother who lost a son, and a sliver of a life exploring a name—just enough of both to leave the reader wanting more. Then, a journey through art, mentioned above. It’s strange and beautiful, and a great opportunity to learn about the great works of fine art, if like this reviewer, you largely skipped-out on art class.</p><p>Finally, we readers are washed up on the shore, like so many dead fish, with a man watching a lodge, and time-displaced, dealing with an all-too-familiar moldy bathroom. A word of warning: if you’ve lived in the the Pacific Northwest, the squelch of wet tile will be all too real. This novella is reminiscent of Jack and the Beanstalk, or another fairy tale of exploring a new land. The phrase “crotchal belch” made me laugh out loud. There are so many great turns of phrase in Masterworks. The story propelled me forward, alternately laughing and cringing. I wanted the protagonist to seize his agency, and change in the ways he so clearly desired. I find these characters at turns fascinating and deeply frustrating. There were so many places where I yelled, “say something” in my head, but this isn’t a story of success, but learning and remembering.</p><p>On the whole, I loved this book. Masterworks, by Simon Jacobs, is a fantastic collection of imagination, and creative bombast. At times it leans into magical realism, in others outright fantasy. There a slightly disjointed nature to these stories, as they’re collected over years of writing, and lead me to hope Simon writes more—a novel perhaps—in the future.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Wardrobe refresh</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-08-20-wardrobe-refresh/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-08-20-wardrobe-refresh/</guid><description>As my clothes gradually wear out, I’m slowly trying to replace everything with my current favorites. This makes for a very simple wardrobe that works for all 4 seasons.
Lots of this stuff is wool, all of it is pretty durable, and when possible I tried to find vendors that were environmentally friendly and smaller.
Shirts 4 tank tops — These are fantastic tank tops. They wick well, don’t get stinky, and look good enough to wear outside of the gym.</description><content:encoded><p>As my clothes gradually wear out, I’m slowly trying to replace everything with my current favorites. This makes for a very simple wardrobe that works for all 4 seasons.</p><p>Lots of this stuff is wool, all of it is pretty durable, and when possible I tried to find vendors that were environmentally friendly and smaller.</p><h2 id="shirts">Shirts</h2><p><a href="https://ryu.com/shop/us/women/tops/standard-issue-racerback-tank">4 tank tops</a> — These are fantastic tank tops. They wick well, don’t get stinky, and look good enough to wear outside of the gym.</p><p><a href="https://jungmaven.com/collections/hemp-shirts-womens-tees-tanks/products/hemp-shirt-ojai-tee-short-sleeve-womens">4 t-Shirts</a> — Comfy, and cool looking. There’re a lot of colors if you don’t want to wear all black all the time.</p><p>2 tailored dress shirts (long sleeve)</p><h2 id="pants">Pants</h2><p><a href="https://www.outdoorvoices.com/products/rectrek-pant?variant=34894691781&amp;size=1">3 pants</a> — I just keep buying these. They’re comfortable, stretch well during activity, and hold up to a lot of punishment.</p><h2 id="shorts">Shorts</h2><p><a href="https://ryu.com/shop/us/women-all/shorts/power-short">2 pairs of shorts</a> — Great for lifting weights, yoga, or just when it’s hot. I wouldn’t wear them to work, but I wouldn’t wear shorts to work generally.</p><h2 id="leggings">Leggings</h2><p><a href="https://ryu.com/shop/us/women/bottoms/cardio-tights">2 pairs of leggings</a> — These stay up during yoga and powerlifting really well. They’re comfortable and keep you dry even if you go out for a drink after working out.</p><h2 id="underwear">Underwear</h2><p><a href="https://www.icebreaker.com/en-us/womens-underwear/siren-hipkini/104704.html">10 pairs of underwear</a> — Wool underwear rules.</p><p><a href="https://www.calvinklein.us/en/womens-clothing/womens-bras/custom-modern-cotton-bralette-52705992">5 sports bras</a> — I keep trying to find something that’s more comfortable, but I keep coming back to these. Simple, and easy.</p><h2 id="socks">Socks</h2><p><a href="https://bombas.com/products/womens-no-shows-one-color-eight-pack?variant=black">8 pairs of socks</a> — Great wool socks that pack light and dry quickly.</p><h2 id="pajamas">Pajamas</h2><p><a href="https://www.foxers.com/black-tomboy-boxer-brief/">3 Shorts with pockets</a> — I love that i can throw a phone or keys in here and check the mail if I’m too lazy to put on pants.</p><h2 id="sweater">Sweater</h2><p><a href="https://www.icebreaker.com/en-us/womens-sweaters/waypoint-crewe-sweater/104316.html?dwvar_104316_color=401">1 sweater</a> — You never know when you need a nice sweater.</p><h2 id="jacket">Jacket</h2><p><a href="https://missionworkshop.com/products/the-torre-womens-high-performance-windpro-hoodie-jacket">Hoodie</a> — Great hoodie. I own two because I think they’re discontinuing them sadly. My backup is probably a Chrome one, I guess.</p><h2 id="rain-coat">Rain coat</h2><p><a href="https://arcteryx.com/us/en/shop/womens/andra-coat">Coat</a> — Very low-key and stealth. This jacket looks just as good in the city as it does on a hike.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>A Weekly Link Newsletter</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-07-21-newsletter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-07-21-newsletter/</guid><description>It’s official: I’ve joined the newsletter trend in earnest. I’ve had a newsletter for a few months now, but I wasn’t sure what to really do with it. Fortunately, I realized what I love to see the most from some of my favorite newsletters is links to what these authors are reading this week—little jewels from internet wanderings.
My re-launched Dill and Fennel newsletter will have links to some of the more interesting or funny things I’ve seen in the previous week.</description><content:encoded><p>It’s official: I’ve joined the newsletter trend in earnest. I’ve had<a href="https://dillandfennel.substack.com">a newsletter</a> for a few months now, but I wasn’t sure what to really<em>do</em> with it. Fortunately, I realized what I love to see the most from some of my<a href="https://craigmod.com/roden/">favorite</a><a href="https://desert.glass">newsletters</a> is links to what these authors are reading this week—little jewels from internet wanderings.</p><p>My re-launched Dill and Fennel newsletter will have links to some of the more interesting or funny things I’ve seen in the previous week. Sometimes these may be links to books, or tweets with a little color commentary. If you read this site, you might enjoy<a href="https://dillandfennel.substack.com/subscribe?utm_source=menu&amp;simple=true&amp;next=https%3A%2F%2Fdillandfennel.substack.com%2F">subscribing</a>.</p><h2 id="this-site">This site</h2><p>I’ll still write here as often as I can, but I found myself wanting a quicker way to write weekly, without needing a<em>big</em> thing to blog about, or something to review. My monthly media diets will still be posted to brookshelley.com as well. It’s been fun to do tiny reviews of books and movies, even if it’s mostly for my own memory of what I consumed in a year. Not using Letterboxed or Goodreads for this was a very conscious decision—I want to own and control my own data. If you keep track of this kind of stuff yourself, or run your own little slice of the internet, I’d love to<a href="mailto:brookshelley@gmail.com">hear about it</a>!</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>iPadOS</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-06-09-ios13/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-06-09-ios13/</guid><description>It’s probably clear by now that I love my iPad Pro. I travel with it, write on it, and practice Japanese on it. When Apple announced iPadOS, it suddenly seemed liked my dream of only using my iPad had come true.
Major updates New home screen With a glance at the home screen, it’s clear that this isn’t iOS 12. Onscreen widgets isn’t exactly revolutionary, but it saves me a slide-over every time I want to check the weather, or which meeting I’m headed to next.</description><content:encoded><p>It’s probably clear by now that I<em>love</em> my iPad Pro. I<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/blog/2019/03/13/travel-kit-update.html">travel</a> with it,<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/blog/2019/05/02/On-Notes-and-ToDos.html">write on it</a>, and<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/blog/2019/01/27/learning-kanji-again.html">practice Japanese</a> on it. When Apple announced<a href="https://www.apple.com/ipados/ipados-preview/">iPadOS</a>, it suddenly seemed liked my dream of only using my iPad had come true.</p><h2 id="major-updates">Major updates</h2><h3 id="new-home-screen">New home screen</h3><p>With a glance at the home screen,<img src="/photos/ipadhome.jpg" alt="photo of home screen with slide-over widgets"> it’s clear that this isn’t iOS 12. Onscreen widgets isn’t exactly revolutionary, but it saves me a slide-over every time I want to check the weather, or which meeting I’m headed to next. It’s pretty cool, and even though it’s in some ways a catch-up to what other platforms have had for a while, I dig it.</p><h3 id="copy--paste--select">Copy &amp; paste &amp; select</h3><p>Copy and pasting also get a refresh in iPadOS, with three-finger gestures copying, cutting, and pasting. I’m not sure how<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/6/18654314/apple-ipad-os-ipados-wwdc-first-look-windows-usb-user-interface-new-features">intuitive it is</a>, but for power-users at least, it should work quite well. I’ve gotten somewhat used to the gestures already. Multiple taps allow for some cool selection specificity, though occasionally this feels more frustrating as I struggle to remember how many taps to select a word. I think this will get better with practice</p><h3 id="swipe-to-type">Swipe to type</h3><p>Ever since I started practicing kanji for an hour or two every day, I noticed I was getting repetitive strain on my thumb and hand. I’m not sure how much this new swipe-to-type will help, but I’m enjoying the faster typing it enables.</p><h3 id="desktop-safari">Desktop Safari</h3><p>This single change is the reason iPadOS is a massive update for so many of us. Desktop versions of websites mean I can finally use Google Docs, or Notion, or Figma without pulling out my MacBook Pro at work. In testing, it seems like it<a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/6/4/18652163/google-docs-ipad-ipados-safari-apple-wwdc-2019">really works</a>, which rules. The first version of the OS just launched, so I’d expect we might see even better support between now and the launch of the OS in the fall.</p><h3 id="sign-in-with-apple">Sign-in with Apple</h3><p>This sign-in upgrade will come to iPad and iPhone, and is an amazing privacy boost for everyone using an iOS device. By removing the need to give your email address to every service I use, Apple is potentially saving me hundreds of unsubscribes and delete from inbox actions, not to mention all the scraping and ad targeting. I’m very stoked.</p><h2 id="minor-changes">Minor changes</h2><h3 id="dark-mode">Dark mode</h3><p>I love dark mode, don’t get me wrong, but this update is a small change compared to the rest of the amazing stuff packed into iPadOS.</p><h3 id="files-updates">Files updates</h3><p>Column view, quick actions, more metadata, and a downloads folder all mean better file management without a desktop. Apple also added the ability to use thumb drives and hard drives in the USB-C drive, which isn’t really something I need, but seems to be a big deal to a lot of folks.</p><h3 id="the-rest">The rest</h3><p><a href="https://www.apple.com/ipados/ipados-preview/features/">The list goes on and on</a></p><h2 id="what-it-means-for-me">What it means for me</h2><p>With iPad OS, I can’t think of a single thing I do on my Mac that I can’t do on my iPad with the exception of working with a very large Github repo (just try downloading and updating a 6gb repo over WiFi, yow). With the addition of Catalyst apps on Mac, I hope that even more developers will devote energy to making powerful and fun iPad apps in the future. This fall will likely bring device updates with minor spec bumps, and likely this time I’ll snag a Cellular version so I can take advantage of<a href="https://support.google.com/fi/answer/6330195?hl=en">Google Fi’s data sim</a>. Until now I’ve always been fine with tethering my iPad to my phone, but international travel makes that impossible due to Google’s restrictions, and since it’s essentially a free add-on, it seems like a no-brainer.</p><p>As of this year, I carry my iPad to most meetings, and almost always bring it instead of my Mac on trips—even for work. This new OS ensures that this will keep being the case. Macs will keep being a great option for my desk at work, but more and more, the iPad and the iPhone are where I prefer to do my computing.</p><p>If you haven’t checked out an iPad in a while, this fall will be a really good time to do so. You might not love it as much as I do, but it might surprise you.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>On the perfect thing</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-05-27-on-the-perfect-thing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-05-27-on-the-perfect-thing/</guid><description>The search for the best, most optimized, beautiful, light, and pleasing things.
Why do we search? Scrolling through my RSS feeds, I’m reminded daily that so much stuff exists. I subscribe to newsletters for fashion, backpacks, apps, and general tech, and every single one has an endless march through the days of new things. This app has two columns for editing! This backpack is “able to transition from work to play and travel.</description><content:encoded><p>The search for the best, most optimized, beautiful, light, and pleasing things.</p><h2 id="why-do-we-search">Why do we search?</h2><p>Scrolling through my RSS feeds, I’m reminded daily that so much<em>stuff</em> exists. I subscribe to newsletters for fashion, backpacks, apps, and general tech, and every single one has an endless march through the days of new things. This<a href="https://www.macstories.net/reviews/ulysses-16-adds-powerful-split-view-editing-on-ipad-plus-ghost-publishing/">app</a> has<em>two columns</em> for editing! This<a href="https://www.carryology.com/liking/industry/best-new-gear-march-2019/">backpack</a> is “able to transition from work to play and travel.”<a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/bombas-socks-review">These</a> are the<em>best socks</em>.</p><p>I could go on.</p><p>The search for the best thing is best represented by the website<a href="https://thewirecutter.com">The Wirecutter</a>, with its incredibly thorough reviews of the<em>best</em> things in almost every category you can imagine. Started by<a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brian_Lam">a guy</a> and his friends to get out of the grind of tech reporting, they began to painstakingly investigate categories of tech, gear, and housewares to recommend one thing you could buy. My friend’s homes are filled with these<em>best</em> things. Hell, mine is too. They’re right most of the time, save for when taste or niche need intervenes. But why do we care?</p><p>Supposedly,<a href="https://www.fastcompany.com/3043858/the-science-of-why-you-should-spend-your-money-on-experiences-not-thing">experiences make us happier than stuff</a>, but we still buy a good amount of stuff. Talking with friends, it seems like most of us like to think we’re getting a deal—by buying the<em>best</em> thing, we’re ensuring that our dollar goes furthest. The single thing we’re buying is categorically superior, and knowing that means we can stop looking, secure in the knowledge that we’ve made the<em>right decision</em>. And yet, I still browse these sites.</p><p>There’s a sense, at least for me, that something could be better. A new thing might suit my needs, or a specific complaint better. Yes, I have a raincoat, but do I have one I can wear near a campfire? Actually,<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/blog/2019/04/08/minimal-travel-clothing.html#jacket">yes, yes I do</a>. In an effort to be minimal in my ownership of things, I’ve also bought quite a few of them. The irony is not lost on me.</p><h2 id="the-happiness-factor">The happiness factor</h2><p>Honestly, I own three backpacks, and three raincoats, because each of them is the<em>best</em> at some aspect of making me smile. There’s no way to quantify this that I’m aware of, but everyone has a thing, or things that are so neat or personal that every use or interaction with them is a small joy. And we all want to<a href="https://konmari.com/products/spark-joy">spark joy</a>, right? As hokey as I’m sure many of you think Konmari’s Shinto-sequel philosophy of things is, it has certainly helped me in pinpointing why I own them. I pared back my clothing, and donated bags of tech detritus. And yet, I still look for new joys.</p><p>Whether it’s a new iOS text editor, or a new pair of lightweight shoes, I browse through my RSS feeds with a delight in seeing fresh things. And fortunately, the delight of looking is relatively free. This daily routine of mine is akin to the window-shopping of old. I’m fascinated by the portrayal of the new things—the praises of their qualities. The search itself makes me happy.</p><h2 id="hobby-hunting">Hobby hunting</h2><p>I’ve found it’s useful to check in every so often on why I do things. Do my habits make me happy? Do I find joy in studying 漢字 every day? Lifting weights? Lightweight packing? Is my search fo the best things also a way to hunt for new hobbies? The answer, for me, to all of those questions is a yes. And frankly I don’t think there’s anything particularly wrong with this search. I do wish that this curiosity could be de-coupled from capitalism, but the world we live in doesn’t seem to wish for the same thing. I think the best we can do is keep on searching if it makes us happy, and share the things we find and the things we own with each other—sharing the joy as well.</p><p>We might all search for our own reasons, but curiosity and interest is a one of the best things of all. When we find satisfaction, the key, I think, is recognizing it, and enjoying it. Until then, happy hunting.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>On notes and todos</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-05-02-on-notes-and-todos/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-05-02-on-notes-and-todos/</guid><description>The latest episode of Supercomputer inspired me to write about how I work with notes, todos, and reminders every day. Part of the episode was centered on their mutual dissatisfaction with various notes apps, which I totally understand. Over the years, I&amp;rsquo;ve used NVAlt, 1Writer, Bear, Evernote, Notes, and more to keep track of my thoughts, posts, and notes. Brett Terpstra keeps a very good list of all iOS text editors that includes information about their cross-platform functionality.</description><content:encoded><p><img src="/photos/iAWriter.png" alt="iawriter"/><p>The<a href="https://supercomputer.transistor.fm/#">latest episode of Supercomputer</a> inspired me to write about how I work with notes, todos, and reminders every day. Part of the episode was centered on their mutual dissatisfaction with various notes apps, which I totally understand. Over the years, I&rsquo;ve used<a href="https://brettterpstra.com/projects/nvalt/">NVAlt</a>, 1Writer, Bear, Evernote, Notes, and more to keep track of my thoughts, posts, and notes. Brett Terpstra keeps a<a href="https://brettterpstra.com/ios-text-editors/"><em>very good list</em></a> of all iOS text editors that includes information about their cross-platform functionality. These days, since I mostly use my iPad and iPhone when I&rsquo;m not at<a href="https://slack.com/">work</a>, it&rsquo;s vital that my notes and todo apps live happily on Mac, and iOS.</p><h2 id="notes-and-posts">Notes and posts</h2><p>Ever since I moved most of my personal computer work to an<a href="http://www.brookshelley.com/blog/2018/11/07/new-ipad-review.html">iPad Pro</a>, I&rsquo;ve wanted to make sure my notes and writing were easily accessible from wherever I happened to compute. I also wanted to post that writing to my<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com">blog</a> which hilariously I first talked about on my now abandoned<a href="https://medium.com/@brookshelley/why-i-built-a-markdown-book-blog-a07e1a6dd163">Medium</a>. Since I post things via Github pages, which is a near-as-makes-no-difference Jekyll instance, I need the ability to push markdown to Github. With<a href="https://workingcopyapp.com/">Working Copy</a>, this is super simple, and if I need to, I can write entire posts in the pretty nice editor that app contains. But, I want more!</p><p>To have a great writing experience, with delightful fonts, a pleasing design, and speedy sync, I use<a href="https://ia.net/writer">iAWriter</a>. It&rsquo;s<em>fantastic</em> for notes, long form writing, and even markdown previewing work docs. In the years since the first version of iAWriter launched, it&rsquo;s become an amazing piece of software. I couldn&rsquo;t find the earliest versions, but<a href="https://www.macworld.com/article/2985482/ia-writer-3-0-1-review-mac-app-gets-back-to-basics-for-focused-writing.html">here&rsquo;s the 2015 version 3</a>. Nowadays, iAWriter can talk to the Files app on iOS natively, which means you can open files from Working Copy, which is registered as a Files location, so you can open files from Github repos in iAWriter. Whether I&rsquo;m drafting a blog post, or updating my list of<a href="http://www.brookshelley.com/books">books</a> that I&rsquo;ve read, I open iAWriter first, after pulling the latest version of my repo in Working Copy. For writing and notes I don&rsquo;t plan to store in my repo, iAWriter keeps them on iCloud as<code>.md</code> files so I don&rsquo;t have to worry about portability or missing files. Because these files live in iCloud, they&rsquo;re searchable using Spotlight on both my iOS and Mac devices—no more depending on launching an app to search. It&rsquo;s wild how good this app combination is, and how fast I&rsquo;m able to find and edit things using iAWriter&rsquo;s native Apple integrations.</p><p>When I&rsquo;m at meetings at work, I also tend to take notes with a<a href="https://www.lamy.com/en/lamy-safari/">pen</a> and a<a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2019/all_about/weeks/">notebook</a> because it<a href="https://www.npr.org/2016/04/17/474525392/attention-students-put-your-laptops-away">helps retention</a> and looks quite a bit less rude to my coworkers or partners. If something needs to be shared, I type it up in Slack or put it in a Readme on a repo.</p><p>But what about my todos?!</p><h2 id="todos">Todos</h2><p>I work at a company in San Francisco who&rsquo;s goal is to &ldquo;make work life simpler, more pleasant and more productive.&rdquo; I think we&rsquo;re good at it, but I&rsquo;ve found that I need a separate place to keep track of my work tasks, my life tasks, and all the random junk I need quick access to when I&rsquo;m going through my week.<a href="https://culturedcode.com/things/">Things</a> is that app for me. I made a Project for everything I work on, and Areas for things like &ldquo;stuff to buy&rdquo; or &ldquo;stuff to watch&rdquo;.</p><p><img src="/photos/projects.png" alt="projects"/><p>My main view is Today, where tasks I need to finish by bedtime live. When the workday ends, anything I haven&rsquo;t accomplished gets moved to tomorrow—this is a conscious choice over having those tasks follow me home. That means that I don&rsquo;t have the psychic dread of &ldquo;more work&rdquo;, but can still look at Things for things like the code to my therapist&rsquo;s office, or a reminder to scoop the cat litter. I love it. Things is the perfect example of just heavy enough feature-wise to handle power-users while only exposing simple features for everyone else. The search is amazing, especially on Mac, where all you need to do is<em>start typing</em>. Sure, there&rsquo;s no location-based reminders, but honestly at a certain point,<em>in my opinion</em> you&rsquo;re just faffing around and avoiding work by adding so many layers to your todo process. Get shit done instead of doing loads of metalwork.</p><h2 id="keeping-track-of-all-of-the-things">Keeping track of all of the things</h2><p>For me, writing and notes goes in iAWriter, and anything I need to<em>do</em> goes into Things. Sometimes my tasks include a link to a relevant Slack conversation, or email in Spark, or website—and other times it&rsquo;s just a note to take some medicine or drop mail off in the mailbox. My projects groupings mean I know historically what I&rsquo;ve accomplished in various areas or work things, and I don&rsquo;t stress too much planning months in the future. Planning, at least at work, is often a team effort, and there&rsquo;s a calendar or a roadmap that I don&rsquo;t need to duplicate in Things. I note what my responsibilities are, and set due dates or targets for those, and leave the rest to where my work actually lives—Slack. If you want to dive more into GTD or w/e, I recommend<a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20190401160435/http://www.43folders.com/2004/09/08/getting-started-with-getting-things-done">43 Folders</a>, which is possibly now disavowed by Merlin, but is still a very smart look at productivity. Generally, simple systems work well for me, and if I look at something, I should either store it, trash it, or use it.</p><p>My systems are super helpful for<em>me</em>, but might not work, or work differently for you. That&rsquo;s totally ok! Hopefully something here was helpful or interesting, and if not, feel free to browse away, and forget~ Work will always be here for you, like a strange nightmare, and how you choose to tackle it is a personal decision.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Formula 1</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-04-13-formula-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-04-13-formula-1/</guid><description>When I mention my love of Formula 1 racing, most of the time I hear, &amp;ldquo;is that like NASCAR?&amp;rdquo; This speaks to the sad lack of F1 information and excitement in the states, and it&amp;rsquo;s a bummer. NASCAR is a sport in its own right, but comparing it to F1 is a bit like comparing rotary phones to an iPhone. F1 is fast, the roads twist this way and that, and most importantly the drivers are from across the globe.</description><content:encoded><p>When I mention my love of Formula 1 racing, most of the time I hear, &ldquo;is that like NASCAR?&rdquo; This speaks to the sad lack of F1 information and excitement in the states, and it&rsquo;s a bummer. NASCAR is a sport in its own right, but comparing it to F1 is a bit like comparing rotary phones to an iPhone. F1 is fast, the roads twist this way and that, and most importantly the drivers are from across the globe. Drama between these drivers, these princes of speed, is often even more entertaining than the drama on the track. With the launch of<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Formula_1:_Drive_to_Survive">Netflix&rsquo;s F1 documentary</a> that covers the events of the 2018 season, my hope is more folks in the states will get excited about the best racing series in the world.</p><h2 id="my-history-with-racing">My history with racing</h2><p>When I was a kid, my uncle was involved in car racing as a pit crew member, and occasional pit chief. He&rsquo;d gotten his start racing motorcycles in the 70s and early 80s, and by the time he&rsquo;d moved away, I&rsquo;d been to a number of CART and Grand Prix races around Dallas. My whole family loved cars. I grew up around Mustangs being worked-on, oil changes, and DIY repairs. I rode a small motorcycle as a kid I inherited from that same uncle who raced and wrenched on cars, and fell deeply in love with speed.</p><p>We watched a few racing series when I was younger, but my attention span meant nothing really stuck. Years later, that changed.</p><h2 id="watching-weekly">Watching weekly</h2><p>After college, I settled into a tech career and had relatively low-key weekends full of TV and reading. The exact impetus escapes me (it was probably Top Gear related), but at one point, I found a way to stream F1 races every week. My new routine was watching the qualification rounds on Saturday, and then watching an F1 race the next day. I was quickly sucked into the dramatic rise of Sebastian Vettel, who seemed to be incapable of failure as he racked-up victories in the Red Bull F1 car. I loved watching Jenson Button, who seemed like a charming enough fellow, and Kimi Raikonnenn, who&rsquo;s dry wit, and sour temperament was weirdly hilarious.</p><p>The modern era of F1 is largely ruled by three teams:</p><pre><code>- [Mercedes](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mercedes-Benz_in_Formula_One): Hamilton &amp; Bottas (Formerly Rosberg)
- [Red Bull](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Red_Bull_Racing): Verstapen &amp; Gasly (Formerly both Ricciardo &amp; Vettel)
- [Ferrari](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scuderia_Ferrari#Domination_in_the_early_2000s): Vettel &amp; LeClerc (Formerly Schumacher &amp; Raikonnen)</code></pre><p>These teams have huge budgets, some of the best drivers, and a cutthroat ability to rule the front positions of almost every race. It&rsquo;s a little frustrating that for the most part, other teams don&rsquo;t win unless there&rsquo;s a big wreck or engine failure, but at least at times the competition between these three is heated.</p><p>If you&rsquo;ve watched the<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Formula_1:_Drive_to_Survive">Netflix documentary</a>, you won&rsquo;t have seen too much about these top teams, as Mercedes and Ferrari declined to participate. But, what you did see was the exciting race to be best-of-the-rest, and a very optimistic goal for Renault or HAAS to become the 3rd or 4th place team one day. Rules changes may eventually help even the field, but until then,<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HurubWM67MM">even back markers can cause a ruckus</a>.</p><h2 id="hope-for-the-future">Hope for the future</h2><p>With a launch of a<a href="https://wseries.com">women&rsquo;s race series</a> that has the stated goal of &ldquo;[giving] remarkable female drivers an opportunity in motorsport that simply hasn’t been available to them before now&rdquo;, I seriously hope one day we&rsquo;ll have a female F1 driver. It&rsquo;s fun enough to watch 20 guys race, but watching a few women shake things up would be incredible. I want young girls to dream of racing at 300km/h and have it be a real possibility. The<a href="https://wseries.com/races/hockenheim/">first race</a> of this rad new series is May 4th, and I can&rsquo;t wait to watch.</p><p>In a different direction, there&rsquo;s an all electric racing series called<a href="https://www.fiaformulae.com/en/championship/teams-and-drivers">Formula E</a>. Due to battery constraints, and I think to make for an exciting race, teams change cars mid-race, and there&rsquo;s odd bonuses to speed that fans can vote on. I&rsquo;ve watched a few of these races, and while I&rsquo;m glad to see a more eco-friendly race start to gain steam, it definitely feels like the neglected little brother of F1 at this point. Perhaps in the future, this race will have its own cache.</p><h2 id="getting-started">Getting started</h2><p>There are a<a href="https://www.techradar.com/news/2019-f1-live-stream-how-to-watch-every-grand-prix-online-from-anywhere">lot</a> of<a href="https://www.strikeout.nu/formula-1">ways</a> to<a href="https://formula1-live.stream">watch</a><a href="http://stream.nbcsports.com/f1/">F1</a><a href="https://f1tv.formula1.com/en/">racing</a>. Some of them are questionable legal, but Formula 1 has it&rsquo;s own<a href="https://www.formula1.com/en/subscribe-to-f1-tv.html#en">streaming plan</a>, which is probably the easiest way to watch if you don&rsquo;t mind spending a little money. Racing series might not be for you, but I hope if you do love it, you share it with folks. It&rsquo;s a cool, weird sport.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Minimal travel clothing</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-04-08-minimal-travel-clothing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-04-08-minimal-travel-clothing/</guid><description>Ten or so years ago, I realized I hated bringing heavy bags with me everywhere I traveled, so I slimmed down my packing to fit in one small backpack. My wardrobe generally cycles between a few pieces, so it wasn’t much of a stretch to adapt it to a month in Japan or Berlin. I usually write a post-trip gear update, but today is all about clothing.
What’re you wearing? Whether it’s a one week or one month-long trip, I bring the same things each time Including what I’m wearing during the flight, here’s the breakdown:</description><content:encoded><p>Ten or so years ago, I realized I hated bringing heavy bags with me everywhere I traveled, so I slimmed down my packing to fit in one<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/blog/2018/05/17/review-invisible-one-mini.html">small backpack</a>. My wardrobe generally cycles between a few pieces, so it wasn’t much of a stretch to adapt it to a month in<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/blog/2019/03/13/travel-kit-update.html">Japan</a> or Berlin. I usually write a post-trip gear update, but today is all about clothing.</p><h2 id="whatre-you-wearing">What’re you wearing?</h2><p>Whether it’s a one week or one month-long trip, I bring the same things each time Including what I’m wearing during the flight, here’s the breakdown:</p><ul><li>3 pairs of<a href="#underwear">underwear</a></li><li>2<a href="#shirts">shirts</a></li><li>2 sports<a href="#underwear">bras</a></li><li>2 pairs of wool<a href="#shoes">socks</a></li><li>1 water-resistant<a href="#jacket">hoodie</a></li><li>(weather-optional) 1<a href="#jacket">jacket</a></li><li>1 pair of<a href="#shoes">shoes</a></li><li>1 pair of<a href="#pants">pants</a></li><li>1 pair of shorts or<a href="#pants">leggings</a></li></ul><p>None of the stuff I wear is particularly cheap, or particularly expensive, but on the whole, it’s held up well to lots of abuse, and many washes. The key to bringing very little clothing is a willingness to wash your clothes in the sink or shower while you bathe. If you find a washing machine, by all means, take advantage of it, but these clothes dry pretty quickly, and I prefer not to hope for something automated. If something gets destroyed (only happened once with some jeans), I can usually find a replacement, but taking stock before a trip of any of your clothing that’s in danger of ripping is a great plan.</p><h2 id="tops-a-nameshirtsa">Tops</h2><p>Day or night, the tops I wear look pretty good, wick sweat ok, and tend to hold up to a day of hiking. I spent a while only wearing wool, but recently got stoked on a few other shirts. Sadly, Ryu doesn’t make the wool shirt I wear anymore, but there are a bunch of brands making wool shirts these days, so have a look around if that appeals to you.</p><p>Usually, if it’s hot or I plan to layer, I wear a<a href="https://ryu.com/shop/us/women/tops/standard-issue-racerback-tank">tank top</a>. No sleeves means no pit stains, and with a hoodie you’re pretty set regardless of the modesty required in a temple or other spot. I’ve had good luck with Ryu and Lucy (though they’ve been bought by North Face, and I don’t know how good they are anymore). Arcteryx used to make a cool wool tank, but they make<a href="https://arcteryx.com/us/en/shop/womens/a2b-scoop-neck-shirt-ss">this</a> now, and if it’s the same fabric, it’s great!</p><p>A friend convinced me to try out these<a href="https://jungmaven.com/collections/hemp-core-tees-tshirt-womens/products/hemp-shirt-ojai-tee-short-sleeve-womens?variant=22065464279088">hemp shirts</a>, and for the first time in years, I wear a few colors. They’re super light, super soft, and don’t get stinky after a few wears.</p><p>I wear one of these shirts while I’m sleeping, and one during the day, and kinda rotate them around. If I’m gone for longer I might bring 2 shirts and a tank top, so I don’t have to wash as much.</p><h2 id="bottoms-a-namepantsa">Bottoms</h2><p>Most of the time I wear<a href="https://www.outdoorvoices.com/products/rectrek-pant?variant=34894684485">Outdoor Voices RecTrek pants</a>, which are comfy, stretchy, and cute. They run out of sizes all the time or I’d have a couple pairs. They dress up for the office ok, but also handle a<em>lot</em> of walking. Since I can’t find another black XL pair, I am currently trying out<a href="https://coalatree.com/collections/apparel/products/slim-fit-trailhead-pants-black">another brand</a>. These Coalatree pants are also pretty great, though the tie at the bottom of each leg is kinda ridiculous. They’re unisex, which means the fit might be weird, but they’ve also got a<em>ergonomic crotch gusset</em> a la<a href="https://www.artofmanliness.com/articles/chuck-norris-action-jeans/">Chuck Norris action jeans</a>. I don’t know<em>why</em> you’d do tons of high kicks in pants, but either of these pairs would handle them with gusto.</p><p>You probably already have your preferred brand of legging, but for me, I’m usually wearing either<a href="https://ryu.com/shop/us/women/bottoms/cardio-tights">Ryu</a> or<a href="https://www.girlfriend.com/collections/leggings/products/black-compressive-high-rise-legging">Girlfriend</a>. I’ve heard great things about Outdoor Voices leggings, but I’m waiting until I destroy a few more old pairs before I try them. For night time, leggings or<a href="https://www.foxers.com/black-tomboy-boxer-brief/">Foxers</a> are great for wandering around my Airbnb or hotel room.</p><h2 id="underwear-a-nameunderweara">Underwear</h2><p>Breathable, light, comfortable, and durable is the name of the game for underwear. I’m always on the search for a pair that hits all four targets. Thus far, some have done ok, but most aren’t that durable. A better pair I tried were<a href="https://knix.com/collections/underwear/products/athletic-bikini">Knix</a>, which were super comfy, but eventually blew up. Sometimes I bring<a href="https://www.meundies.com/products/womens-bikini">MeUndies</a>, but they too tend to fall apart too soon. These wool<a href="https://www.patagonia.com/product/womens-active-briefs-underwear/32396.html?dwvar_32396_color=BLK&amp;cgid=socks-underwear#tile-7=&amp;start=1&amp;sz=24">Patagonia briefs</a> were alright. I feel like I’ll be on the hunt indefinitely, but maybe a few pairs of one of these will do if for you. All three are comfortable, and dry fast, but the Knix and Patagonia pairs are better for sweaty hikes as the MeUndies tend to get a little swamped.</p><p>Three pairs of underwear might seem like too few, and feel free to adjust as necessary, but by and large: one to wear, one to wash, one that’s dry. This motto means you’re almost always set for two days, and worst case, you can dry a pair on the outside of your bag while hiking. The Knix and Patagonia briefs dry in only a few hours, so you could wash before breakfast, and come back, coffee in hand to some clean drawers.</p><p>For bras, I stick to sports bras from Pact or Calvin Klein. I hate underwrites, and sports bras last a lot longer between washes.</p><h2 id="jacket-a-namejacketa">Jacket</h2><p>Your mileage may vary heavily on style and need for this category, but my go-tos always include the<a href="https://missionworkshop.com/products/the-torre-womens-high-performance-windpro-hoodie-jacket">Torre Wind Pro</a>. I recently bought a second one of these, and even though I think Mission Workshop is getting rid of their women’s line (boo hiss), this is an incredible hoodie. It is DWR coated so light rain just falls off, and also fleece-lined so by itself I can handle temperatures down to 8c/46f. Colder or wetter, and I bring an overcoat. The two coats in my rotation right now are the<a href="https://www.arcteryx.com/us/en/shop/womens/codetta-coat">Arcteryx Codetta</a> and the<a href="https://snowpeak.com/products/jk-18au004-fr-rain-trench?variant=13074792972386">Snow Peak FR Rain Trench</a> (which is also<em>fireproof</em>?!). Good layering means even at freezing temperatures, I do well. If it was super cold, I’d probably include a wool sweater to wear under or over my hoodie, and I’d throw my leggings on under my pants.</p><h2 id="shoes-and-socks-a-nameshoesa">Shoes and socks</h2><p><a href="https://bombas.com/products/women-s-solid-invisibles-tan-small?variant=black">Bombas</a> or Darn Tough are the way to go for socks. Most of the time it’s not cold enough to wear longer socks, so I wear no-shows or ankle socks. Wool means these also wick well, and wash easily—depending on your food funk, a couple days is usually fine between washes.</p><p>If it’s cold or wet, I’m wearing<a href="https://www.blundstone.com/shop/black-premium-leather-chelsea-boots-womens-style-558">Blundstones</a>, or<a href="https://www.adidas.com/us/stan-smith-shoes/M20327.html">Stan Smiths</a>. Summer means something light and knit like<a href="https://www.adidas.com/us/samba-sock-primeknit-shoes/CQ2218.html">these Sambas</a>. Lightweight, comfortable, and breathable means you only need one pair of shoes. If they’re black, even sneakers work in many slightly fancy situations. In my opinion, sandals should only show up in a public shower, or on the beach, so I never bring any.</p><h2 id="hat">Hat</h2><p>A wool beanie is great for warmth, so I wear<a href="https://www.tannergoods.com/products/merino-watch-cap">this one from Tanner Goods</a>. It’s expensive, but it holds up.</p><h2 id="plan-ahead">Plan ahead</h2><p>All of my clothing works well for me, but I typically go to Europe or Japan. If you go somewhere much hotter or much colder, you’ll definitely need to adjust, especially if you go from a freezing spot to a hot one. If you end up bringing a lot of stuff for one leg of a trip, you can always mail stuff home too. Layering is your friend. There’re a lot of<a href="https://www.carryology.com/travel/how-what-to-put-in-your-minimalist-travel-capsule-wardrobe/">lists for women</a> that have much more feminine clothing, but that’s not really my jam. For me, functional > cute any day of the week. But, regardless of your style choice, stretchy, lightweight clothing is the way to go.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Learning kanji again</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-01-27-learning-kanji-again/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-01-27-learning-kanji-again/</guid><description>My first Japanese class In 1996 I took my first Japanese class at Austin Community College. I was in middle school at the time, and decided to learn how to read Japanese so I could read literature and comics. The class was fun, and also super weird, since I was the only kid there. I took two semesters, but a lot of life happened at once, so I stopped taking Japanese, and didn’t being again until University, five years later.</description><content:encoded><p><img src="/photos/kanji.jpg" alt="kanji"/><h2 id="my-first-japanese-class">My first Japanese class</h2><p>In 1996 I took my first Japanese class at Austin Community College. I was in middle school at the time, and decided to learn how to read Japanese so I could read literature and comics. The class was fun, and also super weird, since I was the only kid there. I took two semesters, but a lot of life happened at once, so I stopped taking Japanese, and didn’t being again until University, five years later. We used the<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Yookoso-Invitation-Contemporary-Japanese-Learning/dp/0072971207">Yookoso!</a> textbook, and I crammed when I needed to. Outside of watching tv, barely had any practice outside of class. I wanted to visit Japan really bad, but for the time, paying rent was hard enough.</p><h2 id="post-college-life">Post-college life</h2><p>Eventually, I made it to Tokyo—Narita airport a few times, and finally to the city itself. I was both surprised how much I remembered, and depressed at how little I could read. It made sense though. I hadn’t studied in earnest in years, and I can’t say rote memorization was ever my strong suite. I started going to Japan a bit more regularly, and tried to practice, but focused on speaking over anything else. This eventually became more frustrating, because while I could type into Google translate, I never quite knew if the Kanji was correct. Izakayas—one of my favorite places to go—were especially challenging, because outside of saying 「すみません、ぼんじりがありますか?」(Excuse me, do you have chicken tail?) with different food names I knew, ordering was a bear.</p><h2 id="buckling-down">Buckling-down</h2><p>This year I’m going back to Japan again. At the prompting of my friend Jo, who spent a while living in Japan, I dug into<a href="https://www.wanikani.com">Wanikani</a> to formalize study of kanji. I realized that I would never get better at Japanese without memorizing kanji, which would also unlock a better vocabulary. Learning any language is a wild challenge, and with ~1800 kanji to go I feel deeply skeptical that I’ll ever be fluent. I’m glad trying, and as it stands currently I’m on a four-day streak. I also signed-up for a beta app called<a href="http://kanji.garden">Kanji Garden</a>, which has a slick interface. I pushed a bit hard the first few days of using that app, and have ~180 characters I’m reviewing. I remember a decent amount from my days of college classes, but hadn’t officially learned the kon’yomi and on’yomi readings, so it feels a bit like square one.</p><h2 id="頑張って">頑張って！</h2><p>Hopefully, this time next year as I prepare to go to Japan yet another time, I feel prepared to actually read quite a bit. It seems like if I really try to study every day, I’ll make some progress. I’m hopeful, and kind of excited for a future Brook that isn’t wandering around Koenji functionally illiterate.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>2018 in Review</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-12-22-year-in-review/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-12-22-year-in-review/</guid><description>Started in Japan Last year, I hopped on a plane to Tokyo before the countdown began, and landed in the evening of the 1st of January. Making my way to my rental apartment in Koenji, the city was quiet as folks celebrated with their family. It was a strange trip. I got to do my hatsumode at Meiji Jingu with thousands of people, and see the Emperor’s second to last speech before his groundbreaking abdication next year.</description><content:encoded><h2 id="started-in-japan">Started in Japan</h2><p>Last year, I hopped on a plane to Tokyo before the countdown began, and landed in the evening of the 1st of January. Making my way to my rental apartment in Koenji, the city was quiet as folks celebrated with their family. It was a strange trip. I got to do my hatsumode at Meiji Jingu with thousands of people, and see the Emperor’s second to last speech before his groundbreaking abdication next year. Parks were closed, but fortunately, izakayas were open. My friend Magda met up with me later that week, and I showed her Tokyo, Osaka, and Kyoto. It was her first trip to Japan, and we both had a blast eating food and visiting a cool ryokan.</p><h2 id="portland-interlude">Portland (interlude)</h2><p>I spent very little time in Portland this year, it felt like. I traveled slightly less than in 2017, but between bouncing back and forth to Oakland and San Francisco for work and various trips abroad, Snorri and my Portland friends saw me half of every month. I lifted as often as I could, and competed in two internal<a href="/blog/2018/08/14/powerlifting">powerlifting</a> meets. I kept running the board of directors for Basic Rights too. But increasingly, Portland felt like the wrong place for me. When I was in town, I often found myself spending lots of time alone, cooking and eating at home, or seeing movies solo.<a href="/blog/2018/09/10/xoxo-thoughts">XOXO this year</a> was fun, but the friends I spent most of it with were all from the bay. I’d made and lost many friends, and my energy was low. I started thinking more seriously about moving to Oakland during a really busy time at work, so it took a bit for things to settle. Once they did, my company was part of Slack, and I was suddenly moving to Emeryville. I’ll miss so many of my friends in Portland, but as living halfway there and the bay for a few years taught me, it’s a quick flight.</p><h2 id="berlin">Berlin</h2><p>My partner suggested offhandedly at one point that they were going to Europe for a conference, and that it would be cool to meet up in Berlin. I bit, and immediately booked tickets. We stayed in Neukölln, near Tempelhofer Fields, and I immediately fell for the city, the Berliner Weiss, and the vibe. More than a few folks I know have since or before moved to Berlin, and despite wild bureaucratic issues, it seems like a very interesting place to live. I ate tons of döner kebab, and loved visiting LiquidRom (a place I’d described as a brutalist day spa). Mads and I had never spent that long together, and it definitely brought us closer together. I flew home happy, and looking forward to visiting again, and had just about a week in Portland before I flew off again.</p><h2 id="copenhagen">Copenhagen</h2><p>This time, I was on my way via SFO to Copenhagen with my coworkers Brian and Mark to attend and run a booth at KubeCon. It was so,<em>so</em> busy. We ate a lot of smørrebrø, worked out in an old slaughterhouse, and generally had a blast. I spent an extra week there alone, with only a couple days a bit wasted by my conference-acquired cold. Vesterbro was really cool, though I still think it’s odd how many all-you-can-eat sushi places there were. I never rode a bike, which in retrospect is super odd, but I did drink a lot of aquavit, and ate a<em>ton</em> of wienerschnitzel. This turned out to be my last international trip of the year, despite my hope that I could get back to Japan in the fall.</p><h2 id="so-many-flights-to-sfo">So many flights to SFO</h2><p>Various circumstances meant I was flying back and forth to SFO more than once a month during the summer and early fall. There were early morning flights with afternoons returning to Portland for poorly-timed obligations. There were flights with friends, and lots of solo flights. Somehow I never quite managed to get status on a single airline. Near the end of my constant flying, I was happy to learn my new company wanted me to move to the bay by the end of October, and my friend Haley helpfully found me a lovely apartment near lots of friends at the edges of Emeryville and Berkeley. I signed the lease sight-unseen, on the assurance of my partner and the video they took that it was fantastic. It was, in fact, incredible. I finished up everything I could in Portland, had movers come, and took Snorri and myself to our new home.</p><h2 id="settling-into-a-new-eville-life">Settling into a new Eville life</h2><p>I<a href="/blog/2018/11/21/moving-to-the-bay.html">wrote about moving to Emeryville</a> a while ago, and since then it’s gotten even better. I feel like I’ve settled into a schedule here that includes powerlifting, seeing friends, and taking care of my growing plant collection. A very mild fall means I get to wear all my light jackets, and my short bus commute to work led to ample time reading. It’s been great only bringing an<a href="/blog/2018/11/07/new-ipad-review">iPad Pro</a> to and from work for the past few months, and I feel lucky I get to leave my work, and work computer at the office. The holidays were better than I feared, and I got to spend time with a few friends here in the bay, as well as enjoy candles, snacks, and books in my cozy home. It also rules to finally live in the same city as my partner, and figuring out a good cadence in our hangouts has been fun, if sometimes tricky. I hope to spend many more years here.</p><h2 id="looking-towards-2019">Looking towards 2019</h2><p>I’m hopeful 2019 will lead to more books, movies, and fun times with friends and loved ones. Work is amazing, and it feels great to be at a company I really believe in, helping create a product I love using every day. I’m also staying on the board at Basic Rights, and I continue to be proud of our work in immigration rights, trans rights, and racial justice. So much of making this country a better place for everyone means small local changes, and I’m glad to be a small part of that work. I might try to compete more at powerlifting, and I definitely want to go back to Japan and Scandinavia if possible. The economy, at the time I’m writing this, looks like it’s headed towards a shit place, but I hope to keep saving money throughout the year. If everything works out, I’ll even get Snorri a new friend, so he doesn’t have to wait for me to get home from work alone every day. 2019 is another year—a fresh year to live and learn in. I’m looking forward to it.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>My favorite albums of the year</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-12-20-my-favorite-albums-of-the-year/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-12-20-my-favorite-albums-of-the-year/</guid><description>in no particular order On Apple Music
The list Dilly Dally Heaven: I listened to this amazing band’s first album so much in the three years since it came out, and the vocal delivery is raw and beautiful. A true jam.
Ex:Re Ex:Re: A delightfully sad and smart album about lost love, and healing. This was a late-arrival this year, and has already been a constant repeat.
Anna McClellan Yes and No: A similarly raw singing style to Dilly Dally, this is a bummer jam.</description><content:encoded><p><em>in no particular order</em><a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/playlist/favorites-of-2018/pl.u-PJExpCqGgBj">On Apple Music</a></p><h2 id="the-list">The list</h2><p><strong>Dilly Dally</strong><em>Heaven</em>: I listened to this amazing band’s first album so much in the three years since it came out, and the vocal delivery is raw and beautiful. A true jam.</p><p><strong>Ex:Re</strong><em>Ex:Re</em>: A delightfully sad and smart album about lost love, and healing. This was a late-arrival this year, and has already been a constant repeat.</p><p><strong>Anna McClellan</strong><em>Yes and No</em>: A similarly raw singing style to Dilly Dally, this is a bummer jam. The juxtaposition between her low, gritty voice, and when she moves into a higher register is fantastic.</p><p><strong>Gia Margaret</strong><em>There’s Always a Glimmer</em>: Continuing down the bummer album trail, Gia Margaret created a gorgeous album that combines piano, light percussion, and a hint of electronics to create an album that perfectly compliments how I feel when I’m lost in thought.</p><p><strong>The Beths</strong><em>Future Hates Me</em>: This album<em>rips</em>! Like, wow. What a fantastic, tightly instrumented, and infectious pop-punk album. This is a band to watch. It’s almost impossible not to sing along to this.</p><p><strong>The Internet</strong><em>Hive Mind</em>: This is a blessed year—right after getting a new Syd album, 2018 brings a new album from The Internet. Every track is a bop, and is a good way to come back up from some of the bummer tunes listed above.</p><p><strong>Tirzah</strong><em>Devotion</em>: This album feels stripped down to the core of Tirzah’s voice. There’s light instrumentation, and just hypnotic melodies and just enough percussion to get you going.</p><p><strong>Svalbard</strong><em>It’s Hard to Have Hope</em>: This album encapsulates so much of the pain and anger of being a woman in the 2010s. Tracks cover abortion, feminism, and a lot more. Crank this up when you’re lifting weights, or just need to feel seen for a bit.</p><p><strong>Remember Sports</strong><em>Slow Buzz</em>: More amazing pop punk from a band I’ve been repeatedly listening to from before they had to change their name to “Remember Sports”. Their lyrics crack me up sometimes, and I feel real joy listening to these tracks.</p><p><strong>Camp Cope</strong><em>How to Socialise and Make Friends</em>: This is just solid indie rock. I love the lead woman’s voice, and the songs have a punk ethos and feeling, even as they’re a bit slower paced.</p><p><strong>Sara Renberg</strong><em>Night Sands</em>: “I googled elderly lesbians to cheer myself, but the results were all porn”. The grim humor and fantastic delivery of the vocals on this album made me repeat it often. Another great “yea that’s how I’m feeling exactly!” jam.</p><p><strong>Hop Along</strong><em>Bark Your Head Off, Dog</em>: This was definitely a year for listening to gritty female vocals. I have no clue how she sings this way on tour without just shredding her throat, but also it’s so, so fucking good. Every Hop Along album has ruled, and this might be my favorite.</p><p><strong>Half Waif</strong><em>Lavender</em>: I cried to this album on planes a lot this year. Half Waif rules, and if my other picks were kinda rough, her voice might be a salve. This is<em>only her second album</em> and there’s already so much depth.</p><p><strong>Soccer Mommy</strong><em>Clean</em>: Another really, really pretty and sad album. The vibe of this album is so perfect for Fall.</p><p><strong>Let’s Eat Grandma</strong><em>I’m All Ears</em>: This music makes me dance. I got to see them perform earlier this year, and even in Portland, people were getting down. It’s also super clear the women in this band are just stoked to be making these jams.</p><p><strong>Tancred</strong><em>Nightstand</em>: One of the gayer albums I loved this year. At times she reminds me of PJ Harvey, or Fiona Apple. The phrasing and style of her delivery is pitch-perfect.</p><hr><h2 id="a-note-on-listening-this-year">A note on listening this year</h2><p>This isn’t a comprehensive list of what I listened to by any means, and by switching to Apple Music partway through the year, my listening is fractured in a way that’s hard to glue together. Music at home often happens on my Sonos, and still gets sent to Last.fm, I think, but anything on mobile (most of my time) is mostly locally stored as history.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>2018 iPad Pro Review</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-11-07-new-ipad-review/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-11-07-new-ipad-review/</guid><description>Today my phone buzzed to tell me my new iPad had arrived at my office. I rushed down to the mailroom, and eagerly ripped open the packaging. For a few years I’ve used an iPad Pro 9.7” as my primary travel computer when I didn’t need to work on Kubernetes/DevOps stuff, and I’ve loved it. Whether I was watching shows on Netflix or Plex that I’d downloaded before a flight, editing my website in Working Copy, or just editing photos and browsing Twitter, this was the machine I wanted to use.</description><content:encoded><p>Today my phone buzzed to tell me my new iPad had arrived at my office. I rushed down to the mailroom, and eagerly ripped open the packaging. For a few years I’ve used an iPad Pro 9.7” as my primary travel computer when I didn’t need to work on Kubernetes/DevOps stuff, and I’ve loved it. Whether I was watching shows on Netflix or Plex that I’d downloaded before a flight, editing my website in Working Copy, or just editing photos and browsing Twitter, this was the machine I wanted to use.</p><p>Now, I have 1.3” more screen, a more lap-capable keyboard, and 120hz refresh, and I couldn’t be happier.</p><p><img src="/photos/ipad.jpeg" alt="iPad"/><h2 id="the-screen">The screen</h2><p>This iPad might not feel like as huge of a revelation to someone who used the 10.5”, but coming from the 9.7”, this screen feels luxurious. The smooth 120hz refresh rate means opening apps, and moving around looks amazing. The color and viewing angles are still the best in the tablet world, and make my even my MacBook feel like a relic of the past. It’s responsive, bright, and a joy to watch tv on.</p><h2 id="the-case">The case</h2><p>My iPad is the Space Grey color, and it looks excellent. The industrial lines of the sides are reminiscent of my favorite iPhone, the 4. Overall the iPad feels thin, and around the weight of my 9.7” even with the added screen size, and when I have it out of the keyboard folio, I don’t want to put it down. This tablet feels great in my hands. I seriously hope that Apple brings this design language to the next generation of iPhones, even though I wonder if they can while still keeping the glass back for wireless charging.</p><h2 id="the-keyboard-folio">The keyboard folio</h2><p>My main use of the iPad is with a keyboard attached, as I use it as a laptop mostly, which sometimes becomes a handheld tablet for reading. I’m still not convinced there needed to be two viewing angles, but the stiffness and lack of weird folding means it feels pretty great in my lap or on a desk. The tablet-mode keyboard against your fingers thing is slightly odd, but it also reminds me of playing the accordion, which I find funny enough to enjoy it. The keys feel nice and responsive, and largely the same as the 9.7” keyboard. If they changed the keys, I can’t tell. I do enjoy the slightly larger size that matches the bigger device, and my mistypes are few and far-between. Clicking the iPad into the folio feels fast and easy, even if it requires slightly more lining up than previously. With the folio closed, the iPad feel grippy, and like a thin notebook in the best way. The weight and feel, in my opinion, remind you that you’re holding a high quality device. The folio adds a little thickness, but I think it only brings the device to the previous size, so I haven’t felt like it was too thick.</p><h2 id="usb-c">USB-C</h2><p>It’s great. I love using the same charger for this iPad and my MacBook. I already invested in USB-C to lighting cables, so bringing this iPad and no USB spare battery for my iPhone sounds great. I haven’t tried plugging anything weird into the port, but folks at the Verge did their damndest to stump the port.<em>Spoiler</em> it doesn’t work with printers.</p><h2 id="battery-life">Battery life</h2><p>It’s about the same as my old iPad, which is excellent.</p><h2 id="speakers">Speakers</h2><p>There’s four of them. They’re loud, and clear. A+</p><h2 id="faceid">FaceID</h2><p>Just as quick and easy as my previous iPhone X, and possibly a little slower than the XS. I can’t quite tell, but I feel a little like I’m waiting now compared to using my phone. I haven’t timed it though, but generally it’s much better and easier than the TouchID.</p><h2 id="wrap-up">Wrap-up</h2><p>This is the iPad to get—whether you get the 12.9” or the 11”, especially if you haven’t upgraded in a few years. I seriously feel like this is the future of Apple computing, and iOS 13 is sure to bring more advanced features that mean I might not need a Mac outside of my office.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Smoke gets in your eyes</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-20-smokey-skies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-20-smokey-skies/</guid><description>Due to a series of forest fires, Portland has looked like an alien planet for the past few weeks.
Every day I wake up and google &amp;ldquo;air quality&amp;rdquo; to see just how much I need to stay indoors, next to my air filter. My gym has closed for a few days for two weeks, and walking outside just plain sucks.
The only cool part is the sunsets are ridiculous, and the moon is red at night.</description><content:encoded><p>Due to a series of forest fires, Portland has looked like an alien planet for the past few weeks.</p><p><img src="/photos/aqi.png" alt="aqi search"/><p>Every day I wake up and google &ldquo;air quality&rdquo; to see just how much I need to stay indoors, next to my air filter. My gym has closed for a few days for two weeks, and walking outside just plain sucks.</p><p>The only cool part is the sunsets are ridiculous, and the moon is red at night.</p><p>I really hope these fires aren’t an every year occurrence, but I’m not that hopeful, since global warming continues apace. Guess I’ll buy more indoor air filters and a Bane mask.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Powerlifting</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-14-powerlifting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-14-powerlifting/</guid><description>Young Brook Growing up, I never wanted to be big. My parents were both over 6&amp;rsquo; tall, and I worried about being as big as them. Most of my friends ended up being shorter than me, and were usually skinnier too. I was made fun of for being &amp;ldquo;chubby&amp;rdquo; in middle school, and that stuck with me. Being fat or chubby or skinny all rule, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t know that as a kid.</description><content:encoded><h2 id="young-brook">Young Brook</h2><p>Growing up, I never wanted to be big. My parents were both over 6&rsquo; tall, and I
worried about being as big as them. Most of my friends ended up being shorter
than me, and were usually skinnier too. I was made fun of for being &ldquo;chubby&rdquo; in
middle school, and that stuck with me. Being fat or chubby or skinny all rule,
but I didn&rsquo;t know that as a kid. I just thought I was broken, bc I didn&rsquo;t have
a flat chest or whatever the other kids did at 12. I used to worry about my
weight all the time, and no matter what I ate, or didn&rsquo;t eat, I kept some
love-handles. Eventually I got used to my body, and now I love it. There&rsquo;s a
longer story there, but generally not wanting to be &ldquo;big&rdquo; kept me away from
weights, and on a bike.</p><h2 id="present-day">Present day</h2><p>I still keep track of my weight, but on a longer time-scale, and these days,
it&rsquo;s less about getting down to a number, and more in line with general
health-tracking. I did yoga regularly for around three years, but I never felt
stronger, just usually more calm, which rules too. Last summer, I read<a href="https://www.thehairpin.com/2017/08/the-myths-of-bodyweight-training/">The Myth of Bodyweight Training</a> and then a bunch of posts from Casey about powerlifting,
and thought, &ldquo;ok, I&rsquo;ll try this&rdquo;. I heard about<a href="http://boldandbadass.com">Bold &amp; Badass</a> from some<a href="https://2018.xoxofest.com">XOXO</a> friends, and went in for a session. Then I
went back, and back, and back. I took off some time last year due to an
unrelated surgery, and a trip to Japan in January, but since February, I&rsquo;ve
gone two days a week on average, with July and August being closer to three,
and four most days. It feels great, and I feel both stronger and happier while
there and on rest days. The focus and calm I found during yoga is present during
powerlifting, but I can also track progress, which I enjoy because
I&rsquo;m a nerd.</p><h2 id="wtf-is-powerlifting">WTF is &ldquo;powerlifting&rdquo;?</h2><p>Simply put: bench-pressing, squatting, and deadlifting. I usually do accessory
workouts and a lot of stuff that gets my heart-rate up for cardio health, but
those three lifts are the crux of powerlifting, and in competition, the total
of the 3 weights lifted are what your&rsquo;e judged on. It rules. There&rsquo;s so much
complexity and muscle memory involved in doing these lifts well, and it&rsquo;s
really helpful to have a trainer, and start very light. But, once you get the
hang of it, you end up lifting more than you would ever imagine.</p><h2 id="gains">Gains?</h2><p>I still remember my first sessions bench-pressing ~80lbs, squatting ~100lbs,
and deadlifting 65lbs (the bar + 10lbs on each side to lift it up). These days
I&rsquo;m very proud to be bench-pressing 175, squatting 245, and deadlifting 345.
It&rsquo;s been a<em>lot</em> of work to get to this point, but I can see the progress. My
gym is doing a summer of strength at this point, and that means a specific
linear training regimen that means each time I lift with my arms (bench/OHP),
I add 2.5lbs, and each time I lift with my legs (squat/DL), I add 5 lbs.
Once we get to a place where we can&rsquo;t do a 3rd set of 5, after first trying for
a third set of 5-10 for as many weeks as possible, we unload by 10% and start
over. It&rsquo;s freeing knowing what I&rsquo;m going to lift before I start each day, and
having the encouragement of all the awesome folks in my gym as we all strive
to improve our personal numbers. Our competition is with ourselves, largely,
and that&rsquo;s the most fun kind, in my opinion.</p><h2 id="lifting-is-silly">Lifting is silly</h2><p>I want to be clear that the benefits to my mental and physical health also come
with a new type of self-aware humor about the whole thing. Gyms are weird, and
lifting heavy stuff is particularly silly. I&rsquo;m lucky that a lot of my coworkers
also love powerlifting and Olympic weightlifting (clean &amp; jerks, and snatches),
so we can laugh even as we cheer each other on. Being able to enjoy things, and
laugh at/with them is super important to me. Plus, have you seen the long socks
for sumo? JK, they rule.</p><h2 id="getting-started">Getting started</h2><p>If you&rsquo;re stoked on lifting at all, and you&rsquo;re in Portland, come join me at
Bold &amp; Badass, or find a body-positive gym in your area. If you read this, but
still have zero interest, then&hellip; thanks for reading?</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>August shows</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-13-august-shows/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-13-august-shows/</guid><description>A few years ago, after moving to Portland, I discovered a secret: you can do almost anything alone. I&amp;rsquo;d lived in Austin for most of my life, and as I quickly learned once moving, making friends in Portland is a long process. So, on a whim, I started seeing movies by myself. I went to dinner alone with a book. I even saw concerts&amp;hellip; solo, and it was fun. I don&amp;rsquo;t know why we all think you have to do these activities with other people, but when you go alone you don&amp;rsquo;t have to wait for anyone to be ready to go, or to leave.</description><content:encoded><p>A few years ago, after moving to Portland, I discovered a secret: you can do
almost anything alone. I&rsquo;d lived in Austin for most of my life, and as I
quickly learned once moving, making friends in Portland is a long process. So,
on a whim, I started seeing movies by myself. I went to dinner alone with a
book. I even saw concerts&hellip; solo, and it was fun. I don&rsquo;t know why we all
think you have to do these activities with other people, but when you go alone
you don&rsquo;t have to wait for anyone to be ready to go, or to leave. There&rsquo;s no
coordination necessary, and if you want to talk to someone, you can always text
or use Slack. At dinner, I usually bring a book, and just relax with whatever
author I&rsquo;m reading at the time. It&rsquo;s magical.</p><p>This last weekend, I went to two shows: one alone, and one with a new friend I
met in SF at Karaoke who lives in Portland—Hi Mehan.</p><h2 id="hop-along--thin-lips">Hop Along &amp; Thin Lips</h2><p><img src="/photos/photo-2.jpeg" alt="Hop along"/><p>Friday was<a href="https://hopalong.bandcamp.com">Hop Along</a>, with<a href="https://xxthinlipsxx.bandcamp.com">Thin Lips</a> opening. I&rsquo;ve never seen either of these
Philly bands before, but they were both excellent. Thin lips is a punk-y band
with a rad queer lady lead singer, who covers chosen family, dating, and
anxiety. I&rsquo;d never heard of them before this show, but now they&rsquo;re on a regular
rotation in my headphones. Hop Along is a favorite of mine since their first
album, and Frances&rsquo; voice was incredible in person. They have a sound that&rsquo;s
difficult to discuss, so I hope you listen. Her voice is singular, and hella
powerful. I usually have at least one of their songs humming in my head any
given week while I grocery shop, or go on walks. I stood and danced a bit for
both of these bands, and in between, I read on my Kindle iOS app, when I
might&rsquo;ve made small talk. There were a LOT of couples at this show, many of
them queer, which ruled. Seeing bands is kinda cool as a date, in my
experience, because how often do you get to quietly enjoy something with a
loved one?</p><h2 id="deafheaven">Deafheaven</h2><p><img src="/photos/photo.jpeg" alt="Deafheaven"/><p>Sunday night, I saw<a href="https://deafheavens.bandcamp.com">Deafheaven</a>, who&rsquo;re kind
of &ldquo;metal for folks who don&rsquo;t like metal&rdquo;. They&rsquo;re sick, and both times I&rsquo;ve
seen them they play and sing their hearts out. Bonus points for Geroge, the
lead singer, growing out his hipster haircut into some serious 90s metal locks.
Headbanging just works better with long hair. Hung with my friend in between
sets, and made dumb jokes. The openers weren&rsquo;t really my jam, but Deafheaven
put on such a wild long set, I immediately forgot about the first hour or so of
so-so music.</p><p>I&rsquo;ve got a few more shows coming up this year, and I&rsquo;m stoked AF to see Mitski,
especially.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>The old is new again</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-11-posting-on-my-blog/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-11-posting-on-my-blog/</guid><description>Inspired by both Nick and Matt, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to try my hand at blogging again on this site. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how often I&amp;rsquo;ll post, but at least once a month, I&amp;rsquo;ll do a media dietpost, which clips out what I read and watched that month from the long lists I keep. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about other stuff too. We&amp;rsquo;ll see!
I have definitely enjoyed how Matt seems to be posting cool things there instead of Twitter, because it gives me more things to see on RSS.</description><content:encoded><p>Inspired by both<a href="https://roadrunnertwice.dreamwidth.org">Nick</a> and<a href="https://a.wholelottanothing.org">Matt</a>, I&rsquo;ve decided to try my hand at
blogging again on this site. I don&rsquo;t know how often I&rsquo;ll post, but at least
once a month, I&rsquo;ll do a<a href="/tags/mediadiet">media diet</a>post,
which clips out what I read and watched that month from the long lists I keep.
Maybe I&rsquo;ll talk about other stuff too. We&rsquo;ll see!</p><p>I have definitely enjoyed how Matt seems to be posting cool things there
instead of Twitter, because it gives me more things to see on RSS. Speaking of
which, you can subscribe to my rss feed by dropping the URL to this site into
the reader of your choice—I use<a href="http://reederapp.com/ios/">Reeder</a> with<a href="http://newsblur.com">Newsblur</a>.</p><p>There&rsquo;s something of a cool, old-school feel to writing on a blog and having it
delivered to folks daily via RSS, isn&rsquo;t there?</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Invisible One Mini backpack review</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-05-17-review-invisible-one-mini/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-05-17-review-invisible-one-mini/</guid><description>Bags are my thing. Well, bags and shoes. Traveling as much as I do, having a dependable, comfortable, and sleek bag is pretty important. For the past two or so years, I&amp;rsquo;ve depended on my Topo Designs Trip Pack for short trips, and then nested it inside of my Ryu QuickPack for longer trips abroad. This has worked out well, but walking around Copenhagen, and going through a variety of international airport security, I wondered if I could consolidate to one bag, with an easier way to access my laptop and other stuff.</description><content:encoded><p>Bags are my thing. Well, bags and shoes. Traveling as much as I do, having a dependable, comfortable, and sleek bag is pretty important. For the past two or so years, I&rsquo;ve depended on my Topo Designs Trip Pack for short trips, and then nested it inside of my Ryu QuickPack for longer trips abroad. This has worked out well, but walking around Copenhagen, and going through a variety of international airport security, I wondered if I could consolidate to one bag, with an easier way to access my laptop and other stuff. The<a href="https://www.opposethis.com/products/invisible-backpack-one-mini">Invisible One Mini</a> seemed like a great way to test this out. I was drawn to the design of the bag, and the ethos of the company: &ldquo;Each year we reiterate and improve our designs&hellip;&rdquo; which I&rsquo;ve witnessed as I&rsquo;ve watched them iterate over the years.</p><p><img src="/photos/oneminifront.jpeg" alt="One Mini photo"/><h2 id="pockets-and-zips">Pockets and zips</h2><p>My Topo Designs Trip Pack has three compartments—a main area where I can slip my laptop, a zip pouch in that main area, and a front pocket for a Kindle, notebook, etc. I found myself digging around more than I wanted to for my charger, pen, or chapstick. The Invisible One Mini has just a little more organization, and so far, it&rsquo;s made a huge difference.</p><p>The 2018 One Mini has a zipper pocket in the front, that&rsquo;s charmingly asymmetrical. A flap unzips, revealing a pocket that can hold an iPad or Kindle, a zipper-sealable area for keys, chapstick, glasses cloth, etc, and two smaller pouches. These pouches are the perfect size for a portable battery, and a Hobonichi Techo. There&rsquo;s a bit of additional space in the big zipper area for my MacBook charger as well. The entire big pouch is almost the width and heigh of the bag, but because of the clever organization, it doesn&rsquo;t feel like I&rsquo;ll lose things in it.</p><p><img src="/photos/oneminipocket.jpeg" alt="One Mini pocket"/><p>On the top of the bag, there&rsquo;s a big zipper that opens the main compartment, which I use to hold a hoodie, my water bottle, and also a small bag of underwear and clothes for travel. Because of the front organization, I don&rsquo;t need to dig in this compartment often, and only need to keep a few easy-to-find or pack-to-leave unpack-at-destination items in it. This is a big improvement over the Topo Bag.</p><p>Finally, the back of the bag has a top-loading laptop sleeve that&rsquo;s soft and felt-lined. The bottom ends a bit above the bottom of the bag, providing a little cushion area, but I still wouldn&rsquo;t want to throw this bag around with my MacBook in it. Unlike the Ryu or the Topo Designs bags, this separate laptop area means I can dig my MacBook out on the occasions I can&rsquo;t get pre-check and have my laptop scanned separately. I try my damndest to avoid these instances, but inter-Europe travel usually means pulling out all my electronics.</p><p>Previous years of this bag had weird side zips on the front and back for the laptop, a water bottle, and documents and other stuff in the front, but this version feels more usable, and less confusing at a glance. I doubt I&rsquo;ll have any trouble remembering where I put various items, or how to quickly retrieve them. Read more about the year-over-year change<a href="https://www.opposethis.com/blogs/insidethis/invisible-backpack-one-2018">here</a>.</p><h2 id="the-material">The material</h2><p>The entire bag is a light-weight 800x600D waterproof nylon-polyester blend that looks and feels pretty lux. The top handle is a rubber-ish leather-is material that&rsquo;s grippy and feels nice, and the inside of the pack straps is a soft and breathable cloth. The top of the bag is ringed with the same rubberized material, encircling the main compartment. The inside of the two front areas is a gray nylon that feels like smooth quality. All over the bag, the stitches are even and seem made for longevity. I&rsquo;ll update this review later to see how well the bag stood up to travel wear-and-tear, but so far it inspires confidence. I&rsquo;m also curious how well the rain resistance does, as only the laptop sleep area has a waterproof YKK zipper, with the other two using a more standard zip. The pulls have rubber grips, with no dangling pull cords, which means they&rsquo;re slightly more fiddly than the RYU or the Topo bags, but once I&rsquo;ve found the tab, the pull feels smooth.</p><h2 id="the-size">The size</h2><p>This is a small bag, but feels a good deal bigger than my tiny Topo Designs bag. Measuring 38cm x 34cm x 14cm (15"x13.5"x5.5&rdquo;), with a volume of 11L, and a weight of 650g (22oz), it&rsquo;s easy to throw on, but doesn&rsquo;t look dwarfed by my 5'10&rdquo; frame. It sits well on my back, and the clever straps let me cinch it up or down, while the excess strap stays tucked into itself. The main compartment is roomy enough without making the other areas of the bag feel cramped, that I feel pretty confident I could take only this bag for a few weeks abroad.</p><h2 id="wrap-up">Wrap-up</h2><p>I haven&rsquo;t had this bag for long, but my first impressions are that this will be a major part of my travel kit. I can&rsquo;t wait to bring this with me to Oakland, or Japan, to see how well it fits under a seat, or loads and unloads in a crowded subway train.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>A review of the Merry Spinster</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-03-13-merry-spinster-review/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-03-13-merry-spinster-review/</guid><description>“Daughters are as good a thing as any…” begins The Merry Spinster by Danny Ortberg’s wild reimagining of the Little Mermaid that ends in such grim fashion as to make the reader nod solemnly and intone, “truly, these are the end of times.” And yet, what a romp of a dark timeline. Unlike Texts from Jane Eyre, his first book of imagined text conversations from literary characters, this reader at least felt prepared for these fables, stories, and tall-tales through study of European folklore.</description><content:encoded><p>“Daughters are as good a thing as any…” begins<em>The Merry Spinster</em> by Danny Ortberg’s wild reimagining of the Little Mermaid that ends in such grim fashion as to make the reader nod solemnly and intone, “truly, these are the end of times.” And yet, what a romp of a dark timeline. Unlike<em>Texts from Jane Eyre</em>, his first book of imagined text conversations from literary characters, this reader at least felt prepared for these fables, stories, and tall-tales through study of European folklore. Even more, each story brought a sly smile to my face as I discovered the layers of joyful twisting of stories well and lesser-known.</p><p>“Fear Not: An Incident Log” tells of a heavenly bureaucrat who, they assure us, “(has) never once been reprimanded for how I comport myself under the sun.” We spend the story learning of the machinations of a certain kind of supernatural world, adjacent to the typical christian god, angels, and satan. As I read this story, I laughed out loud in public, and felt a welling of joy.</p><p>Another tale that wormed its soft, velveteen pages into my heart was “The Rabbit” — about a boy who gives his love to a toy that may or may not be sucking the life force of the child away. It’s devilish fun. Each story in this collection has a sparkle in its eye, and just a bit of dirt on its face, as if to say, “Who, me? I couldn’t have broken the window, Ms., as I studied all day.” This is a collection for rascals, miscreants, and students of folktale who smoked behind the liberal arts building, and threw rocks at their shadow.</p><p>As a reader, I tore through these tales quickly, but as with any fairytale, I plan to revisit these regularly, until their devilish stories take the place of better known tellings. Ortberg surely has a gift, revealed by his early work in frightening children’s tales on The Toast, but for his sophomore publication, I can see a writer hitting his stride, and stretching his legs. I can’t wait to see what further fictions he brings us. The Merry Spinster is a triumph.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Sister spit</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2016-04-16-sister-spit-piece-pre-cunt-up/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2016-04-16-sister-spit-piece-pre-cunt-up/</guid><description>Note: This was a cunt-up piece, so it was delivered in chunks, read out of a hat, interspersed with Cooper Lee Bombardier’s piece about the same time period/culture. As such, it’s a little disjointed. Enjoy~
A time and a place I wasn’t part of, but read about eagerly. The drugs, the fucking, and the sisterhood that I dreamed of from my bed in Texas. I wouldn’t have been accepted, I know, because of who I am.</description><content:encoded><p>Note: This was a cunt-up piece, so it was delivered in chunks, read out of a hat, interspersed with Cooper Lee Bombardier’s piece about the same time period/culture. As such, it’s a little disjointed. Enjoy~</p><p>A time and a place I wasn’t part of, but read about eagerly. The drugs, the fucking, and the sisterhood that I dreamed of from my bed in Texas. I wouldn’t have been accepted, I know, because of who I am. At the time, I was closeted, and scared. At the time I was falling for my straight friends, and stealing clothes to feel a little more whole. The music that got me through was Tori, Ani, PJ. I didn’t know enough about your books, but now when I read them, I feel a pang of nostalgia for a time I missed — for something that can only exist as a perfect picture of a time gone by. I would have gotten so fucked up. I like to think that if I existed then I would have partied with you. I like to think that somehow I could get around the politics of exclusion that were so often a part of your world. The fashion of that time is back, and when I wear my docs with a short skirt, I think, there’s still time. Valencia isn’t the same as it was, but I still roam that street, getting tattooed and kissing so many girls.</p><p>I flag every day. I see other dykes, and wink. I pick girls up, and make sure gloves are in my bag. My transsexuality is not a debt I owe anyone — it’s a deep felt bank of energy and power. I teach and learn from other women, and in this way, I join a line of sisterhood that ties back to yours.</p><p>The dykes I know don’t always know of their elders, their roots in culture. They fuck, write, and dance to the tunes and the works of your peers. Our youths are all fleeting, but we live them forever through the words we speak and put down to paper.</p><p>My 30s are a chance to relive my 20s — back then I couldn’t live the way I needed to, and I felt so alone. Now I fly around the world and revel in my dyke magic. We learned from you — we learned that so many of the drugs and smokes you took are anathema to us now. We live in fear of tomorrow, but also in the hope that we might have one. Our crisis is global, where yours was personal. We fight for the trans women of color, the sex workers, the women that are murdered every day, and you fought for space, and against a disease that seemed to kill everyone it touched.</p><blockquote><h1 id="she-swaggers-down-the-streets-in-her-leather-at-night-you-like-the-way-she-mounts-her-harley-davison-bike-jump-on-the-back-she-gives-it-a-rev-dont-think-shes-gonna-top-you-cos-shes-belly-up-in-bed--tribe-8">“She swaggers down the streets in her leather at night, you like the way she mounts her Harley Davison bike. Jump on the back, she gives it a rev, don’t think she’s gonna top you, cos she’s belly up in bed.” — Tribe 8</h1></blockquote><p>Except, I’m not. At least not every time. I top, and am topped. My gender and my sex are both more expansive than the binaries of top/bottom. I am a switch. a Dyke that loves to be inside and for you to be inside. A fist fills me up, and it says “you exist.”</p><p>I didn’t know about Riot Grrl until after it had shifted, become something else. I saw Kathleen Hanna speak recently, and she said “we need to do something better, we need to make sure that when we say ‘all girls to the front, we mean PoC, we mean trans women.’”</p><blockquote><h1 id="but-you-cant-stop-the-fire-that-burns">“But you can’t stop the fire that burns</h1><h1 id="inside-of-me">Inside of me</h1><h1 id="you-think-i-dont-know">You think I don’t know</h1><h1 id="im-here-to-tell-you">I’m here to tell you</h1><h1 id="i-do--bikini-kill">I do” — Bikini Kill</h1></blockquote><p>The trans men I know are often from your time — they learned and grew, and at times they feel like big brothers. I learn the secrets, the handshakes from them. They introduce me to the heroes I would have if I had heroes. They made space for themselves, and didn’t make space for us, but I don’t really blame them. We are all fighting for ourselves at the end of the day, and for my brothers, I often think they just wanted to live another day, more comfortable than the day before. Maybe we deserve some comfort, but I don’t know if we deserve community. Community comes from shared experience, yes, but mostly it comes from fighting, fucking, and talking together. It’s hard won, it’s built on pain and history. We can build a new community that takes the best of your past, and the best of mine, and opens its doors for all of our loves, all our trans siblings.</p><p>Stealth is a word we both roll our eyes at. We know why folks do it, and safety is a real problem, but to get rid of our histories? to hide from our pasts? Instead we hope to embrace ourselves as a whole, and remember even the bad times. It’s harder, and it hurts, but we grow so much more than if we pretended we were born whole-cloth, that the desperate times, grasping for the truth, had never occured.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>No cis men</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2016-04-15-no-cis-men/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2016-04-15-no-cis-men/</guid><description>no cis men, says the sign on the door and i read, prove yourself are you woman enough to enter this building not woman like dresses but woman like a body you didn’t get for free the feeling that these spaces want to spit us out like we won’t be safe from the pain of judgement because it follows us in and comes out through their eyes
do you see me?</description><content:encoded><p>no cis men, says the sign on the door
and i read, prove yourself
are you woman enough to enter this building
not woman like dresses
but woman like a body you didn’t get for free
the feeling that these spaces want to spit us out
like we won’t be safe from the pain of judgement
because it follows us in
and comes out through their eyes</p><p>do you see me?
do you see what I am trying to do?
who i am, and what i am
am i more to you than a token
or just a tragic figure
am i someone you could fuck
someone you could fall in love with
can i come to your party and feel at home?</p><p>they check my id and find the F
the sign they look for to say “you’re good”
but i see the glint of doubt in your eyes
when i say thanks and my voice sounds
just a little too deep
the foot to head look they give
doesn’t read as checking me out
so much as vetting my existence
i feel a shiver of fear, and swallow it down</p><p>i dance and flirt as armor against the other
this belonging feels like a battle
and i am not one to give up easy</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Pack light and still enjoy the trip</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2016-04-14-pack-light-and-still-enjoy-the-trip/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2016-04-14-pack-light-and-still-enjoy-the-trip/</guid><description>Why I choose to travel with a 16L bag everywhere I go.
The Past Years ago, I stopped checking bags when I flew. I’d seen too many things get lost over the years, my own and other’s, and couldn’t stomach the thought of landing somewhere again, only to lose all my possessions. So, I began using a canvas duffel bag, as well as a small backpack.
The bag is grey, and around 30L in volume, has little toggle closures, and a couple internal pockets.</description><content:encoded><p>Why I choose to travel with a 16L bag everywhere I go.</p><h2 id="the-past">The Past</h2><p>Years ago, I stopped checking bags when I flew. I’d seen too many things get lost over the years, my own and other’s, and couldn’t stomach the thought of landing somewhere again, only to lose all my possessions. So, I began using a canvas duffel bag, as well as a small backpack.</p><p>The bag is grey, and around 30L in volume, has little toggle closures, and a couple internal pockets. It was great for trips in the car to Dallas to see my partner at the time’s family, or anywhere that I didn’t need to carry it. But it was horrible for planes and walking.</p><p>For a while, I just dealt with the shoulder pain and annoyance of a single, cross-chest strap full of gear, in addition to my backpack. But it hurt, and I didn’t really like the way I looked, carrying two different bags. I still felt much better about my setup than I would with a large rectangle of soon-to-be-lost gear, but I wanted to simplify more.</p><p><em>A note on my able-bodied privilege</em> This choice to carry a smaller bag, regardless of weight, is one that I was able to make because of my body. For those with chronic pain, or difficulty carrying weight on their back for whatever reason, my setup will likely not work. I see a lot of folks get frustrated with rolling bags, and I have shared that sentiment in the past, but it is very shitty to the folks who need those bags for any reason.</p><h2 id="simplify-your-gear">Simplify your gear</h2><p><em>Pack lighter by packing less</em></p><h3 id="clothing">Clothing</h3><p>The first thing I did to simplify, was to see what I could live without. Many of the<em>extras</em> that I was sure of needing got tossed. No more extra shoes for a trip. No more than the number of underwear I would need for the trip (and often less — it’s easy to hand-wash). Two bras (<strong>Nude label</strong>). A couple shirts that could also be hand-washed easily (yoga tank-tops from<strong>Lucy</strong>). Wool socks, usually two pairs. With my wardrobe thus whittled, I turned to my love of books.</p><h3 id="books">Books</h3><p>In the past I always brought at least 3 books with me on trip of more than 3 or 4 days, as I’d likely go through all of them. Books are heavy. Like, really heavy, and not very easy to pack tightly, especially if they’re lengthy. A<strong>Kindle</strong> helped fix that problem immediately. I bought the cheapest one, with ads, and loaded it up with a few books I’d acquired over the years, and some free ones from Project Gutenberg. I don’t like giving my money to Amazon, but there are other ways to buy books that support independent bookstores. Now I could carry as many books as I wanted, and acquire new ones instantly, without needing to add to the weight of my pack. Don’t get me wrong, I still love the smell and feel of books, and have a library at home that I treasure, but just like my other stuff, I don’t need to travel with everything I care about.</p><h3 id="electronics">Electronics</h3><p>When it came to electronics, I was already pretty lightweight. I had the ability to afford a<strong>Macbook Air</strong>, and learned that each year I could sell the previous one and buy a new one for ~100 dollars or so if I kept it from getting banged up. This 13&rdquo;, slim laptop could go most anywhere with me with a minimal strain on my back. I had a slender<strong>Tom Bhin</strong> sleeve for it, and its charger. I also had my<strong>iPhone</strong>, my Kindle (as mentioned above), and a small USB cable for both. In recent years, I’ve switched to the<strong>Macbook</strong>, which is even smaller and lighter than the Air. My company bought me a Kindle Paperwhite, so now I can read on dark planes with minimal disturbance. I also purchased an<strong>Anker</strong> powercore 15600 that can charge my phone ~6 times before needing to be charged itself. It’s a little heavy, but has made a huge difference in how I travel, as I don’t need to worry as much about finding an outlet when I am sure to need directions and contact with folks via Twitter, email, or text. For headphones, I’ve always loved in-ear ones, but on long flights, they are painful at best. I got a pair of **ATH-M40Xs **that I adore, and usually wear them around my neck when I’m not listening to them on trips. When I get where I am traveling, I often leave them in the room and switch to my<strong>RHA 10Ti</strong> in-ear-monitors. There are better headphones for the price, but these work well for me, and most-importantly, fit into my phone while the case is on it, unlike my<strong>Shure 215k</strong> that I previously wore everywhere.</p><p>The final electronic device I bring is a vibrator. At home, I have quite the array, and particularly love my wireless<strong>Magic Wand</strong>. But, taking a note from a friend about not becoming dependent on what amounts to a power tool, I travel with the easily-packed<strong>JimmyJane Form 2</strong>. It does the trick, has a travel mode (so it doesn’t vibrate in my bag), and is waterproof to boot.</p><h3 id="other-clothes">Other clothes</h3><p>When I go anywhere with either changeable temperature, or the likelihood of rain, I bring my<a href="http://www.ilsejacobsen.com/womens-raincoat-RAIN50.html?c=76695">**Ilse Jacobsen Raincoat 50</a> **jacket. It’s black, minimally adorned, and waterproof. I love it. Before I had this jacket, I always brought my older<strong>Marmot Precip</strong>, which could be stowed in my bag easily, unlike this new jacket. With warmer weather, I will probably return to that jacket, for ease of carry.</p><p>Yoga pants are the best. For both comfort on the plane, and versatile city exploring, I always bring a pair of yoga leggings that are black, and durable. The ones I have now are from Lucy, but anything will do. With these, my socks, and the yoga tanks I wear, the key is wicking. I sweat easily, and don’t always have a great way to wash clothes, so having clothing that stays pretty stink-free, and dry, is a huge plus. It also packs down really easily due to the thinness of the fabric. You might want something a little thicker if you get cold more easily. Sometimes I bring wool tights too, to wear under these or my jeans.</p><p>For pants, I also bring a pair of high-waisted, stretchy black jeans. This is a style choice, but I love them. I pack these in my bag while flying, and then wear them around half the time I’m on my trip. I also bring a small pair of shorts (<strong>Foxers</strong>), for sleeping and wandering around my hotel, or hostel.</p><h3 id="toiletries">Toiletries</h3><p>I don’t wear much makeup, and that means my toiletry packing is pretty straightforward. I bring a stick of eyeliner, a stick of lipstain, some coconut-oil deodorant, essential oil, and a toothbrush. I pack these in the front pocket of my backpack, along with my medicine, and some hand-sanitizer for those times I have no idea where to wash my hands, but want to eat.</p><p>I also bring a water bottle, which is a<strong>Hydroflask</strong>, but have thought about getting a collapsable water bottle, the<strong>Vapur</strong>, soon. (Edit: I got a Vapor bottle, and it’s amazing. It can fold up and fit in the small front zipper of my Fjalraven bag along with the makeup and pill-bottle I keep in there. A+)</p><h3 id="the-bag">The bag</h3><p>I switch between two bags these days, depending on condition. If there will be a lot of rain, or I expect my bag to get jostled significantly, I bring my<strong>Mission Workshop 21L Sancturary</strong> bag. It’s super durable, and has held up to international travel and mistreatment in my often clumsy hands, and stayed strong for the past 6 years or so. In an effort to get even lighter, as well as have something cuter to walk around cities like NYC with, I picked up a<strong>Fjalraven Kånken</strong> bag. At 16L, it’s pretty small, but I can still fit all my packed gear inside. My only complaint with this bag, is that with my stuff in it, it can be difficult to get my laptop out in the TSA line. I never dealt with this problem using my Mission Workshop bag, because it has a folding top, that allows for easy access to the laptop in the back. The Fjalraven is a zipper system at the front of the bag, so I have to roll the top back with it unzipped to pull out my laptop. I’m considering cutting the bag and adding another zipper, but we’ll see. It’s less of a problem with the bag less tightly packed, so it’s likely this will just lead to me packing a little bit less each time, and that’s not so bad.</p><p><em>Final recommendation:</em> Years ago I read an article written by a designer who decided to travel without any clothes, save for enough underwear to get her through the trip. She loved the opportunity to hit up a thrift store and buy interesting outfits, which she would re-sell, or donate at the end of her trip. She figured she was saving hassle by not bringing extra clothes, and saving money, potentially, by not needing to check a bag. I love this idea, but as a woman who has a hard time finding well-fitting clothes (I’m 5'10, athletic, and wide-hipped), I don’t want to take that kind of risk. But, if you love shopping, have a frame that is more welcoming to thrift clothes, and feel ok with buying and getting rid of these temporary outfits, then I recommend trying her style of light packing. You might find that the short-lived nature of these clothes inspire you to make riskier or more interesting choices, and maybe even mailing a few pieces back home.</p><h2 id="wrap-up">Wrap up</h2><p>There are many reasons why I’ve decided to pack as light as I do, and it’s become a thing I both enjoy and find ways to challenge as I continue to travel regularly. Questioning the stuff I own, and finding a way to make cute outfits with limited options is a fun way to make the most of a limited budget, or a temporarily limited wardrobe. A lot of folks I know love to bring large bags with extra shoes, more clothes than they wear, and options for most gear. I’m glad they found what works for them, but I’m also very happy to have figured out a minimal pack that feel like I have enough for a week or two. However you decide to pack, light, heavy, or not at all, I hope you enjoy your travels, take some pictures, and breath.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>My year-end review of 2015</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-12-19-my-year-end-review-of-2015/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-12-19-my-year-end-review-of-2015/</guid><description>Marginally better! 2015: it sounds like we’re really moving
Score 2015/?</description><content:encoded><p>Marginally better!
2015: it sounds like we’re really moving</p><h2 id="score">Score</h2><p>2015/?</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>NYC</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-11-9-nyc-my-second-home/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-11-9-nyc-my-second-home/</guid><description>New York is my home for two months out of the year, but I only recently became acquainted with it. Growing up in Texas, I got the idea from my dad that NYC was some kind of devil city. He regarded it as a liberal place with people who walked too fast, and were too greedy. The first time I visited in my mid-twenties, I realized just how wrong he was.</description><content:encoded><p>New York is my home for two months out of the year, but I only recently became acquainted with it. Growing up in Texas, I got the idea from my dad that NYC was some kind of devil city. He regarded it as a liberal place with people who walked too fast, and were too greedy. The first time I visited in my mid-twenties, I realized just how wrong he was.</p><h3 id="my-first-visit">My first visit</h3><p>At this point, I was liberal myself, and the city didn’t seem particularly evil to me. There were people literally EVERYWHERE, though in less quantities than Taipei and Chennai, both of which I visited before NYC. The density of any of those cities is slightly overwhelming for me, as I’m happier in a group of 2–6 people, but I learned quickly that I can put my headphones on and they disappear. To a degree, music makes the city feel like a river that I’m floating through or a strange movie set. Interactions with strangers aren’t necessary in the way that waving at folks on the street seems normal in Portland or Texas. In a way, I found the anonymity and brusqueness refreshing.</p><h3 id="food">Food</h3><p>As a food nerd, I also find the ubiquity of delicious meals incredibly appealing, though I will never get used to the constant lines and hype around restaurants who can only hope to fit a handful of people at a time, ensuring long waits. Still, I feast each time I visit my 2nd home. Often I will pick a particular cuisine, and try to find the 5 best examples of its preparation, be it ramen, izakaya food, or southern fried chicken. Food tourism is a major industry from what I can tell. Food isn’t cheap, but then neither is anything else in NYC. I budget to spend $60 a day in NYC on food alone, and many times I’ve blown right by that. I’d imagine if I lived there more regularly, I would cook more often, but the temptations of restaurants and carts is too high for me to pass up during each visit. I’ve yet to dive into the fine-dining scene, as I’m loathe to wear heels or hose, but I’ve heard great things about upscale restuarants. For now, I think I’ll stick to the sub-$10 congee bowl with youtiao.</p><h3 id="getting-around">Getting around</h3><p>A huge part of my love of the city is the transport. Many of my friends in NYC seem to avoid the subway, opting for Uber, taxis, or bicycles, but I love it. To me, trains are a pinnacle of old, cool technology. They’re dependable (largely), safe (except occasionally from scary folks), and inexpensive. Waiting on the platform, or slumped in a molded plastic seat, I have time to read books, listen to music, and contemplate hard problems at work or in life. In a city that moves so quickly, these brief pauses are my respite. Without them, I don’t think I could handle the bustle or the pace of NYC.</p><h3 id="memento-mori">Memento mori</h3><p>That said, I think the city wants us dead. The distinct sense I get from NYC is one of antagonism. The people can be ok at times, but the city itself pulses with too much, and too harsh. Not only are there actual dangers in the city, but the sheer speed at which everything is moving ensures that if you stumble emotionally, physically, or in spirit, the weight of the city-as-inexorable-movement will grind you into dust. Perhaps the industry or part of New York you encounter on a daily basis can mitigate this for a time, but by and large, NYC is hard to thrive in. High rents, cold winters, humid-as-hell summers, and complex transit — if you are thinking of visiting or moving from a sleepy locale, test the waters in a few seasons first.</p><h3 id="finally">Finally</h3><p>For myself, making friends was the most important part of enjoying my time in NYC. They ensure that I have activities in the city or in Brooklyn, as well as support and kind faces. With growing familiarity and the increased time I spend in the city, I now love it as a second home, and am excited to drop in for a few weeks at a time, to partake in the drug of NYC. And I’m equally happy to fly home, disembark from the plane, and breath in the cool, crisp air of Portland.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Thoughts on GHC</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-10-19-thoughts-on-ghc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-10-19-thoughts-on-ghc/</guid><description>Arrival
“This conference is GIGANTIC!” was my first thought upon arriving at Grace Hopper. This year’s attendance was around 10,000 folks, mostly women, and the largest conference besides SXSW that I’ve attended. Like many tech conferences, GHC had an invaluable app that showed a stream of comments from attendees as well as a schedule and other information. Once I signed in, I spent a lot of time networking and finding folks from out of town as my chosen track “Open-Source” was largely bereft of personally relevant content.</description><content:encoded><p>Arrival</p><p>“This conference is GIGANTIC!” was my first thought upon arriving at Grace Hopper. This year’s attendance was around 10,000 folks, mostly women, and the largest conference besides SXSW that I’ve attended. Like many tech conferences, GHC had an invaluable app that showed a stream of comments from attendees as well as a schedule and other information. Once I signed in, I spent a lot of time networking and finding folks from out of town as my chosen track “Open-Source” was largely bereft of personally relevant content. Like most of the tracks, the content was focused around introductory ideas and concepts more suited to students just entering the tech world. GHC also boasted a huge job fair, and walking around was pleasantly surreal as it was comprised of 99% women, unlike just about any large room I’ve been in.</p><h3 id="panel">Panel</h3><p>My panel was very well received. It took place in an 500 person auditorium (super daunting), but our attendence was closer to 150. I spoke with my book’s editor Elissa Shevinsky, Ellen Spertus from Mills College (late of Google), and Dom DeGuzman from Twilio. Our topic was how to work with and around HR when you are in an oppressed or marginalized group, and despite the rather somber subject, there were laughs and later tears as our attendees came to talk to us and thank us. I was able to discuss the very important role of intersectionality when doing feminist work, and participating in diversity/inclusion discussions. I also brought to light some practical ways to include and help trans folks.</p><h3 id="highlights">Highlights?</h3><p>Two particular highlights in meeting people were Isis Anchalee, who started #ilooklikeanengineer, and Megan Smith, the CTO of America. There was also an LGBT (though I’m not sure why the G existed for a women’s conference) meetup at the convention center, and the turnout of around 80 women was heartening.</p><h3 id="the-future">The future</h3><p>Due to the nature of speaking and my suspicion that the conference content wouldn’t be incredibly applicable, I only attended one day of it. From talking to my friends, it sounds like I didn’t miss anything too great. I think Grace Hopper could still become a wonderful conference, but for now it is primarily centered on hiring and introductory talks for white and asian-american cisgender heterosexual women. It’s unfortunate that both the size, and leadership of the conference preclude many sessions that would be beneficial, or smaller talks that could be more intimate and informative. I filled out feedback forms with honest content, and I hope that GHC and Anita Borg take note, and that next year is marginally better.</p><p>I’ll end with a quote from a woman who spoke to me tearfully after my talk: “I was so happy to be here at a conference with women, but I’m realizing just how many of us it still leaves out and doesn’t help or include.”</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>LWT NYC Summit</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-10-05-lesbians-who-tech-nyc-summit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-10-05-lesbians-who-tech-nyc-summit/</guid><description>Due to stress, the talk I am about to give usually overshadows the talks before mine. Fortunately, LWT was such a jam-packed speaker event that I was able to tune into the talks and not get eaten by nerves. There were a neat mix of 5 minute ignite talks about things like tackling systemic oppression, government tech work, and imposter syndrome. Some of these talks were similar to others I’ve heard, and the audience was so different than what I usually experience at a conference that I was a little sad we didn’t get past some of the 101 talks.</description><content:encoded><p>Due to stress, the talk I am about to give usually overshadows the talks before mine. Fortunately, LWT was such a jam-packed speaker event that I was able to tune into the talks and not get eaten by nerves. There were a neat mix of 5 minute ignite talks about things like tackling systemic oppression, government tech work, and imposter syndrome. Some of these talks were similar to others I’ve heard, and the audience was so different than what I usually experience at a conference that I was a little sad we didn’t get past some of the 101 talks.</p><p>It’s certainly possible that many of the women and other folks there were hearing about imposter syndrome or trans-inclusiveness for the first time, but I’d love to have more talks that dig into the meat of intersectional feminism in tech.</p><h3 id="a-few-talks">A few talks</h3><p>In the morning of Friday, there was a neat presentation by Diane Feinberg of Pixar on how they handle lighting and building a scene into something more than just 3D renderings.
The interview right before I spoke was with a senior Amazon employee concerning the NYTimes story, and she was able to add color and detail to both how the story turned out against the actual quotes and information given to the reporter, as well as what she’s changed since then.</p><p>After my talk, Edith Windsor was a particular delight, and had more than a few of us tearing up at her description of being a closeted gay woman at IBM in the 60s.</p><h3 id="generally">Generally</h3><p>I generally enjoyed the conference, but wish the compressed Friday schedule spread more evenly over Saturday and Sunday, instead of making them largely social/hackathon. I was also a little saddened to see banks so heavily represented in the recruiting area, but this is also my first NYC conference, so perhaps that is typical.</p><h3 id="tldr">TL;DR</h3><p>Overall, I think this is a worthwhile conference, and I am going to try to attend the SF summit as well in February.
Feel free to hit me up with any particular questions you have. They recorded the talks during a live-stream, and you can watch any them at<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vD-nwKUZ3LI">this link</a></p></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>