<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>blog on dill &amp; fennel</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/categories/blog/</link><description>Recent content in blog on dill &amp; fennel</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Copyright Brook Shelley 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.brookshelley.com/categories/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2019 iOS Homescreen</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-28-2019-iphone-homescreen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-28-2019-iphone-homescreen/</guid><description>Another year has rushed past, and with it, another iPhone update and some changes to my phone since last year&amp;rsquo;s setup. My use of a single screen of apps continues, with a few major and minor changes alongside.
I&amp;rsquo;ve posted these for the past few years, so if you want to see what apps I was using in 2017, here you go.
Some things change 3 app dock—I moved my Twitter app out of my dock in order to spend less time on Twitter.</description></item><item><title>Favorite Albums of 2019</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-26-favorite-albums-2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-26-favorite-albums-2019/</guid><description>The Playlist Here&amp;rsquo;s all the albums I really loved this year easily accessible as an Apple Playlist.
The Albums 1) Cheap Queen — King Princess
Bless lesbian musicians. King Princess first caught my attention with the song Pussy is God, which damn. This album is a bop.
2) Emily Alone — Florist
A deeply sparse, sad album that I enjoy quite a bit. Florist has always made beautiful songs, but this is a so quiet and so delightful.</description></item><item><title>DevRel Tour Packing List</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-06-devreltour-packing-list/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-06-devreltour-packing-list/</guid><description>As usual, when I go on a DevRel tour, I like to write about what I&amp;rsquo;ve packed. This trip was a 3 week journey from Tokyo, through Kyoto, to Osaka, and back. As I write this, halfway through the trip, I feel very good about the amount of stuff I brought.
Bags RYU Quick Pack 18L Topo Designs Trip Pack Last time I went to Japan, I brought the DSPTCH Waist Bag as my day bag, and my shoulders immediately regretted it.</description></item><item><title>A letter</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-10-08-letter-to-myself/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-10-08-letter-to-myself/</guid><description>(this is a very earnest post, and if you&amp;rsquo;re here for backpacks and travel, maybe skip this one)
Hey Brook,
This letter in a sci-fi tale would come to you out of the ether, dropping onto your iBook G3 on some particularly dark night of the soul. I&amp;rsquo;m you, but 16 years older, and hopefully a little wiser.
(Spoiler alert)
The next few years will be a lot of fun, but also really, really tough.</description></item><item><title>XOXO 2019</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-09-10-xoxo-2019/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-09-10-xoxo-2019/</guid><description>A return to form This year marked my 4th XOXO, and my 3rd at Revolution Hall. Last year was big, which meant it was even harder to wave at, or spend time with the other amazing attendees I knew. This year, it felt just right. I still waved at too many folks, and wished I had time to have a number of small dinners over the next year instead of so many “hey, I see you, sorry I’ve gotta run!</description></item><item><title>Masterworks review</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-09-03-masterworks-review/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-09-03-masterworks-review/</guid><description>I wish I knew more about art. Reading the titular story, I found myself reaching for my phone to understand each scene in the strange and delightful post-apocalyptic tale. As I held the painting in my mind, and explored the flooded wastes with Liam, Nell, and Co. I found myself enamored by the framing. How often are our relationships held together by a retelling of an old picture? Are we always trying to build a life out of the classics of our youth?</description></item><item><title>Wardrobe refresh</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-08-20-wardrobe-refresh/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-08-20-wardrobe-refresh/</guid><description>As my clothes gradually wear out, I’m slowly trying to replace everything with my current favorites. This makes for a very simple wardrobe that works for all 4 seasons.
Lots of this stuff is wool, all of it is pretty durable, and when possible I tried to find vendors that were environmentally friendly and smaller.
Shirts 4 tank tops — These are fantastic tank tops. They wick well, don’t get stinky, and look good enough to wear outside of the gym.</description></item><item><title>A Weekly Link Newsletter</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-07-21-newsletter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-07-21-newsletter/</guid><description>It’s official: I’ve joined the newsletter trend in earnest. I’ve had a newsletter for a few months now, but I wasn’t sure what to really do with it. Fortunately, I realized what I love to see the most from some of my favorite newsletters is links to what these authors are reading this week—little jewels from internet wanderings.
My re-launched Dill and Fennel newsletter will have links to some of the more interesting or funny things I’ve seen in the previous week.</description></item><item><title>iPadOS</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-06-09-ios13/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-06-09-ios13/</guid><description>It’s probably clear by now that I love my iPad Pro. I travel with it, write on it, and practice Japanese on it. When Apple announced iPadOS, it suddenly seemed liked my dream of only using my iPad had come true.
Major updates New home screen With a glance at the home screen, it’s clear that this isn’t iOS 12. Onscreen widgets isn’t exactly revolutionary, but it saves me a slide-over every time I want to check the weather, or which meeting I’m headed to next.</description></item><item><title>On the perfect thing</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-05-27-on-the-perfect-thing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-05-27-on-the-perfect-thing/</guid><description>The search for the best, most optimized, beautiful, light, and pleasing things.
Why do we search? Scrolling through my RSS feeds, I’m reminded daily that so much stuff exists. I subscribe to newsletters for fashion, backpacks, apps, and general tech, and every single one has an endless march through the days of new things. This app has two columns for editing! This backpack is “able to transition from work to play and travel.</description></item><item><title>On notes and todos</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-05-02-on-notes-and-todos/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-05-02-on-notes-and-todos/</guid><description>The latest episode of Supercomputer inspired me to write about how I work with notes, todos, and reminders every day. Part of the episode was centered on their mutual dissatisfaction with various notes apps, which I totally understand. Over the years, I&amp;rsquo;ve used NVAlt, 1Writer, Bear, Evernote, Notes, and more to keep track of my thoughts, posts, and notes. Brett Terpstra keeps a very good list of all iOS text editors that includes information about their cross-platform functionality.</description></item><item><title>Formula 1</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-04-13-formula-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-04-13-formula-1/</guid><description>When I mention my love of Formula 1 racing, most of the time I hear, &amp;ldquo;is that like NASCAR?&amp;rdquo; This speaks to the sad lack of F1 information and excitement in the states, and it&amp;rsquo;s a bummer. NASCAR is a sport in its own right, but comparing it to F1 is a bit like comparing rotary phones to an iPhone. F1 is fast, the roads twist this way and that, and most importantly the drivers are from across the globe.</description></item><item><title>Minimal travel clothing</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-04-08-minimal-travel-clothing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-04-08-minimal-travel-clothing/</guid><description>Ten or so years ago, I realized I hated bringing heavy bags with me everywhere I traveled, so I slimmed down my packing to fit in one small backpack. My wardrobe generally cycles between a few pieces, so it wasn’t much of a stretch to adapt it to a month in Japan or Berlin. I usually write a post-trip gear update, but today is all about clothing.
What’re you wearing?</description></item><item><title>Learning kanji again</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-01-27-learning-kanji-again/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-01-27-learning-kanji-again/</guid><description>My first Japanese class In 1996 I took my first Japanese class at Austin Community College. I was in middle school at the time, and decided to learn how to read Japanese so I could read literature and comics. The class was fun, and also super weird, since I was the only kid there. I took two semesters, but a lot of life happened at once, so I stopped taking Japanese, and didn’t being again until University, five years later.</description></item><item><title>2018 in Review</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-12-22-year-in-review/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-12-22-year-in-review/</guid><description>Started in Japan Last year, I hopped on a plane to Tokyo before the countdown began, and landed in the evening of the 1st of January. Making my way to my rental apartment in Koenji, the city was quiet as folks celebrated with their family. It was a strange trip. I got to do my hatsumode at Meiji Jingu with thousands of people, and see the Emperor’s second to last speech before his groundbreaking abdication next year.</description></item><item><title>My favorite albums of the year</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-12-20-my-favorite-albums-of-the-year/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-12-20-my-favorite-albums-of-the-year/</guid><description>in no particular order On Apple Music
The list Dilly Dally Heaven: I listened to this amazing band’s first album so much in the three years since it came out, and the vocal delivery is raw and beautiful. A true jam.
Ex:Re Ex:Re: A delightfully sad and smart album about lost love, and healing. This was a late-arrival this year, and has already been a constant repeat.
Anna McClellan Yes and No: A similarly raw singing style to Dilly Dally, this is a bummer jam.</description></item><item><title>2018 iPad Pro Review</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-11-07-new-ipad-review/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-11-07-new-ipad-review/</guid><description>Today my phone buzzed to tell me my new iPad had arrived at my office. I rushed down to the mailroom, and eagerly ripped open the packaging. For a few years I’ve used an iPad Pro 9.7” as my primary travel computer when I didn’t need to work on Kubernetes/DevOps stuff, and I’ve loved it. Whether I was watching shows on Netflix or Plex that I’d downloaded before a flight, editing my website in Working Copy, or just editing photos and browsing Twitter, this was the machine I wanted to use.</description></item><item><title>Smoke gets in your eyes</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-20-smokey-skies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-20-smokey-skies/</guid><description>Due to a series of forest fires, Portland has looked like an alien planet for the past few weeks.
Every day I wake up and google &amp;ldquo;air quality&amp;rdquo; to see just how much I need to stay indoors, next to my air filter. My gym has closed for a few days for two weeks, and walking outside just plain sucks.
The only cool part is the sunsets are ridiculous, and the moon is red at night.</description></item><item><title>Powerlifting</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-14-powerlifting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-14-powerlifting/</guid><description>Young Brook Growing up, I never wanted to be big. My parents were both over 6&amp;rsquo; tall, and I worried about being as big as them. Most of my friends ended up being shorter than me, and were usually skinnier too. I was made fun of for being &amp;ldquo;chubby&amp;rdquo; in middle school, and that stuck with me. Being fat or chubby or skinny all rule, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t know that as a kid.</description></item><item><title>August shows</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-13-august-shows/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-13-august-shows/</guid><description>A few years ago, after moving to Portland, I discovered a secret: you can do almost anything alone. I&amp;rsquo;d lived in Austin for most of my life, and as I quickly learned once moving, making friends in Portland is a long process. So, on a whim, I started seeing movies by myself. I went to dinner alone with a book. I even saw concerts&amp;hellip; solo, and it was fun. I don&amp;rsquo;t know why we all think you have to do these activities with other people, but when you go alone you don&amp;rsquo;t have to wait for anyone to be ready to go, or to leave.</description></item><item><title>The old is new again</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-11-posting-on-my-blog/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-11-posting-on-my-blog/</guid><description>Inspired by both Nick and Matt, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to try my hand at blogging again on this site. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how often I&amp;rsquo;ll post, but at least once a month, I&amp;rsquo;ll do a media diet post, which clips out what I read and watched that month from the long lists I keep. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about other stuff too. We&amp;rsquo;ll see!
I have definitely enjoyed how Matt seems to be posting cool things there instead of Twitter, because it gives me more things to see on RSS.</description></item><item><title>Invisible One Mini backpack review</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-05-17-review-invisible-one-mini/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-05-17-review-invisible-one-mini/</guid><description>Bags are my thing. Well, bags and shoes. Traveling as much as I do, having a dependable, comfortable, and sleek bag is pretty important. For the past two or so years, I&amp;rsquo;ve depended on my Topo Designs Trip Pack for short trips, and then nested it inside of my Ryu QuickPack for longer trips abroad. This has worked out well, but walking around Copenhagen, and going through a variety of international airport security, I wondered if I could consolidate to one bag, with an easier way to access my laptop and other stuff.</description></item><item><title>A review of the Merry Spinster</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-03-13-merry-spinster-review/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-03-13-merry-spinster-review/</guid><description>“Daughters are as good a thing as any…” begins The Merry Spinster by Danny Ortberg’s wild reimagining of the Little Mermaid that ends in such grim fashion as to make the reader nod solemnly and intone, “truly, these are the end of times.” And yet, what a romp of a dark timeline. Unlike Texts from Jane Eyre, his first book of imagined text conversations from literary characters, this reader at least felt prepared for these fables, stories, and tall-tales through study of European folklore.</description></item><item><title>Sister spit</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2016-04-16-sister-spit-piece-pre-cunt-up/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2016-04-16-sister-spit-piece-pre-cunt-up/</guid><description>Note: This was a cunt-up piece, so it was delivered in chunks, read out of a hat, interspersed with Cooper Lee Bombardier’s piece about the same time period/culture. As such, it’s a little disjointed. Enjoy~
A time and a place I wasn’t part of, but read about eagerly. The drugs, the fucking, and the sisterhood that I dreamed of from my bed in Texas. I wouldn’t have been accepted, I know, because of who I am.</description></item><item><title>No cis men</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2016-04-15-no-cis-men/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2016-04-15-no-cis-men/</guid><description>no cis men, says the sign on the door and i read, prove yourself are you woman enough to enter this building not woman like dresses but woman like a body you didn’t get for free the feeling that these spaces want to spit us out like we won’t be safe from the pain of judgement because it follows us in and comes out through their eyes
do you see me?</description></item><item><title>Pack light and still enjoy the trip</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2016-04-14-pack-light-and-still-enjoy-the-trip/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2016-04-14-pack-light-and-still-enjoy-the-trip/</guid><description>Why I choose to travel with a 16L bag everywhere I go.
The Past Years ago, I stopped checking bags when I flew. I’d seen too many things get lost over the years, my own and other’s, and couldn’t stomach the thought of landing somewhere again, only to lose all my possessions. So, I began using a canvas duffel bag, as well as a small backpack.
The bag is grey, and around 30L in volume, has little toggle closures, and a couple internal pockets.</description></item><item><title>My year-end review of 2015</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-12-19-my-year-end-review-of-2015/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-12-19-my-year-end-review-of-2015/</guid><description>Marginally better! 2015: it sounds like we’re really moving
Score 2015/?</description></item><item><title>NYC</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-11-9-nyc-my-second-home/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-11-9-nyc-my-second-home/</guid><description>New York is my home for two months out of the year, but I only recently became acquainted with it. Growing up in Texas, I got the idea from my dad that NYC was some kind of devil city. He regarded it as a liberal place with people who walked too fast, and were too greedy. The first time I visited in my mid-twenties, I realized just how wrong he was.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts on GHC</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-10-19-thoughts-on-ghc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-10-19-thoughts-on-ghc/</guid><description>Arrival
“This conference is GIGANTIC!” was my first thought upon arriving at Grace Hopper. This year’s attendance was around 10,000 folks, mostly women, and the largest conference besides SXSW that I’ve attended. Like many tech conferences, GHC had an invaluable app that showed a stream of comments from attendees as well as a schedule and other information. Once I signed in, I spent a lot of time networking and finding folks from out of town as my chosen track “Open-Source” was largely bereft of personally relevant content.</description></item><item><title>LWT NYC Summit</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-10-05-lesbians-who-tech-nyc-summit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-10-05-lesbians-who-tech-nyc-summit/</guid><description>Due to stress, the talk I am about to give usually overshadows the talks before mine. Fortunately, LWT was such a jam-packed speaker event that I was able to tune into the talks and not get eaten by nerves. There were a neat mix of 5 minute ignite talks about things like tackling systemic oppression, government tech work, and imposter syndrome. Some of these talks were similar to others I’ve heard, and the audience was so different than what I usually experience at a conference that I was a little sad we didn’t get past some of the 101 talks.</description></item></channel></rss>