<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>backpacks on dill &amp; fennel</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/backpacks/</link><description>Recent content in backpacks on dill &amp; fennel</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Copyright Brook Shelley 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/backpacks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pandemic travel: 1</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-16-traveling-during-a-pandemic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-16-traveling-during-a-pandemic/</guid><description>Wow, things sure are quiet&amp;hellip;
Before it was clear we were headed for a pandemic, I booked a “treat yourself” trip to Japan. After a great first year at Slack, I wanted a nice non-work trip to really relax and refresh before going back into 2020 with a renewed sense of vigor.
Unfortunately, in the following weeks COVID-19 grew at a wild rate, the cases in the United States were clearly skyrocketing despite a complete failure of the CDC and leadership to provide ample testing.</description><content:encoded><p><strong>Wow, things sure are quiet&hellip;</strong></p><p>Before it was clear we were headed for a pandemic, I booked a “treat yourself” trip to Japan. After a great first year at Slack, I wanted a nice non-work trip to really relax and refresh before going back into 2020 with a renewed sense of vigor.</p><p>Unfortunately, in the following weeks COVID-19 grew at a wild rate, the cases in the United States were clearly skyrocketing despite a complete failure of the CDC and leadership to provide ample testing. My company cancelled business travel, but left it to us to determine our risk profile for personal travel, so I reached out to friends in the US and Japan to take stock. After a weekend of thinking and reading, I decided to travel to Japan unless flights were cancelled.</p><h2 id="the-trip-begins">The trip begins</h2><p>Many travelers had clearly cancelled their flights, as the plane was largely empty. Out of caution and care for passengers, the staff of the JAL plane were all wearing masks, and taking extra measures to clean and prepare our plane as well. As I boarded and settled-in, my first thought was “I wish folks too health this seriously all the time”.</p><p>Our flight was fairly bumpy, but I managed to sleep for a few hours, and even eat a bit before landing at HND. The usual self-service immigration booths were closed, but as one of the only visitors, I still made it through immigration and customs in minutes. As usual, the customs agent gave me an odd look for my small backpack and lack of luggage.</p><h2 id="the-bag">The bag</h2><p>This trip I brought a single bag: the<a href="https://bellroy.com/products/studio-backpack/venture/black">Bellroy Studio in Venture Weave Black</a>. After many trips with my RYU Quick Pack with a smaller day bag, I looked forward to a single light bag instead. So far on this trip, it’s been a comfortable bag, that easily hauls between locations. I haven’t used it very much outside of traveling to my hotels, as due to the virus I haven’t done a lot of writing from coffee shops or hiking. I used this bag daily for the past few months to go to work though, and am confident it would also be great to take a couple things with me to a coffee shop.</p><p>My packing list was pretty typical:</p><h3 id="clothes">Clothes</h3><ul><li>1 pairs of<a href="https://darntough.com/products/womens-ss18-vertex-no-show-tab-ultra-light">Darn Tough wool socks</a></li><li>1<a href="https://www.icebreaker.com/en-us/womens-tops/cool-lite-solace-short-sleeve-scoop/104640.html">wool shirt from Icebreaker</a></li><li>1 pair of<a href="https://www.outdoorvoices.com/products/rectrek-pant">RekTrek pants from OV</a></li><li>1<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Snow-Peak-Womens-Rain-Trench/dp/B07MWC4KZ8">Snow Peak FR trench</a></li><li>2 pairs of<a href="https://negativeunderwear.com/collections/underwear/products/black-whipped-high-rise">Negative underwear</a></li><li>1 sports bra</li><li>1<a href="https://www.amazon.com/Arcteryx-Eagan-Tank-Top-Womens/dp/B078XHPXJH/ref=pd_sbs_468_4/136-2112403-2472869">tank from Arcteryx</a></li><li>1 pair of<a href="https://www.foxers.com/boxer-briefs/">shorts from Foxers</a></li></ul><h3 id="electronics">Electronics</h3><ul><li>iPad 11” Cellular</li><li>Kindle Oasis</li><li>Switch Lite</li><li>Anker 10kmah battery</li><li>Cables</li><li><a href="https://satechi.net/products/usb-c-magnetic-charging-dock">Satechi watch charger</a> (got this for free from a Satechi rep. Thanks!)—short review: this is a little more compact and chill than bringing a watch cable, and can stick into the side of my iPad to let me charge while I’m writing. It’s a little more awkward plugged into a battery, but not too bad. It’s<a href="https://www.apple.com/shop/product/MX2G2AM/A/apple-watch-magnetic-charging-cable-03m?fnode=83">only 10 bucks more than an Apple charger</a> so if you don’t have a travel charger this might be a good idea.</li></ul><h3 id="other-stuff">Other stuff</h3><ul><li><a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2020/all_about/weeks/">Hobonichi Weeks</a></li><li><a href="https://www.kaweco-pen.com/en">Kaweco fountain pen</a></li><li>Toiletries in a<a href="https://matadorup.com/products/flatpak-toiletry-case">Matador bag</a> which so far, wow. I love this little bag.</li></ul><p>I’m additionally wearing a duplicate of most of what I brought, save for the jacket and sleep clothes. I’m also testing out some<a href="https://us.soakwash.com/collections/laundry-soap">new laundry soap</a> while I’m here to see if it can keep my clothes fresh without needing a full in-shower scrub.</p><h2 id="koenji-social-distancing">Koenji social distancing</h2><p>My trip started in Koenji, where I stayed at my<a href="https://www.bna-hotel.com">favorite BNA</a>. By and large, I kept to my room, or did some socially-distanced hiking around Suginami. Lawson was a block away, and provided coffee and onigiri, but I also had coffees at Coffee AMP and INC near the train station. Honestly, other than mounting panic online, I found it to be relaxing to stick close to home. I went out for food a couple of times, but honestly felt a little afraid to go out. If I were in Oakland right now, it’s likely I wouldn’t have left the house this week at all, save for a walk around the block.</p><h2 id="to-be-continued">To be continued&hellip;</h2><p><em>read<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-17-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-two/">part 2</a> or<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-19-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-three/">part 3</a></em></p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Bellroy Studio Pack Review</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-12-13-bellroy-studio-pack-review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-12-13-bellroy-studio-pack-review/</guid><description>A new backpack for everyday carry, and travel.
First Sight After first getting my new Bellroy sling, I fell in love with the delightful material for these bags. A few months later in Iitoya in Japan, I got to see their new Shift backpack in person, and almost bought one on the spot. that bag was a little larger than I need, but then I saw this. With the launch of the Studio Backpack, Bellroy has made an excellent bag that holds a little or a lot without every looking absurd.</description><content:encoded><p><img src="/photos/bellroybackpack.jpeg" alt="Bellroy Studio Backpack"/><p>A new backpack for everyday carry, and travel.</p><h2 id="first-sight">First Sight</h2><p>After first getting my new Bellroy sling, I fell in love with the delightful material for these bags. A few months later in Iitoya in Japan, I got to see their new Shift backpack in person, and almost bought one on the spot. that bag was a little larger than I need, but then I saw<a href="https://bellroy.com/products/studio-backpack/venture/black">this</a>. With the launch of the Studio Backpack, Bellroy has made an excellent bag that holds a little or a lot without every looking absurd.</p><h2 id="sizing">Sizing</h2><p>For quite a while, I’ve<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/blog/2019/11/06/devreltour-packing-list.html">brought my Topo Trip Pack</a> to work as it fits my coffee bottle, iPad, journal, and a few other things perfectly. Adding in a spare jacket could stuff it pretty tight, but I preferred that to hauling a bag that was typically too large. With the Studio Backpack, my everyday stuff fits well, with ample space, but the shallow depth of the bag means it looks nice even unloaded.</p><h3 id="measurements">Measurements</h3><p>This is a slim, but tall-ish bag that measures 500L x 370W x 100D mm or 19.69”x14.57”x3.94”.</p><p>It has an 18-liter capacity, which while entry isn’t nearly as big feeling as my similarly-sized RYU Quick Pack. It weighs 650g or 1.43lbs, nearly half the weight of the<a href="https://ryu.com/shop/us/quick-pack/quick-pack-lux">RYU</a>, and only a little heavier than the 567g<a href="https://topodesigns.com/products/trip-pack?variant=946319253">Topo Trip Pack</a>.</p><p>All-in-all, this bag feels like a great balance between a daily size and one that I could fly around the world with.</p><h2 id="features">Features</h2><p><img src="/photos/bellroysmall.jpg" alt="Bellroy Front Pocket"/><p>This bag is a top-loader, with a generously-wide opening, and a fidlock magnetic closure I can open with one hand using the small fabric loop. This flap makes for an easy way to use the main compartment, while keeping the rain off of my stuff. On the outside, there’s a pocket a little bit lower than mid-way that zips shut, and has pockets for pens, AirPods, and a few other things along with a key loop on a long fabric loop. Usually, I keep a Hobonichi Weeks, a Kaweco fountain pen, house keys, AirPods Pro and my work badge in here.</p><p>Inside of the main bag area, there’s a laptop area that can hold up to a 16” MacBook Pro—the new one with the real escape key—or an iPad Pro of either size. The bottom of the bag is generously padded to keep your stuff safe, and the laptop sleeve ends before the bottom for more safety. On the front wall of the main bag opening there is another zipped compartment for glasses, cables, or other odds and ends that you don’t need as often.</p><p><img src="/photos/mainbellroy.jpg" alt="Bellroy Main Pocket"/><h2 id="colors-and-materials">Colors and Materials</h2><p>I have the black version of this bag, which I find delightful, though if I could customize it, I might have chosen a light purple or blue interior instead of the tan it comes with from Bellroy. Bellroy won me over on the idea that a lighter or brighter interior helps in finding your gear, though as a top-loader, even bright fabric doesn’t help you dig at the bottom of the bag. The Venture Weave fabric feels very strange, but in a cool, high-end way, and does a good job shrugging off rain. There are leather accents in various places on the bag that give it a little extra luxury.</p><h2 id="rating">Rating</h2><p>This bag rules, and I’ve thoroughly enjoyed it for the past few weeks. I plan to take it on my next trip abroad, and likely won’t bring a separate daypack. I think this bag will be comfortable on a hike, or fully-loaded with my typical travel gear. If you need a bit more space, I highly recommend checking out Bellroy’s other larger version of this, the<a href="https://bellroy.com/products/shift-backpack/venture/moss">Shift pack</a>.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>DevRel Tour Packing List</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-06-devreltour-packing-list/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-06-devreltour-packing-list/</guid><description>As usual, when I go on a DevRel tour, I like to write about what I&amp;rsquo;ve packed. This trip was a 3 week journey from Tokyo, through Kyoto, to Osaka, and back. As I write this, halfway through the trip, I feel very good about the amount of stuff I brought.
Bags RYU Quick Pack 18L Topo Designs Trip Pack Last time I went to Japan, I brought the DSPTCH Waist Bag as my day bag, and my shoulders immediately regretted it.</description><content:encoded><p>As usual, when I go on a DevRel tour, I like to write about what I&rsquo;ve packed. This trip was a 3 week journey from Tokyo, through Kyoto, to Osaka, and back. As I write this, halfway through the trip, I feel very good about the amount of stuff I brought.</p><h2 id="bags">Bags</h2><ul><li>RYU Quick Pack 18L</li><li>Topo Designs Trip Pack</li></ul><p><img src="/photos/ryubag2019.jpeg" alt="bags"/><p><img src="/photos/travelbag2019.jpeg" alt="bag2"/><p>Last time I went to Japan, I brought the DSPTCH Waist Bag as my day bag, and my shoulders immediately regretted it. I think my days or a one-shoulder bag with a computer are pretty much over. This time I returned to my tried and true setup. I’ve reviewed or written about both of these bags previously.</p><p><img src="/photos/drybags2019.jpeg" alt="drybags"/><ul><li>Two Sea-to-summit dry bags</li></ul><p>These are great for clothes and toiletries, and additionally ensure that even in a downpour I can keep a few things dry.</p><ul><li>One Topo Designs accessory bag</li></ul><p><img src="/photos/drybagsinside.jpeg" alt="drybagsinsidebigbag"/><p>This time around, I loaded my toothbrush and some other non-leaky toiletries into this bag because I noticed the metal tip of my electric toothbrush kept<em>almost</em> poking through my dry bag.</p><h2 id="clothes">Clothes</h2><p><img src="/photos/clothes.jpeg" alt="clothes"/><h3 id="jackets">Jackets</h3><ul><li>Mission Workshop Torre Windshell</li></ul><p>My daily jacket. I’ve got two of these and they’re awesome. Not quite waterproof, but warm enough, and water-resistant enough for a drizzle and temperatures between 7-20C (mid-40s to mid-60s F).</p><ul><li>Arcteryx Cordetta</li></ul><p>If it rains, I’m covered.</p><h3 id="shirts">Shirts</h3><ul><li>Wool t-shirts from Ryu and Icebreaker</li></ul><p>A great way to stay dry and warm or cool. These wash easily and are comfy for all-day-travel.</p><h3 id="pants">Pants</h3><ul><li>Two pairs of Outdoor Voices RecTrek pants</li></ul><p>I wear these to work daily, and they’re pretty ideal. Comfy, flexible, and a bit water-resistant. The pockets are also<em>huge</em> which means my phone fits easily in a front pocket.</p><h3 id="shoes-and-socks">Shoes and socks</h3><ul><li>Blundstones</li><li>Bombas no-show</li></ul><p>These shoes go on and off pretty easily, and look nice enough for business meetings while still feeling good for longer walks. Half of this trip was a vacation, where I wandered around all day, including hiking. I almost went with my new KOIO shoes, but at the last minute, opted for slip-one with a<em>lot</em> of grip.</p><h3 id="underwear">Underwear</h3><ul><li>Wool stuff from Icebreaker</li></ul><p>Wool is the way to go. I’ve tried other solutions and they were nice enough, but ultimately, wool holds up the best and wicks super well.</p><h2 id="tech-gear">Tech gear</h2><p><img src="/photos/electronics2019.jpeg" alt="electronics"/><ul><li>Kindle Oasis</li><li>Battery</li><li>USB-C -> C, and Lightning: iPad and iPhone</li><li>USB-A -> Watch</li><li>USB-A -> Micro: Kindle</li><li>iPad Pro 10.5 w/ Smart Keyboard</li></ul><p>At some point, maybe I can travel with only USB-C cables, but that world doesn’t exist yet. Fortunately my external battery has a USB-C port and a USB-A port, so I use those two to charge my phone and watch at night. On the plane my USB-C to USB-C cable means I can top-up my iPad if I play too many games or get low mid-season of a tv show. It completely boggles the mind why the Kindle isn’t a USB-C device yet. Seriously. It’s 2019.</p><h2 id="other-stuff">Other stuff</h2><p><img src="/photos/weeks2019.jpeg" alt="weeks"/><ul><li>Toiletries</li><li>Hobonichi Weeks &amp; Kaweco Al EF fountain pen</li><li>お土産</li></ul><p>The usual assortment of unguents, potions, and a toothbrush, along with my trusty new pen and notebook. I<em>love</em> this Kaweco pen, which is both completely blacked-out, and compact. I also brought some small gifts for 東京と大阪の同僚。</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Minimal travel clothing</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-04-08-minimal-travel-clothing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-04-08-minimal-travel-clothing/</guid><description>Ten or so years ago, I realized I hated bringing heavy bags with me everywhere I traveled, so I slimmed down my packing to fit in one small backpack. My wardrobe generally cycles between a few pieces, so it wasn’t much of a stretch to adapt it to a month in Japan or Berlin. I usually write a post-trip gear update, but today is all about clothing.
What’re you wearing? Whether it’s a one week or one month-long trip, I bring the same things each time Including what I’m wearing during the flight, here’s the breakdown:</description><content:encoded><p>Ten or so years ago, I realized I hated bringing heavy bags with me everywhere I traveled, so I slimmed down my packing to fit in one<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/blog/2018/05/17/review-invisible-one-mini.html">small backpack</a>. My wardrobe generally cycles between a few pieces, so it wasn’t much of a stretch to adapt it to a month in<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/blog/2019/03/13/travel-kit-update.html">Japan</a> or Berlin. I usually write a post-trip gear update, but today is all about clothing.</p><h2 id="whatre-you-wearing">What’re you wearing?</h2><p>Whether it’s a one week or one month-long trip, I bring the same things each time Including what I’m wearing during the flight, here’s the breakdown:</p><ul><li>3 pairs of<a href="#underwear">underwear</a></li><li>2<a href="#shirts">shirts</a></li><li>2 sports<a href="#underwear">bras</a></li><li>2 pairs of wool<a href="#shoes">socks</a></li><li>1 water-resistant<a href="#jacket">hoodie</a></li><li>(weather-optional) 1<a href="#jacket">jacket</a></li><li>1 pair of<a href="#shoes">shoes</a></li><li>1 pair of<a href="#pants">pants</a></li><li>1 pair of shorts or<a href="#pants">leggings</a></li></ul><p>None of the stuff I wear is particularly cheap, or particularly expensive, but on the whole, it’s held up well to lots of abuse, and many washes. The key to bringing very little clothing is a willingness to wash your clothes in the sink or shower while you bathe. If you find a washing machine, by all means, take advantage of it, but these clothes dry pretty quickly, and I prefer not to hope for something automated. If something gets destroyed (only happened once with some jeans), I can usually find a replacement, but taking stock before a trip of any of your clothing that’s in danger of ripping is a great plan.</p><h2 id="tops-a-nameshirtsa">Tops</h2><p>Day or night, the tops I wear look pretty good, wick sweat ok, and tend to hold up to a day of hiking. I spent a while only wearing wool, but recently got stoked on a few other shirts. Sadly, Ryu doesn’t make the wool shirt I wear anymore, but there are a bunch of brands making wool shirts these days, so have a look around if that appeals to you.</p><p>Usually, if it’s hot or I plan to layer, I wear a<a href="https://ryu.com/shop/us/women/tops/standard-issue-racerback-tank">tank top</a>. No sleeves means no pit stains, and with a hoodie you’re pretty set regardless of the modesty required in a temple or other spot. I’ve had good luck with Ryu and Lucy (though they’ve been bought by North Face, and I don’t know how good they are anymore). Arcteryx used to make a cool wool tank, but they make<a href="https://arcteryx.com/us/en/shop/womens/a2b-scoop-neck-shirt-ss">this</a> now, and if it’s the same fabric, it’s great!</p><p>A friend convinced me to try out these<a href="https://jungmaven.com/collections/hemp-core-tees-tshirt-womens/products/hemp-shirt-ojai-tee-short-sleeve-womens?variant=22065464279088">hemp shirts</a>, and for the first time in years, I wear a few colors. They’re super light, super soft, and don’t get stinky after a few wears.</p><p>I wear one of these shirts while I’m sleeping, and one during the day, and kinda rotate them around. If I’m gone for longer I might bring 2 shirts and a tank top, so I don’t have to wash as much.</p><h2 id="bottoms-a-namepantsa">Bottoms</h2><p>Most of the time I wear<a href="https://www.outdoorvoices.com/products/rectrek-pant?variant=34894684485">Outdoor Voices RecTrek pants</a>, which are comfy, stretchy, and cute. They run out of sizes all the time or I’d have a couple pairs. They dress up for the office ok, but also handle a<em>lot</em> of walking. Since I can’t find another black XL pair, I am currently trying out<a href="https://coalatree.com/collections/apparel/products/slim-fit-trailhead-pants-black">another brand</a>. These Coalatree pants are also pretty great, though the tie at the bottom of each leg is kinda ridiculous. They’re unisex, which means the fit might be weird, but they’ve also got a<em>ergonomic crotch gusset</em> a la<a href="https://www.artofmanliness.com/articles/chuck-norris-action-jeans/">Chuck Norris action jeans</a>. I don’t know<em>why</em> you’d do tons of high kicks in pants, but either of these pairs would handle them with gusto.</p><p>You probably already have your preferred brand of legging, but for me, I’m usually wearing either<a href="https://ryu.com/shop/us/women/bottoms/cardio-tights">Ryu</a> or<a href="https://www.girlfriend.com/collections/leggings/products/black-compressive-high-rise-legging">Girlfriend</a>. I’ve heard great things about Outdoor Voices leggings, but I’m waiting until I destroy a few more old pairs before I try them. For night time, leggings or<a href="https://www.foxers.com/black-tomboy-boxer-brief/">Foxers</a> are great for wandering around my Airbnb or hotel room.</p><h2 id="underwear-a-nameunderweara">Underwear</h2><p>Breathable, light, comfortable, and durable is the name of the game for underwear. I’m always on the search for a pair that hits all four targets. Thus far, some have done ok, but most aren’t that durable. A better pair I tried were<a href="https://knix.com/collections/underwear/products/athletic-bikini">Knix</a>, which were super comfy, but eventually blew up. Sometimes I bring<a href="https://www.meundies.com/products/womens-bikini">MeUndies</a>, but they too tend to fall apart too soon. These wool<a href="https://www.patagonia.com/product/womens-active-briefs-underwear/32396.html?dwvar_32396_color=BLK&amp;cgid=socks-underwear#tile-7=&amp;start=1&amp;sz=24">Patagonia briefs</a> were alright. I feel like I’ll be on the hunt indefinitely, but maybe a few pairs of one of these will do if for you. All three are comfortable, and dry fast, but the Knix and Patagonia pairs are better for sweaty hikes as the MeUndies tend to get a little swamped.</p><p>Three pairs of underwear might seem like too few, and feel free to adjust as necessary, but by and large: one to wear, one to wash, one that’s dry. This motto means you’re almost always set for two days, and worst case, you can dry a pair on the outside of your bag while hiking. The Knix and Patagonia briefs dry in only a few hours, so you could wash before breakfast, and come back, coffee in hand to some clean drawers.</p><p>For bras, I stick to sports bras from Pact or Calvin Klein. I hate underwrites, and sports bras last a lot longer between washes.</p><h2 id="jacket-a-namejacketa">Jacket</h2><p>Your mileage may vary heavily on style and need for this category, but my go-tos always include the<a href="https://missionworkshop.com/products/the-torre-womens-high-performance-windpro-hoodie-jacket">Torre Wind Pro</a>. I recently bought a second one of these, and even though I think Mission Workshop is getting rid of their women’s line (boo hiss), this is an incredible hoodie. It is DWR coated so light rain just falls off, and also fleece-lined so by itself I can handle temperatures down to 8c/46f. Colder or wetter, and I bring an overcoat. The two coats in my rotation right now are the<a href="https://www.arcteryx.com/us/en/shop/womens/codetta-coat">Arcteryx Codetta</a> and the<a href="https://snowpeak.com/products/jk-18au004-fr-rain-trench?variant=13074792972386">Snow Peak FR Rain Trench</a> (which is also<em>fireproof</em>?!). Good layering means even at freezing temperatures, I do well. If it was super cold, I’d probably include a wool sweater to wear under or over my hoodie, and I’d throw my leggings on under my pants.</p><h2 id="shoes-and-socks-a-nameshoesa">Shoes and socks</h2><p><a href="https://bombas.com/products/women-s-solid-invisibles-tan-small?variant=black">Bombas</a> or Darn Tough are the way to go for socks. Most of the time it’s not cold enough to wear longer socks, so I wear no-shows or ankle socks. Wool means these also wick well, and wash easily—depending on your food funk, a couple days is usually fine between washes.</p><p>If it’s cold or wet, I’m wearing<a href="https://www.blundstone.com/shop/black-premium-leather-chelsea-boots-womens-style-558">Blundstones</a>, or<a href="https://www.adidas.com/us/stan-smith-shoes/M20327.html">Stan Smiths</a>. Summer means something light and knit like<a href="https://www.adidas.com/us/samba-sock-primeknit-shoes/CQ2218.html">these Sambas</a>. Lightweight, comfortable, and breathable means you only need one pair of shoes. If they’re black, even sneakers work in many slightly fancy situations. In my opinion, sandals should only show up in a public shower, or on the beach, so I never bring any.</p><h2 id="hat">Hat</h2><p>A wool beanie is great for warmth, so I wear<a href="https://www.tannergoods.com/products/merino-watch-cap">this one from Tanner Goods</a>. It’s expensive, but it holds up.</p><h2 id="plan-ahead">Plan ahead</h2><p>All of my clothing works well for me, but I typically go to Europe or Japan. If you go somewhere much hotter or much colder, you’ll definitely need to adjust, especially if you go from a freezing spot to a hot one. If you end up bringing a lot of stuff for one leg of a trip, you can always mail stuff home too. Layering is your friend. There’re a lot of<a href="https://www.carryology.com/travel/how-what-to-put-in-your-minimalist-travel-capsule-wardrobe/">lists for women</a> that have much more feminine clothing, but that’s not really my jam. For me, functional > cute any day of the week. But, regardless of your style choice, stretchy, lightweight clothing is the way to go.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Travel kit update</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-03-13-travel-kit-update/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-03-13-travel-kit-update/</guid><description>Since 2019, I updated my kit a little bit, but mostly it stayed the same.
One old bag, one new My Ryu Quickpack was a delight once-again, as I used it to transport all my gear to Japan, and then from city to city. Most days it sat in my room as I travelled around with my DSPTCH Waist Bag or just what I could fit in my pockets. Ergonimically, this bag is one of the most comfortable bags I&amp;rsquo;ve owned, but due to its size, I don&amp;rsquo;t like hauling it around all day.</description><content:encoded><p>Since 2019, I updated my kit a<a href="https://twitter.com/brookshelley/status/1100823338497105921">little bit</a>, but mostly it stayed the same.</p><h2 id="one-old-bag-one-new">One old bag, one new</h2><p>My Ryu Quickpack was a delight once-again, as I used it to transport all my gear to Japan, and then from city to city. Most days it sat in my room as I travelled around with my DSPTCH Waist Bag or just what I could fit in my pockets. Ergonimically, this bag is one of the most comfortable bags I&rsquo;ve owned, but due to its size, I don&rsquo;t like hauling it around all day. I hoped that the DSPTCH bag would work really well during day to day travel, and it probably would have if it hadn&rsquo;t rained every day. The waist bag isn&rsquo;t waterproof (boo), or particularly comfortable for long stretches (double boo), due to the one shoulder setup. I wear the Waist Bag to work almost every day, but for way less time, so I&rsquo;d forgotten how little continual stress my left shoulder can take. Also, I learned that with<a href="https://www.arcteryx.com/us/en/shop/womens/codetta-coat">my rain coat</a> on, the bag slides up uncomfortably against my neck, so next time I&rsquo;ll need a day backpack again. Most days, I chose not to bring a bag to avoid this discomfort. I hauled my LAMY Safari pen + a<a href="https://www.jetpens.com/Hobonichi-Techo-Weeks/ct/4399">Hobonichi Weeks</a>, my phone, and some tissue paper, so a bag was overkill mostly.</p><h2 id="two-jackets">Two jackets</h2><p>I took my Arcteryx coat to Japan, and it served me well, despite being a<em>little</em> tight. However, I wandered into a Snow Peak store early in the trip, and my friend Sarah and the shopkeeper convinced me to try on a steeply discounted<a href="https://snowpeak.com/collections/outerwear-1/products/jk-18au004-fr-rain-trench?variant=13074792972386">Japanese XL<em>fire resistant</em> jacket</a>. It fit like a charm, and was long enough to easily cover my knees so I could stay warm and dry in the constant rain. I alternated between the two coats through the rest of the wet trip, but with both in my RYU bag, there wasn&rsquo;t much room for other stuff. I never plan on buying much in Japan, and certainly not clothes, so this was a pleasant surprise. As a back-up, I had a packable Baggu tote, but I never had to resort to carrying stuff in the tote on the way home. If I were traveling to a rainy area again, I&rsquo;d only bring one coat, and which one would depend on how much layering I needed to do. It&rsquo;s kinda nice to have options.</p><h2 id="just-enough-space">Just enough space</h2><p>By the end of my trip the RYU bag was a<em>tight</em> zip. I bought two manga tankoban, and one Japanese novel, as well as a series of gachapon souvenirs,<a href="https://www.tokyoweekender.com/2015/05/japanese-lucky-charms-the-guide-to-omamori/">omamori</a>, and a load of Vick&rsquo;s lozenges because of my cold. Everything fit, along with my two jackets, but only<em>just</em> so. I wore my DSPTCH bag on the front, outside of the RYU to get on the plane or train, but I could stuff it in if I needed to.</p><h2 id="planned-changes">Planned changes</h2><p>Next trip, if the weather is similar, my plan is to bring one jacket, and not buy another. Additionally, two pairs of pants was really beneficial, but<a href="http://www.coalatree.com/collections/kachula/products/trailhead-adventure-pant">a new pair I bought</a> should pack better than<a href="https://shop.nordstrom.com/s/nike-nikelab-x-mmw-womens-pants/4796841">the Nike pants</a> I brought, so that will save some space. My<a href="http://www.goby.co/products/electric-toothbrush-all-black">new toothbrush</a> worked swimmingly, and I didn&rsquo;t bring a charger, since my trip was ~2 weeks. I brought just enough toiletries, and that felt nice. I wish I&rsquo;d brought a tank top to sleep in, as I only had two shirts, so I felt like one was always a little funky from sleep, but because they wick, it was alright. For a daypack, I might look for an ultralight packable daypack, like one from Matador or<a href="http://www.ynotmade.com/en/shop/splitshift/?sku=5808">YNOT</a>, but my Topo Designs bag is probably good enough.</p><h2 id="next-trip">Next trip</h2><p>Next time I fly, it’s a short trip to Portland for a conference I’m doing a talk at with some friends. Two days means I’ll bring my Oppose This bag, and have a chill, easy time. Hopefully I’ll get to go back to Japan later this year and test this whole load-out again.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>Pack light and still enjoy the trip</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2016-04-14-pack-light-and-still-enjoy-the-trip/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2016-04-14-pack-light-and-still-enjoy-the-trip/</guid><description>Why I choose to travel with a 16L bag everywhere I go.
The Past Years ago, I stopped checking bags when I flew. I’d seen too many things get lost over the years, my own and other’s, and couldn’t stomach the thought of landing somewhere again, only to lose all my possessions. So, I began using a canvas duffel bag, as well as a small backpack.
The bag is grey, and around 30L in volume, has little toggle closures, and a couple internal pockets.</description><content:encoded><p>Why I choose to travel with a 16L bag everywhere I go.</p><h2 id="the-past">The Past</h2><p>Years ago, I stopped checking bags when I flew. I’d seen too many things get lost over the years, my own and other’s, and couldn’t stomach the thought of landing somewhere again, only to lose all my possessions. So, I began using a canvas duffel bag, as well as a small backpack.</p><p>The bag is grey, and around 30L in volume, has little toggle closures, and a couple internal pockets. It was great for trips in the car to Dallas to see my partner at the time’s family, or anywhere that I didn’t need to carry it. But it was horrible for planes and walking.</p><p>For a while, I just dealt with the shoulder pain and annoyance of a single, cross-chest strap full of gear, in addition to my backpack. But it hurt, and I didn’t really like the way I looked, carrying two different bags. I still felt much better about my setup than I would with a large rectangle of soon-to-be-lost gear, but I wanted to simplify more.</p><p><em>A note on my able-bodied privilege</em> This choice to carry a smaller bag, regardless of weight, is one that I was able to make because of my body. For those with chronic pain, or difficulty carrying weight on their back for whatever reason, my setup will likely not work. I see a lot of folks get frustrated with rolling bags, and I have shared that sentiment in the past, but it is very shitty to the folks who need those bags for any reason.</p><h2 id="simplify-your-gear">Simplify your gear</h2><p><em>Pack lighter by packing less</em></p><h3 id="clothing">Clothing</h3><p>The first thing I did to simplify, was to see what I could live without. Many of the<em>extras</em> that I was sure of needing got tossed. No more extra shoes for a trip. No more than the number of underwear I would need for the trip (and often less — it’s easy to hand-wash). Two bras (<strong>Nude label</strong>). A couple shirts that could also be hand-washed easily (yoga tank-tops from<strong>Lucy</strong>). Wool socks, usually two pairs. With my wardrobe thus whittled, I turned to my love of books.</p><h3 id="books">Books</h3><p>In the past I always brought at least 3 books with me on trip of more than 3 or 4 days, as I’d likely go through all of them. Books are heavy. Like, really heavy, and not very easy to pack tightly, especially if they’re lengthy. A<strong>Kindle</strong> helped fix that problem immediately. I bought the cheapest one, with ads, and loaded it up with a few books I’d acquired over the years, and some free ones from Project Gutenberg. I don’t like giving my money to Amazon, but there are other ways to buy books that support independent bookstores. Now I could carry as many books as I wanted, and acquire new ones instantly, without needing to add to the weight of my pack. Don’t get me wrong, I still love the smell and feel of books, and have a library at home that I treasure, but just like my other stuff, I don’t need to travel with everything I care about.</p><h3 id="electronics">Electronics</h3><p>When it came to electronics, I was already pretty lightweight. I had the ability to afford a<strong>Macbook Air</strong>, and learned that each year I could sell the previous one and buy a new one for ~100 dollars or so if I kept it from getting banged up. This 13&rdquo;, slim laptop could go most anywhere with me with a minimal strain on my back. I had a slender<strong>Tom Bhin</strong> sleeve for it, and its charger. I also had my<strong>iPhone</strong>, my Kindle (as mentioned above), and a small USB cable for both. In recent years, I’ve switched to the<strong>Macbook</strong>, which is even smaller and lighter than the Air. My company bought me a Kindle Paperwhite, so now I can read on dark planes with minimal disturbance. I also purchased an<strong>Anker</strong> powercore 15600 that can charge my phone ~6 times before needing to be charged itself. It’s a little heavy, but has made a huge difference in how I travel, as I don’t need to worry as much about finding an outlet when I am sure to need directions and contact with folks via Twitter, email, or text. For headphones, I’ve always loved in-ear ones, but on long flights, they are painful at best. I got a pair of **ATH-M40Xs **that I adore, and usually wear them around my neck when I’m not listening to them on trips. When I get where I am traveling, I often leave them in the room and switch to my<strong>RHA 10Ti</strong> in-ear-monitors. There are better headphones for the price, but these work well for me, and most-importantly, fit into my phone while the case is on it, unlike my<strong>Shure 215k</strong> that I previously wore everywhere.</p><p>The final electronic device I bring is a vibrator. At home, I have quite the array, and particularly love my wireless<strong>Magic Wand</strong>. But, taking a note from a friend about not becoming dependent on what amounts to a power tool, I travel with the easily-packed<strong>JimmyJane Form 2</strong>. It does the trick, has a travel mode (so it doesn’t vibrate in my bag), and is waterproof to boot.</p><h3 id="other-clothes">Other clothes</h3><p>When I go anywhere with either changeable temperature, or the likelihood of rain, I bring my<a href="http://www.ilsejacobsen.com/womens-raincoat-RAIN50.html?c=76695">**Ilse Jacobsen Raincoat 50</a> **jacket. It’s black, minimally adorned, and waterproof. I love it. Before I had this jacket, I always brought my older<strong>Marmot Precip</strong>, which could be stowed in my bag easily, unlike this new jacket. With warmer weather, I will probably return to that jacket, for ease of carry.</p><p>Yoga pants are the best. For both comfort on the plane, and versatile city exploring, I always bring a pair of yoga leggings that are black, and durable. The ones I have now are from Lucy, but anything will do. With these, my socks, and the yoga tanks I wear, the key is wicking. I sweat easily, and don’t always have a great way to wash clothes, so having clothing that stays pretty stink-free, and dry, is a huge plus. It also packs down really easily due to the thinness of the fabric. You might want something a little thicker if you get cold more easily. Sometimes I bring wool tights too, to wear under these or my jeans.</p><p>For pants, I also bring a pair of high-waisted, stretchy black jeans. This is a style choice, but I love them. I pack these in my bag while flying, and then wear them around half the time I’m on my trip. I also bring a small pair of shorts (<strong>Foxers</strong>), for sleeping and wandering around my hotel, or hostel.</p><h3 id="toiletries">Toiletries</h3><p>I don’t wear much makeup, and that means my toiletry packing is pretty straightforward. I bring a stick of eyeliner, a stick of lipstain, some coconut-oil deodorant, essential oil, and a toothbrush. I pack these in the front pocket of my backpack, along with my medicine, and some hand-sanitizer for those times I have no idea where to wash my hands, but want to eat.</p><p>I also bring a water bottle, which is a<strong>Hydroflask</strong>, but have thought about getting a collapsable water bottle, the<strong>Vapur</strong>, soon. (Edit: I got a Vapor bottle, and it’s amazing. It can fold up and fit in the small front zipper of my Fjalraven bag along with the makeup and pill-bottle I keep in there. A+)</p><h3 id="the-bag">The bag</h3><p>I switch between two bags these days, depending on condition. If there will be a lot of rain, or I expect my bag to get jostled significantly, I bring my<strong>Mission Workshop 21L Sancturary</strong> bag. It’s super durable, and has held up to international travel and mistreatment in my often clumsy hands, and stayed strong for the past 6 years or so. In an effort to get even lighter, as well as have something cuter to walk around cities like NYC with, I picked up a<strong>Fjalraven Kånken</strong> bag. At 16L, it’s pretty small, but I can still fit all my packed gear inside. My only complaint with this bag, is that with my stuff in it, it can be difficult to get my laptop out in the TSA line. I never dealt with this problem using my Mission Workshop bag, because it has a folding top, that allows for easy access to the laptop in the back. The Fjalraven is a zipper system at the front of the bag, so I have to roll the top back with it unzipped to pull out my laptop. I’m considering cutting the bag and adding another zipper, but we’ll see. It’s less of a problem with the bag less tightly packed, so it’s likely this will just lead to me packing a little bit less each time, and that’s not so bad.</p><p><em>Final recommendation:</em> Years ago I read an article written by a designer who decided to travel without any clothes, save for enough underwear to get her through the trip. She loved the opportunity to hit up a thrift store and buy interesting outfits, which she would re-sell, or donate at the end of her trip. She figured she was saving hassle by not bringing extra clothes, and saving money, potentially, by not needing to check a bag. I love this idea, but as a woman who has a hard time finding well-fitting clothes (I’m 5'10, athletic, and wide-hipped), I don’t want to take that kind of risk. But, if you love shopping, have a frame that is more welcoming to thrift clothes, and feel ok with buying and getting rid of these temporary outfits, then I recommend trying her style of light packing. You might find that the short-lived nature of these clothes inspire you to make riskier or more interesting choices, and maybe even mailing a few pieces back home.</p><h2 id="wrap-up">Wrap up</h2><p>There are many reasons why I’ve decided to pack as light as I do, and it’s become a thing I both enjoy and find ways to challenge as I continue to travel regularly. Questioning the stuff I own, and finding a way to make cute outfits with limited options is a fun way to make the most of a limited budget, or a temporarily limited wardrobe. A lot of folks I know love to bring large bags with extra shoes, more clothes than they wear, and options for most gear. I’m glad they found what works for them, but I’m also very happy to have figured out a minimal pack that feel like I have enough for a week or two. However you decide to pack, light, heavy, or not at all, I hope you enjoy your travels, take some pictures, and breath.</p></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>