<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Fennel &amp; Dill</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/brookshelley/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Fennel &amp; Dill</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Copyright Brook Shelley 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.brookshelley.com/brookshelley/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Favorite Movies of 2019</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/brookshelley/posts/2020-01-01-my-favorite-movies-of-2019/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/brookshelley/posts/2020-01-01-my-favorite-movies-of-2019/</guid><description>Out of 74 movies, I wanted to pick a few that really stood out, and then talk briefly about a few that I really didn't enjoy. I went to the theater quite a bit this year, as I live pretty close to one with couch-seats and luckily have a few film-buddies to meet up with. Other films that I didn't get a chance to see while they were on the big screen were rented at home or watched through a myriad of streaming services I've accrued over the years.</description></item><item><title>Media diet for December</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/brookshelley/posts/2019-12-31-media-diet-for-december/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/brookshelley/posts/2019-12-31-media-diet-for-december/</guid><description>Books Dept. of Speculation — Jenny Offill
A gorgeous and sad book that captures long relationships so well. I loved for narrator and the strange poetic style of storytelling. I read this in two sittings and was enraptured.
Dead Astronauts — Jeff Vandermeer
This book did some interesting things with time, and some deeply annoying things with text. I feel like I know what he was doing with this book largely, and support his environmental aims (a+ murderous blue fox), but it never really came together for me.</description></item><item><title>What I learned from sending a newsletter this year</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/brookshelley/posts/2019-12-30-what-i-learned-from-sending-a-newsletter-this-year/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/brookshelley/posts/2019-12-30-what-i-learned-from-sending-a-newsletter-this-year/</guid><description>Way back in February of 2019, I sent my first newsletter—a repost of a blog post about learning Japanese, then petered out for a bit. In July, I began sending weekly link emails, which I managed to keep up through the end of the year. It's been quite a fun Sunday activity, so I thought I'd chat a bit about what the experience of weekly link writing was like.
Why links?</description></item><item><title>My Favorite Books of 2019</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/brookshelley/posts/2019-12-16-my-favorite-books-of-2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/brookshelley/posts/2019-12-16-my-favorite-books-of-2019/</guid><description>This year I read 55 books and a lot of graphic novels. Fortunately, most of them were pretty great, which made it even harder to pick out my five favorite. I gravitated towards a lot of fantasy and sci-fi in 2019 as a nice way to escape or even think about a potentially scarier future. My plan to keep reading primarily female authors also paid off.
In no particular order, here’s the list:</description></item><item><title>Bellroy Studio Pack Review</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/brookshelley/posts/2019-12-13-bellroy-studio-pack-review/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/brookshelley/posts/2019-12-13-bellroy-studio-pack-review/</guid><description>A new backpack for everyday carry, and travel.
First Sight After first getting my new Bellroy sling, I fell in love with the delightful material for these bags. A few months later in Iitoya in Japan, I got to see their new Shift backpack in person, and almost bought one on the spot. that bag was a little larger than I need, but then I saw this. With the launch of the Studio Backpack, Bellroy has made an excellent bag that holds a little or a lot without every looking absurd.</description></item><item><title>xoxo 2015</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/brookshelley/posts/2015-09-14-xoxo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/brookshelley/posts/2015-09-14-xoxo/</guid><description>XOXO Fest recap
This is my first XOXO, and as with many festivals or conferences where I know I might be overwhelmed, I was a little apprehensive. It helped so much that we had Slack setup for XOXO months in advance. I met tons of rad people in and around the tech industry while I was online, and then when the XOXO started, I was prepared with a group of new and old friends.</description></item><item><title>on being alone</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/brookshelley/posts/2014-3-4-on-being-alone/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/brookshelley/posts/2014-3-4-on-being-alone/</guid><description>A bit about this last few months.
It first hit me the night she left. The quiet. Before, there was rustling in the house, subtle signs of her presence, affection in the same space. Now, the night was too quiet, her form did not move with breath next to me. I was alone. My cats tried to fill the void. The wandered, and meowed, and looked for her in closets and cabinets — or so it seemed to me, as I projected my sadness onto them.</description></item><item><title>The Allure of the Minimal and Disconnected</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/brookshelley/posts/2013-04-26-the-allure-of-the-minimal-and-disconnected/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/brookshelley/posts/2013-04-26-the-allure-of-the-minimal-and-disconnected/</guid><description>The Future Most films that show our future are full of glitz and glamour, a fantastical land of flying vehicles. People live in clean, modern homes, and have their lives radically improved through technology, and want for nothing. Families and workers seamlessly keep in touch, and share parts of their lives with their friends and companions, and generally embrace the technology all around them.
If there is any enemy or ill feeling in the protagonist, it is usually an overlord or corporation that is taking over or slowly consuming their society.</description></item></channel></rss>