<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>homescreen on dill &amp; fennel</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/homescreen/</link><description>Recent content in homescreen on dill &amp; fennel</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Copyright Brook Shelley 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/homescreen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>2019 iOS Homescreen</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-28-2019-iphone-homescreen/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-11-28-2019-iphone-homescreen/</guid><description>Another year has rushed past, and with it, another iPhone update and some changes to my phone since last year&amp;rsquo;s setup. My use of a single screen of apps continues, with a few major and minor changes alongside.
I&amp;rsquo;ve posted these for the past few years, so if you want to see what apps I was using in 2017, here you go.
Some things change 3 app dock—I moved my Twitter app out of my dock in order to spend less time on Twitter.</description><content:encoded><p>Another year has rushed past, and with it, another iPhone update and some changes to my phone since<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/blog/2018/12/14/2018-iphone-homescreen-update.html">last year&rsquo;s setup</a>. My use of a single screen of apps continues, with a few major and minor changes alongside.</p><p><img src="/photos/2019iphone.png" alt="2019 iPhone Screen"/><p>I&rsquo;ve posted these for the past few years, so if you want to see what apps I was using in<a href="https://medium.com/@brookshelley/2017-homescreen-ac92817eae60">2017, here you go</a>.</p><h2 id="some-things-change">Some things change</h2><p><strong>3 app dock</strong>—I moved my Twitter app out of my dock in order to spend less time on Twitter. I figured if I wanted to to launch it I could easily search for it, but perhaps by having it out of reach I wouldn&rsquo;t launch the app out of habit or boredom. This worked pretty well.</p><p><strong>Fantastical</strong>—Last year I said &ldquo;This is definitely the app I am most interested in replacing.&rdquo; I replaced it with<strong>iOS Calendar</strong> not too long after writing this post because of the cleaner look, date view icon, and a better visualization of my next meeting on my phone and watch. I also really hate how Fantastical uses space on the iPad. I still hope that someday Apple opens up the ability to change icons based on events or time, but until they do, I&rsquo;ll have a hard time moving away from the default calendar.</p><p><strong>Bear</strong>—I moved completely off of Bear in favor of<strong>iAWriter</strong>, largely due to<a href="https://workingcopy.app">Working Copy</a>, which is an excellent Git client for iOS devices, and means I can use iAWriter&rsquo;s file function to open up posts like this one that live in my personal blog&rsquo;s Drafts folder.</p><p><strong>Google Maps</strong>—I moved back to<strong>Apple Maps</strong>. In general Apple Maps got a lot better, and works better on my watch. Also, in Japan, Apple Maps often shows results from TabeLog, which tends to have much better local recommendations.</p><p><strong>Tweetbot</strong>—I replaced this with the weird beta Twitter app<strong>twttr</strong>. It&rsquo;s hidden in a folder now to encourage me to not use it as often, and that is working pretty well.</p><p><strong>Fiery Feeds</strong>—<em><strong>Reeder 4</strong> came out</em> and it&rsquo;s amazing. I moved to Reeder 4 on all of my devices, and I love it. The read later feature has also replaced Safari&rsquo;s read later for me in all instances. I don&rsquo;t use Bionic reading, but it&rsquo;s a neat feature regardless. I continue to use<a href="https://feedbin.com">Feedbin</a> to back my RSS.</p><h2 id="some-things-stay-the-same">Some things stay the same</h2><p><strong>Overcast</strong> — Overcast is great. This year it just got better, from CarPlay, to the watch, to my phone. I am really excited for Marco to update for more Airplay 2 features as he mentioned in a recent episode of<a href="https://atp.fm/episodes/352">ATP</a>. There are other podcast apps out there, but for smart-speed, playlists, and everything else, there is only Overcast.</p><p><strong>Spark</strong>—I kept using Spark this year, especially as they updated for a great black-screened-OLED-friendly dark mode, and<a href="https://sparkmailapp.com/blog/new-design-dark-mode-ios13">rethought their entire interface in 2.5</a>. This is a great email app on all my devices, and has fantastic keyboard support for iPadOS.</p><p><strong>Apple Music</strong>—I&rsquo;ve barely opened Spotify all year. Apple Music keeps getting better, and it seems like more of my friends have moved over to it as well.</p><p><strong>Things</strong>—This app is how I keep track of all my work and personal tasks. It&rsquo;s incredible. Keyboard shortcuts are available on iOS and Mac, and in general this app is a great example of how a cross-platform app should function.</p><p><strong>Apple Photos</strong>—This app got a lot better in iOS 13, and I really enjoy it. Not much else to say.</p><p><strong>Slack</strong>—I work at Slack still, and it&rsquo;s still a great app.</p><p><strong>Single folder</strong>—65 extra apps live in this folder. They range from rarely-used travel apps for work, to translation apps, to video and banking apps. I don&rsquo;t<em>love</em> all of the apps in this folder, but I regularly go through them to make sure they&rsquo;re still needed.</p><h2 id="the-best-of-the-rest">The best of the rest</h2><p>A few of the apps that live inside my large catch-all folder and are opened via search.</p><p><strong>Working Copy</strong>—This app is amazing. In addition to functioning as a great Git tool, it also has syntax and code-highlighting for tons of languages. I don&rsquo;t work in Working Copy all the time, but when I&rsquo;m iPad-only, I use it quite a bit for work and my personal projects.</p><p><strong>Google Fi</strong>—I moved to Google Fi last year from AT&amp;T largely due to the free and easy international roaming. It&rsquo;s great.</p><p><strong>Tsurukame</strong>—This is my daily second job. I spend around two hours a day in this app and reading in order to become fully literate in Japanese. As I write this, I&rsquo;m at level 39, and have over 1300 Kanji above Guru level. Learning Japanese is super hard, but worth it.</p><p><strong>Plex</strong>—Lots of video sources live here. It&rsquo;s a great app, and I wish other video streaming services would learn from Plex&rsquo;s great example.</p><p><strong>1Password</strong>—All my passwords live here, and are super long and complex. Similar to Things, I don&rsquo;t think I could work the same way without 1Password.</p><h2 id="wrap-up">Wrap-up</h2><p>Last year I suggested my list of apps might not shift much, but five of my major home screen apps changed due to updates and simplicity. I&rsquo;m happy this year with the apps that I use and due to my requirements of quality Apple Watch, Mac, and iPadOS cross-platform functionality the bar is really high for other apps to knock these off of my phone. I&rsquo;m very excited about iOS 14, especially with news that it might be more stable than the particularly rough iOS 13 release. Perhaps Apple will give more features to devs that unlock unimagined new functionality. We&rsquo;ll find out in 6 months.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>2018 iPhone Homescreen</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-12-14-2018-iphone-homescreen-update/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-12-14-2018-iphone-homescreen-update/</guid><description>Back to a single screen.
It’s been a year and change since I posted about my iPhone apps and homescreen. I tend to try out new apps pretty often, but now that I use an iPad and an Apple Watch every day, I generally stick with things that support all 3 of my screens well. Some apps have stuck around, but many have been replaced by better (for me) choices. Trying to settle into apps that I use for a long stretch is challenging as businesses fail, or apps stagnate, so here we are.</description><content:encoded><p>Back to a single screen.</p><p><img src="/photos/iphone2018.jpeg" alt="iphone"/><p>It’s been a year and change since I posted about my<a href="https://medium.com/@brookshelley/2017-homescreen-ac92817eae60">iPhone apps and homescreen</a>. I tend to try out new apps pretty often, but now that I use an iPad and an Apple Watch every day, I generally stick with things that support all 3 of my screens well. Some apps have stuck around, but many have been replaced by better (for me) choices. Trying to settle into apps that I use for a long stretch is challenging as businesses fail, or apps stagnate, so here we are.</p><h2 id="old-apps">Old apps</h2><p><strong>Timepage</strong>—without support for the new style of WatchOS complications, I switched to Fantastical again. I don’t<em>love</em> it, but I want to use the same app in both places.</p><p><strong>Casts</strong>—replaced with<strong>Overcast</strong>.</p><p><strong>Maps</strong>—replaced with<strong>Google Maps</strong>.</p><p><strong>Airmail</strong>—replaced with<strong>Spark</strong>.</p><p><strong>Twitter</strong>—replaced with<strong>Tweetbot</strong>.</p><p><strong>Spotify</strong>—replaced with<strong>Apple Music</strong>.</p><p><strong>Instagram</strong>—I quit Instagram around the start of 2018 in a dual-effort to rid myself of FB-owned apps, and to stop using an increasingly user-antagonistic app that really bummed me out more than it made me happy.</p><p><strong>Todoist</strong>—replaced with<strong>Things</strong>.</p><p><strong>Google Photos</strong>—replaced with<strong>Apple Photos</strong>.</p><p><strong>iCloud Drive</strong>—this became<strong>Files</strong>.</p><p><strong>Tons of folders</strong>—this felt overwhelming, and eventually I decided against it, and went back to titles instead of emoji, and now whittled my apps down to a single folder.</p><h2 id="new-apps">New apps</h2><p><strong>Fantastical</strong>—this is an<em>ok</em> calendaring app. I don&rsquo;t love the visual style, or the colors, but compared to my other options this is what I have available. Timepage doesn&rsquo;t have new watch complications. Google Calendar doesn&rsquo;t even have a watch app. iOS Calendar is ok, but doesn&rsquo;t do NLP well, or handle meetings/etc well. This is definitely the app I am most interested in replacing.</p><p><strong>Fiery Feeds</strong>—Reeder 4 is perpetually<em>coming soon</em>, so my allegiance to it is on pause until the 4th iteration brings support for my new iPad, and other nice things like full-text display. Fiery Feeds, despite an icon that I vaguely loathe, is a great app with a solid dark mode, and a bunch of cool options. It&rsquo;s very customizable, and can adapt a bit to your style of RSS. I wish it had a Mac app, but AFAIK the only great RSS reader that works everywhere is Reeder.</p><p><strong>Spark</strong>—I don&rsquo;t use email as often anymore now that I work at a company that doesn&rsquo;t use email (we really don&rsquo;t). But, when I do, Spark is great. Solid watch app. Solid Mac and iPad support, including keyboard shortcuts. I still hope for iOS dark mode support in the future, because on Mac the style is awesome. The calendar in this app is<em>almost</em> good enough to have me ditch my actual calendar, but unfortunately there&rsquo;s no way for Spark to show its calendar on my watch.</p><p><strong>Tweetbot</strong>—<a href="http://apps-of-a-feather.com">RIP third-party Twitter apps</a>. I use this app in defiance of Twitter&rsquo;s bad policy, and honestly the lack of likes and notifications is kind of a feature for me at this point. DMs are vaguely useless, but most of those conversations have moved to my favorite place to chat: Slack.</p><p><strong>Google Maps</strong>—I used Apple Maps pretty happily for a while, but eventually I wanted more recommendations and ratings, and I refuse to use Yelp for that. If Apple Maps connected to Foursquare, or supported commute scheduling, I&rsquo;d be back in a heartbeat. Also somehow Google Maps understands that SF trans-bay busses pick up at a temporary terminal, and Apple things they don&rsquo;t exist because the Salesforce garden of hubris is closed.</p><p><strong>Things</strong>—I love Things. Years ago when I worked for a certain fruit company, many of my coworkers used Things. I didn&rsquo;t really get it at the time, but also I didn&rsquo;t really get having things _to do_. Things helps me be an adult, and get things done. I run my life out of here, largely, and dump anything from chores to tv show recommendations in here. The new iOS dark mode support is spectacular. Similarly to Spark, the support of a calendar is<em>almost</em> good enough to not use a calendar app, but alas, the watch problem persists. Also the calendar is read-only, which could create an issue.</p><p><strong>Apple Music</strong>—I moved over from Spotify, mostly to try it out, and to have access to my music on my watch. It&rsquo;s fine? I don&rsquo;t really know if I prefer this app to Spotify, but it does what I want, plays the music I want to play, and works well on my Sonos and in my car. Recommendations have gotten better, and while I wish it did a better job of knowing which bands I like have new albums, I usually find out. Concert notifications would also be cool, if I were making a feature request. Oh, and also dark mode. Please.</p><h2 id="the-best-of-the-rest">The best of the rest</h2><p><strong>Slack</strong>—My love for the Slack app is strong. My friends live here. My chosen family lives here. My work lives here. I don&rsquo;t know what I would do without Slack. Before I worked for Slack, my company depended on Slack for everything from deploys, to bugs, to developer relations. Now that I work here, I&rsquo;m so happy how much I can accomplish inside of Slack. There&rsquo;s no way to fully express how much joy I feel doing my work in Slack. Seriously. This app redefines work.</p><p><strong>Bear</strong>—I really like Bear. Many notes that have actions end up in Things, but Bear is my dumping ground for workout stats, meeting notes, travel lists, and other assorted ephemera. When I wrote about Bear in 2017, I did more of my long-form writing in it, but now that has mostly moved to iAWriter. Bear always felt a little weird for long-form writing, and iAWriter&rsquo;s new duospaced font is<em>chef&rsquo;s kiss</em>. I still wish I could choose a black theme with a custom highlight color, because I hate orange and gold, but çest la vie.</p><p><strong>iAWriter</strong>—this app lives in a folder, but for my iPad and my Mac, it&rsquo;s how I write. The ability to open files that life in Working Copy, that really live in a Github repo that runs this site is ideal The colors are what I would choose if I had full-control. It&rsquo;s truly a masterful writing app.</p><h2 id="moving-to-a-search-first-model">Moving to a “search first” model</h2><p>When I moved all of my apps to one screen, and began stuffing the majority in a single folder, I wanted to see if I would use search. On my iPad or my Mac, I almost always open apps with Spotlight, but on my iPhone, I usually would flick through screens or folders, aimlessly looking for<em>something to tap</em>, or even hunt for the app I use to book movie tickets. This felt like a waste of time, and further, became a nervous habit. Now that I mostly search for apps, I find myself doing less nervous flicking, and mostly put my phone down when I don&rsquo;t have something to<em>do</em> with it. Out of sight, out of mind seems to be effective for me—maybe that says something about my object permanence? Lol.</p><h2 id="wrap-up">Wrap-up</h2><p>I really want a new calendar app. I want someone to come into the calendar world and shake it up—or I want Spark or Things to have access to show their calendar on my watch. Or, I want Timepage to update their watch integration. Other than that, I&rsquo;m pretty happy with my setup at this point, and find my phone helpful, pleasant, and additive. I&rsquo;m curious to see how many of these apps I use again a year from now, but I have a feeling the list might not shift much. If you&rsquo;re a phone fidgeter, I definitely recommend putting most of your apps in one folder, and maybe even<a href="https://medium.com/@brookshelley/reclaim-your-time-with-parental-controls-9224612a6c1b"><em>reclaiming your time</em></a>. If you have apps you<em>love</em> that you want to talk about, hit me up @brookshelley on Twitter, or leave a small gift at the base of the largest tree in your town. I will know.</p></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>