<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>thoughts on dill &amp; fennel</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/thoughts/</link><description>Recent content in thoughts on dill &amp; fennel</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Copyright Brook Shelley 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>on the perfect thing</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-05-27-on-the-perfect-thing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-05-27-on-the-perfect-thing/</guid><description>The search for the best, most optimized, beautiful, light, and pleasing things.
Why do we search? Scrolling through my RSS feeds, I’m reminded daily that so much stuff exists. I subscribe to newsletters for fashion, backpacks, apps, and general tech, and every single one has an endless march through the days of new things. This app has two columns for editing! This backpack is “able to transition from work to play and travel.</description></item><item><title>slower reading</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-02-10-slower-reading/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-02-10-slower-reading/</guid><description>With the death of Google Reader in 2013 it seems like many folks gave up on RSS. Fortunately, not only is RSS still alive, but it's thriving. Between Newsletters and a return to blogging by many writers, thinkers, and web folks, RSS is an excellent way to find news and joy. While Twitter and other networks flounder, open standards provide a simple way to read. RSS means no trolls and no reply gifs.</description></item><item><title>learning kanji again</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-01-27-learning-kanji-again/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-01-27-learning-kanji-again/</guid><description>My first Japanese class In 1996 I took my first Japanese class at Austin Community College. I was in middle school at the time, and decided to learn how to read Japanese so I could read literature and comics. The class was fun, and also super weird, since I was the only kid there. I took two semesters, but a lot of life happened at once, so I stopped taking Japanese, and didn’t being again until University, five years later.</description></item><item><title>moving to the bay</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-11-21-moving-to-the-bay/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-11-21-moving-to-the-bay/</guid><description>Queers and Steers As a Texan, and a lesbian, I knew eventually I’d end up in California. That’s what we do. We leave Texas, and go west. I’ve spent the past four years hundreds of miles north in Portland, OR working remotely for various companies. I loved the trees, and the few amazing friends I made there, but found it hard to get through the long, lonely winters. It didn’t help that most of my jobs were remote—Portland has a burgeoning tech scene, but in general jobs haven’t kept up with rising cost of living.</description></item><item><title>post-xoxo thoughts</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-09-10-xoxo-thoughts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-09-10-xoxo-thoughts/</guid><description>In my previous post, I talked about anticipating XOXO 2018, which ended last night. Today, I am tired, happy, and trying to remember what to do for work when I'm not awkwardly wandering around a stadium full of 2000+ people.
So. Many. People. This year I was overwhelmed by the size of XOXO in ways I hadn't been in the past. To be fair, two years ago I was only a year into working from home, whereas now I'm 3 years a hermit, but still, 2000 people is a lot.</description></item><item><title>3rd XOXO &amp; 1 Year Later</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-09-05-3rd-xoxo-and-anniversary/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-09-05-3rd-xoxo-and-anniversary/</guid><description>My 3rd XOXO Thinking about the next few days in Portland, I'm thrilled beyond measure. So many new and old friends will be in my city, wandering around, making and showing art, and eating tons of food. When I first attended XOXO in 2015 I had no idea what to expect. I'd been to SXSW for years, growing-up in Austin, but never before had I felt so surrounded by rad, like-minded people.</description></item><item><title>smoke gets in your eyes</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-20-smokey-skies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-20-smokey-skies/</guid><description>Due to a series of forest fires, Portland has looked like an alien planet for the past few weeks.
Every day I wake up and google &amp;ldquo;air quality&amp;rdquo; to see just how much I need to stay indoors, next to my air filter. My gym has closed for a few days for two weeks, and walking outside just plain sucks.
The only cool part is the sunsets are ridiculous, and the moon is red at night.</description></item><item><title>powerlifting</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-14-powerlifting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-14-powerlifting/</guid><description>Young Brook Growing up, I never wanted to be big. My parents were both over 6&amp;rsquo; tall, and I worried about being as big as them. Most of my friends ended up being shorter than me, and were usually skinnier too. I was made fun of for being &amp;ldquo;chubby&amp;rdquo; in middle school, and that stuck with me. Being fat or chubby or skinny all rule, but I didn't know that as a kid.</description></item><item><title>NYC</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-11-9-nyc-my-second-home/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-11-9-nyc-my-second-home/</guid><description>New York is my home for two months out of the year, but I only recently became acquainted with it. Growing up in Texas, I got the idea from my dad that NYC was some kind of devil city. He regarded it as a liberal place with people who walked too fast, and were too greedy. The first time I visited in my mid-twenties, I realized just how wrong he was.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts on Grace Hopper Conference</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-10-19-thoughts-on-grace-hopper/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-10-19-thoughts-on-grace-hopper/</guid><description>Arrival
“This conference is GIGANTIC!” was my first thought upon arriving at Grace Hopper. This year’s attendance was around 10,000 folks, mostly women, and the largest conference besides SXSW that I’ve attended. Like many tech conferences, GHC had an invaluable app that showed a stream of comments from attendees as well as a schedule and other information. Once I signed in, I spent a lot of time networking and finding folks from out of town as my chosen track “Open-Source” was largely bereft of personally relevant content.</description></item></channel></rss>