<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>process on dill &amp; fennel</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/process/</link><description>Recent content in process on dill &amp; fennel</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Copyright Brook Shelley 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/process/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>One year of newsletter</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-12-30-what-i-learned-from-sending-a-newsletter-this-year/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-12-30-what-i-learned-from-sending-a-newsletter-this-year/</guid><description>Way back in February of 2019, I sent my first newsletter—a repost of a blog post about learning Japanese, then petered out for a bit.</description><content:encoded><p>Way back in February of 2019, I sent my first newsletter—a repost of a<a href="https://dillandfennel.substack.com/p/learning-japanese-again">blog post about learning Japanese</a>, then petered out for a bit. In July, I began sending<a href="https://dillandfennel.substack.com/p/weekly-links">weekly link emails</a>, which I managed to keep up through the end of the year. It&rsquo;s been quite a fun Sunday activity, so I thought I&rsquo;d chat a bit about what the experience of weekly link writing was like.</p><h2 id="why-links">Why links?</h2><p>This year I got really stoked about Robin Sloan&rsquo;s<a href="https://desert.glass">Year of the Meteor</a> newsletter, which was full of incredible links that led me to read quite a bit, and even<a href="https://underarmbalm.com">change my deodorant brand</a>. Robin consistently finds interesting and strange things all over the web, and I thought, perhaps I could do the same. I struggle to find writing topics at times, but I still journal daily, and try to keep up a writing practice during the fallow uninspired periods. A weekly newsletter seemed like an excellent idea, but I tend to write less, and not more.</p><h3 id="a-brief-digression">A brief digression</h3><p>I&rsquo;ve found that writers are usually in one of two camps: the underwriters, and the overwriters. As a member of the former camp, I can crank out 1-2000 words in no time, but asking me to go beyond that is a torture, whereas my overwriting friends tend to need an editor to get down to 2000. Because of this the idea of writing a novel, or even a longish short story is really hard to consider—but short creative nonfiction? Hell yes.</p><h2 id="ok-back-to-the-links">Ok, back to the links</h2><p>Having realized I wasn&rsquo;t able to creatively write every week without a good prompt, I settled on looking around the web through the week, and sending my baubles to you, the reader, on Sundays. I settled on Sunday because it felt like a good time to have coffee and enjoy a little surfing around. Perhaps you do this reading on another day, but for me, Sundays are for coffee and words.</p><h2 id="finding-links">Finding links</h2><p>The links I share come from all over the place. Sometimes I reshare things I found in another newsletter, like<a href="https://www.densediscovery.com">Dense Discovery</a>, and other times, they come from my<a href="https://feedbin.com">long list of RSS feeds</a> (feel free to request my OPML file). I read quite a bit every day, both on and offline, so it really isn&rsquo;t hard to find a few tidbits to share.</p><h2 id="the-satisfaction-of-analytics">The satisfaction of analytics</h2><p>I don&rsquo;t spend a lot of time thinking about how many readers I&rsquo;ve amassed (spoiler, not many), but I do love that I can see that folks generally<em>are</em> reading the emails I send out. There&rsquo;s a small sense of accomplishment when I know that someone has found something neat because I shared it. I really do love a recommendation, and it seems like some of you do as well.</p><h2 id="platforms">Platforms</h2><p>This year began on<a href="https://substack.com">Substack</a>, which seems like a decent platform, and has attracted<a href="https://www.shatnerchatner.com">more than</a> a<a href="https://grace.substack.com">few friends</a> as users. As someone who isn&rsquo;t really planning to find success or payment via a newsletter, my main goals were something easy to use, and ideally something I could send content to directly from<a href="https://ia.net/writer">iAWriter</a>, my markdown editor of choice.</p><p>With that in mind, I was eager to switch to<a href="https://buttondown.email">ButtonDown</a> after reading about it via Robin Sloan. I love how both the<a href="https://www.notion.so/639bdb37786e489a960d4810ee6ce351?v=58ef759254094357bdb04d715e9c518b">roadmap</a> and<a href="https://buttondown.email/running-costs">costs</a> are fully public, and the developer responds really quickly via email. This small, sustainable app is something I&rsquo;m really keen on supporting, as I love sustainable apps much more than venture-funded privacy-less hockey-stick comapnies. Plus using Working Copy and Shortcuts, I managed to build on top of their really<a href="https://api.buttondown.email/v1/schema">easy to use API</a>, and now have a one-button send draft to ButtonDown</p><h2 id="next-year">Next year</h2><p>My plan currently is to just<em>keep on keeping on</em> with this weekly links newsletter, and aspire to continuing monthly blog posts about longer topics. If you have things you&rsquo;d love to see, or things you want to chat about, you know<a href="mailto:brookshelley+blog@gmail.com">how to reach me</a>.</p><p>Have a fantastic new year, and I&rsquo;ll see you next Sunday!</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>A Weekly Link Newsletter</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-07-21-newsletter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-07-21-newsletter/</guid><description>It’s official: I’ve joined the newsletter trend in earnest. I’ve had a newsletter for a few months now, but I wasn’t sure what to really do with it.</description><content:encoded><p>It’s official: I’ve joined the newsletter trend in earnest. I’ve had<a href="https://dillandfennel.substack.com">a newsletter</a> for a few months now, but I wasn’t sure what to really<em>do</em> with it. Fortunately, I realized what I love to see the most from some of my<a href="https://craigmod.com/roden/">favorite</a><a href="https://desert.glass">newsletters</a> is links to what these authors are reading this week—little jewels from internet wanderings.</p><p>My re-launched Dill and Fennel newsletter will have links to some of the more interesting or funny things I’ve seen in the previous week. Sometimes these may be links to books, or tweets with a little color commentary. If you read this site, you might enjoy<a href="https://dillandfennel.substack.com/subscribe?utm_source=menu&amp;simple=true&amp;next=https%3A%2F%2Fdillandfennel.substack.com%2F">subscribing</a>.</p><h2 id="this-site">This site</h2><p>I’ll still write here as often as I can, but I found myself wanting a quicker way to write weekly, without needing a<em>big</em> thing to blog about, or something to review. My monthly media diets will still be posted to brookshelley.com as well. It’s been fun to do tiny reviews of books and movies, even if it’s mostly for my own memory of what I consumed in a year. Not using Letterboxed or Goodreads for this was a very conscious decision—I want to own and control my own data. If you keep track of this kind of stuff yourself, or run your own little slice of the internet, I’d love to<a href="mailto:brookshelley@gmail.com">hear about it</a>!</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>On notes and todos</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-05-02-on-notes-and-todos/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-05-02-on-notes-and-todos/</guid><description>The latest episode of Supercomputer inspired me to write about how I work with notes, todos, and reminders every day. Part of the episode was centered on their mutual dissatisfaction with various notes apps, which I totally understand.</description><content:encoded><p><img src="/photos/iAWriter.png" alt="iawriter"/><p>The<a href="https://supercomputer.transistor.fm/#">latest episode of Supercomputer</a> inspired me to write about how I work with notes, todos, and reminders every day. Part of the episode was centered on their mutual dissatisfaction with various notes apps, which I totally understand. Over the years, I&rsquo;ve used<a href="https://brettterpstra.com/projects/nvalt/">NVAlt</a>, 1Writer, Bear, Evernote, Notes, and more to keep track of my thoughts, posts, and notes. Brett Terpstra keeps a<a href="https://brettterpstra.com/ios-text-editors/"><em>very good list</em></a> of all iOS text editors that includes information about their cross-platform functionality. These days, since I mostly use my iPad and iPhone when I&rsquo;m not at<a href="https://slack.com/">work</a>, it&rsquo;s vital that my notes and todo apps live happily on Mac, and iOS.</p><h2 id="notes-and-posts">Notes and posts</h2><p>Ever since I moved most of my personal computer work to an<a href="http://www.brookshelley.com/blog/2018/11/07/new-ipad-review.html">iPad Pro</a>, I&rsquo;ve wanted to make sure my notes and writing were easily accessible from wherever I happened to compute. I also wanted to post that writing to my<a href="https://www.brookshelley.com">blog</a> which hilariously I first talked about on my now abandoned<a href="https://medium.com/@brookshelley/why-i-built-a-markdown-book-blog-a07e1a6dd163">Medium</a>. Since I post things via Github pages, which is a near-as-makes-no-difference Jekyll instance, I need the ability to push markdown to Github. With<a href="https://workingcopyapp.com/">Working Copy</a>, this is super simple, and if I need to, I can write entire posts in the pretty nice editor that app contains. But, I want more!</p><p>To have a great writing experience, with delightful fonts, a pleasing design, and speedy sync, I use<a href="https://ia.net/writer">iAWriter</a>. It&rsquo;s<em>fantastic</em> for notes, long form writing, and even markdown previewing work docs. In the years since the first version of iAWriter launched, it&rsquo;s become an amazing piece of software. I couldn&rsquo;t find the earliest versions, but<a href="https://www.macworld.com/article/2985482/ia-writer-3-0-1-review-mac-app-gets-back-to-basics-for-focused-writing.html">here&rsquo;s the 2015 version 3</a>. Nowadays, iAWriter can talk to the Files app on iOS natively, which means you can open files from Working Copy, which is registered as a Files location, so you can open files from Github repos in iAWriter. Whether I&rsquo;m drafting a blog post, or updating my list of<a href="http://www.brookshelley.com/books">books</a> that I&rsquo;ve read, I open iAWriter first, after pulling the latest version of my repo in Working Copy. For writing and notes I don&rsquo;t plan to store in my repo, iAWriter keeps them on iCloud as<code>.md</code> files so I don&rsquo;t have to worry about portability or missing files. Because these files live in iCloud, they&rsquo;re searchable using Spotlight on both my iOS and Mac devices—no more depending on launching an app to search. It&rsquo;s wild how good this app combination is, and how fast I&rsquo;m able to find and edit things using iAWriter&rsquo;s native Apple integrations.</p><p>When I&rsquo;m at meetings at work, I also tend to take notes with a<a href="https://www.lamy.com/en/lamy-safari/">pen</a> and a<a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/2019/all_about/weeks/">notebook</a> because it<a href="https://www.npr.org/2016/04/17/474525392/attention-students-put-your-laptops-away">helps retention</a> and looks quite a bit less rude to my coworkers or partners. If something needs to be shared, I type it up in Slack or put it in a Readme on a repo.</p><p>But what about my todos?!</p><h2 id="todos">Todos</h2><p>I work at a company in San Francisco who&rsquo;s goal is to &ldquo;make work life simpler, more pleasant and more productive.&rdquo; I think we&rsquo;re good at it, but I&rsquo;ve found that I need a separate place to keep track of my work tasks, my life tasks, and all the random junk I need quick access to when I&rsquo;m going through my week.<a href="https://culturedcode.com/things/">Things</a> is that app for me. I made a Project for everything I work on, and Areas for things like &ldquo;stuff to buy&rdquo; or &ldquo;stuff to watch&rdquo;.</p><p><img src="/photos/projects.png" alt="projects"/><p>My main view is Today, where tasks I need to finish by bedtime live. When the workday ends, anything I haven&rsquo;t accomplished gets moved to tomorrow—this is a conscious choice over having those tasks follow me home. That means that I don&rsquo;t have the psychic dread of &ldquo;more work&rdquo;, but can still look at Things for things like the code to my therapist&rsquo;s office, or a reminder to scoop the cat litter. I love it. Things is the perfect example of just heavy enough feature-wise to handle power-users while only exposing simple features for everyone else. The search is amazing, especially on Mac, where all you need to do is<em>start typing</em>. Sure, there&rsquo;s no location-based reminders, but honestly at a certain point,<em>in my opinion</em> you&rsquo;re just faffing around and avoiding work by adding so many layers to your todo process. Get shit done instead of doing loads of metalwork.</p><h2 id="keeping-track-of-all-of-the-things">Keeping track of all of the things</h2><p>For me, writing and notes goes in iAWriter, and anything I need to<em>do</em> goes into Things. Sometimes my tasks include a link to a relevant Slack conversation, or email in Spark, or website—and other times it&rsquo;s just a note to take some medicine or drop mail off in the mailbox. My projects groupings mean I know historically what I&rsquo;ve accomplished in various areas or work things, and I don&rsquo;t stress too much planning months in the future. Planning, at least at work, is often a team effort, and there&rsquo;s a calendar or a roadmap that I don&rsquo;t need to duplicate in Things. I note what my responsibilities are, and set due dates or targets for those, and leave the rest to where my work actually lives—Slack. If you want to dive more into GTD or w/e, I recommend<a href="http://web.archive.org/web/20190401160435/http://www.43folders.com/2004/09/08/getting-started-with-getting-things-done">43 Folders</a>, which is possibly now disavowed by Merlin, but is still a very smart look at productivity. Generally, simple systems work well for me, and if I look at something, I should either store it, trash it, or use it.</p><p>My systems are super helpful for<em>me</em>, but might not work, or work differently for you. That&rsquo;s totally ok! Hopefully something here was helpful or interesting, and if not, feel free to browse away, and forget~ Work will always be here for you, like a strange nightmare, and how you choose to tackle it is a personal decision.</p></content:encoded></item><item><title>The old is new again</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-11-posting-on-my-blog/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-11-posting-on-my-blog/</guid><description>Inspired by both Nick and Matt, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to try my hand at blogging again on this site. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how often I&amp;rsquo;ll post, but at least once a month, I&amp;rsquo;ll do a media dietpost, which clips out what I read and watched that month from the long lists I keep.</description><content:encoded><p>Inspired by both<a href="https://roadrunnertwice.dreamwidth.org">Nick</a> and<a href="https://a.wholelottanothing.org">Matt</a>, I&rsquo;ve decided to try my hand at
blogging again on this site. I don&rsquo;t know how often I&rsquo;ll post, but at least
once a month, I&rsquo;ll do a<a href="/tags/mediadiet">media diet</a>post,
which clips out what I read and watched that month from the long lists I keep.
Maybe I&rsquo;ll talk about other stuff too. We&rsquo;ll see!</p><p>I have definitely enjoyed how Matt seems to be posting cool things there
instead of Twitter, because it gives me more things to see on RSS. Speaking of
which, you can subscribe to my rss feed by dropping the URL to this site into
the reader of your choice—I use<a href="http://reederapp.com/ios/">Reeder</a> with<a href="http://newsblur.com">Newsblur</a>.</p><p>There&rsquo;s something of a cool, old-school feel to writing on a blog and having it
delivered to folks daily via RSS, isn&rsquo;t there?</p></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>