<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>process on dill &amp; fennel</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/process/</link><description>Recent content in process on dill &amp; fennel</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Copyright Brook Shelley 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/process/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What I learned from sending a newsletter this year</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-12-30-what-i-learned-from-sending-a-newsletter-this-year/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-12-30-what-i-learned-from-sending-a-newsletter-this-year/</guid><description>Way back in February of 2019, I sent my first newsletter—a repost of a blog post about learning Japanese, then petered out for a bit. In July, I began sending weekly link emails, which I managed to keep up through the end of the year. It&amp;rsquo;s been quite a fun Sunday activity, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d chat a bit about what the experience of weekly link writing was like.</description></item><item><title>A Weekly Link Newsletter</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-07-21-newsletter/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-07-21-newsletter/</guid><description>It’s official: I’ve joined the newsletter trend in earnest. I’ve had a newsletter for a few months now, but I wasn’t sure what to really do with it. Fortunately, I realized what I love to see the most from some of my favorite newsletters is links to what these authors are reading this week—little jewels from internet wanderings.
My re-launched Dill and Fennel newsletter will have links to some of the more interesting or funny things I’ve seen in the previous week.</description></item><item><title>on notes and todos</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-05-02-on-notes-and-todos/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-05-02-on-notes-and-todos/</guid><description>The latest episode of Supercomputer inspired me to write about how I work with notes, todos, and reminders every day. Part of the episode was centered on their mutual dissatisfaction with various notes apps, which I totally understand. Over the years, I&amp;rsquo;ve used NVAlt, 1Writer, Bear, Evernote, Notes, and more to keep track of my thoughts, posts, and notes. Brett Terpstra keeps a very good list of all iOS text editors that includes information about their cross-platform functionality.</description></item><item><title>the old is new again</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-11-posting-on-my-blog/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-08-11-posting-on-my-blog/</guid><description>Inspired by both Nick and Matt, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to try my hand at blogging again on this site. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how often I&amp;rsquo;ll post, but at least once a month, I&amp;rsquo;ll do a media diet post, which clips out what I read and watched that month from the long lists I keep. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about other stuff too. We&amp;rsquo;ll see!
I have definitely enjoyed how Matt seems to be posting cool things there instead of Twitter, because it gives me more things to see on RSS.</description></item></channel></rss>