<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>japan on dill &amp; fennel</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/japan/</link><description>Recent content in japan on dill &amp; fennel</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Copyright Brook Shelley 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/japan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Traveling During a Pandemic: Part Five</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-24-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-five/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-24-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-five/</guid><description>Before it was clear we were headed for a pandemic, I booked a “treat yourself” trip to Japan. After a great first year at Slack, I wanted a nice non-work trip to really relax and refresh before going back into 2020 with a renewed sense of vigor. Previously, I wrote about my time in Asakusa.
Last day in Asakusa What was supposed to be my last day in Asakusa started late.</description></item><item><title>Traveling during a pandemic: part four</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-22-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-four/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-22-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-four/</guid><description>Before it was clear we were headed for a pandemic, I booked a “treat yourself” trip to Japan. After a great first year at Slack, I wanted a nice non-work trip to really relax and refresh before going back into 2020 with a renewed sense of vigor. Previously, I wrote about my time in Onomichi.
Yakitori party/焼き鳥のパーテイ After a drink at my hotel’s bar, I got a hot tip to check out a yakitori place a ten-minute walk away.</description></item><item><title>Traveling during a pandemic: part three</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-19-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-three/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-19-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-three/</guid><description>Before it was clear we were headed for a pandemic, I booked a “treat yourself” trip to Japan. After a great first year at Slack, I wanted a nice non-work trip to really relax and refresh before going back into 2020 with a renewed sense of vigor. Previously, I wrote about my time in Osaka.
Heading south Hopping on a call in the morning with Haley, Drl, and Zech was a nice way to start my last morning in Osaka.</description></item><item><title>Traveling during a pandemic: part two</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-17-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-two/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-17-traveling-during-a-pandemic-part-two/</guid><description>Wow, things sure are quiet&amp;hellip;
Before it was clear we were headed for a pandemic, I booked a “treat yourself” trip to Japan. After a great first year at Slack, I wanted a nice non-work trip to really relax and refresh before going back into 2020 with a renewed sense of vigor. Previously, I wrote about packing and my initial few days in Koenji in western Tokyo.
Off to Kyoto Tokyo station and the Tokaido Shinkansen were both relatively empty, which was very odd to experience.</description></item><item><title>Traveling during a pandemic</title><link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-16-traveling-during-a-pandemic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-03-16-traveling-during-a-pandemic/</guid><description>Wow, things sure are quiet&amp;hellip;
Before it was clear we were headed for a pandemic, I booked a “treat yourself” trip to Japan. After a great first year at Slack, I wanted a nice non-work trip to really relax and refresh before going back into 2020 with a renewed sense of vigor.
Unfortunately, in the following weeks COVID-19 grew at a wild rate, the cases in the United States were clearly skyrocketing despite a complete failure of the CDC and leadership to provide ample testing.</description></item></channel></rss>