<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>review on dill &amp; fennel</title>
    <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in review on dill &amp; fennel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Copyright Brook Shelley 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>iPad Magic Keyboard Review</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-04-24-ipad-magic-keyboard-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-04-24-ipad-magic-keyboard-review/</guid>
      <description>Watching friends and reviewers get their new Magic Keyboards in the mail all week was brutal, because every word I read about them, and video I watched just made me want to touch one more.</description>
      <content:encoded><p><img src="/photos/magickeyboard.jpg" alt="iPad and Magic Keyboard"></p>
<p>Watching friends and reviewers get their new Magic Keyboards in the mail all week was brutal, because every word I read about them, and video I watched just made me want to touch one more. In the time of quarantine, there’s no store to visit to try new products out, so instead we’re left waiting for delivery, and hoping everything lives up to our dreams.</p>
<p>In a sentence: this is my new favorite keyboard.</p>
<h2 id="heavy">Heavy</h2>
<p>My first thought when I took the Magic Keyboard package out of the mailbox was, “yow, this <em>is</em> heavy.” After taking the keyboard out of its packaging, the heft remained, but once I attached my iPad to it and started typing, I forgot all about the weight. Sure, this will be a bit heavier for travel, but the modularity is worth it for me. I can’t wait to type on this while traveling, then pull the iPad off the keyboard to carry around for reading in a park, or watching a tv show. It makes me wish it were possible to pull the screen off of my work computer and walk around with it too!</p>
<h2 id="modular">Modular</h2>
<p>Ever since getting the Smart Keyboard, my iPad basically never left it. I carried my iPad around daily, fingers pressed into the keys awkwardly on the back of the screen. The previous keyboard for the iPad was also super strange in its own way, but looking back, having a primary iPad case expose you to the keyboard buttons constantly when all you want to do is read is so silly. This new Magic Keyboard makes no concessions to using it while <em>not</em> typing. The ease of removing the iPad from the keyboard (I’m almost tempted to call it a dock) is such that I don’t even think about taking my iPad with me to another room, sans keyboard. This mode-changing makes the iPad feel even more futuristic than it did before, especially because my hands are only now becoming accustomed to the thin, metallic body of the iPad, instead of the strange rubber skin of the keyboard case its lived in up until now.</p>
<h2 id="thunk">Thunk</h2>
<p>So, what’s the keyboard actually like to type on?</p>
<p>Fantastic.</p>
<p>Unlike most folks, I really enjoyed both the butterfly keyboard in my MacBook, and the cloth-covered one on the Smart Keyboard. I enjoyed the short-travel, and the weird texture, but the feel and thunk of this new keyboard is even better. I don’t really care about the backlighting, and I’m a little bit more concerned about the gaps that invite in stray drops of water, but as I mentioned above, I don’t plan to carry this with me all the time, so it’s more likely I’ll have a glass of wine sans non-waterproof keyboard, and keep drinks away when I plan to <em>type</em>.</p>
<p>I typed this review on the new keyboard, and the experience was absolutely fantastic. The new trackpad <em>is</em> small, but the ability to quickly laser-target my edits is a delight. No longer do I have to tap, stab, tap tap, arrow, arrow, arrow. I can just point, and click, and voila. When I’m not at work, I more or less <em>only</em> use my iPad, and this new keyboard means the typing I do will be faster, feel better, and even sound more pleasingly thunky.</p>
<h2 id="should-you-buy-it">Should you buy it?</h2>
<p>Do you type on your iPad? Do you want to? Have you been tempted to plug your iPad into a monitor and use a Bluetooth trackpad? Do you love writing on the go?</p>
<p>If so, then this is probably the right keyboard for you. If you only occasionally reach for your iPad to watch YouTube videos, or are the kind of person who thinks traveling with an iPad <strong>and</strong> a MacBook is totally acceptable, then save your $300. In the same way that I’ve never purchased an Apple Pencil, many iPad users will never purchase this keyboard, and I think that’s totally fine. But the folks that do buy one, and get to experience the entirely wonderful experience of typing and editing will be incredibly satisfied, I think.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bellroy Studio Pack Review</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-12-13-bellroy-studio-pack-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-12-13-bellroy-studio-pack-review/</guid>
      <description>A new backpack for everyday carry, and travel.
First Sight After first getting my new Bellroy sling, I fell in love with the delightful material for these bags.</description>
      <content:encoded><p><img src="/photos/bellroybackpack.jpeg" alt="Bellroy Studio Backpack"></p>
<p>A new backpack for everyday carry, and travel.</p>
<h2 id="first-sight">First Sight</h2>
<p>After first getting my new Bellroy sling, I fell in love with the delightful material for these bags. A few months later in Iitoya in Japan, I got to see their new Shift backpack in person, and almost bought one on the spot. that bag was a little larger than I need, but then I saw <a href="https://bellroy.com/products/studio-backpack/venture/black">this</a>. With the launch of the Studio Backpack, Bellroy has made an excellent bag that holds a little or a lot without every looking absurd.</p>
<h2 id="sizing">Sizing</h2>
<p>For quite a while, I’ve <a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/blog/2019/11/06/devreltour-packing-list.html">brought my Topo Trip Pack</a> to work as it fits my coffee bottle, iPad, journal, and a few other things perfectly. Adding in a spare jacket could stuff it pretty tight, but I preferred that to hauling a bag that was typically too large. With the Studio Backpack, my everyday stuff fits well, with ample space, but the shallow depth of the bag means it looks nice even unloaded.</p>
<h3 id="measurements">Measurements</h3>
<p>This is a slim, but tall-ish bag that measures 500L x 370W x 100D mm or 19.69”x14.57”x3.94”.</p>
<p>It has an 18-liter capacity, which while entry isn’t nearly as big feeling as my similarly-sized RYU Quick Pack. It weighs 650g or 1.43lbs, nearly half the weight of the <a href="https://ryu.com/shop/us/quick-pack/quick-pack-lux">RYU</a>, and only a little heavier than the 567g <a href="https://topodesigns.com/products/trip-pack?variant=946319253">Topo Trip Pack</a>.</p>
<p>All-in-all, this bag feels like a great balance between a daily size and one that I could fly around the world with.</p>
<h2 id="features">Features</h2>
<p><img src="/photos/bellroysmall.jpg" alt="Bellroy Front Pocket"></p>
<p>This bag is a top-loader, with a generously-wide opening, and a fidlock magnetic closure I can open with one hand using the small fabric loop. This flap makes for an easy way to use the main compartment, while keeping the rain off of my stuff. On the outside, there’s a pocket a little bit lower than mid-way that zips shut, and has pockets for pens, AirPods, and a few other things along with a key loop on a long fabric loop. Usually, I keep a Hobonichi Weeks, a Kaweco fountain pen, house keys, AirPods Pro and my work badge in here.</p>
<p>Inside of the main bag area, there’s a laptop area that can hold up to a 16” MacBook Pro—the new one with the real escape key—or an iPad Pro of either size. The bottom of the bag is generously padded to keep your stuff safe, and the laptop sleeve ends before the bottom for more safety. On the front wall of the main bag opening there is another zipped compartment for glasses, cables, or other odds and ends that you don’t need as often.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/mainbellroy.jpg" alt="Bellroy Main Pocket"></p>
<h2 id="colors-and-materials">Colors and Materials</h2>
<p>I have the black version of this bag, which I find delightful, though if I could customize it, I might have chosen a light purple or blue interior instead of the tan it comes with from Bellroy. Bellroy won me over on the idea that a lighter or brighter interior helps in finding your gear, though as a top-loader, even bright fabric doesn’t help you dig at the bottom of the bag. The Venture Weave fabric feels very strange, but in a cool, high-end way, and does a good job shrugging off rain. There are leather accents in various places on the bag that give it a little extra luxury.</p>
<h2 id="rating">Rating</h2>
<p>This bag rules, and I’ve thoroughly enjoyed it for the past few weeks. I plan to take it on my next trip abroad, and likely won’t bring a separate daypack. I think this bag will be comfortable on a hike, or fully-loaded with my typical travel gear. If you need a bit more space, I highly recommend checking out Bellroy’s other larger version of this, the <a href="https://bellroy.com/products/shift-backpack/venture/moss">Shift pack</a>.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XOXO 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-09-10-xoxo-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-09-10-xoxo-2019/</guid>
      <description>A return to form This year marked my 4th XOXO, and my 3rd at Revolution Hall. Last year was big, which meant it was even harder to wave at, or spend time with the other amazing attendees I knew.</description>
      <content:encoded><h2 id="a-return-to-form">A return to form</h2>
<p>This year marked my 4th XOXO, and my 3rd at Revolution Hall. Last year was <em>big</em>, which meant it was even harder to wave at, or spend time with the other amazing attendees I knew. This year, it felt just right. I still waved at too many folks, and wished I had time to have a number of small dinners over the next year instead of so many “hey, I see you, sorry I’ve gotta run!” However, I got to spend time with a smallish group of friends, see all the talks I wanted, and even play some <a href="http://www.killerqueenblack.com">amazing</a> <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IJ_I8SSVKto">new</a> <a href="https://play.date">games</a>.
If you’ve never been to XOXO, and you make things on the internet, and enjoy building relationships, this is a great place for you.</p>
<h2 id="day-one">Day one</h2>
<p>As usually, the first day of the conference was a social one—with Glitch doing an <a href="https://glitch.com/~appy-hour">Appy Hour</a>, and Panic showing off the <a href="https://play.date">Playdate</a>. It was super cool seeing all the strange community games and creations of Glitch users, along with a few presentations, and the Playdate is something I can’t wait to own. Topped-off with a dinner at Kachka, a lot of upcoming games, and one of the <a href="https://www.polygon.com/videos/2019/9/9/20849172/unraveled-how-to-calculate-pet-hp-hit-points">most hilarious videos</a> I’ve seen in a while, wherein Brian Gilbert attempts to calculate his pet’s HP, Friday was a delight. The weather held, the <a href="https://twitter.com/brookshelley/status/1171647388001406976?s=21">toilets were uniquely chill</a>, and the layout of the festival ensure I could wander and find neat things.</p>
<h2 id="day-two">Day two</h2>
<p>One of the first pieces of advice I’d give anyone going to a multi-day festival is “don’t drink too much on the first night”. I didn’t take my own advice. I wasn’t ill, but a combination of 3 glasses of wine and too little sleep meant 10am felt <em>very</em> early. Thankfully my hotel had Proud Mary coffee, and XOXO had Deadstock. A breakfast sandwich from Fried Egg I’m in Love completed my resurrection.</p>
<p>Day two felt a little longer, as I sat through every talk, alternately crying and laughing. A definite emotional rollercoaster. Helen and Hrishikesh were excellent hosts, and seeing their banter develop over the weekend makes me hope they host again next year. I missed the Andy’s camaraderie at times, but I hope <em>only</em> being responsible for the whole festival was a nice change from also MCing.</p>
<p>Lunch was Basilisk. Unbeatable fried chicken I eat every time I visit Portland. Yes, even when I’m there for hours.</p>
<p>Favorite talks from Saturday: Harry Brewis (very funny guy who I didn’t know anything about beforehand), Hundred Rabbits (delightful French Canadian vegan sailors), and Soleil Ho (what happens when you become the representation?!).</p>
<p>After a quick dinner, I sat down for a night of unforgettable podcasts. I watched a man interview a chainsaw, and was utterly destroyed by Demi and Miel with special guests Neil and Mike doing Ray Parker Jr’s Ghostbuster song. The number of folks I heard singing “bustin’ makes me feel good” after this podcast taping tells me I wasn’t alone.</p>
<h2 id="day-3-closing-time">Day 3 (Closing time)</h2>
<p>Coffee. Sandwich. Almost there. I was wiped at this point, but the talks were delightful. Mikki Kendall, Jenny Odell, and Rhea Butcher were my favorites from Sunday. A great mix of comedy and art. Food highlights were Navarre (another favorite), and dinner at Sardine Head. OMG Sardine Head. Oxidated white wine. Salt-cured anchovy. Dang.</p>
<p>The karaoke list was full by the time my friends and I got back from dinner, and a cab ride that included an episode of <a href="https://twitter.com/brookshelley/status/1170902500083322880?s=21">King of the Hill</a>. It was fun watching various speakers and friends sing Pavement, Lizzo, and of course, the Ghostbuster’s theme. I ended my night with my friends Jenny and Joe, drinking on the balcony at my hotel. Our friend André’s room was right by the balcony, and he wandered out mid-way through. That moment of kismet was generally how the whole conference felt—friends wandering by, saying hi, and going on adventures.</p>
<h2 id="a-great-year">A great year</h2>
<p>XOXO at its best feels like what I imagine a community <em>should</em> feel like. It’s full of new people, old people, dear friends, and acquaintances. If XOXO was every day, I would lose my mind, but once a year, it feels incredible to be surrounded by so many people I care about, as we’re inspired together by talks, art, and each other. I’m so glad I got to go to Portland, for the first time as a non-resident, for XOXO. I can’t wait for another year of this magical festival, and hope many of the same folks will get to attend. My only regret is that I can’t somehow bring Snorri with me too. He’d hate it.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masterworks review</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-09-03-masterworks-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-09-03-masterworks-review/</guid>
      <description>I wish I knew more about art. Reading the titular story, I found myself reaching for my phone to understand each scene in the strange and delightful post-apocalyptic tale.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>I wish I knew more about art. Reading the titular story, I found myself reaching for my phone to understand each scene in the strange and delightful post-apocalyptic tale. As I held the painting in my mind, and explored the flooded wastes with Liam, Nell, and Co. I found myself enamored by the framing. How often are our relationships held together by a retelling of an old picture? Are we always trying to build a life out of the classics of our youth? There’s a survey of life, and an exploration of lost moments in these vignettes.</p>
<p>The opening tale of this collection plants us in Ohio, a place, we see, where even supportive friends or loved ones can’t save you from the yawning abyss. The suburban Olive Garden echoes in my mind with all the breadsticks I absorbed through my high school years. These youth were me, and the chasm felt real then too. From there, we follow a mother who lost a son, and a sliver of a life exploring a name—just enough of both to leave the reader wanting more. Then, a journey through art, mentioned above. It’s strange and beautiful, and a great opportunity to learn about the great works of fine art, if like this reviewer, you largely skipped-out on art class.</p>
<p>Finally, we readers are washed up on the shore, like so many dead fish, with a man watching a lodge, and time-displaced, dealing with an all-too-familiar moldy bathroom. A word of warning: if you’ve lived in the the Pacific Northwest, the squelch of wet tile will be all too real. This novella is reminiscent of Jack and the Beanstalk, or another fairy tale of exploring a new land. The phrase “crotchal belch” made me laugh out loud. There are so many great turns of phrase in Masterworks. The story propelled me forward, alternately laughing and cringing. I wanted the protagonist to seize his agency, and change in the ways he so clearly desired. I find these characters at turns fascinating and deeply frustrating. There were so many places where I yelled, “say something” in my head, but this isn’t a story of success, but learning and remembering.</p>
<p>On the whole, I loved this book. Masterworks, by Simon Jacobs, is a fantastic collection of imagination, and creative bombast. At times it leans into magical realism, in others outright fantasy. There a slightly disjointed nature to these stories, as they’re collected over years of writing, and lead me to hope Simon writes more—a novel perhaps—in the future.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 in Review</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-12-22-year-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-12-22-year-in-review/</guid>
      <description>Started in Japan Last year, I hopped on a plane to Tokyo before the countdown began, and landed in the evening of the 1st of January.</description>
      <content:encoded><h2 id="started-in-japan">Started in Japan</h2>
<p>Last year, I hopped on a plane to Tokyo before the countdown began, and landed in the evening of the 1st of January. Making my way to my rental apartment in Koenji, the city was quiet as folks celebrated with their family. It was a strange trip. I got to do my hatsumode at Meiji Jingu with thousands of people, and see the Emperor’s second to last speech before his groundbreaking abdication next year. Parks were closed, but fortunately, izakayas were open. My friend Magda met up with me later that week, and I showed her Tokyo, Osaka, and Kyoto. It was her first trip to Japan, and we both had a blast eating food and visiting a cool ryokan.</p>
<h2 id="portland-interlude">Portland (interlude)</h2>
<p>I spent very little time in Portland this year, it felt like. I traveled slightly less than in 2017, but between bouncing back and forth to Oakland and San Francisco for work and various trips abroad, Snorri and my Portland friends saw me half of every month. I lifted as often as I could, and competed in two internal <a href="/blog/2018/08/14/powerlifting">powerlifting</a> meets. I kept running the board of directors for Basic Rights too. But increasingly, Portland felt like the wrong place for me. When I was in town, I often found myself spending lots of time alone, cooking and eating at home, or seeing movies solo. <a href="/blog/2018/09/10/xoxo-thoughts">XOXO this year</a> was fun, but the friends I spent most of it with were all from the bay. I’d made and lost many friends, and my energy was low. I started thinking more seriously about moving to Oakland during a really busy time at work, so it took a bit for things to settle. Once they did, my company was part of Slack, and I was suddenly moving to Emeryville. I’ll miss so many of my friends in Portland, but as living halfway there and the bay for a few years taught me, it’s a quick flight.</p>
<h2 id="berlin">Berlin</h2>
<p>My partner suggested offhandedly at one point that they were going to Europe for a conference, and that it would be cool to meet up in Berlin. I bit, and immediately booked tickets. We stayed in Neukölln, near Tempelhofer Fields, and I immediately fell for the city, the Berliner Weiss, and the vibe. More than a few folks I know have since or before moved to Berlin, and despite wild bureaucratic issues, it seems like a very interesting place to live. I ate tons of döner kebab, and loved visiting LiquidRom (a place I’d described as a brutalist day spa). Mads and I had never spent that long together, and it definitely brought us closer together. I flew home happy, and looking forward to visiting again, and had just about a week in Portland before I flew off again.</p>
<h2 id="copenhagen">Copenhagen</h2>
<p>This time, I was on my way via SFO to Copenhagen with my coworkers Brian and Mark to attend and run a booth at KubeCon. It was so, <em>so</em> busy. We ate a lot of smørrebrø, worked out in an old slaughterhouse, and generally had a blast. I spent an extra week there alone, with only a couple days a bit wasted by my conference-acquired cold. Vesterbro was really cool, though I still think it’s odd how many all-you-can-eat sushi places there were. I never rode a bike, which in retrospect is super odd, but I did drink a lot of aquavit, and ate a <em>ton</em> of wienerschnitzel. This turned out to be my last international trip of the year, despite my hope that I could get back to Japan in the fall.</p>
<h2 id="so-many-flights-to-sfo">So many flights to SFO</h2>
<p>Various circumstances meant I was flying back and forth to SFO more than once a month during the summer and early fall. There were early morning flights with afternoons returning to Portland for poorly-timed obligations. There were flights with friends, and lots of solo flights. Somehow I never quite managed to get status on a single airline. Near the end of my constant flying, I was happy to learn my new company wanted me to move to the bay by the end of October, and my friend Haley helpfully found me a lovely apartment near lots of friends at the edges of Emeryville and Berkeley. I signed the lease sight-unseen, on the assurance of my partner and the video they took that it was fantastic. It was, in fact, incredible. I finished up everything I could in Portland, had movers come, and took Snorri and myself to our new home.</p>
<h2 id="settling-into-a-new-eville-life">Settling into a new Eville life</h2>
<p>I <a href="/blog/2018/11/21/moving-to-the-bay.html">wrote about moving to Emeryville</a> a while ago, and since then it’s gotten even better. I feel like I’ve settled into a schedule here that includes powerlifting, seeing friends, and taking care of my growing plant collection. A very mild fall means I get to wear all my light jackets, and my short bus commute to work led to ample time reading. It’s been great only bringing an <a href="/blog/2018/11/07/new-ipad-review">iPad Pro</a> to and from work for the past few months, and I feel lucky I get to leave my work, and work computer at the office. The holidays were better than I feared, and I got to spend time with a few friends here in the bay, as well as enjoy candles, snacks, and books in my cozy home. It also rules to finally live in the same city as my partner, and figuring out a good cadence in our hangouts has been fun, if sometimes tricky. I hope to spend many more years here.</p>
<h2 id="looking-towards-2019">Looking towards 2019</h2>
<p>I’m hopeful 2019 will lead to more books, movies, and fun times with friends and loved ones. Work is amazing, and it feels great to be at a company I really believe in, helping create a product I love using every day. I’m also staying on the board at Basic Rights, and I continue to be proud of our work in immigration rights, trans rights, and racial justice. So much of making this country a better place for everyone means small local changes, and I’m glad to be a small part of that work. I might try to compete more at powerlifting, and I definitely want to go back to Japan and Scandinavia if possible. The economy, at the time I’m writing this, looks like it’s headed towards a shit place, but I hope to keep saving money throughout the year. If everything works out, I’ll even get Snorri a new friend, so he doesn’t have to wait for me to get home from work alone every day. 2019 is another year—a fresh year to live and learn in. I’m looking forward to it.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 iPad Pro Review</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-11-07-new-ipad-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-11-07-new-ipad-review/</guid>
      <description>Today my phone buzzed to tell me my new iPad had arrived at my office. I rushed down to the mailroom, and eagerly ripped open the packaging.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>Today my phone buzzed to tell me my new iPad had arrived at my office. I rushed down to the mailroom, and eagerly ripped open the packaging. For a few years I’ve used an iPad Pro 9.7” as my primary travel computer when I didn’t need to work on Kubernetes/DevOps stuff, and I’ve loved it. Whether I was watching shows on Netflix or Plex that I’d downloaded before a flight, editing my website in Working Copy, or just editing photos and browsing Twitter, this was the machine I wanted to use.</p>
<p>Now, I have 1.3” more screen, a more lap-capable keyboard, and 120hz refresh, and I couldn’t be happier.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/ipad.jpeg" alt="iPad"></p>
<h2 id="the-screen">The screen</h2>
<p>This iPad might not feel like as huge of a revelation to someone who used the 10.5”, but coming from the 9.7”, this screen feels luxurious. The smooth 120hz refresh rate means opening apps, and moving around looks amazing. The color and viewing angles are still the best in the tablet world, and make my even my MacBook feel like a relic of the past. It’s responsive, bright, and a joy to watch tv on.</p>
<h2 id="the-case">The case</h2>
<p>My iPad is the Space Grey color, and it looks excellent. The industrial lines of the sides are reminiscent of my favorite iPhone, the 4. Overall the iPad feels thin, and around the weight of my 9.7” even with the added screen size, and when I have it out of the keyboard folio, I don’t want to put it down. This tablet feels great in my hands. I seriously hope that Apple brings this design language to the next generation of iPhones, even though I wonder if they can while still keeping the glass back for wireless charging.</p>
<h2 id="the-keyboard-folio">The keyboard folio</h2>
<p>My main use of the iPad is with a keyboard attached, as I use it as a laptop mostly, which sometimes becomes a handheld tablet for reading. I’m still not convinced there needed to be two viewing angles, but the stiffness and lack of weird folding means it feels pretty great in my lap or on a desk. The tablet-mode keyboard against your fingers thing is slightly odd, but it also reminds me of playing the accordion, which I find funny enough to enjoy it. The keys feel nice and responsive, and largely the same as the 9.7” keyboard. If they changed the keys, I can’t tell. I do enjoy the slightly larger size that matches the bigger device, and my mistypes are few and far-between. Clicking the iPad into the folio feels fast and easy, even if it requires slightly more lining up than previously. With the folio closed, the iPad feel grippy, and like a thin notebook in the best way. The weight and feel, in my opinion, remind you that you’re holding a high quality device. The folio adds a little thickness, but I think it only brings the device to the previous size, so I haven’t felt like it was too thick.</p>
<h2 id="usb-c">USB-C</h2>
<p>It’s great. I love using the same charger for this iPad and my MacBook. I already invested in USB-C to lighting cables, so bringing this iPad and no USB spare battery for my iPhone sounds great. I haven’t tried plugging anything weird into the port, but folks at the Verge did their damndest to stump the port. <em>Spoiler</em> it doesn’t work with printers.</p>
<h2 id="battery-life">Battery life</h2>
<p>It’s about the same as my old iPad, which is excellent.</p>
<h2 id="speakers">Speakers</h2>
<p>There’s four of them. They’re loud, and clear. A+</p>
<h2 id="faceid">FaceID</h2>
<p>Just as quick and easy as my previous iPhone X, and possibly a little slower than the XS. I can’t quite tell, but I feel a little like I’m waiting now compared to using my phone. I haven’t timed it though, but generally it’s much better and easier than the TouchID.</p>
<h2 id="wrap-up">Wrap-up</h2>
<p>This is the iPad to get—whether you get the 12.9” or the 11”, especially if you haven’t upgraded in a few years. I seriously feel like this is the future of Apple computing, and iOS 13 is sure to bring more advanced features that mean I might not need a Mac outside of my office.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Review of Invasions</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-10-14-invasions-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-10-14-invasions-review/</guid>
      <description>It begins with a rip, the tearing sound of velcro—mix and match nipples kick off this delightfully strange collection of speculative fiction, trans body-horror, and water-logged zombies.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>It begins with a rip, the tearing sound of velcro—mix and match nipples kick off this <a href="http://www.instarbooks.com/books/invasions.html">delightfully strange collection</a> of speculative fiction, trans body-horror, and water-logged zombies. Calvin impressed me last year with his part in <a href="https://medium.com/@brookshelley/a-review-of-meanwhile-elsewhere-166ec11bff7d">Meanwhile, Elsewhere</a>, revisited here as the excellent Rent, Don&rsquo;t Sell. This story explores a world in which bodies are traded for a time for fitness or fetish and how trans people deal with this faustian bargain. Another tale invites us to an isolated cabin for a wedding party that begins to fray at the edges in a blizzard. And, while every story isn&rsquo;t is a life-or-death one, but the weight of mortality permeates each page.</p>
<p>Whether the reader is wandering a bathhouse, stumbling through the streets, newly minted as a middle-aged-man, we are reminded each time that the world doesn&rsquo;t quite fit us. Invasions captures the feeling of being trans, even in innocuous settings. It&rsquo;s never Cronenberg, but regardless of how wild the twist, it&rsquo;s grounded and bodied in a way he couldn&rsquo;t imagine. Occasionally, a story follows an ostensibly cisgender person, to probe the space around a trans life, and to me these are the most speculative: &ldquo;What do they see in us? What do they think?&rdquo; To answer this question, one protagonist even employs a psychic talent to sift through memory and desire in those around him, even through their final moments.</p>
<p>This collection also challenges ideas around surgery, queer bodies, and perception. In Eternal Boy, we meet a queer person figuring out their gender, but at odds with their presentation as a boy; they&rsquo;re uncertain about the way women see them, but also willing to overlook those feelings for a chance to hook up. These characters are complicated; they&rsquo;re often anti-heroes, or even villains. We need more trans villains in a world of trans characters that are almost always a sob story or a heartwarming tale. I&rsquo;m here for the dirty, confused, angry, and alien.</p>
<p>One of closing stories is about a surgery center full of the wild variety of trans folks I&rsquo;ve met: from older late-transitioning women, to confident girls with their moms. Not content to let cis people be the only foil for trans protagonists, Calvin writes the interplay between intergenerational and intergender conflict and love wonderfully. On the heels of You Wouldn&rsquo;t Have Known is the more general body horror of pregnancy and a failure of the healthcare system.</p>
<p>Invasions is one of the best collections I&rsquo;ve read in quite some time, and I can&rsquo;t wait to see Calvin&rsquo;s next book or collection. <a href="http://www.instarbooks.com/books/invasions.html">Pick up a copy today</a>. This writer is one to watch, and tell your friends about—a real trans-writers-writer. He delivered on the promise of his story in Meanwhile, Elsewhere with gusto, and blew this reader away.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSPTCH Waist Bag Review</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-10-04-dsptch-waist-bag/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-10-04-dsptch-waist-bag/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I ordered a medium Sling Pack after deciding I wanted a very small bag to bring with me to meetings or coffee shops where I only needed my iPad and a few other sundries.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>Recently, I ordered a <a href="https://www.dsptch.com/collections/packs/products/sling-pouch-medium">medium Sling Pack</a> after deciding I wanted a very small bag to bring with me to meetings or coffee shops where I only needed my iPad and a few other sundries. 11pm is not a great time to make <em>decisions</em>, so I clicked the order button before I checked measurements, and was sad when I realized it didn&rsquo;t actually fit my 9.7&quot; iPad. Luckily, I was already flying to San Francisco a week later, and was able to exchange it for the <a href="https://www.dsptch.com/products/waist-bag-black">Waist Bag</a>, after trying it on in the store. (An aside: the guy at DSPTCH was super nice, and really helpful, which further won me over. I think they have lots of great stuff, so even if this bag is too small for you, check it out.)</p>
<p>TL;DR this bag is fantastic for exactly what I bought it for—carrying an iPad and a few other things to meetings, or very short trips. A+ would buy again.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/wb_front.jpeg" alt="Front"></p>
<h2 id="pockets-and-zips">Pockets and zips</h2>
<p>I <em>love</em> the way the pockets and zipper are laid out in this bag. The top of the bag is accessible via a single, incredibly tactile zipper pull. Seriously, this zipper pull is rad. Once unzipped, the main compartment is broken into two parts: one slightly padded iPad sleeve, and a slightly larger main area with a D-ring for keys. My 12&quot; MacBook <em>fits</em> in the main area, which WOW. Not much else fits in the main area if I put my laptop in here, but still, this is unbelievably cool. With an iPad, a Kindle Oasis, a rolled-up shirt, a pair of underwear, keys, and toiletries this compartment is pretty tightly packed, but the zipper is sufficiently robust (it&rsquo;s a big YKK), so I don&rsquo;t feel worried about it failing.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/wb_main.jpeg" alt="Main"></p>
<p>The front of the bag is a flap with two super cool magnetic <a href="http://www.fidlock.com/en/fasteners/snap.html">Fidlock®</a> snaps. Pulling down slightly on each side reveals two slightly baggy pockets with elastic at the top. These pockets both have a vertical separation between the front and back of the pocket. I can fit a <a href="https://www.anker.com/products/variant/powercore-13000-c/A1216011">USB-C battery pack</a> and cables, plus some headphones on one side, and a <a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/">Hobonichi Techo</a>, a <a href="https://www.jetpens.com/LAMY-Safari-Fountain-Pen-Charcoal-Black-Fine-Nib/pd/5075?gclid=EAIaIQobChMImKKypcvt3QIVhWB-Ch2pAQarEAQYAiABEgKbO_D_BwE">Lamy Safari</a>, and keycards, lip balm, and essential oil in the other. I&rsquo;ve also fit a Kindle Oasis in one of the pockets, but it was a tight fit, and I prefer keeping it in the main bag pocket. The ease of popping open the snaps after pulling the bag around to the front reminds me why I loved messenger bags back in the day. It&rsquo;s super cool. I love having all of my stuff easily-accessible, but I&rsquo;m also glad my load ends up light enough not to hurt my shoulder. More on that later.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/wb_pockets.jpeg" alt="Pockets"></p>
<h2 id="material">Material</h2>
<p>The DSPTCH site says this bag is 1680D Ballistic Nylon with DWR coating, lined with 410D Nylon Packcloth with DWR coating. I haven&rsquo;t tested this bag in the rain yet, but the zip isn&rsquo;t seam-sealed, so while I&rsquo;d trust it in a light rain, I wouldn&rsquo;t swim with it. I bring a dry bag with me everywhere for toiletries though, and it&rsquo;s sufficiently large I could put the bag in it in a pinch, so I&rsquo;m not too worried. The material feels very nice, and high-quality, and the stitching and construction inspires confidence. The zipper pull is lightly textured on both sides, as well as contoured for a thumb and forefinger such that every use of it makes me smile.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/wb_zip.jpeg" alt="Main"></p>
<p>This is a bag you will want to open and close. The Fidlock® snaps are similarly fun to use. The strap is pretty solid as well, and my only complaint is that I wish the clasp was metal/magnetic instead of plastic, even though the plastic feels solid. This bag generally feels like it will hold up for over 10 years, and Dpstch warranties it, which gives me even more confidence as I lug it around. I&rsquo;d be amiss if I didn&rsquo;t mention the &ldquo;high air flow back mesh for longer periods of wear,&rdquo; which means I don&rsquo;t end up with <em>as much</em> sweat on my back when I&rsquo;m walking around in over environments &gt;20˚.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/wb_back.jpeg" alt="Back"></p>
<h2 id="size">Size</h2>
<p>This is a <em>small</em> bag. You can wear it over the shoulder, as a cross body, either in front or on your back, or as a fanny-pack/waist bag as the name indicates. In inches, it measures at 8L, or 13&quot; x 9&quot; x 1.5&quot; at 1.1lbs, but the numbers belie how much it can carry. This is the kind of bag your friends say &ldquo;wow&rdquo; to as you slide out a 9.7&quot; iPad or 12&quot; MacBook. This bag fits really well on the floor under a seat on a plane without compromising foot space. It also feels great to walk in a crowd or get onto a crowded train knowing I won&rsquo;t bonk anyone with this bag, as it barely sticks out from my back. It&rsquo;s very easy to adjust the strap that goes around my chest as well, and it&rsquo;s easy to slide this bag around to the front when I need to pull something out. I&rsquo;ve occasionally worn this bag on my hip/butt as a fanny-pack, and while I think it looks a little silly, it&rsquo;s very comfortable—your mileage may vary on style/feel.</p>
<h2 id="wrap-up">Wrap-up</h2>
<p>Overall, I love this bag, and look for every opportunity to bring it with me. In my effort to downsize and travel lightly, I&rsquo;ve found this to be a perfect companion. Every interaction I have with this bag feels great, and makes me smile. If you need something small to bring a few things to your next meeting, concert, or short trip, I highly recommend the <a href="https://www.dsptch.com/products/waist-bag-black">DSPTCH Waist Bag</a>. It&rsquo;s <em>seriously good</em> and my suspicion is the rest of their gear is equally great.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invisible One review</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-05-17-review-invisible-one-mini/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-05-17-review-invisible-one-mini/</guid>
      <description>Bags are my thing. Well, bags and shoes. Traveling as much as I do, having a dependable, comfortable, and sleek bag is pretty important.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>Bags are my thing. Well, bags and shoes. Traveling as much as I do, having a dependable, comfortable, and sleek bag is pretty important. For the past two or so years, I&rsquo;ve depended on my Topo Designs Trip Pack for short trips, and then nested it inside of my Ryu QuickPack for longer trips abroad. This has worked out well, but walking around Copenhagen, and going through a variety of international airport security, I wondered if I could consolidate to one bag, with an easier way to access my laptop and other stuff. The <a href="https://www.opposethis.com/products/invisible-backpack-one-mini">Invisible One Mini</a> seemed like a great way to test this out. I was drawn to the design of the bag, and the ethos of the company: &ldquo;Each year we reiterate and improve our designs&hellip;&rdquo; which I&rsquo;ve witnessed as I&rsquo;ve watched them iterate over the years.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/oneminifront.jpeg" alt="One Mini photo"></p>
<h2 id="pockets-and-zips">Pockets and zips</h2>
<p>My Topo Designs Trip Pack has three compartments—a main area where I can slip my laptop, a zip pouch in that main area, and a front pocket for a Kindle, notebook, etc. I found myself digging around more than I wanted to for my charger, pen, or chapstick. The Invisible One Mini has just a little more organization, and so far, it&rsquo;s made a huge difference.</p>
<p>The 2018 One Mini has a zipper pocket in the front, that&rsquo;s charmingly asymmetrical. A flap unzips, revealing a pocket that can hold an iPad or Kindle, a zipper-sealable area for keys, chapstick, glasses cloth, etc, and two smaller pouches. These pouches are the perfect size for a portable battery, and a Hobonichi Techo. There&rsquo;s a bit of additional space in the big zipper area for my MacBook charger as well. The entire big pouch is almost the width and heigh of the bag, but because of the clever organization, it doesn&rsquo;t feel like I&rsquo;ll lose things in it.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/oneminipocket.jpeg" alt="One Mini pocket"></p>
<p>On the top of the bag, there&rsquo;s a big zipper that opens the main compartment, which I use to hold a hoodie, my water bottle, and also a small bag of underwear and clothes for travel. Because of the front organization, I don&rsquo;t need to dig in this compartment often, and only need to keep a few easy-to-find or pack-to-leave unpack-at-destination items in it. This is a big improvement over the Topo Bag.</p>
<p>Finally, the back of the bag has a top-loading laptop sleeve that&rsquo;s soft and felt-lined. The bottom ends a bit above the bottom of the bag, providing a little cushion area, but I still wouldn&rsquo;t want to throw this bag around with my MacBook in it. Unlike the Ryu or the Topo Designs bags, this separate laptop area means I can dig my MacBook out on the occasions I can&rsquo;t get pre-check and have my laptop scanned separately. I try my damndest to avoid these instances, but inter-Europe travel usually means pulling out all my electronics.</p>
<p>Previous years of this bag had weird side zips on the front and back for the laptop, a water bottle, and documents and other stuff in the front, but this version feels more usable, and less confusing at a glance. I doubt I&rsquo;ll have any trouble remembering where I put various items, or how to quickly retrieve them. Read more about the year-over-year change <a href="https://www.opposethis.com/blogs/insidethis/invisible-backpack-one-2018">here</a>.</p>
<h2 id="the-material">The material</h2>
<p>The entire bag is a light-weight 800x600D waterproof nylon-polyester blend that looks and feels pretty lux. The top handle is a rubber-ish leather-is material that&rsquo;s grippy and feels nice, and the inside of the pack straps is a soft and breathable cloth. The top of the bag is ringed with the same rubberized material, encircling the main compartment. The inside of the two front areas is a gray nylon that feels like smooth quality. All over the bag, the stitches are even and seem made for longevity. I&rsquo;ll update this review later to see how well the bag stood up to travel wear-and-tear, but so far it inspires confidence. I&rsquo;m also curious how well the rain resistance does, as only the laptop sleep area has a waterproof YKK zipper, with the other two using a more standard zip. The pulls have rubber grips, with no dangling pull cords, which means they&rsquo;re slightly more fiddly than the RYU or the Topo bags, but once I&rsquo;ve found the tab, the pull feels smooth.</p>
<h2 id="the-size">The size</h2>
<p>This is a small bag, but feels a good deal bigger than my tiny Topo Designs bag. Measuring 38cm x 34cm x 14cm (15&quot;x13.5&quot;x5.5&quot;), with a volume of 11L, and a weight of 650g (22oz), it&rsquo;s easy to throw on, but doesn&rsquo;t look dwarfed by my 5'10&quot; frame. It sits well on my back, and the clever straps let me cinch it up or down, while the excess strap stays tucked into itself. The main compartment is roomy enough without making the other areas of the bag feel cramped, that I feel pretty confident I could take only this bag for a few weeks abroad.</p>
<h2 id="wrap-up">Wrap-up</h2>
<p>I haven&rsquo;t had this bag for long, but my first impressions are that this will be a major part of my travel kit. I can&rsquo;t wait to bring this with me to Oakland, or Japan, to see how well it fits under a seat, or loads and unloads in a crowded subway train.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My year-end review of 2015</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-12-19-my-year-end-review-of-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2015-12-19-my-year-end-review-of-2015/</guid>
      <description>Marginally better! 2015: it sounds like we’re really moving
Score 2015/?</description>
      <content:encoded><p>Marginally better!
2015: it sounds like we’re really moving</p>
<h2 id="score">Score</h2>
<p>2015/?</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
