<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hiking on dill &amp; fennel</title>
    <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/hiking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hiking on dill &amp; fennel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Copyright Brook Shelley 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 03:00:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/hiking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hiking</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-09-03-hiking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 03:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-09-03-hiking/</guid>
      <description>Hiking Thanks to my friend Lena, I got to test out my new hiking shoes today at Redwood Regional Park.</description>
      <content:encoded><h1 id="hiking">Hiking</h1>
<p>Thanks to my friend Lena, I got to test out my new hiking shoes today at Redwood Regional Park.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/onshoes.jpg" alt="On shoes"></p>
<p>We did a very chill 5 mile hike with 1500’ climb and a total descent of 1000’.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/redwoodhiking.jpg" alt="redwood hiking path"></p>
<p>I think my workout program is really helping because while it wasn’t always easy to hike this trail, it was super doable and really fun. I ended-up with only a couple small blisters I chalk up to brand new shoes.</p>
<p>The thought of crowded trails during COVID was stressful, but the reality of hiking during the day (since I’m on vacation this week) was incredibly relaxing. I think we saw a total of 10 people over the course of 2 hours, and everyone was masked. We also saw a bunch of lizards, and cute dogs.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/forest.jpg" alt="forest"></p>
<p>The forest paths were naturally very cool, and relaxing, and even the sunny bits were around 20C/68F which meant we didn’t need to constantly stop to hydrate.  I haven’t hiked a lot since I lived in Texas, so I’m looking forward to trying to do more hiking even without flying anywhere. Lena and I talked about how much walking we both enjoy doing when traveling, but how we’re less likely to do so in our hometown. Hopefully I can do a bit more and actually embrace traveling close to home.</p>
<p><img src="/photos/me_hiking.jpg" alt="me"></p>
<p>Thanks again Lena for encouraging me to get out and walk!</p>
<p><img src="/photos/lena.jpg" alt="lena"></p>
<p>(I didn’t really edit these photos—all straight out of the JPEG processor of my <a href="https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2020-08-07-a-few-weeks-with-a/">new Ricoh GRIII</a>.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
