<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>queer on dill &amp; fennel</title>
    <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/queer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in queer on dill &amp; fennel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Copyright Brook Shelley 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.brookshelley.com/tags/queer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A letter</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-10-08-letter-to-myself/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-10-08-letter-to-myself/</guid>
      <description>(this is a very earnest post, and if you&amp;rsquo;re here for backpacks and travel, maybe skip this one)
Hey Brook,</description>
      <content:encoded><p>(this is a very earnest post, and if you&rsquo;re here for backpacks and travel, maybe skip this one)</p>
<p>Hey Brook,</p>
<p>This letter in a sci-fi tale would come to you out of the ether, dropping onto your iBook G3 on some particularly dark night of the soul. I&rsquo;m you, but 16 years older, and hopefully a little wiser.</p>
<p>(Spoiler alert)</p>
<p>The next few years will be a lot of fun, but also really, really tough. You will lose friends and family to cancer, then to divorce and&hellip;</p>
<p>You transition. You finally do it, and it goes mostly ok! You don&rsquo;t talk to family anymore, but you probably saw that coming, and it&rsquo;s fine because you have friends who love and support you.</p>
<p>Your finances will get worse for a while. Really bad. You&rsquo;re going to spend a little while sleeping in your car and on folks' couches. It sucks. You&rsquo;ll smoke too many cigarettes, and do some ridiculous stuff.</p>
<p>It works out.</p>
<p>Eventually, you get a job with folks who you really like, and they encourage you. You join a company that is doing amazing stuff with messaging (kind of like IRC, but way, way cooler—you&rsquo;ll see). After a year, you get a little bit of stock, and finally pay off your student loan debt that you&rsquo;ll have ground down for 13 years. It will feel great.</p>
<p>You&rsquo;ll see a therapist, and a doctor, and a dentist with a regular cadence. It will help. I promise.</p>
<p>You&rsquo;ll love, you&rsquo;ll lose, and you&rsquo;ll get back on that horse. Ultimately, you&rsquo;ll do a <em>lot</em> of reading and spend a lot of time with your best friend, a cat named Snorri. You and Snorri will travel from Austin, to Portland, to Oakland, with a <em>ton</em> of flights in between to Europe, Asia, Canada, and NYC.</p>
<p>I know what it feels like a lot of nights right now. It sucks. It&rsquo;s real, and you&rsquo;ve had a hard time. Most people you know won&rsquo;t get it, and you deserve better. When you get older you&rsquo;ll know more people who&rsquo;ve also gone through a lot of shit, and they&rsquo;ll be good listeners, and you&rsquo;ll listen a lot too. Don&rsquo;t stop loving, and don&rsquo;t stop trying to be open with your friends. It pays off more often than not. Your biggest asset is your heart. Don&rsquo;t lose it.</p>
<p>I love you, and I can&rsquo;t wait for you to get to where I am now. For all the good times, and the bad ones, just know I&rsquo;m here in the future cheering you on.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masterworks review</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-09-03-masterworks-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2019-09-03-masterworks-review/</guid>
      <description>I wish I knew more about art. Reading the titular story, I found myself reaching for my phone to understand each scene in the strange and delightful post-apocalyptic tale.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>I wish I knew more about art. Reading the titular story, I found myself reaching for my phone to understand each scene in the strange and delightful post-apocalyptic tale. As I held the painting in my mind, and explored the flooded wastes with Liam, Nell, and Co. I found myself enamored by the framing. How often are our relationships held together by a retelling of an old picture? Are we always trying to build a life out of the classics of our youth? There’s a survey of life, and an exploration of lost moments in these vignettes.</p>
<p>The opening tale of this collection plants us in Ohio, a place, we see, where even supportive friends or loved ones can’t save you from the yawning abyss. The suburban Olive Garden echoes in my mind with all the breadsticks I absorbed through my high school years. These youth were me, and the chasm felt real then too. From there, we follow a mother who lost a son, and a sliver of a life exploring a name—just enough of both to leave the reader wanting more. Then, a journey through art, mentioned above. It’s strange and beautiful, and a great opportunity to learn about the great works of fine art, if like this reviewer, you largely skipped-out on art class.</p>
<p>Finally, we readers are washed up on the shore, like so many dead fish, with a man watching a lodge, and time-displaced, dealing with an all-too-familiar moldy bathroom. A word of warning: if you’ve lived in the the Pacific Northwest, the squelch of wet tile will be all too real. This novella is reminiscent of Jack and the Beanstalk, or another fairy tale of exploring a new land. The phrase “crotchal belch” made me laugh out loud. There are so many great turns of phrase in Masterworks. The story propelled me forward, alternately laughing and cringing. I wanted the protagonist to seize his agency, and change in the ways he so clearly desired. I find these characters at turns fascinating and deeply frustrating. There were so many places where I yelled, “say something” in my head, but this isn’t a story of success, but learning and remembering.</p>
<p>On the whole, I loved this book. Masterworks, by Simon Jacobs, is a fantastic collection of imagination, and creative bombast. At times it leans into magical realism, in others outright fantasy. There a slightly disjointed nature to these stories, as they’re collected over years of writing, and lead me to hope Simon writes more—a novel perhaps—in the future.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Review of Invasions</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-10-14-invasions-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2018-10-14-invasions-review/</guid>
      <description>It begins with a rip, the tearing sound of velcro—mix and match nipples kick off this delightfully strange collection of speculative fiction, trans body-horror, and water-logged zombies.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>It begins with a rip, the tearing sound of velcro—mix and match nipples kick off this <a href="http://www.instarbooks.com/books/invasions.html">delightfully strange collection</a> of speculative fiction, trans body-horror, and water-logged zombies. Calvin impressed me last year with his part in <a href="https://medium.com/@brookshelley/a-review-of-meanwhile-elsewhere-166ec11bff7d">Meanwhile, Elsewhere</a>, revisited here as the excellent Rent, Don&rsquo;t Sell. This story explores a world in which bodies are traded for a time for fitness or fetish and how trans people deal with this faustian bargain. Another tale invites us to an isolated cabin for a wedding party that begins to fray at the edges in a blizzard. And, while every story isn&rsquo;t is a life-or-death one, but the weight of mortality permeates each page.</p>
<p>Whether the reader is wandering a bathhouse, stumbling through the streets, newly minted as a middle-aged-man, we are reminded each time that the world doesn&rsquo;t quite fit us. Invasions captures the feeling of being trans, even in innocuous settings. It&rsquo;s never Cronenberg, but regardless of how wild the twist, it&rsquo;s grounded and bodied in a way he couldn&rsquo;t imagine. Occasionally, a story follows an ostensibly cisgender person, to probe the space around a trans life, and to me these are the most speculative: &ldquo;What do they see in us? What do they think?&rdquo; To answer this question, one protagonist even employs a psychic talent to sift through memory and desire in those around him, even through their final moments.</p>
<p>This collection also challenges ideas around surgery, queer bodies, and perception. In Eternal Boy, we meet a queer person figuring out their gender, but at odds with their presentation as a boy; they&rsquo;re uncertain about the way women see them, but also willing to overlook those feelings for a chance to hook up. These characters are complicated; they&rsquo;re often anti-heroes, or even villains. We need more trans villains in a world of trans characters that are almost always a sob story or a heartwarming tale. I&rsquo;m here for the dirty, confused, angry, and alien.</p>
<p>One of closing stories is about a surgery center full of the wild variety of trans folks I&rsquo;ve met: from older late-transitioning women, to confident girls with their moms. Not content to let cis people be the only foil for trans protagonists, Calvin writes the interplay between intergenerational and intergender conflict and love wonderfully. On the heels of You Wouldn&rsquo;t Have Known is the more general body horror of pregnancy and a failure of the healthcare system.</p>
<p>Invasions is one of the best collections I&rsquo;ve read in quite some time, and I can&rsquo;t wait to see Calvin&rsquo;s next book or collection. <a href="http://www.instarbooks.com/books/invasions.html">Pick up a copy today</a>. This writer is one to watch, and tell your friends about—a real trans-writers-writer. He delivered on the promise of his story in Meanwhile, Elsewhere with gusto, and blew this reader away.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No cis men</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2016-04-15-no-cis-men/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2016-04-15-no-cis-men/</guid>
      <description>no cis men, says the sign on the door and i read, prove yourself are you woman enough to enter this building not woman like dresses but woman like a body you didn’t get for free the feeling that these spaces want to spit us out like we won’t be safe from the pain of judgement because it follows us in and comes out through their eyes</description>
      <content:encoded><p>no cis men, says the sign on the door
and i read, prove yourself
are you woman enough to enter this building
not woman like dresses
but woman like a body you didn’t get for free
the feeling that these spaces want to spit us out
like we won’t be safe from the pain of judgement
because it follows us in
and comes out through their eyes</p>
<p>do you see me?
do you see what I am trying to do?
who i am, and what i am
am i more to you than a token
or just a tragic figure
am i someone you could fuck
someone you could fall in love with
can i come to your party and feel at home?</p>
<p>they check my id and find the F
the sign they look for to say “you’re good”
but i see the glint of doubt in your eyes
when i say thanks and my voice sounds
just a little too deep
the foot to head look they give
doesn’t read as checking me out
so much as vetting my existence
i feel a shiver of fear, and swallow it down</p>
<p>i dance and flirt as armor against the other
this belonging feels like a battle
and i am not one to give up easy</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On being alone</title>
      <link>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2014-3-4-on-being-alone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.brookshelley.com/posts/2014-3-4-on-being-alone/</guid>
      <description>A bit about this last few months.
It first hit me the night she left. The quiet. Before, there was rustling in the house, subtle signs of her presence, affection in the same space.</description>
      <content:encoded><p>A bit about this last few months.</p>
<p>It first hit me the night she left. The quiet. Before, there was rustling in the house, subtle signs of her presence, affection in the same space. Now, the night was too quiet, her form did not move with breath next to me. I was alone. My cats tried to fill the void. The wandered, and meowed, and looked for her in closets and cabinets — or so it seemed to me, as I projected my sadness onto them.</p>
<p>We were together for 6 years, and that never gets easier to say. We married. We are still, as of now, married. We are lesbians, but we didn’t start off looking like that. We both moved fast, without asking the questions that may have avoided the heartache. It’s hard to ask those questions when you’re having such a good time. When I looked at her, I saw someone that I could spend my days with — could grow old with — could sit in silence on a long journey with or excitedly discuss one of our new projects. This soured.</p>
<p>Near the end, when I looked at her, I only saw pain. I was reminded of the anguish and agony of being unloved and unattractive. I didn’t know, I would say, what I did. But it was immaterial. There wasn’t <em>one</em> thing at all, rather, there were myriad difficulties and decisions and micro-agressions that led to our parting. I thought I would be willing to work on these problems, but she spared me the need. She just moved out… while I was on a video podcast. There was the briefest acknowledgement that this would be difficult, and then, as if she’d never been there, she was out of my house.</p>
<p>She said she’d never felt attraction for me, and that she probably had never been in love. It’s impossible for me to know if this is true, or just the result of years of cohabitation and the daily chore of partnership. I fear both the aloneness this made me feel, and the gaping maw of quiet and inner-dialogue that her leaving put me into. For me, I didn’t leave the partnership in time. My recovery will be a slow one.</p>
<p>The entire breakup happened at an incredibly inopportune time after a huge number of life changes were still settling. My relationships, even outside of that one, were in turmoil and freshness. I had experienced one of the most significant experiences through coming out as a lesbian, and as a trans woman, and many of my friends didn’t call so much afterwards. I found a new community, or at least other people I could relate to, through twitter. They were spread far and wide across American and Canada, and the flight miles I will rack up visiting them are immense. I don’t know if we are on twitter because we’re all alone together, or if our shared experiences and hurts are just too much to not have the 140 character pressure-release valve. Ultimately, I don’t like to question it too much. My friends are amazing now. I feel, finally, like a person that might be ok, someday.</p>
<p>The loneliness of a breakup is a special kind of bitterness. Nothing removes that taste, that tang of regret and sadness, except time. My apartment is filled with friends on occasion, but I still need someone to also call it home. It took months for me to be ok with the idea, but I am finding a roommate. Not a lover this time, or a girlfriend, but an actual roommate. This will be my first in seven years. This was also the first time I’ve lived alone. I hate it. I crave quiet and space at times, but in this void, I’ve sought nothing but noise and other living, breathing people. I want to crave quiet again. I want to argue over who does the dishes, and watch the worst shows on Netflix because we’re bored and lazy and maybe a little too drunk from brunch.</p>
<p>This quiet, this space, will be filled. My life will continue, and I will meet someone. I will meet someones awesome, possibly. We will talk and romance and date. Someday they will move in. I fear the cycle repeating, but it is a human cycle of death and rebirth. Of beginnings and endings. I am at a beginning.</p>
</content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
